<bill session="119" type="h" number="379" updated="2025-10-29T08:06:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthcare Freedom and Choice Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthcare Freedom and Choice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the rule relating to "Short-Term, Limited-Duration Insurance and Independent, Noncoordinated Excepted Benefits Coverage" (89 Fed. Reg. 23338 (April 3, 2024)) shall have no force or effect.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2025-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000595" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2025-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-24T20:09:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthcare Freedom and Choice Act

This bill nullifies a rule regarding short-term, limited-duration health insurance&#160;plans. The rule was promulgated by the Internal Revenue Service,&#160;Employee Benefits Security Administration, and Department of Health and Human Services; is titled&#160;Short-Term, Limited-Duration Insurance and Independent, Noncoordinated Excepted Benefits Coverage; and was published April 3, 2024.

Short-term, limited-duration health insurance plans are plans that may only offer coverage for a limited amount of time and are exempt from the market requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (e.g., coverage of individuals with preexisting conditions).

The rule limits the length of the initial contract period for such a plan to no more than three months and, taking into account any renewals or extensions, the maximum coverage period to no more than four months. The rule also includes within the maximum renewal period limitation a new plan sold by the same issuer, or any issuer that is a member of the same controlled group, to the same policyholder within a 12-month period.

Regulations in effect prior to the rule this bill nullifies permitted short-term, limited-duration health insurance plans with an initial contract period of fewer than 12 months and a maximum coverage period of up to 36 months, including renewals and extensions.</summary>
</bill>
