<bill session="109" type="h" number="5359" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:29Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the automobile fuel economy provisions of title 49, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to set fuel economy standards for passenger automobiles based on one or more vehicle attributes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the automobile fuel economy provisions of title 49, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to set fuel economy standards for passenger automobiles based on one or more vehicle attributes.</title>
    <title type="popular">Fuel Economy Standards bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000213"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 109-475.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-22" calendar="Union" number="263">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 263.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-07-06T14:26:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends federal transportation law to revise passenger automobile fuel economy standards (CAFE standards) to require that average fuel economy standards in effect for the preceding model year for a passenger automobile shall apply to such model year and beyond if the Secretary of Transportation does not prescribe new average fuel economy standards for a given model year. Authorizes the Secretary to prescribe regulations amending average fuel economy standards for passenger automobiles to a maximum feasible average fuel economy level that the Secretary decides automobile manufacturers can achieve in a model year based on one or more vehicle attributes related to fuel economy. (Currently, the Secretary can prescribe average fuel economy standards that the Secretary decides are the maximum feasible average fuel economy level for that model year). Eliminates the congressional approval requirement if the Secretary prescribes an amendment that makes an average fuel economy standard more stringent.

Directs the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to conduct a study, and report the results to Congress and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, on the effects of the requirement of separate fuel economy calculations for domestic and foreign automobiles.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-475</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
