<bill session="112" type="h" number="6127" updated="2019-11-15T21:01:01Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Liquidity Enhancement for Small Public Companies Act</title>
    <title type="display">Liquidity Enhancement for Small Public Companies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to enable national securities exchanges to provide financial incentives to market-makers that adhere to objective standards that increase the liquidity and depth of the public capital markets and promote enhanced trading and price-discovery for smaller public companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2012-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-12T20:56:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Liquidity Enhancement for Small Public Companies Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) from proposing, adopting, maintaining, or enforcing any rule, regulation, policy, or procedure that bars a national securities exchange from implementing a program under which either the exchange, an entity that lists securities on a national securities exchange, an entity determined appropriate by the SEC, or any other entity determined appropriate by a national securities exchange provides financial incentives to market makers that adhere to standards of market quality established by the rules of the exchange.

Prohibits a registered national securities association from adopting, maintaining, or proposing any rule, regulation, policy, or procedure that bars a national securities exchange from implementing a program under which the securities of an issuer determined appropriate by the SEC for listing on a national securities exchange provides financial incentives to market makers that adhere to standards of market quality established by the exchange.</summary>
</bill>
