<bill session="118" type="s" number="2388" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cybersecurity for Rural Water Systems Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cybersecurity for Rural Water Systems Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to establish a cybersecurity circuit rider program to provide cybersecurity-related technical assistance to certain entities that operate rural water or wastewater systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-14T15:46:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cybersecurity for Rural Water Systems Act 

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a cybersecurity circuit rider program to&#160;provide cybersecurity technical assistance for rural water and wastewater systems.

The program must be structured similarly to the USDA Circuit Rider Program. (Under this program, USDA&#160;provides technical assistance to rural water systems that serve areas with populations of 10,000 or fewer people and are experiencing day-to-day operational, financial, or managerial issues.)

Specifically, the cybersecurity circuit rider program must provide technical assistance to rural water or wastewater systems to

provide rapid assessments of the system's current ability or inability to respond to cybersecurity&#160;threats and&#160;protect cyber infrastructure,develop reasonable protocols to enhance&#160;cybersecurity protection,provide assistance to address inadequate cyber protection plans, anddocument a system's current state of water supply cyber protection.&#160;&#160;

&#160;

&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
