<bill session="118" type="h" number="3844" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sustainable Agriculture Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sustainable Agriculture Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to provide for an additional goal of the Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority (AGARDA) to enhance the role of agriculture in innovative sustainability solutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000474" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2023-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-05T19:58:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Sustainable Agriculture Research Act

This bill revises the goals of the Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority (AGARDA).

Specifically, the bill expands the goals to require AGARDA to enhance the role of sustainable agriculture in innovative voluntary resilience solutions in the United States through the development of agricultural technologies that may address

 the impact of extreme weather on crop production; the effects of drought and the potential of building water holding capacity in soils on croplands and rangelands; the expansion of the potential for long-term carbon storage through sustainable agriculture; increased economic and practical feasibility for renewable and sustainable energy on farms and in the agriculture industry; increased voluntary adoption of conservation practices that sequester carbon and build on-farm climate resilience; and increased economic and practical feasibility for, and voluntary adoption of, precision agriculture technology. The bill defines precision agriculture as managing, tracking, or reducing crop or livestock production inputs (including seed, feed, fertilizer, chemicals, water, and time) at a heightened level of spatial and temporal granularity to improve efficiencies, reduce waste, and maintain environmental quality.</summary>
</bill>
