<bill session="119" type="s" number="2995" updated="2025-10-24T13:31:47Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shutdown Guidance for Financial Institutions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shutdown Guidance for Financial Institutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal financial regulators to issue guidance encouraging financial institutions to work with consumers and businesses affected by a Federal Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2025-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5689" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-24T13:30:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shutdown Guidance for Financial Institutions Act 

This bill directs financial regulators&#226;&#8364;&#8221;including the Federal Reserve Board, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration&#226;&#8364;&#8221;to jointly issue guidance relating to a government shutdown.

Specifically, financial regulators must issue guidance encouraging financial institutions to

work with consumers and businesses affected by a shutdown,recognize that consumers and businesses affected by a shutdown may lose access to credit and face temporary hardship in making payments on debts,consider efforts to modify terms on existing loans or extend new credit to assist consumers and businesses affected by a shutdown, andtake steps to prevent adverse credit information from being reported in a manner that harms consumers affected by a shutdown.In addition, financial regulators must jointly issue a press release to notify financial institutions, consumers, and businesses&#160;of this guidance in the event of a government shutdown.

Financial regulators must also complete a report after a government shutdown regarding the guidance's effectiveness and update the guidance if any shortcoming are identified in the report.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
