<bill session="118" type="s" number="2413" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RINA</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regional Integration and Normalization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RINA</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand and strengthen the Abraham Accords and the Negev Forum, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2023-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2023-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-01T16:30:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Regional Integration and Normalization Act of 2023 or RINA

This bill requires and authorizes actions to support the Abraham Accords and the Negev Forum. (The Abraham Accords are agreements to normalize or improve relations between Israel and four members of the Arab League: the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, Morocco, and Sudan. The Negev Forum is a framework for cooperation in the Middle East and North Africa involving several countries including Israel, Egypt, Morocco, and the United States.)

The bill establishes within the Department of State the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for the Abraham Accords, Negev Forum, and Related Integration and Normalization Fora and Agreements. The office's responsibilities include (1) leading diplomatic efforts to strengthen and expand the Negev Forum and the Abraham Accords, and (2) implementing U.S. policy to expand normalization within the Middle East and North Africa.

The bill also authorizes activities related to the Abraham Accords and the Negev Forum, such as (1) expanding the participation of Negev Forum countries in the Middle East Desalination Research Center; (2) supporting interfaith dialogue between Abraham Accords countries, Negev Forum countries, and other relevant actors; (3) expanding educational and cultural exchange programs; and (4) authorizing grants for initiatives to facilitate scientific and industrial research cooperation between the relevant countries.

Furthermore, the bill establishes within the State Department the Young Middle East Leaders Initiative to build the capacity of young leaders in Negev Forum countries to address issues such as energy diversification, education and coexistence, and regional security.</summary>
</bill>
