<bill session="116" type="s" number="5031" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Progressive Consumption Tax Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Progressive Consumption Tax Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a progressive consumption tax and to reform the income tax, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7544-7553" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7544-7553" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax treatment of families"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-09T19:21:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Progressive Consumption Tax Act of 2020

This bill revises the federal income tax system by, among other things, imposing a 10% consumption tax on specified supply items, including (1) the sale or provision of property; (2) the performance of services; (3) the grant, assignment, or surrender of real property; (4) the creation, grant, transfer, assignment, or surrender of any right; (5) financial supplies; and (6) entry into, or release from, an obligation or agreement to perform or refrain from performing an act. The bill specifies certain exempt supplies to which the tax does not apply.

The bill reduces to three the number of brackets for the individual income tax and reduces the income tax rate to a maximum level of 28%. It treats long-term capital gains and dividends as ordinary income.

It also provides for a family allowance based on filing status.

The bill repeals limitations on certain itemized tax deductions and restores previously repealed tax deductions, including the deductions for state and local taxes and personal casualty losses. It eliminates the alternative minimum tax.

The bill reduces the corporate income tax rate to 17%.</summary>
</bill>
