<bill session="119" type="s" number="854" updated="2025-11-18T19:41:01Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Risky Research Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Risky Research Review Act</title>
    <title type="display">Risky Research Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to establish the Life Sciences Research Security Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2025-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Paul without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="164">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 164.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1864" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-14T19:52:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Risky Research Review Act

This bill establishes the Life Sciences Research Security Board to oversee the award of federal funding for high-risk life sciences research.&#160;High-risk life sciences research means&#160;the study of an organism,&#160;virus, or related product that could be misapplied to pose a significant threat to the public or could enhance the transmissibility or&#160;virulence of certain high-risk&#160;pathogens (e.g., Ebola).

Specifically, the bill establishes the board as an independent agency that must review proposed high-risk life sciences research, determine whether a federal agency may award funding for the research, and determine minimum required controls for funded research. Entities that are seeking federal funding must attest to whether their research is high-risk life sciences research. Agencies must certify the validity of these attestations and submit proposed high-risk life sciences research to the board. Agencies must also notify the board of intended awards for other life sciences research for potential review.&#160;

In making&#160;its determinations, the board must consider specified&#160;factors,&#160;including whether the benefits of the research outweigh the&#160;risks. The bill prohibits agencies from awarding federal funding for high-risk life sciences research without approval of the board or for life sciences research currently under board review. The board may also&#160;review awards that were made&#160;before the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment.

Entities that fail to properly&#160;attest to the nature of their research may lose their eligibility for funding. Additionally, agency employees who fail to comply with the bill's requirements are subject to disciplinary action.</summary>
</bill>
