<bill session="116" type="h" number="9005" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Workforce Diversity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Workforce Diversity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to Hispanic-serving institutions, historically Black colleges and universities, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions, Tribal Colleges or Universities, regional community-based organizations, and national minority medical associations, for counseling, mentoring and providing information on financial assistance to prepare underrepresented minority individuals to enroll in and graduate from health professional schools and to increase services for underrepresented minority students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000586"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6637" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8200" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4819" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-03T16:37:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Workforce Diversity Act

This bill requires the Health Resources and Services Administration to support diversity in the health care workforce, including by awarding grants to minority-serving colleges and universities and other organizations to prepare minority individuals underrepresented in the health care workforce to enroll in health professional schools.</summary>
</bill>
