<bill session="118" type="h" number="2751" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to increase participation in community solar programs and the receipt of associated benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2023-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5259" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-10T17:10:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2023

This bill sets forth provisions that support access to community solar energy and increases the allowable time period for a long-term contract between the General Services Administration (GSA) and a public utility.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a program to increase access to community solar energy programs for individuals, businesses, nonprofit organizations, states, local governments, and tribal governments. In addition, DOE must, to the extent practicable, expand existing grant, loan, and financing programs to include community solar programs.

Further, the bill modifies requirements under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 for electric utilities, including by requiring each electric utility to offer a community solar program that provides all ratepayers, including low-income ratepayers, equitable and demonstrable access to such program.

Finally, the bill allows the GSA to make a public utility contract for a period of up to 30 years. Currently, the GSA may make a public utility contract for up to 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
