<bill session="119" type="s" number="1213" updated="2025-11-19T03:33:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Elections from Deceptive AI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Elections from Deceptive AI Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the distribution of materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media relating to candidates for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2025-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5272" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-01T20:45:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect Elections from Deceptive AI Act

This bill prohibits the distribution of materially deceptive audio or visual media that is generated by artificial intelligence (AI) relating to federal candidates.

The bill generally prohibits individuals, political committees, and other entities from knowingly distributing materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media in carrying out a federal election activity or of a federal candidate for the purpose of&#160;(1) influencing an election, or (2) soliciting funds. This prohibition does not apply to certain entities, such as radio or television broadcasting stations that broadcast such media with disclosures as part of a bona fide newscast.

The bill also permits a federal candidate whose voice or likeness appears in such materially deceptive AI-generated audio or visual media to bring a civil action for injunctive relief or damages.</summary>
</bill>
