<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="695" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:32Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2829" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-03-09T13:51:13-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000517"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy to provide for a corporation to-- (A) advise States on establishing laws and policies to address alcohol and other drug issues, based on the model State drug laws developed by the President's Commission on Model State Drug Laws in 1993; and (B) revise such model State drug laws and draft supplementary model State laws to take into consideration changes in the alcohol and drug abuse problems in the State involved.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in House Report 109-387 to require the Director of ONDCP to provide for a program that advises states on establishing laws and policies to address alcohol and other drug issues, as well as drafting and revising model state drug laws. The amendment authorizes $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011 for that purpose.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-03-09T13:51:13-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lungren, Daniel E. amendment (A010) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09T13:46:47-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Lungren, Daniel E..</text>
      <reference ref="CR H833-834" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H833" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09T13:46:47-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Lungren, Daniel E..</text>
      <reference ref="CR H833-834" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H833" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09T13:51:13-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09T13:51:13-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lungren, Daniel E. amendment (A010) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
