<bill session="118" type="h" number="598" updated="2024-11-19T09:05:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Earth Act to Stop Climate Pollution by 2030</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Earth Act to Stop Climate Pollution by 2030</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure 100 percent renewable electricity, zero emission vehicles, and regenerative agriculture by 2030 to address global warming caused by human activity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2023-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2023-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2024-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2023-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2023-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2023-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000617" joined="2023-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2024-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2023-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-24T12:58:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Earth Act to Stop Climate Pollution by 2030

This bill addresses climate change by establishing requirements concerning renewable energy, zero emission vehicles, regenerative agriculture, and tax incentives related to climate transition costs. Specifically, the bill requires that by 2030, 100% of

 electricity sold by certain retail electric suppliers must be from renewable energy resources (e.g., wind energy); new motor vehicles (e.g., certain cars and trucks) sold by manufacturers must be zero emission vehicles; land and livestock managed by certain publicly-traded corporations must be managed with regenerative agricultural practices. The Department of Energy (DOE), the Department of Transportation, and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must create grants to pay up to 50% of the costs of meeting those requirements.

DOE must also issue regulations regarding the sourcing, recycling, and disposal of materials used to manufacture renewable energy sources (e.g., equipment that stores renewable energy). The goals of the regulations must be to (1) eliminate the use of rare earth metals in the manufacture of those sources, and (2) ensure the recycling of all such materials.

USDA must issue regulations that (1) require the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions resulting from certain land or livestock corporations, and (2) ensure the well-being of animals raised for human consumption or the production of dairy products.

The bill also provides tax incentives for electric suppliers, vehicle manufacturers, and such corporations to meet the requirements established by this bill by allowing them to double certain tax deductions for qualified capital climate transitions costs.</summary>
</bill>
