<bill session="119" type="s" number="190" updated="2025-10-16T21:26:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Pacific Research Board Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">North Pacific Research Board Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="display">North Pacific Research Board Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the operations of the North Pacific Research Board.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2025-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cruz with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 119-80.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-10-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="189">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 189.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-17T20:14:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">North Pacific Research Board Enhancement Act

This bill makes certain changes to the North Pacific Research Board, including changes to the board&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s composition and allocations for funding for administrative expenses. The board sets research priorities and administers grants to support research on fisheries and marine ecosystems in the waters surrounding Alaska.

Specifically, this bill adds to the board one additional member to represent Alaska Natives. This board member must have personal knowledge of and direct experience with subsistence uses of resources (the practice of relying on the surrounding environment as a source of food and material). The bill also imposes a three-year term limit on those board members representing fishing interests and Alaska Natives, and permits such members to serve one additional term upon reappointment.

With respect to funding, under current law the board may use up to 15% of grant&#160;program&#160;funding for administrative expenses (e.g., support for the board and grant administration). Under the bill, if the program's total funding in a given fiscal year is less than its total funding in the prior fiscal year, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration may increase the 15% cap on administrative expenses for that fiscal year. Any such increase must prioritize supporting the board&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s continued operation, maximizing funds directed to research, and maintaining high-quality grant administration. Further, the bill waives the 15% cap altogether for five years following the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-80</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
