<bill session="108" type="h" number="3334" updated="2023-01-15T07:32:52Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-21T14:41:47-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-21T14:41:47-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Riverside-Corona Feeder Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design and construction of the Riverside-Corona Feeder in cooperation with the Western Municipal Water District of Riverside, California.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Riverside-Corona Feeder Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2003-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000274" joined="2003-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-643.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-07" calendar="Union" number="387">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 387.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21T14:38:18-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21T14:38:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7261" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21T14:38:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3334.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-21T14:41:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7261" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21T14:41:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wells"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-10T19:27:43Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 7, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the Western Municipal Water District, to participate in a project to plan, design, and construct the Riverside-Corona Feeder, which includes 20 groundwater wells and 28 miles of pipeline in San Bernardino and Riverside Counties, California. Limits the Federal share of the cost to: (1) plan, design, and construct the project to the lesser of 35 percent of the project's total cost or $50 million; and (2) complete the necessary planning study associated with the project to 50 percent of the total study cost. Directs that in-kind services performed by the District be considered a part of the local cost share to complete the project.

Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary to participate in the design, planning, and construction of: (1) projects to treat impaired surface water, reclaim and reuse impaired groundwater, and provide brine disposal within the Santa Ana Watershed, in cooperation with the Yucaipa Valley Water District; and (2) a project to reclaim and reuse wastewater, including degraded groundwaters, within and outside of the service area of the City of Corona Water Utility, in cooperation with the City of Corona Water Utility. Limits the Federal share of each of the project costs to 25 percent.

Prohibits the Secretary from using or providing funds under this Act for project operation or maintenance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-643</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
