<bill session="108" type="h" number="4550" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:13Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe, Efficient, Coordinated, Unified, Revitalized, Enhanced Visa Waiver Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To secure the visa waiver program under section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe, Efficient, Coordinated, Unified, Revitalized, Enhanced Visa Waiver Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000424"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001050" joined="2004-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2004-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000392" joined="2004-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2004-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001148" joined="2004-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2004-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000044" joined="2004-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Terminals (Transportation)"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-28T18:17:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe, Efficient, Coordinated, Unified, Revitalized, Enhanced Visa Waiver Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish an electronic system that requires aliens seeking entry to the United States under the visa waiver program (VWP) to submit biographical information prior to embarkation. Requires such system to: (1) make electronic determinations of eligibility for admission within 30 minutes; (2) require carriers and other corporations providing transportation to inquire electronically, prior to embarkation, whether the alien has been determined eligible for admission and to respond to such inquiries within 90 seconds; and (3) be deployed as soon as possible.

Requires the Secretary: (1) to charge a fee to VWP aliens that ensures the recovery of the full costs of establishing and operating the system; and (2) in developing the system, to consult with and allow for review by a private sector group consisting of experts in travel, tourism, privacy, national security, or computer security issues.

Amends the Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act to extend by one year: (1) the deadline for installing equipment and software at U.S. ports of entry to allow biometric comparison and authentication of machine-readable passports issued by VWP countries; and (2) the deadline for VWP aliens to present such passports.

Authorizes the Secretary to grant up to two extensions of the new deadlines where the VWP country is making substantial progress toward issuing machine-readable, tamper-resistant passports that incorporate biometric and document authentication identifiers.</summary>
</bill>
