<bill session="112" type="h" number="6404" updated="2020-02-10T16:50:31Z">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delphi Pensions Restoration Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Delphi Pensions Restoration Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make available funds from the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 for funding pension benefits with respect to former employees of Delphi Corporation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2012-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3544" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-10-16T15:03:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Delphi Pensions Restoration Act of 2012 - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to require transfer to the Delphi Retired Employees Fund of all proceeds from the sale or transfer, after enactment of this Act, of any stock, warrant, or financial instrument acquired by the Secretary of the Treasury in connection with providing financial assistance to the General Motors Corporation (GM).

Establishes the Delphi Retired Employees Fund in the Treasury for payments to eligible employees separated from Delphi Corporation who participated in a now terminated Delphi-sponsored defined benefit plan, but who are not covered by any agreement between GM and participants in another defined benefit plan under which GM pays covered participants nonforfeitable benefits equal to the amount they would have been entitled to receive under the plan but for the plan's termination.

Makes the Fund available to pay each eligible separated employee an amount equal to such nonforfeitable benefits, reduced by any amounts already paid the employee by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) under the Employee Retirement Security Act of 1974 (ERISA).</summary>
</bill>
