<bill session="118" type="sr" number="934" updated="2025-08-26T21:38:31Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-18">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution amending the broadcasting and recording procedures of the Senate.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution amending the broadcasting and recording procedures of the Senate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2024-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7171" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7182-7183" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-26T21:38:05Z" status="Passed Senate">This resolution amends the Senate floor broadcasting and recording procedures.

Specifically, the resolution applies the existing television and radio procedures more broadly to broadcasting and recording. The resolution also removes references to the original broadcast pilot program.

Among other things, the resolution generally maintains the requirements that

broadcast coverage and recordings provide&#160;continuous, gavel-to-gavel coverage of Senate floor proceedings;video broadcast coverage&#160;follows the individuals who are speaking, except during roll call votes, when the cameras must show the entire chamber;the Committee on Rules and Administration provide oversight for broadcast coverage and recordings of Senate proceedings;the Senate Recording Studio administers the recording of coverage, under the direction of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate;broadcast coverage be available on a live basis and free of charge for news-gathering,&#160;educational, or information&#160;distribution entities; andthe use of recorded footage for political campaign purposes is prohibited.</summary>
</bill>
