<bill session="111" type="h" number="5068" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:07Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Surplus Uranium Disposition Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to barter, transfer, or sell surplus uranium from the inventory of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surplus Uranium Disposition Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2010-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3233" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-01T20:39:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Surplus Uranium Disposition Act of 2010 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to barter, transfer, or sell uranium to eligible entities at fair market value.

Requires eligible entities to: (1) obtain a combined operating license for a reactor approved by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC); and (2) possess a license from the NRC in order to obtain uranium under this Act.

Requires the Secretary of Energy to offer to barter, transfer, or sell to eligible entities, on a first-come, first-served basis and at fair market value, 20 million pounds of uranium for initial cores for projects to build new reactors.

Authorizes the Secretary to barter, transfer, or sell uranium to eligible entities on a first-come, first-served basis, at fair market value following a prescribed schedule for 2010-2013 and subsequent years.

Requires a recipient to sell such uranium at fair market value.

Prohibits the use of funds or other value obtained from the barter, transfer, or sale of uranium, without a specific appropriation by Congress, to implement other programs of the Department of Energy (DOE).

 Requires the Secretary to: (1) maintain a sufficient inventory of uranium to meet current and foreseeable needs of the missions and programs of DOE and designated agencies; and (2) maintain a reserve inventory of uranium that contains at least 20 million pounds of uranium.

Permits the Secretary to release uranium from the reserve inventory only if a national energy emergency is declared by the President.</summary>
</bill>
