<bill session="117" type="h" number="6217" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:04Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Access to Affordable Credit for Small Businesses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Access to Affordable Credit for Small Businesses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to license lending institutions to make loans under section 7(a) of the Small Business Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2021-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2690" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T18:45:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Access to Affordable Credit for Small Businesses Act

This bill establishes rules related to the authorization of lending institutions (including banks, small business lending companies, non-federally regulated lenders, and non-depository lending institutions) to make loans under the 7(a) Program of the Small Business Administration (SBA). Under the 7(a) Program, the SBA provides business loans and loan guaranties to small business borrowers unable to obtain financing elsewhere.

Specifically, the SBA must ensure that these lending institutions and other entities (1) provide an independent audit that examines adherence to all applicable federal laws and regulations regarding anti-money laundering, counterterrorist financing, sanctions, and financial crimes; and (2) implement a compliance program that is designed to conform with relevant anti-money laundering laws and regulations.</summary>
</bill>
