<bill session="118" type="h" number="1682" updated="2025-11-19T01:43:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide consumer protections for students.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="889" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-22T19:58:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Students from Worthless Degrees Act

This bill makes an institution of higher education (IHE) ineligible to receive federal student financial assistance if it fails to meet certain requirements. It also requires an IHE to make certain certifications about its gainful employment programs.

Specifically, an IHE that offers a degree or certificate program to prepare students for entry into a profession that requires licensing or certification as a precondition for entry is not eligible to receive any federal student financial assistance unless (1) a student is fully qualified to take the required entry examination or be licensed or certified for the profession upon the successful completion of the program, and (2) the institution provides timely placement for all of the academically related pre-licensure requirements for entry into the profession (e.g., clinical placements or internships).

An IHE must also certify that each eligible gainful employment program meets specified requirements, including approval or accreditation by a recognized agency and satisfaction of applicable educational prerequisites for professional licensure or certification. If an IHE does not satisfy such prerequisites, it must notify a student who intends to enroll in the program and obtain a handwritten acknowledgement from the student that they wish to enroll.

Lastly, an IHE that offers distance education or correspondence courses must be legally authorized within each state in which its enrolled students are located.</summary>
</bill>
