<bill session="108" type="h" number="1299" updated="2023-01-15T22:33:36Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hydrogen Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Spark M. Matsunaga Hydrogen Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1990, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydrogen Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydrogen Fuel Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000586"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-17T17:02:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Hydrogen Fuel Act of 2003, or Hydrogen Act - Amends the Spark M. Matsunaga Hydrogen Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1990 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to: (1) prepare a comprehensive interagency coordination plan for research, development, and demonstration programs and activities designated under such Act; and (2) conduct a program to transfer technology to the private sector in order to foster the exchange of generic, nonproprietary information and technology developed under this Act among industry, academia, and the Federal Government.

Declares that the goals of the research and development program are to enable: (1) a decision by automakers by 2015 to offer affordable and technically viable hydrogen fuel cell vehicles in the mass consumer market; and (2) production and delivery to consumers of model year 2020 hydrogen fuel cell vehicles meeting specified requirements.

Instructs the Secretary to conduct a research and development and demonstration programs for: (1) hydrogen infrastructure; (2) fuel cells and fuel cell technologies including hydrogen-powered fuel cell vehicles; and (3) hydrogen codes, standards, and safety protocols. Prescribes implementation guidelines.

Directs the President to establish an interagency task force to: (1) address development of designated hydrogen infrastructure, fuel cells in government applications, and vehicle hydrogen fuel system integrity safety; and (2) coordinate interagency programs and activities, including information exchange.

Replaces the Hydrogen Technnical Advisory Panel with the Hydrogen Technical and Fuel Cell Advisory Committee to advise the Secretary on the programs and activities under such Act.

Repeals the Hydrogen Future Act of 1996.</summary>
</bill>
