<bill session="118" type="s" number="4912" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2024-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BITCOIN Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BITCOIN Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boosting Innovation, Technology, and Competitiveness through Optimized Investment Nationwide Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Strategic Bitcoin Reserve and other programs to ensure the transparent management of Bitcoin holdings of the Federal Government, to offset costs utilizing certain resources of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-19T16:40:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Boosting Innovation, Technology, and Competitiveness through Optimized Investment Nationwide Act of 2024 or the BITCOIN Act of 2024

This bill provides for the acquisition and storage of the cryptocurrency Bitcoin by the U.S. government.

The Department of the Treasury must purchase one million Bitcoins over a five-year period and hold the Bitcoins in trust for the United States. All Bitcoins acquired under this bill must be held for at least 20 years unless used to retire outstanding federal debt.

The bill directs Treasury to establish a Strategic Bitcoin Reserve for the secure storage of U.S. Bitcoins. The reserve must be a decentralized network of secure facilities across the United States. Existing U.S.&#160;Bitcoin holdings must be transferred to the reserve.&#160;States may voluntarily store Bitcoin holdings in the reserve in segregated accounts.

The bill also reduces the total amount of U.S. dollars Federal Reserve banks may hold in surplus and requires Federal Reserve banks to remit a certain amount of net earnings annually to the purchase of Bitcoins.</summary>
</bill>
