<bill session="109" type="h" number="1540" updated="2019-11-15T21:33:26Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drinking Water Standards Preservation Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Drinking Water Standards Preservation Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide procedures for claims relating to drinking water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001139"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2005-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000074" joined="2005-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU09" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF15" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-19T14:41:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Drinking Water Standards Preservation Act of 2005 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to establish liability standards for a public water system for damages arising from injury (including personal injury, death, or property damage) allegedly caused by delivery of contaminated water containing either regulated or unregulated contaminants. Requires for both regulated and unregulated contaminants that the plaintiff establish that there is substantial scientific evidence that the kind of injury alleged could be caused by such substance in the amounts present and that the substance did, in fact, cause the injury. Requires proof: (1) in the case of regulated contaminants, that the water system violated the regulation, was negligent and that the violation caused the injury; and (2) in the case of unregulated contaminants, that the water system knew or should have known that the substance at that level was likely to cause such injury and that it was feasible to remove the contaminant to a safe level. Directs the court to make determinations regarding proof requirements in a special pretrial proceeding and to give binding effect to any findings of fact, conclusions of law, or determinations of State agencies exercising primary enforcement authority.</summary>
</bill>
