<bill session="116" type="s" number="2131" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Investment to Grow Manufacturing in America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Investment to Grow Manufacturing in America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to increase access to capital for small business concerns that are manufacturers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2019-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3730" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-28T18:20:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Investment to Grow Manufacturing in America Act

This bill provides incentives, investment, and resources for U.S. small manufacturers.

Specifically, the bill increases the maximum loan guarantee rate for Small Business Association (SBA) loans to manufacturers, and it increases the limit for loans to be used for plant acquisition, construction, conversion, and expansion.

The bill also eliminates guarantee fees paid by small manufacturers for loans under $350,000 and reduces the fees on loans over that amount. For acquisition and construction loans, the bill reduces the financing requirement for small manufacturers and increases the allowable debt refinancing for facility expansions. Small manufacturers are further authorized to lease a greater percentage of their facility to obtain financing.

In addition, the bill authorizes discount debentures to manufacturers and provides leverage capacity in the Small Business Investment Company program for investments in small manufacturers (1) in low or moderate income areas, rural areas, or areas of high unemployment; or (2) that are veteran-, minority-, or women-owned, have demonstrated employment growth, or are vital to national security.

The bill further directs the SBA to use its existing resources to provide training and education to small manufacturers on how to navigate application processes for receiving assistance from SBA programs. Lastly, the bill directs the SBA to ensure its business loan programs provide adequate support for innovative technologies in manufacturing.</summary>
</bill>
