<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>986</number>
    <updateDate>2024-07-24T15:23:03Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2024-07-24T15:23:03Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2023-03-27</introducedDate>
    <congress>118</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2023-03-27T21:18:30Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-03-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-03-27</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000367</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Klobuchar, Amy [D-MN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Amy</firstName>
        <lastName>Klobuchar</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001047</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Capito, Shelley Moore [R-WV]</fullName>
        <firstName>Shelley</firstName>
        <lastName>Capito</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>WV</state>
        <middleName>Moore</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2023-03-27</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
        <updateDate>2023-04-20T15:15:16Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2023-03-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2023-10-16T16:42:07Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>STOP Act 2.0</b></p> <p>This bill revises requirements related to advance electronic data (AED) on international mail shipments. (The STOP Act of 2018 requires international mail shipments coming into the United States to have AED to address the threat of synthetic opioids and other dangerous items.)</p> <p>Specifically, the bill establishes a new criminal penalty for knowingly misrepresenting the country of origin of an international mail shipment in order to avoid AED requirements.</p> <p>Additionally, five years after enactment, the bill terminates U.S. Customs and Border Protection's authority to exclude countries from AED requirements.</p> <p>The bill establishes additional reporting requirements related to AED, including a requirement for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to report the results of randomized tests of packages entering the United States.</p> <p>Further, the bill authorizes DHS, the Department of Justice, and the U.S. Postal Service to enter into partnerships with private parcel services or other private information technology entities to develop technology and processes for identifying the origin of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances. </p> <p>The bill also authorizes DHS to share with and receive information from foreign governments regarding (1) shippers with a history of transporting illegal substances, and (2) best practices for detecting the substances. </p> <p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection must train its officers in detecting illicit fentanyl and other synthetic opioids.</p> <p>Finally, the bill directs the Government Accountability Office to evaluate the implementation of the STOP Act of 2018.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>STOP Act 2.0</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>STOP Act 2.0</title>
        <updateDate>2024-07-24T15:23:03Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>STOP Act 2.0</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:41:20Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to increase the criminal penalty for mail fraud involving misrepresentation of the country of origin, to terminate the authority to exclude countries from the requirement to transmit advance electronic information for 100 percent of mail shipments under the STOP Act of 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-04-12T02:59:05Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2023-03-27T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-118s986is/xml/BILLS-118s986is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2023-03-27</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
