<bill session="117" type="h" number="4107" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify and reform rules relating to investigations and whistleblowers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">IRS Whistleblower Program Improvement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRS Whistleblower Program Improvement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2021-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2055" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-13T19:21:37Z" status="Introduced in House">IRS Whistleblower Program Improvement Act of 2021

This bill modifies provisions of the Internal Revenue Code relating to whistleblower protections. Specifically, the bill

 revises the standard for review of whistleblower awards in the Tax Court to require a de novo review standard (currently, the standard is abuse of discretion); exempts whistleblower awards from reductions due to budget sequestration; establishes a rebuttable presumption that whistleblowers would suffer harm if their identities were disclosed in a Tax Court proceeding; modifies the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) whistleblower report to require inclusion of a list and description of the top 10 tax avoidance schemes disclosed by whistleblowers; requires the IRS to pay interest on whistleblower awards if not paid within one year of receipt of proceeds collected from whistleblower disclosures, allows the IRS to retain 3% of whistleblower proceeds (up to $10 million) to pay administrative costs of the whistleblower program; and allows payment of the attorney fees of whistleblowers regardless of whether the whistleblower award was paid through the mandatory or the discretionary whistleblower award program.</summary>
</bill>
