<bill session="116" type="h" number="244" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing Conservation and Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To maximize land management efficiencies, promote land conservation, generate education funding, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Advancing Conservation and Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Conservation and Education Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-14">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-639.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-14" calendar="Union" number="524">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 524.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-04T18:41:33Z" status="Reported to House">Advancing Conservation and Education Act

 This bill allows the states of Alaska, Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, New Mexico, North Dakota, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming (western states) to relinquish state land grant parcels wholly or primarily within eligible areas and select, in exchange, public land within the state.

The bill defines eligible areas as lands within the outer boundaries of units or components of the National Park, National Wilderness Preservation, National Wildlife Refuge, or National Landscape Conservation Systems, areas identified by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior through a inventory carried out in accordance with the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (FLPMA) as having wilderness characteristics as of the enactment of this bill or in a land use plan that was finalized under the FLPMA, certain designated lands within the National Forest System or administered by the BLM, and sentinel landscapes designated by the Department of Agriculture, Department of Defense, or Interior.

 Interior shall create a process for the relinquishment of such parcels.

 A western state may select, and Interior may convey, lands that are mineral in character.

 The overall value of the state land grant parcels and the public land to be conveyed shall be equal or made equal.

The bill sets forth requirements regarding hazardous materials on land to be conveyed, water rights, grazing permits, road rights-of-ways, and protection of Indian rights.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-639</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
