<bill session="110" type="s" number="2620" updated="2022-02-03T05:12:46Z">
  <state datetime="2008-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for a temporary increase of the Federal medical assistance percentage under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a temporary increase of the Federal medical assistance percentage under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2008-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2008-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2008-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="5268" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-03-07T20:12:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Provides that, if the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) determined under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act without regard to this Act for a state for FY2008 is less than the FMAP as so determined for FY2007, the FY2007 FMAP shall be substituted for the FMAP for the third and fourth calendar quarters of FY2008, before the application of this Act.

Provides that, if the FMAP determined without regard to this Act for a state for FY2009 is less than the FMAP as so determined for FY2008, the FY2008 FMAP shall be substituted for the FMAP for the first, second, and third calendar quarters of FY2009, before the application of this Act.

Provides that, for each eligible state for the third and fourth calendar quarters of FY2008, and for the first, second, and third calendar quarters of FY2009, the FMAP shall be increased by 2.95 percentage points.

Provides for an increase in the cap on Medicaid payments to Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.</summary>
</bill>
