<bill session="118" type="h" number="5705" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AACCENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AACCENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Augmentative and Alternative Communication Centers of Excellence and National Technical Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Nogales Wastewater Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support national training, technical assistance, and resource centers, to ensure that all individuals with significant expressive communication disabilities have access to the augmentative and alternative communication the individuals need to interact with others, in order to learn, work, socialize, and take advantage of all aspects of life in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2023-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4643" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="128" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2904" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-17T19:52:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Augmentative and Alternative Communication Centers of Excellence and National Technical Assistance Act or the AACCENT Act

This bill establishes a grant program to create national resource centers on augmentative and alternative communication.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to award three grants in geographically diverse regions to establish a network of these resource centers for individuals with significant expressive communication disabilities, particularly through improved access to tools, technologies, strategies, training, and other methods.

Significant expressive communication disabilities are communication disabilities (other than communication disabilities that are primarily visual or auditory in nature) that prevent or significantly limit an individual from understanding or being understood using spoken words.

Nogales Wastewater Improvement Act of 2023

The bill also establishes requirements to address wastewater from the International Outfall Interceptor, which is a pipeline that carries wastewater from the United States-Mexico border to the Nogales International Wastewater Treatment Plant. The plant, which is located in Rio Rico, Arizona, treats sewage and wastewater originating from Nogales, Mexico, and Nogales, Arizona.

The bill transfers the ownership, operations, and maintenance of the pipeline from the city of Nogales, Arizona, to the U.S. Section of the International Boundary and Water Commission. The commission must construct, operate, and maintain a debris screen at the pipeline's Manhole One for intercepting debris and drugs coming into the United States from Nogales, Mexico.

The bill also limits the portion of the costs that the city of Nogales, Arizona, must pay for the Nogales sanitation project.</summary>
</bill>
