<bill session="116" type="h" number="8390" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require the Director of the National Science Foundation to establish a grant program to make grants to eligible entities to develop instructional content on artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the National Science Foundation to establish a grant program to make grants to eligible entities to develop instructional content on artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2020-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-02T17:02:40Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the National Science Foundation (NSF), beginning not later than January 1, 2022, to award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities (e.g. a state research agency, a federal research agency, and an institution of higher education) to research the development of instructional content for teachers of a public elementary school or secondary school in accordance with a comprehensive and structured series of exercises (1) appropriate to each grade level; and (2) designed to convey the principles behind, mechanics of, and societal implications or ethics of the use of artificial intelligence; and (3) provide teaching instructions for teachers at elementary schools or secondary schools on such mechanisms when needed.

The NSF shall establish, and appoint individuals to, a review board to select the grant recipients.

The bill includes as a mathematics and science teacher, with respect to the Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship Program, a teacher at an elementary school or secondary school who instructs from a curriculum that incorporates, to a substantial degree, quantitative data analysis.</summary>
</bill>
