<bill session="118" type="h" number="6066" updated="2025-01-07T14:27:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HATIKVAHH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Halting Appropriations for Terrorist-supporting Institutions that Knowingly provide Valued Assets to Hamas and Hezbollah Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HATIKVAHH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit funding to international organizations that provide resources or other support to foreign terrorist organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-07T14:27:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Halting Appropriations for Terrorist-supporting Institutions that Knowingly provide Valued Assets to Hamas and Hezbollah Act or the HATIKVAHH Act

This bill suspends federal assistance to certain international organizations determined to support&#160;or cooperate with Hamas, Hezbollah, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, Palestine Liberation Front, Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, the Iranian Revolutionary Guard, or other groups designated as terrorist organizations operating in Gaza or Judea and Samaria.

The Department of State shall make such determinations on international organizations receiving federal funding that operate in Gaza or Judea and Samaria and periodically report to Congress. The State Department shall make a determination on each United Nations agency as a separate international organization.</summary>
</bill>
