<bill session="111" type="s" number="1666" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to satisfy certain conditions before issuing to producers of mid-level ethanol blends a waiver from certain requirements under the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to satisfy certain conditions before issuing to producers of mid-level ethanol blends a waiver from certain requirements under the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2009-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000803" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2009-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9328"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9329" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-10-06T19:58:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to allow the introduction into commerce of a mid-level ethanol blend (an ethanol-gasoline blend containing greater than 10% ethanol) for use in conventional gasoline-powered onroad or nonroad vehicles and nonroad engines only if: (1) EPA's Science Advisory Board submits to the Administrator, and the Administrator provides for public notice and comment, a report describing the impact of the blend on such vehicles, emissions, and associated materials compatibility and consumer issues, the ability of the gasoline distribution infrastructure to introduce the blend without widespread misfueling by consumers, and the estimated ability of consumers to purchase gasoline other than that blend in in all areas of the United States by five years after the blend is introduced; (2) the permit or authorization is granted through the fuels and fuel additives waiver process under the Clean Air Act and the Administrator formally responds to the Board's recommendations in the waiver announcement; and (3) the blend is introduced for general use in all conventional gasoline-powered onroad and nonroad vehicles and nonroad engines in widespread use as of the date on which the Administrator authorizes that introduction.</summary>
</bill>
