<bill session="117" type="s" number="668" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to permit Governors of States to regulate intrastate endangered species and intrastate threatened species, to amend the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to permit the taking of certain black vultures and ravens, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5550" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-25T19:05:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Endangered Species Management Self-Determination Act

This bill revises requirements governing the management of endangered or threatened species, establishes a process to compensate land owners under certain circumstances, and removes protections for black vultures and ravens.

The Department of the Interior or the Department of Commerce must obtain the consent of each state for adding species to the list of threatened or endangered species when the species is present in the state.

A state may regulate endangered or threatened species that are only present within the state. If a state elects to regulate them, it is given exclusive authority to manage them. State action with respect to such species is not subject to judicial review.

Species are taken off the federal list after five years, but Interior may petition for the species to be relisted. The bill requires congressional approval before a species may be listed as endangered or threatened.

The bill eliminates awards of attorney fees in citizen suits concerning endangered or threatened species.

Owners or lessees of property may apply to Interior for a determination of whether a proposed property use will violate requirements governing endangered or threatened species. The use is deemed compliant if Interior fails to respond within 90 days. The owners and lessees may seek monetary compensation for unfavorable determinations.

The bill removes migratory bird protections provided to black vultures and ravens in certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
