<bill session="118" type="h" number="7327" updated="2024-07-12T16:31:48Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Front Line Multimission Hospitals Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Front Line Multimission Hospitals Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to ensure adequate consideration of payment rates for multimission hospitals under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2024-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2024-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-12T16:31:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Front Line Multimission Hospitals Act of 2024

This bill allows for increased payment adjustments under Medicaid for certain hospitals that provide multiple&#160;types of services for Medicaid-eligible or uninsured individuals (i.e., multimission hospitals).

Specifically, the bill allows hospitals to receive higher disproportionate share hospital payments under Medicaid for costs associated with physician services, emergency medical services, or services provided at federally qualified health centers or other clinical outpatient settings, if such services are provided to maintain a certain level of care under Medicaid. The hospital's patient population must meet certain higher indexes with respect to the number of Medicaid-eligible and uninsured individuals served.

Additionally, state Medicaid programs must ensure that relevant payment plans for these hospitals support the financial viability of the hospitals and their ability to provide the requisite level of care under Medicaid.</summary>
</bill>
