<bill session="109" type="h" number="5209" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:42Z">
  <state datetime="2006-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Tissue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the oversight and regulation of tissue banks and the tissue donation process, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Tissue Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2006-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000070" joined="2006-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000523" joined="2006-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2006-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2006-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2609" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tissue banks"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-06-03T13:53:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Tissue Act - Requires the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to inspect, at least once every two years, each establishment that engages in the manufacture of human cells, tissues, and cellular and tissue-based products. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a user fee to fund such inspections.

Requires the FDA to conduct periodic audits of all documentation submitted by each such establishment to determine compliance with all applicable requirements, including requirements related to ensuring: (1) that human cells, tissues, or cellular or tissue-based products are obtained legally; (2) that donor eligibility and donor medical history interviews are based on accurate information that was not provided or obtained in a fraudulent manner; and (3) current good tissue practice.

Requires the Secretary to publish a model form containing minimum requirements for establishments to use in obtaining consent from a potential donor of human cells, tissues, or cellular or tissue-based products. Sets forth penalties for failing to comply with model form requirements or for knowingly using fraudulent information.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) accredit establishments and the personnel of such establishments who participate in the recovery, processing, storage, labeling, packaging, or distribution of human cells, tissues, or cellular or tissue-based products; and (2) define "reasonable payments" that are associated with donation of human tissue and tissue-based products for purposes of the National Organ Transplant Act.</summary>
</bill>
