<bill session="118" type="s" number="75" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lifting Local Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lifting Local Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure equal treatment for religious organizations in the Federal provision of social services programs, grantmaking, and contracting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2023-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2023-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="74" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4789" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-25T21:24:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lifting Local Communities Act

This bill specifies that government entities may not discriminate against religious organizations when awarding federal funds for social services programs (i.e., government programs that provide services for low-income individuals and communities, such as child care, transportation, employment, housing, and meal services).

Specifically, religious organizations are eligible to apply for and receive federal funds to provide services for social services programs on the same basis as private, nonreligious organizations. Additionally, government entities may not discriminate against private organizations on the basis of religion when selecting funding recipients.

Organizations that receive federal funds for social services programs may not discriminate against individuals on the basis of religion when providing services. If an individual objects to the character or affiliation of a private organization that is providing a service as part of a social services program, government entities must provide the individual with reasonable alternatives.

Religious organizations may bring civil actions against entities for violations.</summary>
</bill>
