<bill session="118" type="s" number="2088" updated="2025-11-19T03:07:18Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wounded Knee Massacre Memorial and Sacred Site Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Knee Massacre Memorial and Sacred Site Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wounded Knee Massacre Memorial and Sacred Site Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to complete all actions necessary for certain land to be held in restricted fee status by the Oglala Sioux Tribe and Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2023-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-170.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-01">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Schatz without amendment. With written report No. 118-208.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-08-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="472">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 472.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3371" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-21T15:37:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wounded Knee Massacre Memorial and Sacred Site Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to complete all actions necessary to place approximately 40 acres of land in Oglala Lakota County, South Dakota, into restricted fee status for the Oglala Sioux Tribe and the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe. Restricted fee status refers to land that is owned by a tribe or tribal member but is subject to restrictions by the United States against alienation (i.e., sale or transfer) or encumbrance (e.g., liens, leases, or rights-of-way) by operation of law.

The bill requires the land to be held and maintained as a memorial and sacred site, as outlined by the document titled Covenant Between the Oglala Sioux Tribe and the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe and dated October 21, 2022. Further, it prohibits commercial development and gaming activity on the land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-208</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
