<bill session="116" type="h" number="8680" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:28Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Occupational Licensing Board Antitrust Damages Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Occupational Licensing Board Antitrust Damages Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide immunity from liability under section 4 of the Clayton Act for damages in cases against occupational licensing boards that meet appropriate standards, to provide for the establishment of those standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001062" joined="2020-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-17T14:53:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Occupational Licensing Board Antitrust Damages Relief Act of 2020

This bill establishes immunity from antitrust liability for an official action taken by an occupational licensing board, or any member, officer, employee, or agent of the board, as long as specified requirements are met.

These requirements include that the board be established in a state where (1) all members of the board must be appointed or assigned by the chief executive officer, the legislature, or other elected officer of the state; (2) the board must include public representation; and (3) there is required to be a mechanism in effect under which a person aggrieved by an action of the board has the right to contest the action, review all evidence, receive a final decision in writing, and appeal an adverse decision to an independent adjudicator.</summary>
</bill>
