<bill session="117" type="h" number="3784" updated="2022-12-30T17:32:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote scientific research and development opportunities for connected technologies that advance precision agriculture capabilities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2021-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1395" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-15T16:28:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Act of 2021

This bill supports research and development for connected technologies that advance precision agriculture.

In awarding grants under its sensor systems and networked systems programs, the National Science Foundation (NSF) shall consider certain research and development on sensor connectivity in environments of intermittent connectivity and intermittent computation.

The NSF must prioritize applications that incorporate distance learning tools and approaches in awarding grants under the Advanced Technological Education Program to (1) junior or community colleges to develop or improve associate degree or certificate programs in an in-demand industry sector or occupation; or (2) institutions of higher education partnering with private sector employers, industry partnerships, or sector partnerships that commit to offering apprenticeships, internships, research opportunities, or applied learning experiences to enrolled students.

The Government Accountability Office shall provide (1) a technology assessment of precision agriculture technologies; and (2) a review of federal programs that provide support for precision agriculture research, development, adoption, education, or training.</summary>
</bill>
