<bill session="117" type="h" number="2894" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Civilian Cyber Security Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Civilian Cyber Security Reserve as a pilot project to address the cyber security needs of the United States with respect to national security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civilian Cyber Security Reserve Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000613"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2021-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1324" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-12T15:52:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Civilian Cyber Security Reserve Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Defense to each create a temporary Civilian Cyber Security Reserve within their agencies to address U.S. cybersecurity needs with respect to national security.

Reserve members must be former federal employees or former military personnel, have cybersecurity expertise, and obtain any necessary security clearances, in addition to any other criteria specified by each agency. Membership in the reserves is contingent on a mutual agreement between the agency and the individual. Reserves may consist of different components, with one component obligated to respond to a call to activation and the other not obligated to do so; each agency may establish penalties for those individuals who fail to respond when required.

The Government Accountability Office and each agency must evaluate and report on the reserves, including whether they should be made permanent.</summary>
</bill>
