<bill session="116" type="h" number="9052" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PPS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PPS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing a Patronage System Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose limits on excepting competitive service positions from the competitive service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-08T15:38:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing a Patronage System Act or the PPS Act

This bill prohibits executive agency positions in the competitive service from being placed in the excepted service, unless such positions are placed in Schedules A through E as in effect on September 30, 2020. The bill also prohibits positions in the excepted service from being placed in any schedule other than the aforementioned schedules.

On October 21, 2020, the President issued an executive order titled Creating Schedule F in the Excepted Service. The order places executive agency positions that are of a confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character, and that are not normally subject to change as a result of a presidential transition, under a new schedule in the excepted service (Schedule F) instead of the competitive service. The order also requires any such positions in the excepted service to be reclassified to Schedule F.</summary>
</bill>
