<bill session="117" type="h" number="2232" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:01Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Help Students Vote Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education that participate in programs under such title to distribute voter registration forms to students enrolled at the institution, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help Students Vote Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="992" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-19T21:45:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Help Students Vote Act

This bill addresses voter registration&#160;of students who attend&#160;institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student-aid programs. The bill also directs IHEs to use a specified portion of federal work-study grants to compensate students for civic engagement activities.

Specifically, the bill (1) requires IHEs to make every reasonable effort to distribute voter registration applications to each of their students at least twice a year, (2) authorizes grants to IHEs that greatly exceed the requirements governing the distribution of voter registration applications, and (3) allows civil actions against IHEs that violate the requirements.

In addition, the bill requires IHEs to use a specified portion of federal work-study grants to compensate students who are employed in civic engagement activities, including voter registration, nonpartisan voter engagement, and voter participation work.</summary>
</bill>
