<bill session="118" type="s" number="1088" updated="2025-11-19T03:33:24Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">North Dakota Trust Lands Completion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the relinquishment and in lieu selection of land and minerals in the State of North Dakota, to restore land and minerals to Indian Tribes within the State of North Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">North Dakota Trust Lands Completion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Dakota Trust Lands Completion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">North Dakota Trust Lands Completion Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-132.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="276">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 276.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7153" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7153-7155" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T17:26:18-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T18:04:56-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2405" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-05T22:32:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">North Dakota Trust Lands Completion Act of 2023

This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to exchange, at the election of North Dakota, certain federal land for certain state land of substantially equal value.

Specifically, subject to valid existing rights, if North Dakota elects to relinquish a parcel of state land located wholly or partially within the boundaries of any Indian reservation, the bill authorizes North Dakota to select one or more parcels of federal land of substantially equivalent value within that state.

No later than 60 days after Interior approves North Dakota's selection of federal land, Interior shall initiate the actions necessary to convey the federal land to the state.

As consideration for the conveyance of the federal land, North Dakota shall concurrently relinquish and convey the state land to Interior. Land conveyed to Interior that is within the boundaries of a reservation becomes part of the reservation on request of the tribe.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-132</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
