<bill session="111" type="h" number="2380" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:14Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Raise Wages, Cut Carbon Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce social security payroll taxes and to reduce the reliance of the United States economy on carbon-based energy sources.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Raise Wages, Cut Carbon Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2009-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-22T19:19:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Raise Wages, Cut Carbon Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an environmental tax on: (1) any taxable carbon substance (i.e., coal, including lignite and peat, petroleum and any petroleum product, and natural gas that is extracted, manufactured, or produced in, or imported into, the United States); and (2) imported taxable products that account for a specified level of carbon substances used in the United States. Sets the amount of the tax at $15.00 per ton in 2010, and increases and adjusts for inflation such amount each year until the tax is $100 in 2040 and in subsequent years.

Provides for a reduction in social security taxes by an amount determined by the Secretary of the Treasury to reflect the amount of revenues generated by the taxes imposed by this Act. Appropriates net revenues from such taxes to the social security trust funds.

Requires a two-thirds vote of the House of Representatives or the Senate to increase the amount of the tax on taxable carbon substance or imported products beyond the amount required to compensate for the aggregate reduction in revenues resulting from the lower rates of social security taxes provided by this Act (i.e., revenue neutrality).</summary>
</bill>
