<amendment session="110" chamber="s" number="155" updated="2022-02-03T05:24:48Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2007-01-31">withdrawn</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000595"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-01-23"/>
  <description>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for cooperative governing of individual health insurance coverage offered in interstate commerce, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 regarding the disposition of unused health benefits in cafeteria plans and flexible spending arrangements and the use of health savings accounts for the payment of health insurance premiums for high deductible health plans purchased in the individual market.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Proposed amendment SA 155 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-31">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1364" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-30">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1307" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-29">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1267" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-26">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1212-1213" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1136" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Amendment SA 155 proposed by Senator DeMint to Amendment SA 100. (consideration: CR S1035-1038) To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for cooperative governing of individual health insurance coverage offered in interstate commerce, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 regarding the disposition of unused health benefits in cafeteria plans and flexible spending arrangements and the use of health savings accounts for the payment of health insurance premiums for high deductible health plans purchased in the individual market.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-24">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 155 proposed by Senator DeMint to Amendment SA 100.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1035-1038" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-23">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
