<bill session="117" type="h" number="8288" updated="2023-08-22T14:30:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LAUNCHES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LAUNCHES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leveraging American Understanding of Next-generation Challenges Exploring Space Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate access to electromagnetic spectrum for commercial space launches and commercial space reentries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2022-07-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-21T20:18:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Leveraging American Understanding of Next-generation Challenges Exploring Space Act or the LAUNCHES Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to facilitate access to specified broadband spectrum frequencies for commercial space launches and reentries.

Under current law, commercial missions launching from the United States to space must use government-owned spectrum to communicate with the rockets during launch, and private companies must apply to the FCC to receive special temporary authority to use such spectrum. On June 28, 2021, the FCC issued a final rule adopting a nonfederal secondary allocation of the 2200-2290 megahertz frequencies of the electromagnetic spectrum for use during commercial space launches and reentries.

The bill requires the FCC to adopt service rules for access to additional frequencies for commercial space launches and reentries and complete associated rulemaking activities (e.g., those that set technical specifications and eligibility requirements) to implement the allocation of the frequencies.

The FCC must also streamline the process for access authorizations, providing for (1) authorizations to access specified frequencies for multiple commercial space launches and reentries from one or more launch or reentry sites, (2) authorizations for multiple uses of such frequencies for a commercial space launch or reentry, (3) automation of the FCC's review process for access applications, and (4) increased coordination between the FCC and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to speed the review of such applications.</summary>
</bill>
