<bill session="118" type="s" number="831" updated="2025-11-19T04:34:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transnational Repression Policy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transnational Repression Policy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address transnational repression by foreign governments against private individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2024-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-05-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3654" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-29T20:54:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transnational Repression Policy Act

This bill seeks to reduce transnational repression (the actions of foreign governments to intimidate, silence, or harm members of diaspora and exile communities to prevent them from exercising their human rights).

This bill requires the President to impose property- and visa-blocking sanctions on certain foreign persons (individuals and entities) that directly engage in transnational repression.

This bill also requires the Department of State to develop a strategy to promote initiatives that (1) enhance international awareness of transnational repression; (2) address transnational repression, including by raising the costs of perpetrating repressive activities and by protecting targeted individuals and groups; and (3) conduct outreach to those targeted by foreign governments.

Additionally, the State Department and the Department of Justice must provide training to certain individuals (e.g., relevant federal employees and law enforcement partners)&#160;on specified aspects of transnational repression.

The bill also directs the intelligence community to prioritize, to the extent feasible,&#160;the identification of those perpetrating transnational repression against communities in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
