<bill session="117" type="h" number="6716" updated="2022-12-30T04:18:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Burial Sites and Cultural Resources Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Burial Sites and Cultural Resources Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 to protect Native American burial sites, village sites, and cultural resources discovered at civil works projects of the Corps of Engineers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2022-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2022-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2022-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-20T15:13:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Native American Burial Sites and Cultural Resources Protection Act

This bill directs the Department of the Army to identify, and cooperate with appropriate property owners to set aside, areas that may be used for the reburial of Native American human remains and funerary objects that

 have been identified or discovered at the site of a civil works project carried out, or operated and maintained, using federal funds; have been rightfully claimed by any affected Indian tribe; and can be reburied in a manner secure from future disturbances. Army shall issue written guidance for recovery and reburial that meets or exceeds the recovery and reburial standards in policy statements and guidance issued by the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation.

Army may not exercise the power of eminent domain to acquire any property for use for reburial.

Army may convey to an affected Indian tribe for use as a cemetery or reburial area any area that is located on land owned by Army and has been identified and set aside in accordance with this bill.</summary>
</bill>
