<bill session="118" type="h" number="2594" updated="2024-12-21T09:05:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">China Technology Transfer Control Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">China Technology Transfer Control Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To control the export to the People's Republic of China of certain technology and intellectual property important to the national interest of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-06T17:08:28Z" status="Introduced in House">China Technology Transfer Control Act of 2023

This bill controls exports of certain national interest technology and intellectual property to China.

Specifically, covered technology or intellectual property includes items that (1) would contribute significantly to the Chinese military to the detriment of U.S. national security, (2) are included in a designated list of product components compiled by the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), or (3) are used by China to violate human rights or religious liberties.

The President must control exports to China of any covered technology or intellectual property. Further, the President must sanction (1) a foreign person who sells to China or purchases from China any covered item, and (2) a Chinese person who knowingly uses a covered item provided to them in violation of U.S. export control law.

In addition to a specified list of industries subject to the bill, the USTR must identify certain products from China that either receive designated support from the Chinese government or are used by China to violate human rights or religious liberties.</summary>
</bill>
