<bill session="111" type="h" number="563" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:10Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCHIP Expansion for Kids in Need Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">SCHIP Expansion for Kids in Need Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to require States to provide priority under the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) to children in families with gross income below 200 percent of the Federal poverty level.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001232"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001247" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2009-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2009-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-18T21:26:29Z" status="Introduced in House">SCHIP Expansion for Kids in Need Act of 2009 - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP) to require states to provide SCHIP priority to children in families with gross income below 200% of the federal poverty level.

Declares that no state child health plan shall be considered approved for a fiscal year unless the state has developed and submitted to the Secretary of Health and Human Services a plan to assure that all qualified low-income children are covered by creditable health coverage, such a plan has been approved, and the state implements it beginning with FY2010.

Declares that no payment to a state that increases its state child health plan income eligibility level above the one in effect as of the enactment of this Act shall be made for any amount expended for an individual whose family income exceeds the unincreased income eligibility level unless no more than 10% percent of qualified low-income children residing in the state are still not covered under creditable health coverage.</summary>
</bill>
