<bill session="108" type="s" number="484" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:41Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Omnibus Mercury Emission Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to establish requirements concerning the operation of fossil fuel-fired electric utility steam generating units, commercial and industrial boiler units, solid waste incineration units, medical waste incinerators, hazardous waste combustors, chlor-alkali plants, and Portland cement plants to reduce emissions of mercury to the environment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Mercury Emission Reduction Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2003-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2941-2942"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Electric appliances"/>
    <term name="Electric batteries"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fetus"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical wastes"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Sedimentation"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Omnibus Mercury Emission Reduction Act of 2003 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations to establish standards for mercury and mercury compound emissions applicable to: (1) electric utility steam generating units; (2) coal- and oil-fired boiler units of a specified capacity; (3) chlor-alkali plants that use the mercury cell production process; and (4) dust from Portland cement plants. Sets forth permit requirements.Requires the Administrator to authorize methods of emissions control.Establishes mercury emission baselines for electric utility and coal- and oil-fired boiler units.Requires the regulations to ensure that recovered mercury is disposed of in a manner that ensures that: (1) mercury hazards are not transferred between environmental media; and (2) there is no release of mercury into the environment.Directs the Administrator to establish a program of long-term disposal research and publicize emission data for each facility.Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator to publish a list of mercury-containing items to be separated and removed from the waste streams that feed solid waste facilities.Requires mercury-content labeling by manufacturers.Requires persons that transfer solid waste that may contain a listed mercury-containing item to submit separation and removal plans.Directs the Administrator to promulgate regulations concerning measurement of mercury emissions from solid waste combustion flue gases.Requires permits for solid waste incineration units to specify inspection, entry, monitoring, compliance certification, and reporting requirements. Directs the Administrator to require incineration units that exceed the maximum emission rate to install measures that will result, within three years, in a rate below the specified maximum.Prohibits, three years after this Act's enactment, the sale of mercury-containing products unless the manufacturer has been granted an exemption.Requires reports on reductions of mercury emissions from medical and hazardous waste incinerators, military uses of mercury, the sources and extent of emissions in North America, sedimentation trends in water bodies of concern, and fish consumption advisories.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Administrator to establish an advisory committee to report on the progress made in complying with this Act's amendments.Requires a study of mercury stockpiles and retirement. Increases funding for the National Atmospheric Deposition Program Mercury Deposition Network.</summary>
</bill>
