<bill session="117" type="h" number="6236" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:03Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FAIRNESS in Flood Insurance Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIRNESS in Flood Insurance Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fixing Announcements for Intermittent Remapping and Notification Expectations to Stop Surprises in Flood Insurance Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator to provide certain notices to property owners when undertaking remapping in geographic areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000103"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-06T15:14:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Fixing Announcements for Intermittent Remapping and Notification Expectations to Stop Surprises in Flood Insurance Act of 2021 or the FAIRNESS in Flood Insurance Act of 2021 

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide notice through the mail to property owners of any revision or update to any floodplain areas and flood risk zones identified, delineated, or established under the National Flood Insurance Program for coverage and rate purposes. Specifically, such notice must be provided not less than 15 days before the remapping process begins. The bill also sets forth notification requirements regarding the remapping appeals process and the finalization of the remapping process.</summary>
</bill>
