<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="657" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4437" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-12-16T16:34:24-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) to reduce the immigration application processing backlog to 6 months within a period of 1 year; and authorizes innovative pilot initiatives to eliminate the backlog and prevent further backlog from recurring.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 109-350 to require the U.S.Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) to reduce the immigration application processing backlog to 6 months within a period of 1 year; to authorize the Director of USCIS to implement innovative pilot initiatives to eliminate the backlog and prevent further backlog from recurring and encourages initiatives such as increasing or transferring personnel to areas with the greatest backlog, streamlining regulations and paperwork filing processes, upgrading information technology, and increasing the number of immigration service centers.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-12-16T16:34:24-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Velazquez amendment (A021) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T16:25:13-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A021) offered by Ms. Velazquez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11953-11954" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11953" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T16:25:13-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A021) offered by Ms. Velazquez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11953-11954" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11953" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T16:34:24-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T16:34:24-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Velazquez amendment (A021) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
