<bill session="109" type="s" number="1960" updated="2018-02-03T22:36:23Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-03">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Integrity in Professional Sports Act</title>
    <title type="display">Integrity in Professional Sports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the health and safety of all athletes, to promote the integrity of professional sports by establishing minimum standards for the testing of steroids and other performance-enhancing substances and methods by professional sports leagues, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2005-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000888" joined="2005-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12345"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="280">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 280.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1334" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3084" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-02-18T17:35:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Integrity in Professional Sports Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the individual records of athletes achieved as a result of performance-enhancing substances or methods should be invalidated.

Prohibits a professional sports league from organizing, sponsoring, endorsing, promoting, producing, or recognizing a professional sports event without adopting and enforcing a testing policy for performance-enhancing drugs that meets or exceeds the standards specified in this Act.

Requires each such league to adopt policies and procedures that: (1) proscribe the use of prohibited substances and methods; (2) provide for random testing of each professional athlete at least five times a year; and (3) proscribe any employee or contractor of the league, the team or club, or the professional athletes' union from complicity in an offense by an athlete.

 Provides that the testing policy shall be violated if: (1) a test reveals the presence of a prohibited substance or its metabolites or markers; (2) evidence of the use of a prohibited substance or method is discovered; (3) an athlete refuses to submit to a test; (4) an athlete tampers with the testing process; (5) a league or union representative administers a prohibited substance or method to any athlete a or assists, encourages, aids, abets, or covers up any other type of complicity involving an offense by a professional athlete.

Allows a league to provide an individual athlete an exemption for a particular prohibited substance or method for a documented medical condition.

Sets penalties as a minimum of two years' suspension for the first violation, permanent suspension for any subsequent violation, and public disclosure of the name of the violator and substance involved.

Allows the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to seek civil penalties for violations of this Act.

Requires the United States Boxing Commission (after it is established) to promulgate uniform performance-enhancing substance testing standards for professional boxing consistent with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
