<bill session="109" type="h" number="5366" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:29Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Continuity of Operations Demonstration Project Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a demonstration project to enhance the ability of Federal agencies to continue to operate during an extended emergency situation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuity of Operations Demonstration Project Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000874" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000589" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2006-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000784" joined="2006-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Decentralization in government"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Telecommuting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-07-11T19:00:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Continuity of Operations Demonstration Project Act - Directs the Chief Human Capital Officers Council and the Interagency Continuity of Operations Working Group, in order to test the preparedness of the federal government to continue to operate in the event of an extended emergency situation, to jointly provide for a demonstration project under which two or more agencies shall perform a representative range of government services and operations (both essential and nonessential) under circumstances simulating a situation in which federal employees are, as a result of a sudden and unexpected contingency, required to work: (1) from locations apart from their usual and customary workplace, including from home and from agency-designated facilities; and (2) for a continuous period of not less than ten consecutive workdays.

Directs the Council, in carrying out the demonstration project, to ensure that specified requirements are met with respect to: (1) communications; (2) training relating to duties and responsibilities during an emergency situation; (3) access to technologies, information, or other assistance; (4) coordination with the earliest governmentwide continuity of operations interagency exercise; (5) plans detailing which operations will be performed, which employees will perform those operations, and how those operations are to be performed; (6) participation (limited to those employees who would otherwise have been eligible to telework); and (7) coordination with otherwise existing federal telework policies, requirements, and funding.</summary>
</bill>
