<bill session="118" type="h" number="1449" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-19T16:52:02-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-19T16:52:02-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Committing Leases for Energy Access Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Committing Leases for Energy Access Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Committing Leases for Energy Access Now Act</title>
    <title type="short">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="short">Committing Leases for Energy Access Now Act</title>
    <title type="display">CLEAN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to increase the frequency of lease sales, to require replacement sales, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000469"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 118-730.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-12" calendar="Union" number="617">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 617.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-11-18T17:49:37-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1576 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1449 and H.R. 9495. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1449 under a structured rule and H.R. 9495 under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1576.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6089-6094" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:08:05-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1449 and H.R. 9495. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1449 under a structured rule and H.R. 9495 under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:08:56-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Nick LaLota to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:08:56-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1576 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:09:08-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1449.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:29:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1576, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:37:49-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on Grijalva amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:38:25-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1576, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:46:14-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on Grijalva amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:46:30-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:46:44-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T14:46:59-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1449 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:00:15-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6094-6097" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:00:26-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:36:34-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1449.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:37:14-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Stansbury moved to recommit to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6096" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:38:13-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:44:34-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 211 (Roll no. 472).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="473" datetime="2024-11-19T16:52:02-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 171 (Roll no. 473).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6092" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19T16:52:06-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1335" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="947" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2811" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1576" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1229"/>
    <amendment number="h1228"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-11-18T18:48:08Z" status="Reported to House">Committing Leases for Energy Access Now Act or the CLEAN Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to increase the frequency of lease sales under the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 and establishes deadlines for consideration of geothermal drilling permits.

Specifically, Interior must increase the frequency of competitive geothermal lease sales in any state that has pending nominations of federal land to be leased for certain geothermal energy projects. Currently, Interior must hold lease sales at least once every two years. This bill requires Interior to hold a sale at least once a year. If a lease sale is canceled or delayed, then Interior must conduct a replacement sale during the same year. In conducting a lease sale in&#160;a state, Interior must offer all nominated parcels eligible for geothermal development and utilization under the resource management plan in effect for the state.&#160;&#160;

In addition, this bill requires Interior to notify an applicant whether or not its application for a geothermal drilling permit is complete within 30 days of receiving the application. If Interior determines that the application is complete, then it must issue a final decision on the application within 30 days of the date Interior sent the notification.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-730</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
