<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3472</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:44:46Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:44:46Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2008-09-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2008-09-11T18:48:09Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. (text of measure as introduced: CR S8387)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-11</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8386-8387)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000061</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Feingold, Russell D. [D-WI]</fullName>
        <firstName>RUSSELL</firstName>
        <lastName>FEINGOLD</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WI</state>
        <middleName>D.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agricultural innovations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Biomass energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy facilities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Product development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technological innovations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2008-09-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-02-07T17:55:44Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Energy and Technology Advancement Act of 2008 - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Agriculture, in order to further the adoption of technologies developed by the Department of Agriculture (USDA), to establish criteria and procedures to facilitate and encourage businesses and other organizations to: (1) rent government equipment and property for the development of new and improved products and processes; (2) authorize USDA and private sector employees to work together in experimental or production facilities owned by the federal government or a private entity; (3) provide business support services to start-up and small businesses; and (4) enter into cooperative agreements with educational and governmental units to support business incubators for businesses that use technologies and products of interest to the Secretary.</p><p>Requires the Secretary to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan for the development and construction of a biorefinery pilot plant that is able to: (1) produce liquid fuels from woody, agricultural, and other biomass in a flexible, multi-bioproduct manner, in a sustainable manner that addresses life-cycle inputs and outputs, and in quantities sufficient to provide proof of process and to allow for business incubator and support services; and (2) employ thermochemical and biochemical conversion processes in the production of liquid fuels.</p><p>Requires the Secretary to include in the plan a comprehensive estimate of each cost relating to the development and construction of the biorefinery pilot plant.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Energy and Technology Advancement Act of 2008</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Energy and Technology Advancement Act of 2008</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Energy and Technology Advancement Act of 2008</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to further the adoption of technologies developed by the Department of Agriculture, to encourage small business partnerships in the development of energy through biorefineries, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2008-09-11T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s3472is/xml/BILLS-110s3472is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2008-09-11</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. (text of measure as introduced: CR S8387)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
