<bill session="109" type="h" number="5494" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:25Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Identity Theft Protection for the Deceased Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the distribution by the National Technical Information Service of monthly updates of the Death Master List prepared by the Social Security Administration to all nationwide consumer reporting agencies, to require such consumer reporting agencies to maintain a permanent fraud alert in each file of a consumer whose name appears on the Death Master List, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Identity Theft Protection for the Deceased Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2006-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E989-990"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-03-07T18:04:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Identity Theft Protection for the Deceased Act - Directs the National Technical Information Service of the Department of Commerce to provide monthly updates of the Death Master List prepared by the Social Security Administration to each consumer reporting agency described in the Fair Credit Reporting Act.

Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require each such consumer reporting agency to include a fraud alert in the consumer file of each consumer whose name appears on the Death Master List prepared by the Social Security Administration so long as the agency continues to maintain such file.</summary>
</bill>
