<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6537</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:12Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:12Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-12-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-12-16T15:03:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-12-16T15:03:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000287</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Lewis, John [D-GA-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>LEWIS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <district>5</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Digestive and metabolic diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care coverage and access</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health facilities and institutions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health technology, devices, supplies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hospital care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minority health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>User charges and fees</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-01-12T23:02:00Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Improving Care for Kidney Patients Act of 2010 - Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act with respect to kidney disease benefits.</p> <p>Sets at 100% the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) with respect to the placement of an arteriovenous fistula or graft in the hemodialysis treatment of Medicaid beneficiaries.</p> <p> Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to study and report to Congress on: (1) the social, behavioral, and biological factors leading to kidney disease; (2) efforts to slow the progression of kidney disease in minority populations that are disproportionately affected by it; and (3) research gaps in the development of quality measures and care management for patients with end-stage renal disease (ESRD), including pediatric patients.</p> <p>Amends the Social Security Act, with respect to criminal penalties for certain acts, to exclude from the meaning of illegal remuneration the waiver of any fee or cost-sharing by a renal dialysis facility (RDF) in providing chronic kidney disease screening that meets certain criteria.</p> <p>Treats as a hospital for Medicare purposes an institution providing Medicare or Medicaid patients diagnosed with stage IV or stage V kidney disease with educational materials about treatment. Treats as a person qualified to furnish kidney disease education services an RDF meeting specified criteria.</p> <p>Makes eligible to participate in a shared savings program as an accountable care organization (ACO) a group consisting of RDFs, nephrologists, and other service providers and suppliers that treat patients with kidney disease.</p> <p>Prescribes Medicare requirements for coordination of care between hospitals and RDFs for the discharge planning process for an ESRD patient.</p> <p>Specifies Medicare coverage to specialized occlusive dressings used by a patient receiving dialysis treatment for protection against life threatening catheter-related infections during maintenance of personal hygiene at home.<br> </p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General to evaluate and report to Congress on the transportation barriers facing dialysis patients that result in less than 100% compliance with a Medicare plan of care.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, in specified circumstances, to accept the results of a state licensure survey for purposes of determining federal certification of an RDF's compliance with the conditions of Medicare participation. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of HHS to report to Congress on the benefits of recognizing dialysis vascular and peritoneal dialysis access care service sites in order to receive Medicare reimbursement.</p> <p>Revises Medicare requirements for group health plans to: (1) extend the period during which they are primary payers (and Medicare the secondary payer) for ESRD patients; and (2) prohibit denial of a Medigap policy to a ESRD patient. </p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act, as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to allow a group health plan or health insurance issuer to impose restrictions for kidney failure treatment on a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee only if they are reasonable and assure adequate access to out-of-network providers.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Improving Care for Kidney Patients Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Improving Care for Kidney Patients Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act and other Acts to improve Medicare and other benefits for beneficiaries with kidney disease, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Improving Care for Kidney Patients Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-12-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr6537ih/xml/BILLS-111hr6537ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
