<bill session="118" type="s" number="616" updated="2025-06-20T19:33:16Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Amendments</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Technical Corrections Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Amendments</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe Reservation Restoration Act to provide for the transfer of additional Federal land to the Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-120.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Schatz with amendments. With written report No. 118-225.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="517">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 517.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-02T01:07:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Technical Corrections Act of 2023

This bill provides for the transfer of certain federal land located in the Chippewa National Forest in Cass County, Minnesota, to the Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must transfer to the tribe land in the Chippewa National Forest that records maintained by the Bureau of Indian Affairs show was sold without the consent of a majority of the rightful landowners.

Upon agreement between USDA and the tribe, USDA shall substitute alternative National Forest System land located in Cass County on an acre-for-acre basis for those parcels of federal land to be transferred that are found to be unsuitable for the future uses of the tribe.

USDA may transfer land to the tribe on a rolling basis as that land is identified and surveys are completed.

Any such agreement and any transfer of land made pursuant to such agreement shall be considered a final agency action.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-225</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
