<bill session="109" type="h" number="5001" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:56Z">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Information Sharing Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance homeland security information sharing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Information Sharing Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001152"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism, Law Enforcement, and Intelligence" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-12T18:49:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Homeland Security Information Sharing Enhancement Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Under Secretary for Information and Analysis to implement a Homeland Security Advisory System to provide advisories and alerts regarding threats to homeland security. Requires such an advisory or alert to: (1) include information on protective measures and countermeasures; (2) be limited in scope to a specific region, locality, or economic sector; and (3) not use color designations as the exclusive means of specifying threat conditions.

Directs the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) integrate and standardize the information of the Department's intelligence components into a Department information-sharing environment; and (2) designate, for each such component, an information-sharing and knowledge management officer.

Requires the Under Secretary to: (1) establish Department-wide procedures for the review and analysis of information gathered from state, local, tribal, and private-sector sources; (2) develop mechanisms to provide analytical and operational feedback; (3) provide Department employees training and educational opportunities; and (4) evaluate how employees of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis and the Department's intelligence components are utilizing homeland security information.

Directs the Secretary, acting through the Chief Intelligence Officer, to establish a comprehensive information technology architecture for such Office.

Makes the Secretary the executive branch official responsible for disseminating homeland security-related terrorist threat information to state and local government and tribal officials and the private sector. Prohibits any federal official from issuing a homeland security-related analysis, advisory, or alert without the Secretary's approval, with exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
