<bill session="117" type="h" number="3649" updated="2022-12-30T21:29:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Federal recognition to the Mono Lake Kutzadikaa Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mono Lake Kutzadikaa Tribe Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mono Lake Kutzadikaa Tribe Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-23T15:03:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Mono Lake Kutzadika&amp;#7491 Tribe Recognition Act

This bill extends federal recognition to the Mono Lake Kutzadika&amp;#7491 Tribe.

The bill makes the tribe and its members eligible for services and benefits provided to federally recognized tribes and their members, without regard to the existence of a reservation or the location of the residence of any member. The service area of the tribe is considered to be Mono and Inyo counties, California.

In addition, the bill grants the tribe hunting and fishing rights on all federal lands within its aboriginal land area.

Further, the tribe must submit a membership roll to the Department of the Interior as a condition of receiving recognition, services, and benefits. The tribe must maintain the membership roll.

Interior, upon the request of the tribe, must take into trust certain land in Mono County, California, for the benefit of the tribe.</summary>
</bill>
