<bill session="117" type="h" number="7022" updated="2023-09-01T13:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Cybersecurity for the Financial Sector Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Cybersecurity for the Financial Sector Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act to modify requirements relating to the regulation and examination of credit union organizations and service providers, to provide the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency with the authority to regulate the provision of services provided to the Government-sponsored enterprises and Federal Home Loan Banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 22.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Agency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-22T18:49:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Cybersecurity for the Financial Sector Act of 2022 

This bill provides for the regulation and supervision of certain financial organizations and service providers.

Specifically, if a credit union that is subject to examination by the Board of Directors of the National Credit Union Administration delegates the performance of certain activities and services, the delegation must be disclosed and shall be subject to regulation and examination by the board.

Additionally, if the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, any Federal Home Loan Bank, or the Office of Finance of the Federal Home Loan Bank System delegates the performance of certain activities and services, the delegation must be disclosed and shall be subject to regulation and examination by the Federal Housing Finance Agency.</summary>
</bill>
