<bill session="112" type="h" number="1470" updated="2022-03-02T05:25:07Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 5, United States Code, to extend the probationary period applicable to appointments in the civil service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to extend the probationary period applicable to appointments in the civil service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 15 - 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 112-116.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-06-23" calendar="Union" number="67">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 67.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-07-29T20:59:08Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Requires the probationary period before an appointment in the competitive civil service or an inital appointment as a supervisor or manager becomes final to be not less than two years.&#160; Retains existing probationary requirements for preference eligible individuals (i.e., veterans)&#160;initially appointed to positions that exist 180 days after the enactment of this Act.

Requires the head of each agency to ensure that: (1) announcements of vacant positions and offers of appointment clearly state the terms and conditions of the probationary period,&#160;(2) individuals who are required to complete probationary periods receive timely notice of performance requirements, and&#160;(3) certification of successful completion of a probationary period is made.

Revises the definition of "employee" for purposes of adverse action provisions to mean: (1) an individual who has completed not less than two years (currently, one year) of competitive federal service, or (2) an member of the excepted service who has completed not less than two years of current continuous service in the same or a similar position in an executive agency.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-116</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
