<bill session="116" type="s" number="4559" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Russia Bounty Response Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Russia Bounty Response Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to respond to the provision of bounties by the Government of the Russian Federation for the killing of members of the Armed Forces of the United States and members of the Resolute Support Mission led by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and with respect to certain Russian political figures and oligarchs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2020-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-02T16:20:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Russia Bounty Response Act of 2020

This bill requires various actions in response to the influence of Russia's government in South and Central Asia and contains other related provisions.

The Department of State shall report to Congress a strategy for using U.S. diplomacy to counter such Russian influence.

The bill imposes sanctions on various individuals and entities, including (1) Russian President Vladimir Putin or any person acting on his behalf, (2) any senior Russian government official involved in a program to provide bounties for killing members of the U.S. Armed Forces or certain North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) forces in Afghanistan, and (3) individuals and entities that facilitate illicit or corrupt activities on behalf of Putin or other specified persons. The bill imposes civil and criminal penalties related to violations of such sanctions.

The bill also authorizes various activities, including (1) rewards for information about Russian bounties against U.S. Armed Forces anywhere in the world, and (2) State Department activities to counter Russian influence in South and Central Asia.

The State Department shall seek to establish a working group involving officials from the government of Afghanistan to address threats to Afghanistan's security posed by Russia's government. The State Department must also create a Deputy Assistant Secretary position tasked with coordinating efforts to counter Russian influence in South and Central Asia. The President shall also appoint a special envoy tasked with countering Russian influence in the region.</summary>
</bill>
