<bill session="119" type="s" number="750" updated="2025-11-19T05:02:00Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Rural Seniors&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Rural Seniors&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from implementing, enforcing, or otherwise giving effect to a final rule regarding minimum staffing for nursing facilities, and to establish an advisory panel on the nursing home workforce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2025-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1399-1400" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1683" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-14T15:48:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Rural Seniors&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Access to Care Act

This bill prohibits administration, implementation, or enforcement of the rule titled Medicare and Medicaid Programs; Minimum Staffing Standards for Long-Term Care Facilities and Medicaid Institutional Payment Transparency Reporting, which was issued by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services on May 10, 2024.

Specifically, the bill prohibits administration, implementation, or enforcement of provisions that, among other changes, (1) establish minimum staffing standards for nurses in Medicare and Medicaid long-term care facilities, including requiring a nurse to be onsite 24/7 and requiring a minimum of 3.48 total nurse staffing hours per resident per day; and (2) require state Medicaid programs to report on payments to direct care workers and support staff of nursing facilities and intermediate care facilities for individuals with intellectual disabilities.

Also, the bill requires&#160;the Department of Health and Human Services to establish an Advisory Panel on the Nursing Home Workforce. The panel must report annually to Congress, including on workforce shortages and barriers to accessing nursing homes in rural and underserved areas.</summary>
</bill>
