<bill session="118" type="hr" number="478" updated="2024-08-28T22:20:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing disapproval of the withdrawal by the Secretary of the Interior of approximately 22,684 acres of Bureau of Land Management lands in the Railroad Valley of Nye County, Nevada, from all forms of mineral entry under United States law, subject to valid existing rights.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing disapproval of the withdrawal by the Secretary of the Interior of approximately 22,684 acres of Bureau of Land Management lands in the Railroad Valley of Nye County, Nevada, from all forms of mineral entry under United States law, subject to valid existing rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-28T22:20:26Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution expresses disapproval of the withdrawal of certain Bureau of Land Management lands in the Railroad Valley of Nye County, Nevada.

The resolution disapproves the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) decision to decline Nye County's request to act as a cooperating agency throughout the withdrawal process for Railroad Valley and the Department of the Interior authorizing the withdrawal of approximately 22,684 acres in Railroad Valley.

Further, the resolution recommends that federal agencies include requesting states, counties, cities, and municipalities as cooperating agencies for proposed land withdrawals in their jurisdiction or vicinity, at their request.</summary>
</bill>
