<bill session="116" type="s" number="2616" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:39Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alaska Tribal Public Safety Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Tribal Public Safety Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide civil and criminal jurisdiction over Alaska Natives and non-Alaska Natives for certain Indian tribes in the State of Alaska.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-27T19:20:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alaska Tribal Public Safety Empowerment Act

This bill expands the civil and criminal jurisdiction of certain Indian tribes over Alaska Natives and non-Alaska Natives in Alaska.

Specifically, the bill recognizes and affirms that any Indian tribe in Alaska occupying an Alaska Native village may exercise (1) criminal and civil jurisdiction over Alaska Natives in the village; and (2) full civil jurisdiction over Alaska Natives and non-Alaska Natives in the village with respect to issuing and enforcing protection orders, excluding violators of protection orders from the village, and using other appropriate mechanisms to address matters in the village related to protection orders.

The bill also directs the Department of Justice to establish a pilot program to provide certain Indian tribes with (1) general civil jurisdiction over Alaska Natives and non-Alaska Natives present in the Alaska Native village occupied by such tribe; and (2) criminal jurisdiction over Alaska Natives and non-Alaska Natives with respect to specific crimes, such as domestic violence, sexual violence, and stalking.</summary>
</bill>
