<bill session="118" type="h" number="5745" updated="2024-08-21T16:47:32Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Asset Market Structure and Investor Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Asset Market Structure and Investor Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the regulation of digital assets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5966" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-02T13:57:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Digital Asset Market Structure and Investor Protection Act

This bill generally addresses the regulatory treatment of digital assets and digital asset securities.

The bill grants the Commodities Futures Trading Commission authority over digital assets, which (1) are created electronically or digitally through software code; (2) are programmed with rules that govern the creation, supply, ownership, use, and transfer of the asset; (3) have a secure transaction history; and (4) are capable of being transferred through a decentralized method without an intermediate custodian.

Additionally, the bill grants the Securities and Exchange Commission authority over the regulation of digital asset securities, digital assets that provide the holder with (1) equity or debt interest in the issuer, (2) rights to certain payments from the issuer, (3) voting rights in the major corporate actions of the issuer, or (4) liquidation rights in the event of the issuer's liquidation.

Digital assets and digital asset securities are subject to the Bank Secrecy Act for anti-money laundering, reporting, and recordkeeping purposes.

The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may issue digital currency. However, digital assets, digital asset securities, and fiat-based stablecoins (a digital asset pegged to the U.S. dollar or other fiat currency) are not U.S. legal tender. Digital asset fiat-based stablecoins must be registered with and approved by the Department of the Treasury.

Digital assets shall not be covered by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the National Credit Union Administration depository insurance.

The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network must issue rules regarding the use of anonymizing services and other anonymity-enhanced convertible virtual currency services.</summary>
</bill>
