<bill session="119" type="h" number="618" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-15">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="short">Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="display">Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Apex Project, Nevada Land Transfer and Authorization Act of 1989 to include the City of North Las Vegas and the Apex Industrial Park Owners Association, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000590" joined="2025-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2025-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 119-86.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-04-30" calendar="Union" number="61">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 61.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T17:18:11-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T17:18:26-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1980-1982" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T17:18:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 618.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-05-13T17:26:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1980-1981" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T17:26:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2025-06-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3459" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2025-07-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2025-07-15" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="119-24" type="public" datetime="2025-07-15">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 119-24.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-08T21:33:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Apex Area Technical Corrections Act

This bill&#160;provides for the transfer of certain rights-of-way related to the Apex Project from the Department of the Interior to&#160;the city of North Las Vegas and the Apex Industrial Park Owners Association.

Specifically, the bill modifies the Apex Project, Nevada Land Transfer and Authorization Act of 1989, which provided Clark County, Nevada, with the option to acquire certain federal land referred to as the Apex Site for use as sites for industries that generate hazardous materials (including the Kerr-McGee site).&#160;

Under the bill, the Department of the Interior must grant utility and transportation rights-of-way to the city of North Las Vegas and the Apex Industrial Park Owners Association for the connection of existing electric power, water, natural gas, telephone, railroad, and highway facilities to the Kerr-McGee site and the other lands conveyed in accordance with the bill.

Interior must also grant to the city and association such rights-of-way on public lands as may be necessary to support the development as a heavy use industrial zone of some or all of the lands authorized for sale by Interior within the Apex Site that lie outside the boundaries of the Kerr-McGee site.

Transfers by the United States of any additional lands or interests in lands within the Apex Site or rights-of-way issued pursuant to this bill must be conditioned upon compliance with applicable federal land laws.

The withdrawal of the lands within the Apex Site must continue in perpetuity for all of the transferred lands.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-86</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
