<bill session="108" type="h" number="1373" updated="2023-01-15T22:33:34Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IDEA Parental Choice Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide options to States to innovate and improve the education of children with disabilities by expanding the choices for students and parents under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IDEA Parental Choice Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000589" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000429" joined="2003-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000210" joined="2003-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000676" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001152" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2003-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000458" joined="2003-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000260" joined="2003-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E536"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">IDEA Parental Choice Act of 2003 - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to authorize use of funds for parental school choice programs which may involve vouchers for private or public education for students with disabilities.Allows the use of certain research and innovation grant and contract funds to support planning, design, and implementation of State programs that allow parents of children with disabilities a choice of an appropriate public or private school (parental option program).Allows any State with a statewide or local area parental option program that allows use of public funds to pay some or all costs of attendance at a public or private school to supplement those public funds from its IDEA allocation, if the Federal funds are distributed to parents who make a genuine independent choice as to the appropriate school for their child. Provides that a State's allowing a parent to exercise this option fulfills the State's obligation to provide a free appropriate public education with respect to the child with disabilities during the period in which the child is enrolled in the selected school.Authorizes use of IDEA funds for local educational agencies to support reasonable additional expenses for the accommodation of students with disabilities who are eligible to receive supplemental education services, including services from private or faith-based providers, because they attend underachieving schools designated for improvement.Allows, at a State's discretion, students with disabilities up to age six, who meet certain criteria, to be included in IDEA early intervention services programs (thus giving parents the choice to have their child continue with the same service provider).</summary>
</bill>
