<bill session="117" type="h" number="2607" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FASTER Presumptions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish in the Department of Veterans Affairs procedures to determine presumptions of service connection based on toxic exposure, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairly Assessing Service-related Toxic Exposure Residuals Presumptions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FASTER Presumptions Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2021-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2021-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2021-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2021-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-15T16:26:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Fairly Assessing Service-related Toxic Exposure Residuals Presumptions Act or the FASTER Presumptions Act

This bill revises policies and procedures of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) related to establishing or modifying presumptions of service-connection based on toxic exposure. The bill sets up a procedure by which the VA must determine whether to establish, remove, or modify via regulations presumptions of service-connection based on toxic exposure.

Specifically, the bill establishes within the VA the Formal Advisory Committee on Toxic Exposure, the Science Review Board, and the Working Group to assist with the various procedures in establishing or removing presumptions of service-connection. Such procedures include assessing the exposure of veterans to toxic substances during active service, evaluating research on the health effects of exposure, and making recommendations based on the evidence and research.

The bill also establishes the Expert Advisory Panel on Constrictive Bronchiolitis within the VA to develop guidelines for VA research on symptomatic veterans who served on active duty in the Southwest Asia theater of operations and have bronchiolitis.

The Department of Defense must develop and implement a plan to strengthen data collection with respect to members of the Armed Forces (including the reserve components) who are exposed to toxic substances while serving.

The VA must initiate or sponsor various studies related to veterans who served on active duty in certain locations.

Finally, the VA must provide annual training to relevant employees to improve the handling of claims for compensation and benefits that relate to toxic exposure.</summary>
</bill>
