<bill session="117" type="s" number="2497" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, to prohibit nonconsensual release of a nondebtor entity's liability to an entity other than the debtor, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Nondebtor Release Prohibition Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nondebtor Release Prohibition Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2022-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4777" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-07T17:11:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nondebtor Release Prohibition Act of 2021 

This bill addresses the release by bankruptcy courts of creditor or other third-party claims against non-debtors. Complex bankruptcies may involve third-party claims against non-debtors associated with the debtor, such as the debtor's officers, directors, or employees. Currently, in carrying out a bankruptcy plan, bankruptcy courts may release non-debtors from liability (there is a split in the judicial circuits regarding this practice).

The bill generally prohibits a bankruptcy court from (1) releasing or modifying a non-debtor's liability through the approval of a bankruptcy plan or through an order, or (2) enjoining a judicial proceeding or other act to collect or otherwise enforce such a claim or cause of action against a non-debtor. However, the bill provides for the release of such liability if express consent is given by the third party.

The bill also generally limits an order or decree to temporarily enjoin a proceeding against a non-debtor to 90 days.

Additionally, the bill gives appellate jurisdiction to the appropriate U.S. court of appeals regarding an order or decree to temporarily enjoin or stay a proceeding against a non-debtor in a Chapter 11 reorganization bankruptcy case. Currently, U.S. district courts have appellate jurisdiction for these matters.

Upon request of an interested party, and after notice and a hearing, the court shall dismiss a Chapter 11 reorganization bankruptcy case if the debtor was involved in certain restructuring activity that (1) had the intent or foreseeable effect of separating a debtor's assets from a debtor's liabilities and the debtor assuming or retaining such liabilities, and (2) occurred in the 10-year period prior to the filing of the bankruptcy petition.</summary>
</bill>
