<bill session="109" type="s" number="461" updated="2019-11-15T21:52:33Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crosby-Puller Combat Wounds Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="display">Crosby-Puller Combat Wounds Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 37, United States Code, to require that a member of the uniformed services who is wounded or otherwise injured while serving in a combat zone continue to be paid monthly military pay and allowances, while the member recovers from the wound or injury, at least equal to the monthly military pay and allowances the member received immediately before receiving the wound or injury, to continue the combat zone tax exclusion for the member during the recovery period, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2005-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001163" joined="2005-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1722"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1722" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12676"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="771" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-21T20:32:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Crosby-Puller Combat Wounds Compensation Act - Requires a member of the Armed Forces who is wounded or otherwise injured while serving in a combat zone for which special pay is authorized to be paid monthly military pay, during the period in which the member recovers from such wound or injury, that is at least equal to the monthly pay received by the member immediately before receiving the wound or injury. Makes such requirement effective for pay periods beginning on or after September 11, 2001.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to continue during such recovery period the combat zone special pay income tax exclusion. Makes such requirement effective for months beginning on or after the above date.</summary>
</bill>
