<bill session="108" type="s" number="1089" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cuba Transition Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage multilateral cooperation and authorize a program of assistance to facilitate a peaceful transition in Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cuba Transition Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2003-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000059" joined="2003-09-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6714-6715" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cubans"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International organization"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-08T21:14:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cuba Transition Act of 2003 - Directs the the Secretary of State to designate, within the Department of State, a coordinator responsible for designing an overall strategy to coordinate specified preparations for a transition in Cuba that targets economic, political and financial developments.

Authorizes the Secretary to designate specified funds to be provided to the Organization of American States (OAS) for: (1) Inter-American Commission on Human Rights activities relating to the situation of human rights in Cuba; (2) the funding of an OAS emergency fund for the deployment of human rights observers, election support, and election observation in Cuba; and (3) scholarships for Cuban students attending colleges, universities, or other educational programs in member states of the OAS.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should begin consultation with: (1) governments of other Western Hemisphere countries regarding a transition in Cuba; and (2) international partners and governments regarding a multilateral diplomatic and financial support program for response to a transition in Cuba.

Authorizes the President to furnish assistance and provide other support for individuals and independent nongovernmental organizations to support specified democracy-building efforts for Cuba.

Authorizes appropriations to the President to establish a fund to provide assistance to a transition government in Cuba.</summary>
</bill>
