<bill session="118" type="h" number="4144" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FAIR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Assistance to Initiate Repayment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline and improve the Federal student loan repayment system to protect borrowers and taxpayers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000086"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001314" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000632" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001093" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2023-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001136" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001216" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000828" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2023-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4711" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-18T17:45:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Assistance to Initiate Repayment Act or the FAIR Act

This bill makes various changes to the federal student loan system, including by establishing a new income-driven repayment plan and limiting the authority of the Department of Education (ED) to propose or issue regulations and executive actions related to federal student aid programs.

The bill directs ED to provide at least 12 notices to each borrower of a federal student loan indicating (1) the date on which the borrower is required to make monthly loan payments; (2) the borrower's options for repayment; and (3) the options available to a borrower who is in default, including the option to consolidate or rehabilitate loans. ED must also conduct additional outreach to at-risk borrowers.

Additionally, the bill replaces existing federal student loan repayment plans with one standard 10-year repayment plan and one income-driven repayment plan. The bill outlines the terms of this new income-driven repayment plan.

The bill provides deferment options for borrowers with loans made on or after July 1, 2024. The bill prohibits ED from authorizing additional deferment options or periods of deferment other than those authorized by this bill.

The bill allows borrowers to rehabilitate a defaulted loan twice (currently, only once).

The bill also prohibits ED from issuing a proposed rule, final regulation, or executive action related to federal student aid programs if ED determines that the rule, regulation, or action (1) is economically significant, and (2) would result in an increase in a subsidy cost.</summary>
</bill>
