<bill session="118" type="h" number="1677" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Spectrum Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Simplifying Management, Access, Reallocation, and Transfer of Spectrum Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Spectrum Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to provide for an incumbent informing capability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000558"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2023-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-01T17:51:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Simplifying Management, Access, Reallocation, and Transfer of Spectrum Act or the SMART Spectrum Act

This bill requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to implement an incumbent informing capability in its regulation of the electromagnetic spectrum. The bill also outlines minimum requirements for the capability that address protection of classified information and other matters.

Incumbent informing capability is a mechanism that facilitates the sharing of spectrum allocated for both federal and nonfederal uses; it enables federal users to reliably inform nonfederal users when and where the federal systems are operating in order to manage harmful interference between the federal and nonfederal uses.</summary>
</bill>
