<bill session="109" type="h" number="3406" updated="2021-09-29T20:43:10Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Workers Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">United States Workers Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect United States workers from competition of foreign workforces for performance of Federal and State contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2005-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001153" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Offshore manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-05T19:58:05Z" status="Introduced in House">United States Workers Protection Act of 2005 - Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to prohibit: (1) outsourced federal government work from being performed by a contractor or any subcontractor outside the United States unless federal employees previously performed such work outside the United States; (2) work on a contract from being performed outside the United States unless it is necessary in order to meet a requirement for the contract to be performed specifically at a location outside the United States or the President deems it necessary for national security reasons, or the head of the executive agency makes and reports a determination to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget that the property or services needed are available only outside the United States and no property or services available inside the United States would satisfy the agency's need; and (3) federal funds from being disbursed to a state until the Governor of the state has transmitted written certification that none of the funds will be spent for the performance of contracts outside the United States and if the Governor of such state determines that the property and services needed by the state are available only outside the United States and no property or services available inside the United States would satisfy the state's need and transmits a notification of such determination to the agency head administering the authority under which such funds are disbursed to or for such state.</summary>
</bill>
