<bill session="118" type="s" number="11" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFER Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFER Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Auction For Energy Reserves Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to require the Secretary of Energy to stipulate, as a condition on the sale at auction of any petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, that the petroleum products not be exported to certain countries, to prohibit such sales to certain state-owned entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="337" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-22T14:13:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Secure Auction For Energy Reserves Act of 2023 or the SAFER Act of 2023

This bill limits the sale and exportation of petroleum products (e.g., crude oil) from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR). Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to require, as a condition of auction sales, that the petroleum products not be exported to countries that are designated as countries of particular concern for religious freedom under the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998. In addition, the bill establishes limits on auction sales of petroleum products from the SPR to state-owned entities if DOE determines that, as of the dates of the auctions, there are bans on, or the imposition of sanctions by the United States with respect to, the purchase of crude oil from countries. Under such circumstances, state-owned entities must certify that they have not purchased petroleum products from countries subject to such bans or sanctions later than 15 days after the date on which the ban or sanctions went into effect in order to be able to bid in auctions. If DOE determines state-owned entities participating in the auctions have purchased crude oil from such countries after that time period, then DOE may not sell petroleum products from the SPR to such entities.</summary>
</bill>
