<bill session="117" type="s" number="3381" updated="2023-03-08T19:59:11Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Trust Land Homeownership Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Trust Land Homeownership Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tribal Trust Land Homeownership Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Bureau of Indian Affairs to process and complete all mortgage packages associated with residential and business mortgages on Indian land by certain deadlines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2021-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2021-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9162-9164" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 117-518.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-06">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Schatz without amendment. With written report No. 117-232.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="590">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 590.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-23T13:29:36Z" status="Reported to Senate">Tribal Trust Land Homeownership Act of 2021 

This bill sets forth requirements for the processing of a proposed residential leasehold mortgage, business leasehold mortgage, land mortgage, or right-of-way document by the Bureau of Indian Affairs. The bureau must notify lenders upon receipt of such documentation, perform a preliminary review of such documents not later than 10 days after receipt, and approve or disapprove of such documents within 20 or 30 days, depending on the type of application.

Additionally, the bill sets forth requirements for the bureau regarding (1) response times for the completion of certified title status reports, (2) notification of delays in processing, and (3) the form of notices and delivery of certain reports.

The bill also provides relevant federal agencies and Indian tribes with read-only access to the Trust Asset and Accounting Management System maintained by the bureau.

The Government Accountability Office must report on digitizing documents for the purpose of streamlining and expediting the completion of mortgage packages for residential mortgages on Indian land.

Finally, the bill establishes within the bureau's Division of Real Estate Services the position of Realty Ombudsman.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-232</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
