<bill session="116" type="h" number="6344" updated="2022-02-08T23:14:38Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expediting the EIDL Program Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the economic injury disaster loan of the Small Business Administration in response to COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expediting the EIDL Program Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000296"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6312" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-16T16:20:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Expediting the EIDL Program Act of 2020

This bill modifies the disbursement of economic injury disaster loans by the Small Business Administration (SBA) with respect to such loans made in response to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill authorizes the SBA to increase the amount of a disaster loan to a small business by 20% to cover costs related to continuity of operations and risk mitigation improvements. The bill also authorizes the SBA to make such loans to startups and to waive rules related to affiliation, and it requires the SBA to waive the personal guarantee requirement on such loans made to cooperatives.

In addition, an applicant for a disaster loan may request an advance on such loan up to a specified amount, and they shall not be required to repay any amount of an advance if they are subsequently denied a disaster loan. The bill also authorizes the SBA to approve an applicant for a disaster loan that is below a certain amount based solely on the applicant's credit score and to use alternative methods to determine such applicant's ability to repay.

Further, the bill establishes a maximum interest rate on a disaster loan based on an applicant's ability to obtain credit elsewhere, and it expands the qualifying events for which a disaster loan may be awarded to include emergencies involving federal primary responsibility.</summary>
</bill>
