<bill session="109" type="h" number="6119" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:18Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Puget Sound Regional Shellfish Settlement Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the equitable settlement of claims of Indian tribes in the region of Puget Sound, Washington regarding treaty rights to take shellfish from lands in that region, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puget Sound Regional Shellfish Settlement Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001229" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000329" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2006-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5946" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fish culture"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-06T19:48:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Puget Sound Regional Shellfish Settlement Act of 2006 - Approves, ratifies, and confirms the Settlement Agreement entered into by and between specified Indian tribes in the region of Puget Sound, Washington, commercial shellfish growers, the state of Washington, and the United States to resolve certain disputes regarding implementation of tribal treaty rights to take shellfish from certain covered tidelands owned, leased or otherwise subject to harvest by the growers.

Establishes in the Treasury the Puget Sound Regional Shellfish Settlement Trust Fund and the Puget Sound Regional Shellfish Settlement Special Holding Account.





Declares that the Secretary of the Interior shall not be accountable for nor incur any liability for the collection, deposit, management, or nonpayment of a specified state of Washington payment to the tribes pursuant to the Settlement Agreement.

Declares that all right of any other tribe, within 20 years after the deposit of funds in the Special Holding Account, to bring an action to enforce or exercise its treaty rights to take shellfish from public and private tidelands in Washington, including from some lands owned, leased, or otherwise subject to harvest by any and all commercial growers, shall be determined in accordance with the decisions of federal courts in United States v. Washington.

Provides that if any payment by the United States is not paid in the amount or manner specified by this Act, or is not paid within six months after the date specified by the Settlement Agreement, such failure shall give rise to a cause of action by the tribes against the United States. Authorizes the tribes to bring such an action in the U.S. Court of Federal Claims.</summary>
</bill>
