<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="872" updated="2022-02-03T05:22:48Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3867" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2007-10-30T13:21:13-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-10-30"/>
  <description>At the end of title II, add the following (and amend the table of contents accordingly):    SEC. __. PROHIBITION ON CONTRACT AWARDS TO CONTRACTORS IN VIOLATION OF IMMIGRATION LAWS.    Any employer found, based on a determination by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General to have engaged in a pattern or practice of hiring, recruiting or referring for a fee, for employment in the United States an alien knowing the person is an unauthorized alien shall be subject to debarment from the receipt of future Federal contracts under this Act.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 9 printed in House Report 110-407 to provide that any employer found, based on a determination by the Department of Homeland Security or the Attorney General to have engaged in a pattern or practice of hiring, recruiting or referring for a fee, for employment in the United States an alien knowing the person is an unauthorized alien shall be subject to debarment from the receipt of future Federal contracts.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2007-10-30T13:21:13-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Gillibrand amendment (A009) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T13:15:39-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A009) offered by Mrs. Gillibrand.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12184-12185" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12185" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T13:15:39-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A009) offered by Mrs. Gillibrand.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12184-12185" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12185" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T13:21:13-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T13:21:13-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Gillibrand amendment (A009) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
