<bill session="111" type="s" number="3311" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:01Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to improve and enhance the capabilities of the Department of Defense to prevent and respond to sexual assault in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve and enhance the capabilities of the Department of Defense to prevent and respond to sexual assault in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2010-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2010-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001210" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2010-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2010-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2010-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3166-3167"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-25T20:18:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the officials authorized to receive a restricted reporting by a member of the Armed Forces (member) of an allegation of sexual assault without resulting in the initiation of an official investigative process to include judge advocates.

Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to modify the Military Rules of Evidence to provide a member the privilege to refuse to disclose in a military proceeding a confidential communication between a member and a Victim Advocate, if such communication was made to facilitate victim advocacy.

Requires each Sexual Assault Response Coordinator to be a member on active duty or a full-time civilian DOD employee. Prohibits any contractor personnel from acting as Coordinators. Requires each military battalion to have at least one Victim Advocate who is either a member on active duty or a full-time civilian DOD employee. Directs the Secretary to carry out a training and certification program for such Coordinators.

Requires the DOD position of Director of the Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Office to be a position in the Senior Executive Service. Directs the Secretary to standardize and update programs and activities relating to sexual assault prevention and response across the Armed Forces and the military departments.

Requires the Secretary to ensure that training on sexual assault prevention and response is provided to members at each level of professional military education and is uniform across the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
