<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="729" updated="2022-02-03T06:02:40Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1938" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-07-26T16:52:49-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  <description>Amendment to add a sense of Congress that the United States must decrease its dependence on oil from countries that are hostile to the interests of the United States of America and that Canada has long been a strong trading partner and increasing access to their energy resources will create jobs in the United States.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in House Report 112-181 to add a sense of Congress that the United States must decrease its dependence on oil from countries that are hostile to the interests of the United States of America and that Canada has long been a strong trading partner and increasing access to their energy resources will create jobs in the United States.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-07-26T16:52:49-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment (A010) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:46:55-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5527-5529" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5527-5528" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:52:49-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment (A010) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:52:49-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26T16:46:55-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A010) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5527-5529" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5527-5528" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
