<bill session="117" type="h" number="7506" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Era of Preventing End-Stage Kidney Disease Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Era of Preventing End-Stage Kidney Disease Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to preventing end-stage kidney disease, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2022-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2022-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2022-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2022-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2022-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2022-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2022-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2022-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-03T19:54:29Z" status="Introduced in House">New Era of Preventing End-Stage Kidney Disease Act

This bill addresses rare kidney diseases through research, training for health professionals, and other means. It also modifies requirements for Medicare drug plan formularies that include drugs for rare diseases or conditions.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must

 convene a conference focused on diagnosis and treatment of rare kidney diseases; study risk factors, access to care (including to genetic and genomic testing), and other matters related to rare kidney diseases; and establish grants for supporting kidney disease education and referrals in communities of color. HHS may award grants to educate and train health professionals about kidney disease and nephrology. Additionally, health professional schools that receive certain HHS funding for educating underrepresented minority individuals must support postgraduate nephrology training.

The National Institutes of Health (NIH) must report on diversity in its kidney disease research. The NIH may also (1) support research on rare kidney diseases that, among other requirements, includes persons of color in study populations; and (2) establish regional centers of excellence for rare kidney diseases.

The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must evaluate methods for (1) treating rare kidney diseases, with a focus on delaying dialysis and transplant; and (2) raising awareness about rare kidney diseases, including in communities of color.

Furthermore, if a Medicare drug plan formulary includes a drug to treat a rare disease or condition, at least two members of the committee that develops or reviews the formulary must have expertise in the field of medicine related to that drug.</summary>
</bill>
