<bill session="117" type="h" number="6149" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Care for Vulnerable Older Citizens and People with Disabilities through Workforce Advancement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Care for Vulnerable Older Citizens and People with Disabilities through Workforce Advancement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to develop and test an expanded and advanced role for direct-care workers who provide long-term services and supports to older adults and people with disabilities in efforts to coordinate care and improve the efficiency of service delivery, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2021-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-23T18:38:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Care for Vulnerable Older Citizens and People with Disabilities through Workforce Advancement Act of 2021

This bill establishes demonstration projects to improve care and service delivery through the use of direct care workers (e.g., nursing assistants and home health aides) for older adults and individuals with disabilities who have chronic illness or are at risk of institutional placement.

The Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) must award grants to partnerships of health care providers, long-term care facilities, and other organizations to carry out the projects.

Specifically, HRSA must award grants for incorporating direct care workers into interdisciplinary care coordination teams to support transitions in care and prevent unnecessary hospital readmissions. HRSA must also award grants for (1) using the abilities of direct care workers to manage and improve the health of individuals with multiple chronic conditions and long-term care needs; or (2) training direct care workers to take on greater responsibilities in managing specific diseases, such as Alzheimer's disease and diabetes.</summary>
</bill>
