<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1003" updated="2022-02-03T05:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2008-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide increased accountability and transparency in the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide increased accountability and transparency in the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000589" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000071" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001064" joined="2008-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001046" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000492" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000666" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000260" joined="2008-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee chairmen"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee membership"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-03-06T15:26:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends Rule X (Organization of Committees) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to revise the composition of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct. Requires Committee members to be appointed jointly by the Speaker of the House and the minority leader: three from the majority party, three from the minority party, and four former Members who have not been registered lobbyists for the last two years. (Currently the Speaker picks five and the minority leader picks five.)

Limits chairmanship of the Committee to a current Member only.

Rotates chairmanship of the Committee between the two parties from Congress to Congress after the 111th Congress, regardless of which party is in the majority. Requires the chairmanship for the 111th Congress to be held by a member of the majority party.

Amends Rule II (Other Officers and Officials) to require the Inspector General, upon receipt, to transmit to the Committee (without any change) any written information submitted by an outside individual or organization of an alleged violation of the Code of Official Conduct by Members, Delegates, the Resident Commissioner, or House officers or employees.

Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) to require the Committee to publish a monthly report on its investigative activities, without disclosing the name of any individual who is the subject of any allegation or its particulars.

Requires the Committee to: (1) disclose publicly its inability to reach a resolution of an alleged violation; and (2) forward the complaint and all accompanying documentation to the Department of Justice (DOJ) for its consideration if such impasse persists.

Requires the Committee to disclose publicly whether a Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, or House officer or employee is under investigation.</summary>
</bill>
