<bill session="117" type="s" number="1956" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Manufacturing Clean Energy and Energy Efficiency Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a manufacturing clean energy and energy efficiency grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacturing Clean Energy and Energy Efficiency Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-09T19:02:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Manufacturing Clean Energy and Energy Efficiency Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a program within the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy that provides grants to small- or medium-sized manufacturers for projects that will (1) improve their energy efficiency, material efficiency, cybersecurity, or productivity; or (2) reduce their waste production, greenhouse gas emissions, or nongreenhouse gas pollution.

In order to be eligible for grants, manufacturers must have completed energy assessments from Industrial Assessment Centers funded by DOE or third-party assessors that provide equivalent assessments. Only projects that have been recommended in energy assessments are eligible for grants.

The bill also authorizes Industrial Assessment Centers to provide technical assistance to small- and medium-sized manufacturers that have completed energy assessments to upgrade, retrofit, or replace systems or infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
