<bill session="112" type="s" number="322" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:28Z">
  <state datetime="2011-11-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the Alpine Lakes Wilderness in the State of Washington, to designate the Middle Fork Snoqualmie River and Pratt River as wild and scenic rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2011-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/17/2011 without amendment. With written report No. 112-108.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="270">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 270.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="608" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-21T13:59:34Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act - Designates certain land in the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest in the state of Washington, which shall be considered to become a part of the Alpine Lakes Wilderness, as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS).

Makes any land or interests within the proposed boundary acquired by the United States part of the Wilderness.

Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate the Middle Fork Snoqualmie and Pratt Rivers in Washington as scenic and/or wild rivers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 112-108</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
