<bill session="118" type="s" number="1181" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bank Management Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bank Management Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to improve financial stability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1212-1213" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-08T17:41:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bank Management Accountability Act

This bill expands the ability of financial regulators to recover compensation from senior executives or directors at failed banks and financial institutions and to impose bans on their future participation at any financial company.

The bill authorizes the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to recover compensation paid to certain current or former senior executives or directors of an insured depository institution for which FDIC is a receiver or conservator.

If a current or former senior executive or director is substantially responsible for the failed condition of the insured depository institution, FDIC may recover any compensation received during the 2-year period prior to FDIC appointment as receiver or conservator of the insured depository institution, except for cases of fraud, where no time limit shall apply.

The bill also (1) prohibits liability insurance policies from covering such compensation, and (2) authorizes FDIC to prohibit any further participation by those individuals in the affairs of any financial company for not less than 2 years.

Finally, the bill expands the authority of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the FDIC to ban senior executives at systemically important financial institutions in receivership from participating for 2 years in the affairs of any financial company. Specifically, the bill removes the requirement that, to be subject to such a ban, the violation must involve personal dishonesty or demonstrate willful or continuing disregard for the company's safety and soundness.</summary>
</bill>
