<bill session="109" type="s" number="2231" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:06Z">
  <state datetime="2006-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Labor to prescribe additional coal mine safety standards, to require additional penalties for habitual violators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="popular">Coal Mine Safety bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2006-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2006-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2006-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2006-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2006-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2006-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2006-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000059" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2006-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S449-451, S451"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4695" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-03-14T18:45:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to revise regulations prescribed pursuant to the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to require coal mine operators to expeditiously provide notification of any accident where rescue and recovery work is necessary.

Requires the Secretary to revise regulations regarding mine rescue teams to: (1) address training and qualifications for team members, rescue equipment and technology, the structure and organization of teams, and the guidelines about liability and insurance issues; and (2) require that mine operators employ rescue teams to provide a rapid response and have a plan for coordination and communication between the rescue teams and local emergency response personnel.

Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations to require: (1) each coal mine to maintain at strategic locations sufficient emergency supplies of air and self-contained breathing equipment, and independent means of communication with the surface, for people awaiting rescue; and (2) each operator to implement a communication and electronic tracking system to assist in rescue and to equip each person that enters a mine with certain communication and tracking devices.

Requires the Secretary to revise regulations in order to prohibit belt haulage entries from being used to ventilate active working places in any coal mine.

Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations to establish minimum civil penalties for violations: (1) where the operator displays negligence or reckless disregard of a mandatory health or safety standard; and (2) of rescue notification requirements.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish an Office of Science and Technology Transfer within the Mine Safety and Health Administration to conduct research and development to apply advancing sciences and technologies to mines and miner health and safety; (2) review and revise mine health and safety standards with regard to implementing such technologies.

Establishes the position of Miner Ombudsman within the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Labor to be responsible for ensuring the safety of mines through information collection and sharing.</summary>
</bill>
