<bill session="110" type="h" number="582" updated="2020-02-10T16:52:57Z">
  <state datetime="2007-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Teacher Training Expansion Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="display">Teacher Training Expansion Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide the Secretary of Education with authority to give preference, in the distribution of certain grants under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, to local educational agencies and certain public or private nonprofit organizations that provide training to regular education personnel to meet the needs of children with disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2007-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2007-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2007-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2007-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2007-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2007-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000784" joined="2007-01-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E159-160"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-02-23T18:58:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Teacher Training Expansion Act of 2007 - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to authorize the Secretary of Education to give preference to certain entities in selecting recipients for specified IDEA grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements for technical assistance, model demonstration projects, information dissemination, and implementing activities supported by scientifically based research.

Allows such preference to be given to institutions of higher education (IHEs) that are: (1) educating regular education personnel to meet the needs of children with disabilities in integrated settings; (2) educating special education personnel to work in collaboration with regular educators in integrated settings; or (3) successfully recruiting and preparing individuals with disabilities and individuals from groups that are underrepresented in the profession for which the IHE is preparing individuals.

Allows such preference also to be given to local educational agencies, other public agencies, and private nonprofit organizations that: (1) provide training to regular education personnel to meet the needs of children with disabilities in integrated settings; (2) provide training to regular education personnel to work in collaboration with regular educators in integrated settings; or (3) prepare individuals with disabilities and individuals from groups that are underrepresented in the profession for which the entity is preparing individuals.</summary>
</bill>
