<bill session="117" type="s" number="4902" updated="2023-08-31T16:30:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Invent Here, Make Here for Homeland Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Invent Here, Make Here for Homeland Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Invent Here, Make Here for Homeland Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address the preference for United States industry with respect to patent rights in inventions made with Department of Homeland Security research assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2022-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters without amendment. With written report No. 117-239.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="617">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 617.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-28T17:04:17Z" status="Reported to Senate">Invent Here, Make Here for Homeland Security Act

This bill restricts the manufacture abroad of products invented using funding provided by the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Specifically, the bill prohibits a firm or nonprofit organization which receives title to any subject invention developed under a funding agreement with DHS from granting to any person the exclusive right to use or sell such invention unless that person agrees that any products embodying, or produced through the use of, such invention will be manufactured substantially in the United States.

The bill authorizes waivers of this prohibition in certain instances, but&#160;prohibits waivers for products that will be manufactured substantially in a country of concern, including North Korea, China, Russia, and Iran.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-239</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
