<bill session="118" type="s" number="1674" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No START Treaty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No START Treaty Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for better security and accountability with respect to the strategic and non-strategic nuclear arsenals of the Russian Federation and the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-12T16:27:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No START Treaty Act

This bill sets requirements for certain nuclear arms agreements with Russia and bars the expenditure of funds to implement the New START Treaty (a nuclear arms reduction treaty between the United States and Russia signed April 8, 2010) or similar future agreements unless such requirements are met.&#160;

The bill prohibits the President from negotiating or entering into a treaty with Russia that would allow Russia to possess an equal or greater number of nuclear warheads or nuclear-capable delivery systems than the United States unless the treaty or agreement

restricts the size of China's nuclear arsenal;includes measures to ensure that Russia and China are compliant with the terms of the treaty;includes inspections of Chinese nuclear facilities comparable to those for Russian facilities;includes current and future Russian strategic nuclear arms not currently limited by the New START Treaty (e.g., intercontinental hypersonic glide vehicles); andincludes current and future non-strategic nuclear weapons and delivery systems.In the absence of a ratified treaty incorporating such provisions, the President is prohibited from&#160;reducing the size of the U.S. nuclear arsenal or entering into an agreement with Russia or China to limit&#160;or reduce U.S. missile defenses.

Beginning one year after the bill's enactment, no funds may be expended to implement the New START Treaty, or any future agreement with Russia that limits the number of U.S. nuclear warheads or nuclear capable delivery systems, unless the above requirements are included or&#160;already in effect or a waiver is approved.</summary>
</bill>
