<bill session="116" type="s" number="4513" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Climate Equity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Equity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure climate and environmental justice accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2020-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8019" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-23T19:57:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Climate Equity Act of 2020

This bill requires the review and analysis of new legislation, regulation, or federal investments that are related to environmental or climate change issues and sets forth related requirements. The analysis must determine the impacts of such legislation, regulation, or investments on frontline communities (e.g., communities that have experienced environmental injustice or are vulnerable to climate injustice).

Specifically, the bill establishes a Climate and Environmental Equity Office within the Congressional Budget Office. The former must prepare an analysis for each bill or resolution with an environmental or climate change nexus that is reported by any congressional committee. The analysis must include the bill's impacts on frontline communities.

The bill also establishes an Office of Climate and Environmental Justice Accountability within the Office of Management and Budget. Among other things, the former must (1) measure the costs of environmental and climate regulations on frontline communities, (2) review agencies' investments to determine if they have an environmental or climate change nexus and ensure that frontline communities benefit from such investments, and (3) represent the views of frontline communities in the rulemaking process.

Each agency must biannually publish a climate and environmental justice accountability agenda. An agency must prepare and publish a climate and environmental justice analysis for a proposed or final rule that may have a significant impact on a substantial number of residents within frontline communities. Further, each agency must ensure that frontline communities have been given an opportunity to participate in the rulemaking process.</summary>
</bill>
