<bill session="116" type="h" number="4013" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Telehealth Innovation and Improvement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test the effect of including telehealth services in Medicare health care delivery reform models.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telehealth Innovation and Improvement Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="773" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-26T16:05:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Telehealth Innovation and Improvement Act of 2019

This bill establishes (1) a telehealth service model, and (2) Medicare payment&#160;rules with respect to&#160;certain services tested under&#160;the model.

The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall test Medicare coverage of expanded telehealth services, as defined by the bill, in conjunction with existing models that test the use of accountable care organizations, bundled payments, and other coordinated care models under Medicare. The CMS must (1)&#160;establish a methodology for determining the amounts of payment for such services, and (2) provide for evaluations of the service model by an independent entity.

The CMS shall expand the application of a service tested under the model if (1) the&#160;required evaluation demonstrates that the service either reduced Medicare spending without reducing the quality of care or improved the quality of care without increasing spending, and (2) the Chief Actuary of the CMS certifies that such expansion would reduce net program spending. A service that&#160;meets these requirements is defined by the bill as a certified enhanced telehealth service.

Medicare payment for a certified enhanced telehealth service shall equal 80% of the lesser of (1) the actual charge for the service, or (2) the amount determined using the payment methodology established under the test model.

The CMS shall pay for such services without regard to a Medicare beneficiary's location or area of residence.</summary>
</bill>
