<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="166" updated="2022-02-18T20:00:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4521" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-02-03T19:12:09-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000740"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-02-03"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 131 printed in Part D of House Report 117-241 to require the Director of the NSF to commission a study to mea sure the economic impact of inflation on cost-of-living, the American workforce, American international competitiveness, and rural and underserved communities.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires the Director of the NSF to commission a study to mea sure the economic impact of inflation on cost-of-living, the American workforce, American international competitiveness, and rural and underserved communities.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-02-03T19:12:09-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="26">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bice (OK) amendment (A010) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 279 - 153 (Roll no. 26).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T13:25:19-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A010) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T13:19:47-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Mrs. Bice (OK).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H933-934" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H933" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T13:19:47-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A010) offered by Mrs. Bice (OK).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H933-934" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H933" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T19:12:09-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Bice (OK) amendment (A010) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 279 - 153 (Roll no. 26).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T19:12:09-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T19:12:09-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Bice (OK) amendment (A010) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 279 - 153 (Roll no. 26).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
