<bill session="118" type="s" number="1254" updated="2025-11-18T17:05:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate and expand wilderness areas in Olympic National Forest in the State of Washington, and to designate certain rivers in Olympic National Forest and Olympic National Park as wild and scenic rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment. With written report No. 118-184.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-06-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="421">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 421.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2765" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-24T13:36:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act

This bill designates (1) certain federal land in the Olympic National Forest in the state of Washington as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System; and (2) certain other land, identified on the same map as such proposed areas, as potential wilderness.

The bill designates as wild, scenic, or recreational rivers specified segments of the following rivers in the state of Washington

 Elwha River, Dungeness River, Big Quilcene River, Dosewallips River, Duckabush River, Hamma Hamma River, South Fork Skokomish River, Middle Fork Satsop River, West Fork Satsop River, Wynoochee River, East Fork Humptulips River, West Fork Humptulips River, Quinault River, Queets River, Hoh River, Bogachiel River, South Fork Calawah River, Sol Duc River, and Lyre River. The Department of Agriculture may take necessary measures to control fire, insects, and diseases in the wilderness areas designated by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-184</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
