<bill session="119" type="s" number="349" updated="2025-07-16T11:03:19Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fire-Safe Electrical Corridors Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fire-Safe Electrical Corridors Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to permit removal of trees around electrical lines on National Forest System land without conducting a timber sale, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2025-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2025-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2025-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2492" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-12T19:18:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fire-Safe Electrical Corridors Act of 2025

This bill allows the Forest Service to expedite the removal of trees or other vegetation near electrical lines on its lands under certain circumstances. Specifically, the Forest Service may include in special use permits or easements provided to electrical utilities permission to cut, remove, and sell trees or other vegetation near electrical lines on such lands without a separate timber sale if the cutting or removal is consistent with (1) the applicable land and resource management plan, and (2) other applicable environmental laws.

A special use permit or easement that includes permission for cutting and removal of trees or vegetation must include a&#160;requirement that, if the applicable electrical utility sells any portion of the material removed under the permit or easement, the utility must provide to the Forest Service&#160;any proceeds received from the sale, less any transportation costs incurred in the sale.</summary>
</bill>
