<bill session="111" type="h" number="3747" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:54Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Water Efficiency, Conservation, and Adaptation Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote water efficiency, conservation, and adaptation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Efficiency, Conservation, and Adaptation Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2009-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1712" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-27T23:17:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Water Efficiency, Conservation, and Adaptation Act of 2009 - Establishes within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) a WaterSense program to identify and promote water efficient products, buildings, landscapes, facilities, processes, and services (products, facilities, and services) so as to: (1) reduce water use and the strain on water, wastewater, and stormwater infrastructure; (2) conserve energy used to pump, heat, transport, and treat water; and (3) preserve water resources through voluntary labeling of, or other forms of communications about, products, facilities, and services that meet the highest water efficiency and performance criteria.

Sets forth the duties of Administrator of the EPA under the program, including to: (1) establish a WaterSense label and certification procedures and to promote labeled products, facilities, and services for reducing water use and ensuring performance; (2) review and update WaterSense criteria for categories of products, facilities, and services; (3) estimate and make available the production and relative market shares of, and the savings of water, energy, and capital costs of water, wastewater, and stormwater infrastructure attributable to, labeled products, facilities, and services; (4) notify the public of any changes on the adoption of a new or revised WaterSense category, specification, installation criterion, or other criterion and explain such changes; (5) implement other voluntary approaches in commercial, institutional, residential, industrial, and municipal sectors to encourage recycling and reuse technologies to improve water efficiency or lower water use; and (6) apply the WaterSense label as appropriate to water-using products that are labeled by the Energy Star program.

Requires the Administrator to: (1) allocate funds to establish and implement a program of financial incentives for consumer purchase and installation of water-efficient products, facilities, and services; and (2) make grants to owners or operators of specified water systems to address any ongoing or forecasted climate-related impact on the water quality or quantity of a region of the United States for the purposes of mitigating or adapting to the impacts of climate change.</summary>
</bill>
