<bill session="118" type="s" number="5008" updated="2025-02-20T16:53:46Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the railroad track maintenance credit.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the railroad track maintenance credit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2024-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2024-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2024-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2024-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="9522" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-20T16:53:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill increases the annual limit on the tax credit for qualified railroad track maintenance expenses (also referred to as the short line railroad tax credit) and expands eligibility for claiming the credit.

Under current law, the tax credit is limited each tax year to $3,500 multiplied by the sum of the number of miles of railroad track owned or leased by the taxpayer (miles owned or leased) and the number of railroad track miles assigned to the taxpayer by a Class II or III railroad (miles assigned). This bill increases the annual limit to $6,100 multiplied by the sum of miles owned or leased and miles assigned. The $6,100 amount used in the calculation of the tax credit limit is adjusted for inflation for tax years beginning after 2025.

The bill also expands eligibility for the tax credit to include gross expenses for maintaining railroad tracks owned or leased as of January 1, 2024. Under current law, the tax credit is limited to gross expenses for maintaining railroad tracks owned or leased as of January 1, 2015.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
