<bill session="109" type="s" number="1529" updated="2023-01-31T21:13:07Z">
  <state datetime="2006-12-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">City of Yuma Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in the city of Yuma, Arizona.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">City of Yuma Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">City of Yuma Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">City of Yuma Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">City of Yuma Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">City of Yuma Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-273.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-300.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="543">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 543.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11537-11542" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11537-11538" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2006-12-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11538-11539" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08T10:17:52-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-08T12:41:44-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:59:10-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 H9250" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:59:10-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Pombo asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2006-12-09T01:59:31-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/8/2006 H9250" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-09T01:59:34-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-12-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-12-22" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="109-454" type="public" datetime="2006-12-22">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-454.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5226"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2007-01-16T21:49:28Z" status="Public Law">City of Yuma Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey all U.S. interests in specified federal land in Arizona to the city of Yuma, Arizona, in exchange for specified nonfederal land (Railroad Parcels).

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to administer the nonfederal land acquired.

Requires all administrative costs relating to the conveyance of the federal and nonfederal land to be paid by the city to the United States.

Requires an independent appraisal of the federal and nonfederal land in accordance with the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisition and the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice.

Requires the values of the federal and nonfederal land to be equal. Permits the equalization of unequal land values by means of cash equalization payments.

Directs the Secretary to convey to the city, by quitclaim deed, in exchange for its fair market value, all U.S. interests in and to the parcel of land of U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service land located at 356 West First Street in Yuma.

Requires the city, in exchange for such conveyance, to pay to the Secretary consideration in an amount that reflects the fair market value of the land conveyed to the city.

Requires any administrative costs related to such conveyance to be paid by the city to the United States.

 Makes amounts paid to the Secretary as consideration available for: (1) the administrative costs of such conveyance to the city; and (2) the costs of constructing the Kofa National Wildlife Refuge headquarters and visitor center in Yuma.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-300</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
