<bill session="111" type="h" number="5062" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:07Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unconventional Domestic Natural Gas Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to promote domestic natural gas research and development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unconventional Domestic Natural Gas Research and Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000067" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-12T19:01:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Unconventional Domestic Natural Gas Research and Development Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to entitle as the Unconventional Domestic Natural Gas Research and Development Program the existing program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of technologies for ultra-deepwater and unconventional natural gas and other petroleum resource exploration and production.

Requires the Secretary of Energy to seek to establish partnerships with research performers in institutions of higher education and the private sector to undertake research and development not likely otherwise to be undertaken in the absence of support from the program.

Directs the National Energy Technology Laboratory (NETL) to submit to the Secretary of Energy its complementary annual research plan for inclusion as a component of the President's annual budget request to Congress.

Authorizes the program to make awards in the form of grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, or other transactions.

Directs the Secretary, instead of the NETL on the Secretary's behalf, to conduct program review and oversight.

Extends the program through FY2017.

Revises the limitation on program administration funds to set a maximum of the greater of $4 million or (as under current law) 10% of the total funds allocated under the program.

Increases from $50 million to $150 million the amount required to be deposited each fiscal year into the Ultra-Deepwater and Unconventional Natural Gas and Other Petroleum Research Fund after certain allocations have been made from federal royalties, rents, and bonuses derived from federal onshore and offshore oil and gas leases issued under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act.</summary>
</bill>
