<bill session="119" type="h" number="892" updated="2025-06-03T19:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mortgage Rate Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mortgage Rate Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the heads of certain agencies to disclose information about loans insured and guaranteed by such agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000579"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-03T19:47:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Mortgage Rate Reduction Act

This bill authorizes the federal guarantee, or insurance, of certain second mortgages. Specifically, this applies to properties with a first mortgage guaranteed by the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) or the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). For a second mortgage to qualify, the first mortgage on the property must be guaranteed under the same authority.

The bill also requires the publication of mortgage guarantee information by&#160;the FHA, VA, and Department of Agriculture. For each mortgage guaranteed, these agencies must publish the address of the property and the date of the loan.</summary>
</bill>
