<bill session="118" type="s" number="144" updated="2025-11-12T00:34:19Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Chinese Communist SURPRISE Parties Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Chinese Communist Subterfuge via Unregistered Regime Presence Rendered Invisible to Shareholders and Equivalent Parties Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Chinese Communist SURPRISE Parties Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require issuers filing annual reports with the Securities and Exchange Commission to disclose whether the issuers have connections with the Chinese Communist Party, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="747" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-17T15:54:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Chinese Communist Subterfuge via Unregistered Regime Presence Rendered Invisible to Shareholders and Equivalent Parties Act or the No Chinese Communist SURPRISE Parties Act 

This bill requires issuers of securities to annually disclose whether the issuer has established or maintained an organization of the Chinese Communist Party, if an organization of the Chinese Communist Party has participated in the operations of the issuer, and whether the issuer's board of directors (1) owes a fiduciary duty to the issuer and shareholders, and (2) is subject to heightened scrutiny with respect to conflicted controller transactions.</summary>
</bill>
