<bill session="119" type="h" number="501" updated="2025-10-11T19:26:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend certain laws relating to disaster recovery and relief with respect to the implementation of building codes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2025-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 119-319.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-10-03" calendar="Union" number="273">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 273.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-23T19:30:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act of 2025

This bill authorizes local governments to implement the previous edition of building codes with funding from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) and Safeguarding Tomorrow Revolving Loan Fund (RLF) programs. It also establishes a pilot program for residential resilience retrofits under the BRIC program.

Under current law, local governments may use funding provided under the&#160;BRIC and Safeguarding Tomorrow RLF programs to establish and carry out the latest published editions of relevant building codes and standards. The bill allows local governments to use&#160;BRIC grant funding to carry out the latest two published editions (i.e., either the current edition of a building code or the previous edition) and requires&#160;BRIC to consider adoption of either of the latest two editions when determining whether to provide assistance.&#160;The bill also allows local governments to use loan funding from the Safeguarding Tomorrow RLF program for implementing the latest two published editions of building codes, including amendments government entities make to such codes.

Additionally, the bill establishes under the BRIC program a pilot program for states and local governments to provide grants to individuals for residential resilience retrofits (i.e., projects that increase a home&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s resilience to natural hazards). To provide this assistance,&#160;FEMA may use up to 10% of the assistance made available to BRIC applicants annually. The pilot program terminates at the end of FY2028.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-319</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
