<bill session="116" type="h" number="5308" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:04Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Access to School Meals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 and the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to eliminate reduced price breakfasts and lunches and to require that the income guidelines for determining eligibility for free breakfasts and free lunches be 200 percent of the poverty-level, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Access to School Meals Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2020-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2020-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2020-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2020-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2020-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2019-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-17T19:46:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Access to School Meals Act of 2019

This bill revises program requirements under the National School Lunch Program and School Breakfast Program of the Department of Agriculture (USDA).

Specifically, the bill

 eliminates the reduced price school breakfast and lunch programs to include prohibiting USDA from providing reimbursements for such programs, expands the income guidelines for purposes of determining eligibility for free school lunches and breakfasts to make families living at 200% of the poverty-level eligible (currently, families living at 130% or below are eligible), allows states to use Medicaid and Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) participation data to directly certify students for free school lunches and breakfasts, and increases the multiplier from 1.6% to 1.8% for purposes of determining reimbursement under the Community Eligibility Provision that permits schools in high poverty areas to serve all meals free of charge.</summary>
</bill>
