<bill session="108" type="s" number="2009" updated="2023-01-15T09:32:49Z">
  <state datetime="2004-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sound Science for Endangered Species Act Planning Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior to give greater weight to scientific or commercial data that is empirical or has been field-tested or peer-reviewed, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sound Science for Endangered Species Act Planning Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S56"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1662" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-11T17:16:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sound Science for Endangered Species Act Planning Act of 2004 - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) give greater weight to scientific and commercial data that is empirical or that has been field-tested or peer-reviewed in determining that a species is an endangered or threatened species; and (2) promulgate regulations that establish criteria for data to be used as the basis of such a determination. Prohibits the Secretary from determining that a species is endangered or threatened unless the determination is supported by field data. Requires the Secretary to include in the rule-making record of such a determination data collected by landowners. Requires the Secretary to publish a description of additional scientific and commercial data that would assist in the preparation of a recovery plan. Directs the Secretary to: (1) solicit recommendations from the National Academy of Sciences and develop a list of qualified reviewers to participate in independent scientific review actions; and (2) appoint from such list three individuals who shall report on the scientific information and analyses on which final action is based. Requires the Secretary, when consulting with a Federal agency to determine whether agency action will jeopardize an endangered or threatened species or destroy the critical habitat of such species, to: (1) consider information provided by affected States; and (2) allow any person who has sought agency authorization or funding for an action to participate in related consultations.</summary>
</bill>
