<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1097" updated="2022-02-03T05:21:02Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5781" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-06-19T13:43:05-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-06-19"/>
  <description>Amendment makes certain technical and conforming changes to the bill; strikes a requirement for a study by the Government Accountability Office and makes section 4 not effective with respect to births or placements occurring within 6 months of the enactment of the Act.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House report 110-718 to make certain technical and conforming changes to the bill, would strike a requirement for a study by the Government Accountability Office, and would make section 4 not effective with respect to births or placements occurring within 6 months of the enactment of the Act.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-06-19T13:43:05-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="426">
      <text>On agreeing to the Davis (IL) amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 422 - 0 (Roll no. 426).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19T13:18:55-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment and on the bill.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19T13:12:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Davis (IL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5605-5607" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5605" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19T13:12:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Davis (IL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5605-5607" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5605" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19T13:43:05-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Davis (IL) amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 422 - 0 (Roll no. 426).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19T13:43:05-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Davis (IL) amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 422 - 0 (Roll no. 426).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19T13:43:05-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-19">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
