<bill session="117" type="h" number="2940" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing International and Foreign Language Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize title VI of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing International and Foreign Language Education Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001312" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000592" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-01T15:05:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing International and Foreign Language Education Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2027 and otherwise revises international education programs. These programs provide grants to institutions of higher education and related entities to (1) enhance instruction in international and foreign language studies, and (2) promote international business skills and education.

First, the bill reauthorizes programs related to international and foreign language studies. Specifically, it extends (1) the Graduate and Undergraduate Language and Area Centers and Programs, which include the National Resource Centers program; (2) the Language Resource Centers; (3) the Undergraduate International Studies and Foreign Language Programs; and (4) the American Overseas Research Centers.

Next, the bill revises the Foreign Language and Area Studies Fellowships program to permit graduate students to receive a stipend for the beginning, intermediate, or advanced study of a foreign language related to the student's area of specialization.

Further, the bill replaces the existing Technological Innovation and Cooperation for Foreign Information Access program with an international research and innovation program.

Additionally, the bill reauthorizes programs related to international business skills and education. Specifically, it reauthorizes the Centers for International Business Education program. It also reauthorizes the Education and Training program and otherwise makes changes to the program, including by (1) renaming the program; and (2) mandating certain program activities, such as&#160;the incorporation of&#160;specified programs and studies into professional education and technical training curricula.

Finally, the bill permits the Department of Education to prioritize grant applications from minority-serving institutions.</summary>
</bill>
