<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>667</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:54:19Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T05:54:19Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-03-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
            <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2011-05-18T20:07:32Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2012-01-13T18:56:08Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2011-11-10T17:10:38Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-03-29T19:45:12Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 112-113</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1241</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-03-29</actionDate>
          <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-01-13</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 275.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-01-13</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/17/2011 without amendment. With written report No. 112-113.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-01-13</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/17/2011 without amendment. With written report No. 112-113.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-11-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-18</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
            <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-39.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000039</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Tom [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>TOM</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-03-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-03-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-04-07T13:47:51Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act - Establishes the Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area in New Mexico. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Interior to ensure the protection of religious and cultural sites in the Conservation Area and to provide access to them by tribal members. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Conservation Area. </p> <p>Designates the Cerro Del Yuta Wilderness and Rio San Antonio Wilderness as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>80</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-02-07T21:17:03Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p> Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act - Establishes Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area in New Mexico, consisting of approximately 235,980 acres of public land in Taos and Rio Arriba Counties for the purposes of conserving, protecting, and enhancing the cultural, archaeological, natural, ecological, geological, historical, wildlife, educational, recreational, and scenic resources of such Conservation Area. <p>Sets forth requirements for the management of the Conservation Area regarding motorized vehicles and new roads, grazing, collection of pine nuts and firewood for noncommercial use, and utility right-of-way upgrades. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to ensure the protection of religious and cultural sites and to provide occasional access to them by tribal members for traditional cultural and customary uses. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Conservation Area. Makes any acquired land within the boundary of the Conservation Area part of such Area. </p> <p>Bars the changing of the management status of any area within the boundary of the Conservation Area that is: (1) designated as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, or (2) managed as an area of critical environmental concern. </p> <p>Designates the Cerro Del Yuta Wilderness and Rio San Antonio Wilderness as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Makes any acquired land or interests within the boundary of the wilderness areas part of the area in which the land is located. Sets forth requirements for the management of the wilderness areas regarding livestock grazing, protective perimeters and buffer zones, and activities and uses conducted outside the wilderness areas. </p> <p>Releases the public land within the San Antonio Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness from further study for designation as wilderness. </p> <p>Requires the Conservation Area and the wilderness areas designated by this Act to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System. </p> <p>Specifies this Act's effect on fish and wildlife located on public land in New Mexico. </p> <p>Withdraws federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness designated by this Act, including any acquired land and interests, from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in this Act from enlarging, diminishing, or otherwise modifying any treaty rights. </p> <p>Authorizes appropriations.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish the Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2012-01-13T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s667rs/xml/BILLS-112s667rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-03-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s667is/xml/BILLS-112s667is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-01-13</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 275.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
