<bill session="118" type="s" number="3168" updated="2025-11-19T03:24:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-30">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Israel Supplemental Appropriations Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Israel Supplemental Appropriations Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making emergency supplemental appropriations for assistance for the situation in Israel for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2023-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-10-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="232">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 232.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3135" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6126" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6113" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-02T10:41:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Israel Supplemental Appropriations Act of 2023 

This bill provides FY2024 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of State for assistance to Israel. The bill designates the funding as emergency spending, which is exempt from discretionary spending limits.

The bill provides appropriations to DOD for Operation and Maintenance; Procurement; and Research, Development, Test and Evaluation. The funding is provided for purposes such as

 replacing defense articles that were provided to Israel; reimbursing DOD for defense services and training provided to Israel; the procurement of Israel's Iron Dome and David's Sling defense systems; Defense Production Act purchases; and the development of Israel's Iron Beam defense system. The bill provides appropriations to the State Department for

 Diplomatic Programs, including Worldwide Security Protection; Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service; and the Foreign Military Financing Program. In addition, the bill includes several provisions that expand the authorities of the President to transfer defense articles and services from DOD to Israel.

Finally, the bill specifies that the funds provided by this bill may not be used (1) in connection with the war in Ukraine; or (2) for assistance to any entity that is located in the territory of Gaza or is controlled or influenced by Hamas, Palestinian Islamic Jihad, or any other organization that the State Department has designated as a foreign terrorist organization.</summary>
</bill>
