<bill session="119" type="h" number="2084" updated="2025-11-19T02:52:28Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Smoke Exposure Research Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smoke Exposure Research Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Agricultural Research Service to conduct research relating to the exposure of wine grapes to wildfire smoke, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001326" joined="2025-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2025-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2025-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2025-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1042" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-30T12:13:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Smoke Exposure Research Act of 2025

This bill directs the Agricultural Research Service (ARS) to conduct research relating to smoke exposure and wine grapes. This research must be done in coordination with land-grant colleges and universities that are located in California, Oregon, and Washington and have researched the effects of smoke exposure on viticulture and enology operations and practices.

Specifically, ARS must

conduct research to identify the compounds responsible for smoke exposure,conduct research to establish standard methodologies for sampling and testing smoke-exposed wine grapes and smoke-affected wines,establish a reliable database of background levels of smoke exposure compounds that occur naturally in wine grapes,develop risk assessment tools or mitigation methods to reduce or eliminate smoke exposure, andstudy compounds that can act as a barrier between wine grapes and smoke compounds.</summary>
</bill>
