<bill session="116" type="h" number="7141" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defending Against Rosatom Exports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend limitations on the importation of uranium from the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Against Rosatom Exports Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000484"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2020-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-28T15:38:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Defending Against Rosatom Exports Act

This bill extends limits on the importation of Russian low-enriched uranium, a fuel for nuclear reactors, and contains other related provisions. (These limits stem from a 1992 agreement with Russia to end a Department of Commerce antidumping investigation into Russian uranium imports.)

The bill extends these limits, which are currently set to expire in 2020, to 2035. The bill also specifies the maximum amounts of qualifying uranium that may be imported each year for 2021-2035.

Currently, qualifying uranium imported for use in the initial core of a new reactor or for the Department of Energy inventory does not count against these limits. The bill eliminates these two exceptions but maintains an exception for uranium imported for reprocessing and reexportation.

No more than 25% of qualifying uranium may be imported each year under a contract other than a contract exclusively for separative work units. (A separative work unit is the standard unit of measurement for effort expended to enrich uranium.)</summary>
</bill>
