<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="639" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4437" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-12-15T19:01:14-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000552"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <description>At the end of section 109, add the following new subsection: \   (e) ACTION BY INSPECTOR GENERAL.--In the event the Inspector General becomes aware of any improper conduct or wrongdoing in accordance with the contract review required under subsection (a), the Inspector General shall, as expeditiously as practicable, refer information related to such improper conduct or wrongdoing to the Secretary of Homeland Security or other appropriate official in the Department of Homeland Security for purposes of evaluating whether to suspend or debar the contractor.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part B of House Report 109-347 to direct the Inspector General to refer any instances of misconduct or wrongdoing on a contract to the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security or other appropriate official for the purpose of evaluating whether or not suspension or debarment of the contractor is warranted.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-12-15T19:01:14-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Gohmert amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T18:54:06-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Gohmert.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11838-11839" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11838" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T18:54:06-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Gohmert.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11838-11839" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11838" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T19:01:14-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T19:01:14-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Gohmert amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
