<bill session="116" type="s" number="1605" updated="2022-11-01T05:47:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make available necessary disaster assistance for families affected by major disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2914" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-24T15:38:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2019

This bill makes certain individuals and households eligible for housing assistance in connection with a major disaster, including Hurricane Maria of 2017. To be eligible, an individual or household must be (1) occupying an otherwise unused or uninhabited property located in the area for which the major disaster was declared but does not have documented ownership rights to and is not renting the property, or (2) residing or have resided in an area for which the major disaster was declared but does not have documentary proof of residence.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall consider alternative forms of proof to determine the eligibility of an individual or household for assistance.

FEMA shall (1) create and distribute a form declarative statement that applicants for assistance may use to self-certify their eligibility for assistance, and (2) make the statement available in specified languages at all active Disaster Recovery Centers and on its website and social media.

FEMA shall enter into agreements with the Department of Housing and Urban Development to implement a disaster housing assistance program to provide temporary rental assistance to individuals and households displaced by any major disaster during 2017 and 2018, and shall engage in consultations regarding the implementation of such program for future disasters.</summary>
</bill>
