<bill session="117" type="h" number="5960" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">State and Local Government Cybersecurity Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State and Local Government Cybersecurity Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for engagements with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2520" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-10T13:00:19Z" status="Introduced in House">State and Local Government Cybersecurity Act of 2021

This bill provides for collaboration between the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and state, local, tribal, and territorial governments, as well as corporations, associations, and the general public, regarding cybersecurity.

The bill expands DHS responsibilities through grants and cooperative agreements, including provision of assistance and education related to cyber threat indicators, defensive measures, cybersecurity risks or vulnerabilities, and incident response and management.

The bill requires the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center, upon request, to coordinate with entities such as the Multi-State Information Sharing and Analysis Center to engage in specified activities, including to (1) conduct exercises with state, local, tribal, or territorial government entities; (2) provide operational and technical cybersecurity training to such entities; and (3) promote cybersecurity education and awareness.</summary>
</bill>
