<bill session="116" type="h" number="7251" updated="2022-02-09T02:12:30Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Proxy Vote Windfall Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for reductions in the Members' Representational Allowance of Members of the House of Representatives who fail to appear to cast votes or record presence in the House at any time during which proxy voting is permitted in the House.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proxy Vote Windfall Prohibition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2020-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000395" joined="2020-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2020-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2020-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-29T16:56:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Proxy Vote Windfall Prohibition Act

This bill reduces the Members' Representational Allowance (MRA) of a Representative who does not appear in person to cast a vote or record their presence in response to a quorum call while proxy voting is permitted in the House of Representatives.

The MRA is the allowance that each Representative receives to support the conduct of their official and representational duties (e.g., travel costs between their district and the Capitol).The bill reduces the MRA by the amount which would have been paid for the Representative's travel expenses to be present for the vote or quorum call, unless the Representative is carrying out other official and representational duties.

Further, the bill reduces the total amount available for MRAs for the House during the year by the amount of any reductions made under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
