<bill session="118" type="h" number="4651" updated="2025-08-15T15:48:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to issue a report containing information on extraordinary measures available when the debt of the United States Government approaches the statutory limit, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to issue a report containing information on extraordinary measures available when the debt of the United States Government approaches the statutory limit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000583"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-15T15:47:43Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to issue a report when it uses extraordinary measures to meet federal funding obligations without issuing additional Treasury securities.&#160;

(The term extraordinary&#160;measures&#160;generally refers to actions that Treasury may implement to allow the United States to borrow additional funds without exceeding the statutory debt limit. The measures generally include suspensions or delays of debt sales and suspensions or&#160;redemptions of investments in certain government funds.)

The bill requires Treasury to issue the report to the voting members of the Financial Stability Oversight Council, the Office of Financial Research, the House Committee on Financial Services, and the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs upon notifying Congress that it has begun using extraordinary measures. The report must include&#160;&#160;

a list of available extraordinary measures, stated as a dollar amount;a projection of the headroom under the debt limit (i.e., the difference between the current debt limit and the projected operating cash balance of the Treasury) afforded by each extraordinary measure;a projection of the date on which all available headroom afforded by the use of extraordinary measures will be exhausted, the Treasury will have an operating cash balance at or below $50 billion, the debt will be within $50 billion of reaching the limit, and Treasury will be unable to make timely payments on the debt; andan attestation by the Secretary of the Treasury as to whether the debt approaching the limit is an emerging threat to U.S. financial stability.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
