<bill session="117" type="h" number="6425" updated="2022-12-30T03:49:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Achieving Independence through Degrees Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AID Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase the maximum Federal Pell Grant amount, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8363" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-12T21:03:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Achieving Independence through Degrees Act or the AID Act

This bill revises certain federal student-aid programs. Among other changes, the bill expands access to Pell Grants, expands loan counseling requirements, revises the Federal Work-Study Program, updates the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) process, and extends Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits to certain students.

The bill expands access to Pell Grants by (1) increasing the maximum award and indexing it for inflation; (2) increasing the semester eligibility limit to 15 semesters; (3) extending eligibility to certain short-term workforce training programs; (4) excluding from gross income, for income tax purposes, any amount received as a Pell Grant; and (5) allowing Pell Grants to be used for living and non-tuition expenses.

The bill revises student loan counseling requirements applicable to institutions of higher education (IHEs) by requiring annual financial counseling and expanding exit counseling.

Additionally, the bill permanently reauthorizes the Federal Work-Study Program and otherwise revises the program, including by allocating program funds to IHEs based on the amount of Pell Grant funds received by each IHE. It establishes a pilot program that provides work-based learning opportunities for students who demonstrate exceptional financial need.

The bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to allow students to complete FAFSA as independent students under special circumstances. Further, the bill prohibits ED from asking about drug-related convictions on FAFSA.

The bill also allows certain students, including those who have an expected family contribution of zero, to qualify for SNAP benefits.</summary>
</bill>
