<bill session="116" type="s" number="4673" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reaffirming Property Rights Through Natural Gas Act Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reaffirming Property Rights Through Natural Gas Act Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Natural Gas Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to consider certain factors in issuing certificates of public convenience and necessity under that Act, to modify the requirements for the right to exercise eminent domain in construction of pipelines under that Act, to provide that the right of eminent domain may not be exercised under that Act for projects for the exportation of natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-26T12:27:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reaffirming Property Rights Through Natural Gas Act Modernization Act

This bill addresses the use of eminent domain by the holder of a certificate of public convenience and necessity to acquire land or property with respect to the construction and operation of a natural gas pipeline facility, including by (1) ending the legal presumption that natural gas exports are by definition in the public interest, (2) requiring the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to consider certain factors in issuing certificates of public convenience and necessity for natural gas projects, and (3) prohibiting the holder of a certification of public convenience and necessity from exercising the right of eminent domain for a pipeline designed to export liquefied natural gas to a foreign country.</summary>
</bill>
