<bill session="111" type="h" number="4725" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:27Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for the acquisition by the Army Corps of Engineers of the hurricane barrier for the city of New Bedford, Massachusetts and the town of Fairhaven, Massachusetts.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the acquisition by the Army Corps of Engineers of the hurricane barrier for the city of New Bedford, Massachusetts and the town of Fairhaven, Massachusetts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000339"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-24T19:22:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Authorizes the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Corps of Engineers, to acquire all right, title, and interest of the city of New Bedford and the town of Fairhaven, Massachuetts, to the New Bedford-Fairhaven hurricane barrier if an offer is made by the city and the town to convey it to the Secretary, by quitclaim deed without consideration, within two years of this Act's enactment. Permits the city and the town to retain an easement authorizing the construction and recreational use of a boardwalk as a bike path, pedestrian path, boardwalk, and noncommercial fishing pier. Makes the Secretary responsible for the operation and maintenance, repair, replacement, rehabilitation, and structural integrity of the barrier in coordination with the city and the town.</summary>
</bill>
