<bill session="118" type="s" number="3538" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Close the Shadow Banking Loophole Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close the Shadow Banking Loophole Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address applications for deposit insurance submitted by industrial banks to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-09T17:25:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Close the Shadow Banking Loophole Act

This bill provides for the federal regulation and supervision of industrial banks, also known as industrial loan companies (ILCs), and their parent companies. ILCs are state-chartered institutions owned by nonfinancial businesses (parent companies) that provide several services similar to banks, such as originating loans and processing payments. Under current law, the parent companies are not subject to federal banking supervision, however, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) may grant deposit insurance to these institutions.

Under the bill, certain pending ILC deposit insurance applications must receive votes from two-thirds of the&#160;FDIC board to be approved. The bill also sets a deadline for&#160;FDIC to consider pending applications. If FDIC does not approve an application before this deadline, the application is deemed to have been denied.</summary>
</bill>
