<bill session="117" type="h" number="8275" updated="2022-12-29T18:05:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wholesale Produce Market Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wholesale Produce Market Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to submit to Congress a report on improving supply chain shortfalls and infrastructure needs at wholesale produce markets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-13T12:45:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Wholesale Produce Market Review Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to submit to Congress a report on supply chain shortfalls at (1) the five largest wholesale produce markets by annual sales and amount of goods moved for the preceding four calendar years, and (2) a representative sample of eight wholesale produce markets that are not among the largest wholesale produce markets.

The report must contain (1) an analysis of the supply chain shortfalls in each wholesale produce market, including the state of repair of infrastructure; (2) a description of any actions USDA recommends be taken as a result of the analysis; (3) recommendations for wholesale produce market owners and operators, and state and local entities, to improve the identified supply chain shortfalls; and (4) proposals for legislative actions and funding needed to improve the supply chain shortfalls.</summary>
</bill>
