<bill session="109" type="h" number="5475" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:25Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HSA Accessibility and Portability Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to permit a health insurance issuer an alternative to guaranteed issue of health insurance coverage in the small group market in order to promote affordable access to portable health insurance coverage.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HSA Accessibility and Portability Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000572"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001247" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2006-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2006-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Health insurance portability"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-07-24T19:25:15Z" status="Introduced in House">HSA Accessibility and Portability Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize a health insurance issuer to elect, instead of complying with the guaranteed issue requirements (that require a health insurance issuer offering coverage in the small group market in a state to accept every small employer that applies and to accept all eligible individuals without certain restrictions), to: (1) guarantee continuation of coverage through individual health insurance for an individual who no longer qualifies as an eligible individual of the employer at a rate that does not exceed 150% of the standard individual rate applicable to individual coverage in the state; and (2) furnish information for the Secretary of Health and Human Services to monitor the impact of such election on access to, and affordability of, health insurance coverage in the small group market and in the individual market.

Requires such an election to apply to all eligible individuals of that small employer at the time of such election, but does not require applicability to an individual who becomes eligible after such election. Allows an election under this Act to be made only with respect to coverage of a small employer under health insurance coverage that consists of a high deductible health plan and a contribution to a health savings account.</summary>
</bill>
