<bill session="118" type="h" number="2420" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:03Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cattle Fever Tick Eradication Program Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cattle Fever Tick Eradication Program Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to review the Cattle Fever Tick Eradication Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001222" joined="2023-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1836" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8467" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-09T18:21:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Cattle Fever Tick Eradication Program Enhancement Act

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to enter into a contract to evaluate the Cattle Fever Tick Eradication Program. (Under the program, the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service works in coordination with the Texas Animal Health Commission to combat the spread of cattle fever ticks, which can spread a serious cattle disease called bovine babesiosis or cattle fever.)

Specifically, USDA must enter into a contract to review and report on the Cattle Fever Tick Eradication Program with a (1) land-grant college or university, or (2) non-land-grant college of agriculture.

The review must include an evaluation of

 the program's effectiveness with respect to preventing and reducing the spread of tick-borne illnesses in cattle; the program's benefits, and the burdens of compliance, to cattle producers; the treatment protocols developed and implemented under the program; and the federal and state funds allocated to support the program for the most recent fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
