<bill session="117" type="h" number="3037" updated="2023-11-10T04:56:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make available necessary disaster assistance for families affected by major disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 117-653, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Committee on the Budget discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-20" calendar="Union" number="473">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 473.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-12T13:37:01Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2021

This bill makes certain individuals and households eligible for housing assistance in connection with a major disaster, including Hurricane Maria of 2017. To be eligible, an individual or household must be (1) residing on property located in the area for which the major disaster was declared but does not have documented ownership rights to and is not renting such property, or (2) residing or have resided in an area for which the major disaster was declared during the designated incident period.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must consider alternative forms of proof to determine the eligibility of an individual or household for assistance.

FEMA shall create and distribute a declarative form statement that applicants for assistance can use to self-certify eligibility for assistance and shall make the statement available in specified languages at all active Disaster Recovery Centers and on its website and social media.

FEMA may provide financial assistance for repairs to ensure that residences are habitable during longer-term recovery and for permanent housing construction if the President determines that such assistance is a cost effective alternative to other housing solutions.

FEMA shall conduct an analysis comparing the costs, benefits, and effectiveness of assistance provided under the Disaster Housing Assistance Program, including any case management services provided, with other temporary housing options provided by FEMA.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-653</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
