<bill session="116" type="h" number="7803" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Mail-In Voter Fraud Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Mail-In Voter Fraud Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, and the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to provide for enhanced penalties for the fraudulent transmission of ballots by mail in elections for Federal office, to direct the Attorney General to establish a system for receiving reports of incidents of the fraudulent transmission of such ballots by mail, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2020-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000395" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-30T15:09:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Mail-In Voter Fraud Act

This bill provides for enhanced penalties for certain crimes related to federal elections and contains other related provisions.

More specifically, the bill increases the maximum terms of imprisonment for various criminal acts if the act involves multiple ballots related to a federal election. For example, current law allows for a prison term of up to 20 years for certain fraudulent schemes involving the mail. Under this bill, the maximum prison term shall be 30 years if such a mail fraud scheme involves multiple ballots for a federal election.

The bill also requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish a system, including a toll-free hotline and confidential website, for an individual to report instances of fraudulent transmission of ballots by mail in a federal election.

In addition, the bill requires courts to notify state election offices and DOJ when an individual has been recused from serving on a jury on the grounds that the individual is not a U.S. citizen. Each state's election office shall, as part of regular maintenance of its list of eligible voters, remove the name of such an individual from the voter list.</summary>
</bill>
