<bill session="111" type="h" number="4216" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Personal Health Record Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act and titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to establish guidelines to enhance the meaningful use and interoperability of electronic medical records with personal health records, including for purposes of Medicare and Medicaid payment incentives.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Personal Health Record Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2009-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2009-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2897"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-26T20:20:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Personal Health Record Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology, in developing a nationwide health information technology infrastructure, to allow individuals to access their individually identifiable health information.

Requires the inclusion in the Federal Health IT Strategic Plan objectives, milestones, and metrics related to the interoperability of a personal health record with an electronic health record (EHR).

Directs the National Coordinator to develop guidelines for making EHRs interoperable with personal health records for the purpose of improving health care quality, reducing medical errors, and advancing the delivery of patient-centered medical care and health management.

Requires the National Coordinator to report to the appropriate congressional committees on: (1) personal health records, including the extent to which the use of personal health records improve communication between individuals and covered entities and improve patient health management; and (2) issues related to an individual's control of the personal health record.

Requires the HIT Policy Committee to make recommendations for standards and implementation specifications for the interoperability of personal health records and EHRs.

Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to establish as an eligibility requirement for an incentive payment for the meaningful use of EHR technology that a health professional, hospital, or Medicaid provider must demonstrate the availability of certified EHR technology to and use of such technology by individuals furnished items and services by such professional, hospital, or provider in the form of electronic and personal health records.</summary>
</bill>
