<bill session="108" type="s" number="1977" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:27Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the manufacturing industry in the United States by establishing an Assistant Secretary for Manufacturing within the Department of Commerce, an Interagency Manufacturing Task Force, and a Small Business Manufacturing Task Force, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Manufacturers Assistance, Recovery, and Trade Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2004-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2003-11-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16025-16027"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16027-16029" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-11T14:58:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Manufacturers Assistance, Recovery, and Trade Act or SMART Act - Establishes in the Department of Commerce the position of Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Manufacturing to: (1) identify and address the concerns of U.S. manufacturers; (2) develop policies that promote the viability and expansion of U.S. manufacturing; (3) review policies that adversely impact manufacturers; and (4) identify and address issues unique to small manufacturers and those that are exacerbated by the size or limited capital of small manufacturers.

Establishes an Interagency Manufacturing Task Force to maximize, improve, and coordinate Federal agency resources in assisting the manufacturing industry.

Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to establish the position of Assistant United States Trade Representative for Small Business.

Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a Small Business Manufacturing Task Force to evaluate and identify whether SBA programs and services are sufficient to serve the needs of small manufacturers.

Requires the SBA Office of Entrepreneurial Development to develop: (1) new outreach and training programs for small manufacturers and small businesses in the manufacturing supply chain; (2) manufacturing workshops; and (3) programs and services to strengthen small business vendors and suppliers in the manufacturing supply chain.

Amends the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to include small business manufacturing within the SBA loan and international trade programs.</summary>
</bill>
