<bill session="117" type="s" number="1282" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Built To Last Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to identify a consistent, Federal set of best available forward-looking meteorological information and to require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to convene an effort to make such set available, with advice and technical assistance, to standards-developing organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Built To Last Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2760" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-09T19:16:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Built To Last Act of 2021

This bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to identify and support research that enables a consistent, federal set of forward-looking long-term meteorological information that (1) models future extreme weather events, other environmental trends, projections, and up-to-date observations; and (2) is suitable for specified uses, including federal and nonfederal efforts to develop and adopt standards, building codes, and voluntary certifications.

NOAA must provide the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) with mesoscale meteorological information when appropriate or upon request by NIST.

NIST must publish the information and advise and provide technical assistance to organizations that develop standards, model building codes, or voluntary certifications in order for such organizations to appropriately use the information.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy, in coordination with the U.S. Global Change Research Program and the Mitigation Framework Leadership Group, shall designate a working group to identify and support research that enables such forward-looking long-term meteorological information.</summary>
</bill>
