<bill session="117" type="h" number="8707" updated="2023-02-03T04:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farmers Market and Food Bank Local Revitalization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers Market and Food Bank Local Revitalization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide increased financial assistance for farmers markets and farmers' market nutrition programs, to increase local agricultural production through food bank in-house production and local farmer contracting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2022-08-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E837"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-02T23:22:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Farmers Market and Food Bank Local Revitalization Act of 2022

This bill provides for increased support for farmers' markets.

The bill extends through FY2028, expands eligibility for, and increases benefits under the Senior Farmers' Market Nutrition Program.

The bill extends through FY2025 and increases benefits under the Women, Infants, and Children Farmers' Market Nutrition Program.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must make loans, loan guarantees, and grants to public agencies and nonprofit organizations for the construction of new farmers markets or the improvement or rehabilitation of existing farmers markets.

Additionally, the bill requires USDA to establish a pilot grant program in which food banks may voluntarily contract with their local farmers for them to grow produce for food bank programs to promote local procurement of produce.</summary>
</bill>
