<bill session="116" type="h" number="6100" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:04Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to clarify the criminalization of female genital mutilation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">STOP FGM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP FGM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">STOP FGM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">STOP FGM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">STOP FGM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">STOP FGM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2020-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2020-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-506.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-09-16" calendar="Union" number="406">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 406.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T15:19:46-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Jackson Lee moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T15:21:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4589-4592" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T15:21:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6100.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2020-09-21T15:31:03-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4589-4590" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T15:31:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-15">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7509" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2020-12-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2020-12-24">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2021-01-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="116-309" type="public" datetime="2021-01-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 116-309.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3583" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2017" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-15T15:43:38Z" status="Public Law">Strengthening the Opposition to Female Genital Mutilation Act of 2020 or the STOP FGM Act of 2020

 This bill revises the federal criminal statute that prohibits certain conduct often referred to as female genital mutilation (FGM).

Currently, the FGM statute prohibits performing certain procedures&#8212;circumcising, excising, or infibulating the female genitalia of a minor&#8212;for nonmedical purposes. However, it does not define FGM.

In 2018 a federal district court invalidated the FGM statute in United States vs. Nagarwala. The court found, among other things, that the statute exceeds Congress's authority under the Commerce Clause of the Constitution because it (1) lacks detailed, record-based findings regarding how FGM substantially affects interstate commerce; and (2) lacks jurisdictional elements (e.g., requirements that charged offenses have an explicit connection with, or effect on, interstate commerce). In 2019, the Department of Justice (DOJ) decided not to appeal the decision.

This bill creates a statutory definition of female genital mutilation and provides explicit findings regarding the effects of FGM on interstate commerce.

The bill broadens the scope of prohibited FGM-related conduct on a minor to include

 attempting or conspiring to perform FGM; facilitating or consenting to FGM, as a parent, guardian, or caretaker; and transporting a minor for FGM. It expressly requires prohibited FGM-related conduct to have a connection to interstate or foreign commerce.

The bill increases from 5 to 10 years the statutory maximum prison term for an FGM offense. It also prohibits a federal criminal defendant from asserting, as a defense, that FGM is required as a matter of religion, custom, tradition, ritual, or standard practice.

DOJ, in consultation with various federal agencies, must report annually on FGM, including the estimated number of women and girls at risk of or subjected to FGM and actions taken by government agencies to combat the practice.

Finally, the bill expresses the sense of Congress that the court erred in invalidating the existing statute. It expresses, among other sentiments, that Congress elects to amend the statute to clarify the commercial nature of FGM, but that Congress does not ratify the interpretation of the federal district court in Nagarwala.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-506</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
