<bill session="118" type="h" number="171" updated="2025-11-19T03:47:03Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HALT Fentanyl Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Halt All Lethal Trafficking of Fentanyl Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALT Fentanyl Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to the scheduling of fentanyl-related substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2023-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2023-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="568" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="600" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1580" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3629" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="467" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1141" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-13T12:10:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Halt All Lethal Trafficking of Fentanyl Act or the HALT Fentanyl Act

This bill places fentanyl-related substances as a class into schedule I of the Controlled Substances Act. A schedule I controlled substance is a drug, substance, or chemical that has a high potential for abuse; has no currently accepted medical value; and is subject to regulatory controls and administrative, civil, and criminal penalties under the Controlled Substances Act.

Additionally, the bill establishes a new, alternative registration process for schedule I research that is funded by the Department of Health and Human Services or the Department of Veterans Affairs or that is conducted under an investigative new drug exemption from the Food and Drug Administration.

The bill also makes several other changes to registration requirements for conducting research with controlled substances, including

 permitting a single registration for related research sites in certain circumstances, waiving the requirement for a new inspection in certain situations, and allowing a registered researcher to perform certain manufacturing activities with small quantities of a substance without obtaining a manufacturing registration.</summary>
</bill>
