<bill session="111" type="h" number="3436" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TARP Executive Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require chief executive officers of certain financial institutions that receive assistance under title I of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, under the 3rd undesignated paragraph of section 13 of the Federal Reserve Act, or from the Secretary of the Treasury or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation under any other provision of law to submit financial disclosures under the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to the Secretary of the Treasury, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TARP Executive Disclosure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-05T19:55:03Z" status="Introduced in House">TARP Executive Disclosure Act - Requires each chief executive officer of any financial institution that receives federal assistance under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA), or other specified federal law, to report to the Secretary of the Treasury specified financial information required under the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.

Treats the Secretary as the designated agency ethics official for purposes of: (1) taking any action under the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 with respect to any person who fails to file such a report, or who files a false report; (2) acting as custodian of, and providing public access, to reports filed under this Act; and (3) reviewing such reports.

Authorizes the Secretary, in addition to any other specified action against an individual who fails to comply with this reporting requirement, to terminate and require the repayment of the assistance provided to a financial institution which gave rise to the reporting requirement with respect to any of its senior executive officers.

Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to carry out the Secretary's determination with respect to any assistance to the financial institution the Board or the FDIC provided.</summary>
</bill>
