<bill session="117" type="s" number="2227" updated="2022-12-31T05:26:17Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Labor to enter into contracts with industry intermediaries for purposes of promoting the development of and access to apprenticeships in the technology sector, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">CHANCE in TECH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Championing Apprenticeships for New Careers and Employees in Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHANCE in TECH Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2021-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="720" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-22T20:08:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Championing Apprenticeships for New Careers and Employees in Technology Act or the CHANCE in TECH Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to enter into contracts with industry intermediaries to promote the development of and access to apprenticeships in the technology sector.

The Department of Education (ED) may issue CHANCE in TECH Awards for 21st Century Schools to secondary schools or junior or community colleges that demonstrate high achievement in providing students necessary skills to compete in the 21st century workforce. In making an award, ED must consider the availability of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM), career and technical education, and computer technology courses at the schools.</summary>
</bill>
