<bill session="118" type="h" number="6621" updated="2024-11-07T14:53:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Uplift and Revitalization Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Uplift and Revitalization Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide technical assistance for geographically underserved and distressed areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000594" joined="2023-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-07T14:49:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Uplift and Revitalization Assistance Act

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide technical assistance in geographically underserved and distressed areas for USDA rural development programs.

Specifically, USDA must provide (directly or through cooperative agreements) technical assistance and strengthen local capacity to improve USDA rural development program access for local partners (e.g., local governments, businesses, and nonprofit organizations) in geographically underserved and distressed areas.&#160;

Under the bill, a&#160;geographically underserved and distressed area means a rural area (1) in a socially vulnerable community; (2) in a persistent poverty county; (3) in an economically distressed area; or (4) that lacks adequate water services, sewer services, or decent housing in any region near the border between the&#160;United States and Mexico.

On an annual basis, USDA must submit to Congress (and make publicly available)&#160;a report on how the provision of technical assistance under this bill has affected geographically underserved and distressed areas.</summary>
</bill>
