<bill session="117" type="s" number="4441" updated="2023-08-03T12:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for peer support specialists for claimants who are survivors of military sexual trauma, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide for peer support specialists for claimants who are survivors of military sexual trauma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2022-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2022-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2022-12-05" withdrawn="2022-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2022-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2724" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-03T12:29:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill prescribes that a peer support specialist of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must not be responsible for providing assistance to a veteran regarding a claim for compensation for a covered mental health condition (e.g., post-traumatic stress disorder) based on military sexual trauma (MST) experienced during active service. Such specialists must only provide counseling services, guidance, and support and must not participate in the adjudication of the claim.

As part of the forms for claims for compensation for a covered mental health condition based on MST, the VA must include an option for a veteran to elect to be referred to a MST trauma coordinator at the VA facility closest to the veteran's residence.

Additionally, the VA must (1) ensure that its peer support specialists receive annual training on providing peer support regarding MST, and (2) provide annual training on the processing of claims for compensation for covered mental health conditions based on MST to its MST coordinators and peer specialists.</summary>
</bill>
