<bill session="118" type="s" number="2803" updated="2025-11-19T04:56:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wounded Warrior Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Warrior Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to allow for the electronic request of certain records, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4528" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1226" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-03T22:28:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wounded Warrior Access Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish and maintain a secure online tool or website to enable a claimant or their representative to make records requests related to VA claims and benefits. Requests for records must specify in which format the copy is desired. The VA must notify a requester within 10 days that their request has been received and must fulfill the request within 120 days.

The bill also requires the VA to ensure that each time a claimant logs in to a website or online tool of the VA, the website or online tool displays in plain language (1) a warning regarding violations of laws related to agents and attorneys, (2) a link to an online tool to report violations, (3) a link to an online tool to search for a VA-recognized agent or attorney, and (4) a link to a website or online tool providing final decisions on discipline of agents and attorneys for violations.</summary>
</bill>
