<bill session="116" type="s" number="3496" updated="2022-02-09T04:18:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Layoffs During a Public Health Emergency Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Layoffs During a Public Health Emergency Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for Federal financing of short-time compensation programs during public health emergencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1743-1744" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="748" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-13T17:50:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Layoffs During a Public Health Emergency Act of 2020

This bill provides 100% of temporary federal financing of limited short-time compensation (STC) payments in certain states where a public health emergency has been declared. (STC, also known as work sharing, is a program within the federal-state unemployment system that provides pro-rated unemployment compensation to workers whose hours have been reduced in lieu of a layoff.)

The term public health emergency means a public health emergency declared for an area by (1) the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or (2) a state public health official with the authority to declare such an emergency for the area.

Certain states without a STC program may enter into an agreement with the Department of Labor under which Labor will temporarily finance 50% of the state's STC payments.

If such a state subsequently enacts a state law implementing a STC program that meets federal requirements it shall be ineligible for such 50% financing; however, it shall be eligible for the 100% financing. Labor must

 develop and provide model legislative language for states to develop and enact STC programs, including periodically reviewing and revising such language; provide technical assistance and guidance in developing, enacting, and implementing STC programs; and establish certain STC reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
