<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="234" updated="2025-05-13T11:06:15Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2670" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-07-13T22:25:06-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001132"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 32 printed in House Report 118-142 to prohibit the Department of Defense from making participation in training or support for certain race-based concepts a requirement for hiring, promotion, or retention of individuals. Also, the amendment ensures that employees and service members cannot be compelled to declare belief in or participate in training that promotes such concepts as a condition of favorable personnel actions.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment prohibits the Department of Defense from making participation in training or support for certain race-based concepts a requirement for hiring, promotion, or retention of individuals. Amendment ensures that employees and service members cannot be compelled to declare belief in or participate in training that promotes such concepts as a condition of favorable personnel actions.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-07-13T22:25:06-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="310">
      <text>On agreeing to the Crane amendment (A019) Agreed to by recorded vote: 214 - 210 (Roll no. 310).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13T18:05:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A019) offered by Mr. Crane.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3532-3534, H3561-3562" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3532" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13T18:05:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A019) offered by Mr. Crane.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3532-3534, H3561-3562" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3532" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13T22:25:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Crane amendment (A019) Agreed to by recorded vote: 214 - 210 (Roll no. 310).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13T22:25:06-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13T22:25:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
