<bill session="117" type="h" number="7999" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:49Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Transferring GITMO Terrorists to America Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Transferring GITMO Terrorists to America Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the transfer or release of individuals detained at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and the construction or modification of facilities in the United States to house detainees transferred from United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000825"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2022-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2022-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-11T18:59:37Z" status="Introduced in House">No Transferring GITMO Terrorists to America Act of 2022

This bill prohibits the use of Department of Defense (DOD) funds to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release of any individual detained at Guantanamo to or within the United States or its territories or possessions. Individuals detained at Guantanamo means those detained as of October 1, 2009, who are not citizens of the United States or members of the U.S. Armed Forces and are in the custody or under the control of DOD or otherwise under detention.

The bill also prohibits DOD funds from being used to construct or modify any facility in the United States or its territories or possessions to house any individual detained at Guantanamo for the purpose of detention or imprisonment in the custody or under the control of DOD. This prohibition does not apply to any modification of facilities at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</summary>
</bill>
