<bill session="110" type="h" number="1395" updated="2023-01-11T19:55:04Z">
  <state datetime="2007-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent abuse of Government credit cards.</title>
    <title type="display">Government Credit Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Credit Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000358" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2007-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2007-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000289" joined="2007-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2007-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2007-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000550" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000280" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2007-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000043" joined="2008-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001152" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2007-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2007-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000587" joined="2007-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2007-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6115"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO24" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Government Operations and the Federal Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="789" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-27T22:11:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Government Credit Card Abuse Prevention Act of 2007 - Requires the head of each executive agency, except the Department of Defense (DOD), to: (1) establish safeguards and internal controls for purchase cards, convenience checks, and travel cards; and (2) prescribe regulations implementing such safeguards and controls that provide for adverse personnel actions or other punishment against employees for card violations, negligence, misuse, abuse, or fraud.

Requires each agency Inspector General to: (1) periodically conduct risk assessments of agency purchase and travel card programs and associated internal controls, analyze weaknesses and the frequency of improper activity, and develop a plan to determine the scope, frequency, and number of periodic audits of cardholders; (2) perform periodic audits of card holders and report results to the agency head; and (3) report to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OBM) and the Comptroller General on the implementation of recommendations to address audit findings.

Requires DOD regulations that govern the use and control of purchase cards and convenience checks that are issued to DOD personnel to include safeguards and internal controls to ensure that: (1) the Inspector Generals of DOD, the Army, the Navy, and the Airforce periodically conduct risk assessments of the DOD purchase card program and associated internal controls, analyze weaknesses and the frequency of improper activity, and develop a plan to determine the scope, frequency, and number of periodic audits of cardholders; (2) DOD utilizes technologies to prevent or identify fraudulent purchases, including controlling merchant codes and utilizing statistical machine learning and pattern recognition technologies that review the risk of every transaction; and (3) DOD invalidates the purchase card of terminated or transferred employees.

Amends the Travel and Transportation Reform Act of 1998 to require each agency head to establish safeguards and internal controls over travel charge cards. Requires the Administrator of General Services to prescribe regulations governing the implementation of such safeguards and internal controls.

Requires the heads of agencies that have employees who use centrally billed accounts to establish safeguards and internal controls to ensure that agencies: (1) compare items submitted on an employee's travel voucher with items paid using such an account; (2) dispute unauthorized charges and track disputed transactions to ensure appropriate resolution; and (3) submit requests for refunds for fully or partially unused tickets to the holder of the applicable contract for a centrally billed account.</summary>
</bill>
