<bill session="118" type="h" number="1165" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:00Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Privacy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Data Privacy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="display">Data Privacy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to modernize the protection of the nonpublic personal information of individuals with whom financial institutions have customer or consumer relationship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-822.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-05" calendar="Union" number="673">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 673.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-05T11:24:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Data Privacy Act of 2023

This bill addresses the privacy and security of personal information held by financial institutions. The bill expands the application of current protections, it provides individuals with controls for limiting the collection of their information, and it establishes data privacy standards nationwide.

Currently, financial institutions must protect personal information and provide notice about privacy practices. The bill expands personal information protections that currently apply to customers (individuals who have a continuing relationship with a financial institution) to consumers (individuals who have a more limited relationship with a financial institution, such as those who apply for but do not receive a loan). The bill also expands notice requirements to apply to the collection of individual data.

Under the bill, financial institutions must (1) inform individuals for what purpose their data is collected and how the data will be used, and (2) give individuals the opportunity to opt out of data collection. An individual may also end the sharing of the individual's data with third parties, as well as demand the deletion of the individual's data.

The bill also prohibits states from establishing different privacy protections than those at the federal level. Under current law, states are allowed to establish stricter privacy protections.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-822</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
