<bill session="118" type="s" number="3150" updated="2025-11-18T20:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IMF Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMF Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit representatives of the United States from voting at the International Monetary Fund for any Special Drawing Rights allocations, quota increases, or policy modifications that would benefit certain countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6502" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-26T19:15:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">IMF Accountability Act of 2023

This bill imposes requirements on U.S. representatives to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) with regard to certain issues involving China, Russia, Iran, North Korea, Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua, or Afghanistan while under Taliban control.

The President or any U.S. representative to the IMF may not vote to allocate Special Drawing Rights (SDR) to any of these countries unless Congress authorizes such a vote. (The SDR is an international reserve asset maintained by the IMF based on contributions from IMF member countries. SDRs may be exchanged between member countries and may also be exchanged for currencies.)

The bill also requires the Department of the Treasury to direct U.S. representatives to the IMF to oppose any proposal that (1) increases the IMF quota of any of these countries, or (2) modifies certain policies if the modification would allow the IMF to provide funding to any of these countries. (A country's quota determines, among other things, that country's voting power in IMF decisions and access to IMF financing.)</summary>
</bill>
