<bill session="111" type="s" number="3504" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Contraception Education Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a public education and awareness program relating to emergency contraception.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Contraception Education Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5561" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-19T20:20:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency Contraception Education Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to develop and disseminate to the public information on emergency contraception, including, at a minimum, a description of emergency contraception and an explanation of the use, safety, efficacy, and availability of such contraception.

Requires that the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to develop and disseminate to health care providers, including pharmacists, information on emergency contraception that includes, at a minimum: (1) information describing the use, safety, efficacy, and availability of emergency contraception; (2) a recommendation regarding its use in appropriate cases; and (3) information explaining how to obtain copies of information from the CDC.</summary>
</bill>
