<bill session="119" type="h" number="1978" updated="2025-08-28T16:46:59Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy to treat obesity as a disease and reduce the prevalence of obesity in certain Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy to treat obesity as a disease and reduce the prevalence of obesity in certain Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2025-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-28T16:45:41Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to develop a strategy to align its obesity-related programs with the classification of obesity as a medically accepted disease. Additionally, DOD must conduct an educational campaign to promote awareness, diagnosis, and treatment of obesity as a disease in the Armed Forces (the&#160;Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, and Space Force).

The bill also requires DOD to include information regarding unmet weight standards in any reports it submits to Congress regarding&#160;disqualifications for enlistment in, disabilities incurred in, or medical discharges from the Armed Forces.

DOD must submit a report to Congress on the effects of obesity on the readiness of the Armed Forces, including legislative recommendations to address such effects. The Defense Health Agency within DOD must report on the effectiveness of the obesity, food, and nutrition-related programs of DOD in reducing obesity and improving military readiness.

The Government Accountability Office must submit to Congress an analysis of the existing obesity, food, and nutrition-related programs of DOD.</summary>
</bill>
