<bill session="111" type="h" number="46" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:27Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29T14:21:20-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-29T14:21:20-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for payment of an administrative fee to public housing agencies to cover the costs of administering family self-sufficiency programs in connection with the housing choice voucher program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001232"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28T13:59:51-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Baca moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28T14:00:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4862-4864" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28T14:00:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-28T14:10:28-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Baca objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29T14:11:13-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4940" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="221" datetime="2009-04-29T14:21:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 397 - 19 (Roll no. 221).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 4/28/2009 H4862" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29T14:21:21-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-01T14:00:08Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2009 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to revise requirements for the administrative fee payable to public housing agencies to cover the costs of administering family self-sufficiency programs in connection with the housing choice voucher program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.

Prescribes: (1) a base fee for a public housing agency serving 25 or more program participants equal to the costs of employing one full-time family self-sufficiency coordinator (prorated for an agency serving fewer than 25 such participants); and (2) an additional fee for an agency meeting minimum performance standards to cover the costs of employing a second coordinator if the agency has 75 or more participating families, and a third coordinator if it has 125 or more participating families.

 Permits the Secretary to reserve certain amounts to provide support to or reward family self-sufficiency programs that are particularly innovative or highly successful in achieving program goals.</summary>
</bill>
