<bill session="117" type="h" number="7656" updated="2023-08-22T14:30:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Reckless Student Loan Actions Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Reckless Student Loan Actions Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students Act of 2003 to strike the Secretary's unilateral authority during a national emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2022-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2022-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4094" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-21T19:02:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Reckless Student Loan Actions Act of 2022

This bill limits executive authority to (1) suspend or defer federal student loan payments or interest accrual on such loans, and (2) cancel federal student loans.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the President or the Department of Education (ED) from suspending or deferring federal student loan payments or the accrual of interest on such loans for borrowers with annual household incomes over 400% of the federal poverty line.

Further, ED may only suspend or defer federal student loan payments or the accrual of interest for such loans for a total of 90 days after the declaration of a national emergency by the President. ED must submit recommendations to Congress on relief necessary for recipients of student financial-aid assistance.

Additionally, the bill prohibits the President or ED from cancelling the outstanding balances or portions of balances on student loans due to the COVID-19 national emergency or any other national emergency.

Executive or regulatory action to suspend or defer federal student loan payments or to cancel federal student loans shall be subject to congressional review.

The bill also revises the definition of affected individual for purposes of the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students (HEROES) Act of 2003 to exclude from relief under the act (1) an individual who resides or is employed in an area that is declared a disaster area in connection with a national emergency; or (2) an individual who suffered direct economic hardship as a direct result of a war, military operation, or national emergency.</summary>
</bill>
