<bill session="117" type="s" number="1571" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Servicemember Parental Leave Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to expand parental leave for members of the Armed Forces, to reduce the service commitment required for participation in the career intermission program of a military department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemember Parental Leave Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3122" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-10T21:19:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Servicemember Parental Leave Equity Act

This bill modifies Department of Defense parental leave provisions for members of the Armed Forces.

Specifically, the bill increases parental leave for primary caregivers to 18 weeks (currently 12) following the birth of a child and to 12 weeks (currently 6) following the adoption of a child. The bill increases parental leave for a secondary caregiver from 21 days to 12 weeks in connection with the birth or adoption of a child.

Primary or secondary caregivers of a long-term foster child are authorized to take up to 12 weeks of leave in connection with such placement.

Parental leave for a primary or secondary caregiver for a birth, adoption, or foster child placement may be taken in more than one increment. For primary caregivers, the leave must be utilized within one year of the event.

The bill authorizes up to 12 weeks of leave to certain service members who would have been secondary caregivers but for a miscarriage, stillbirth, or infant death.

The following activities required of an active-duty member within a 12-month postpartum period must have the approval of a health care provider and be at the election of the member or in the interest of national security: (1) an order of temporary duty overnight travel or to participate in physically demanding field training exercises, (2) meeting of body composition standards, or (3) passing a physical fitness test.

 The bill also reduces the service commitment required for participation in the Career Intermission Program.</summary>
</bill>
