<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1081" updated="2022-02-03T05:59:29Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5326" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-05-09T23:37:36-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  <description>Amendment prohibits the use of funds to pay salaries of any officer or employee of the Department of Commerce who uses amounts in the Fisheries Enforcement Asset Forfeiture Fund under NOAA for any purpose not specifically authorized.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 32 printed in the Congressional Record to prohibit the use of funds to be used to pay the salary of any officer or employee of the Department of Commerce who uses amounts in the Fisheries Enforcement Asset Forfeiture Fund of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that consists of the sums described in section 311(e)(1) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1861(e)(1)) for any purpose other than a purpose specifically authorized under such section.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-05-09T23:37:36-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="237">
      <text>On agreeing to the Gardner amendment (A048) Agreed to by recorded vote: 357 - 68 (Roll no. 237).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T19:12:02-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A048) offered by Mr. Gardner.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2523, H2553" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2523" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T23:37:36-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T23:37:36-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T23:37:36-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Gardner amendment (A048) Agreed to by recorded vote: 357 - 68 (Roll no. 237).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09T19:12:02-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A048) offered by Mr. Gardner.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2523, H2553" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2523" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
