<bill session="112" type="h" number="6085" updated="2019-02-20T22:36:43Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend section 40 of the Revised Statutes of the United States to clarify that for purposes of determining whether a Member of the House of Representatives is subject to a deduction from in pay by reason of absence from the House on a day, the Member shall be considered to be absent if the Member misses any vote held in the House on that day, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 40 of the Revised Statutes of the United States to clarify that for purposes of determining whether a Member of the House of Representatives is subject to a deduction from in pay by reason of absence from the House on a day, the Member shall be considered to be absent if the Member misses any vote held in the House on that day, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000362" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001252" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2012-07-18" withdrawn="2012-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-11T15:55:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Revised Statutes of the United States with respect to the requirement that the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives deduct from the monthly payments of each Member of the House (or Delegate) the amount of the Member's salary for each day of absence from the House, except in the case of the Member's sickness or the sickness of a family member. Adds Resident Commissioner to Member and Delegate under such requirement.

Considers a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner (Member) to be absent from the House on a day if the individual does not cast a vote on any vote taken in the House (including any vote taken in the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union) on that day.

Requires a written notice to the Speaker of the House about the Member's or family member's sickness under the exception.

Requires the Chief Administrative Officer, within five days after the end of each month, to publish on the House official public Internet site a list showing: (1) specified information regarding each Member whose pay was subject to such a deduction for the month; and (2) each Member who submitted a written notice to the Speaker during the month, together with a copy of the notice.</summary>
</bill>
