<bill session="118" type="h" number="6513" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:02Z">
  <state datetime="2024-10-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">COCOA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COCOA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">COCOA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">COCOA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">COCOA Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">COCOA Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="display">COCOA Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to confirm the requirement that States allow access to designated congressional election observers to observe the election administration procedures in congressional elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2023-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001213" joined="2023-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-29">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 118-361.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-01-29" calendar="Union" number="296">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 296.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T15:28:24-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Steil moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T15:28:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5049-5051" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T15:28:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6513.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-09-09T15:35:02-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5049-5050" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T15:35:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24">
      <text>Senate Committee on Rules and Administration discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2024-09-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25T14:58:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Steil moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5791-5792" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25T14:58:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 6513.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25T15:05:14-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25T16:03:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business. H.R. 6513 - "An Act to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to confirm the requirement that States allow access to designated congressional election observers to observe the election administration procedures in congressional elections."</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5800" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="449" datetime="2024-09-25T16:27:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 413 - 1 (Roll no. 449).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5791" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25T16:27:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-10-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-10-04" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-106" type="public" datetime="2024-10-04">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-106.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="text similarities"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4474" relation="text similarities"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4494" relation="text similarities"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="9779" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3297"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-11-20T22:48:16Z" status="Public Law">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2024 or the COCOA Act of 2024

This act provides statutory authority for designated congressional election observers. Designated congressional election observer refers to an employee of the House of Representatives or the Senate who is designated in writing by the chair or ranking minority member of the House Committee on House Administration or the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration to gather information with respect to an election, including in the event that the election is contested in the House or the Senate and for other purposes permitted by Article I, Section 5, clause 1 and Article I, Section 4, clause 1 of the U.S. Constitution.

The act requires states to provide designated congressional election observers with full access to&#160;clearly observe all elements of administration procedures of federal elections, including access to any area in which a ballot is cast, processed, scanned, tabulated, canvassed, recounted, audited, or certified, including during pre- and post-election procedures.

The act prohibits such an observer from handling ballots or election equipment, advocating for a position or candidate, taking any action to reduce ballot secrecy or voter privacy, taking any action to interfere with the ability of a voter to cast a ballot or an election administrator to carry out the administrator's duties, or otherwise interfering with the election administration process.

The act specifies the conduct for which designated congressional election observers may be removed by election officials. In the event of removal, the election official must, within 24 hours of the observer's removal,&#160;provide written notice to the chair and ranking minority member of the House Committee on House Administration or the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-361</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
