<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="148" updated="2022-02-09T05:53:38Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5314" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-12-09T15:46:52-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000172"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 25 printed in Part B of House Report 117-205 to assert the Government Accountability Office's investigatory powers over the intelligence community. Requires the Director of National Intelligence to ensure that GAO personnel are provided with access to information in possession by the intelligence community that the Comptroller General determines necessary for analysis, evaluation, or investigation requested by the relevant committee of Congress.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to assert the Government Accountability Office's investigatory powers over the intelligence community and require the Director of National Intelligence to ensure that GAO personnel are provided with access to certrain information in possession by the intelligence community.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-12-09T15:46:52-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="438">
      <text>On agreeing to the Ocasio-Cortez amendment (A004) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 233 (Roll no. 438).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09T14:41:09-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A004) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09T14:30:15-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Ms. Ocasio-Cortez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7611-7613, H7615" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7612" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09T14:30:15-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A004) offered by Ms. Ocasio-Cortez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7611-7613, H7615" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7612" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09T15:46:52-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Ocasio-Cortez amendment (A004) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 233 (Roll no. 438).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09T15:46:52-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Ocasio-Cortez amendment (A004) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 233 (Roll no. 438).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09T15:46:52-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
