<bill session="116" type="h" number="7051" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide Federal relief to hog producers, especially family farmers and independent producers, who have been forced to euthanize hogs due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide Federal relief to hog producers, especially family farmers and independent producers, who have been forced to euthanize hogs due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000362"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-25T16:40:01Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to use the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation to provide emergency relief to hog producers to aid in the reduction of intentional depopulation losses of market-ready hogs due to the closure or the reduction in processing capacity of a processing plant related to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic.

USDA may not make a payment for the losses of market-ready hogs unless a veterinarian certifies that such hogs are market-ready hogs, and the number of such hogs for which the hog producer claims a loss. Additionally, USDA may not make payments for (1) any hog losses for which the hog producer does not provide sufficient documentation of ownership; (2) the losses of packer-owned hogs; or (3) the losses of hogs of a producer that is owned, in whole or in part, by any person who is not a U.S. citizen, lawful permanent resident, or entity.

The bill applies for the period beginning on April 1, 2020, and ending on the date that national processing capacity of hog processing plants is equal to or greater than such capacity was on February 1, 2020.</summary>
</bill>
