<bill session="116" type="h" number="3231" updated="2022-11-01T07:02:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REVAMP Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide grants to veterans service organizations for upgrading local chapter facilities, including technology at such facilities, in rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renovate and Enhance Veterans Meeting Halls and Posts Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REVAMP Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2019-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2019-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-26T19:09:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Renovate and Enhance Veterans Meeting Halls and Posts Act of 2019 or the REVAMP Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to award grants to veterans service organizations in rural areas to (1) repair or rehabilitate a facility in a rural area, and (2) acquire or upgrade computers and technology for such a facility.

An organization may not receive a grant in any fiscal year in an amount exceeding the lesser of (1) the aggregate cost of such proposed activities and uses, or (2) $75,000.

An organization that receives such a grant for a fiscal year shall be ineligible for any such grant for the next five fiscal years.

Grants awarded under this bill may not be used for the construction or acquisition of new facilities.</summary>
</bill>
