<bill session="111" type="s" number="1502" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Carbon Storage Stewardship Trust Fund Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program to be managed by the Department of Energy to ensure prompt and orderly compensation for potential damages relating to the storage of carbon dioxide in geological storage units.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Carbon Storage Stewardship Trust Fund Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2009-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7888-7889"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7889-7890" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-03T15:23:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Carbon Storage Stewardship Trust Fund Act of 2009 - Makes the Secretary of Energy responsible for the long-term stewardship of a carbon dioxide storage facility upon the issuance of a certificate of closure for the facility. Authorizes a state to request that the stewardship of a facility located in the state be transferred to the state. Directs the Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to establish standards for monitoring, measurement, verification, and site remediation activities necessary to protect health, safety, and the environment during such stewardship.

Establishes in the Department of Energy (DOE) the Carbon Storage Stewardship and Trust Fund Program. Directs the Secretary to require operators of carbon dioxide storage facilities to: (1) maintain adequate liability insurance during the phases of the facility through receipt of a certificate of closure; and (2) pay a risk-based fee for each ton of carbon dioxide injected by the facility into geological storage units.

Establishes in the Treasury a Carbon Storage Trust Fund, which shall be used to pay long-term stewardship costs, Program administrative costs, and civil claims brought against a facility after closure. Sets forth provisions concerning limitations on, funding of, and adjudication of such claims.</summary>
</bill>
