<bill session="118" type="h" number="4799" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RVC ARE Neo-Nazis Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requiring Verification of Compliance with Abandoning Ruthless Evil Neo-Nazis Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RVC ARE Neo-Nazis Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit assistance under the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative until the President certifies to Congress that the Government of Ukraine is not providing funding, equipment, training, fuel, or other support to the Russian Volunteer Corps, the Azov Battalion, or any other neo-Nazi militia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2023-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-13T23:11:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Requiring Verification of Compliance with Abandoning Ruthless Evil Neo-Nazis Act or RVC ARE Neo-Nazis Act

This bill prohibits the Department of Defense from providing security assistance to Ukraine authorized under the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative until the President certifies to Congress that the government of Ukraine is not providing funding, equipment, training, fuel, or other support to the Russian Volunteer Corps, the Azov Battalion, or any neo-Nazi militia.</summary>
</bill>
