<bill session="111" type="s" number="471" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:42Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">High School Sports Information Collection Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">High School Sports Information Collection Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 to require the Statistics Commissioner to collect information from coeducational secondary schools on such schools' athletic programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2010-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001266" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2009-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2009-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2479"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-14T12:36:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">High School Sports Information Collection Act of 2009 - Amends the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 to require the Commissioner of the National Center for Education Statistics to collect the following information annually from each coeducational secondary school that receives federal financial assistance and that has an athletic program: (1) the number, gender, race, and ethnicity of students that attended the school; and (2) for each team that competed in athletic competition, the number, gender, race, and ethnicity of participants, the total expenditures, the number, gender, employment status, and qualifications of trainers, medical personnel, and coaches, and the number of competitions and practices scheduled.

Requires such schools to: (1) make such information available to students and potential students, upon request, and to the public by October 15 of each school year; (2) ensure that all students at the school are informed of their right to request such information; and (3) annually provide such information to the Commissioner.

Directs the Commissioner to: (1) ensure that such information is posted on the Department of Education's website; (2) notify all secondary schools regarding the availability of the information; and (3) issue guidance on how to collect and report the information required under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
