<bill session="108" type="h" number="5191" updated="2023-01-13T22:01:44Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Count Every Vote Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 3, United States Code, to extend the date provided for the meeting of electors of the President and Vice President in the States, and the date provided for the joint session of Congress held for the counting of electoral votes, in the event of an unresolved controversy or contest relating to the counting of votes in any State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Count Every Vote Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2004-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2004-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2004-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Electoral college"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Express service"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-01T20:05:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Count Every Vote Act of 2004 - Amends Federal law to extend the date provided for the meeting of electors of the President and Vice President in the States, and the date provided for the joint session of Congress held for the counting of electoral votes, in the event of an unresolved controversy or contest relating to the counting of votes in any State.

Changes the date for the meeting of electors, in such an event, from the first Monday after the second Wednesday in December following their appointment to the first day after January 1 following their appointment.

Changes the date for the counting of electoral votes in a joint session of Congress from the sixth day of January succeeding the meeting of the electors in the States to the second day following the extended deadline for the receipt of certificates and votes by the President of the Senate or the Archivist of the United States.

Reduces from six to three days the "safe harbor" period for resolution of any controversy or contest regarding appointment of State electors.</summary>
</bill>
