<bill session="118" type="h" number="4425" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Women in Agriculture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women in Agriculture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to establish the position of Women Farmers and Ranchers Liaison, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2023-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000399" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-25T16:18:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Women in Agriculture Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the position of Women Farmers and Ranchers Liaison within USDA.

Among other things, the liaison must advocate on behalf of women who are farmers and ranchers in interactions with USDA employees and promote the advancement of women in USDA leadership roles. The liaison may also enter into a contract or cooperative agreement to conduct various research, training, and other activities with respect to women who are farmers and ranchers.

The liaison must submit an annual report to Congress on USDA grants, loans, loan guarantees, and cost-share programs for woman-owned agriculture operations.

In addition, the bill expands the USDA high-priority research and extension areas to authorize grants&#160;for developing and making widely available agriculture equipment and machinery that is ergonomically designed for use by women.

Further,&#160;USDA must give priority to certain loans or grants to address the availability, quality, or cost of childcare in an agricultural or rural community.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
