<bill session="115" type="s" number="1534" updated="2023-01-11T13:37:07Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Federal Communications Commission to amend its rules so as to prohibit the application to amateur stations of certain private land use restrictions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4986" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="555" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5515" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-02T18:38:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2017

This bill directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to amend station antenna structure regulations to prohibit a private land use restriction from applying to amateur radio stations if the restriction:

 precludes communications in an amateur radio service, fails to permit a licensee of amateur radio service to install and maintain an effective outdoor antenna on property under its exclusive use or control, or is not the minimum practicable restriction to accomplish the lawful purposes of a community association seeking to enforce the restriction. Before installing an outdoor antenna, however, an amateur radio licensee must obtain a community association's prior approval. A community association may: (1) prohibit installations on common property not under the exclusive control of the licensee, and (2) establish installation rules for amateur radio antennas and support structures.</summary>
</bill>
