<bill session="118" type="h" number="3793" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Access to Lifesaving Drugs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Lifesaving Drugs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require manufacturers of life-saving drugs to submit data and information to assess the stability of the drugs and determine their longest supported expiration date, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2023-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4697" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-21T20:58:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Access to Lifesaving Drugs Act of 2023

This bill allows the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to obtain additional information from manufacturers of life-saving drugs in order to assess and potentially modify the drug's expiration date. (The bill defines life-saving drug as a medical countermeasure or a drug that is in short supply and that is life-supporting, life-sustaining, or intended to be used to prevent or treat a debilitating disease or condition in humans or animals.)

Specifically, the FDA may order a manufacturer of a life-saving drug to submit data and other information from any stage of the drug's development in order to assess the drug's stability and the longest supported expiration date. If such information is not readily available, the FDA may order the manufacturer to conduct additional studies. The FDA may require changes to the drug's label accordingly. Manufacturers that fail to comply are subject to civil penalties.&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
