<bill session="108" type="s" number="2536" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Protection Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enumerate the responsibilities of the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security, to require the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security to designate a senior official to investigate civil rights complaints, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Homeland Security Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Protection Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Protection Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2004-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/18/2004 S7003-7004"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/18/2004 S7004-7005" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment. With written report No. 108-350.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="704">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 704.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="5182" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-18T20:17:59Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Homeland Security Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Protection Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include within the primary mission of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to ensure that civil rights are not diminished by efforts aimed at securing the homeland.

(Sec. 3) Requires DHS's Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties to: (1) report directly to the Secretary of DHS; and (2) review and assess information concerning civil rights abuses and profiling on the basis of race, ethnicity, or religion by DHS employees and officials.

 Includes among the Officer's responsibilities to: (1) assist the Secretary, directorates, and offices of DHS to develop, implement, and periodically review DHS policies and procedures to ensure that the protection of civil rights is appropriately incorporated into DHS programs and activities; (2) oversee compliance with requirements relating to civil rights; (3) coordinate with the DHS privacy officer to ensure that programs, policies, and procedures involving civil rights and privacy considerations are addressed in an integrated and comprehensive manner and that Congress receives appropriate reports regarding such programs; and (4) investigate complaints and information indicating possible abuses not to be investigated by DHS's Inspector General (IG).

(Sec. 4) Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to direct DHS's IG to designate a senior official within the Office of Inspector General to: (1) coordinate Office activities regarding investigations of civil rights abuses; (2) receive, review, and investigate information alleging abuses by DHS employees or by employees of independent contractors or grantees of DHS; (3) ensure that Office personnel receive sufficient training to conduct effective investigations; (4) consult with the Civil Rights Officer regarding such alleged abuses and any policy recommendations that may be founded upon an investigation by the Office; (5) provide such Officer with information regarding investigation outcomes; (6) refer civil rights matters that the IG decides not to investigate to such Officer; (7) ensure that the IG's Office publicizes and provides convenient public access to information regarding the procedure to file complaints or comments concerning civil rights matters and the status of investigations; and (8) inform the Officer of any civil rights deficiencies within DHS.

(Sec. 5) Amends the Homeland Security Act to require the DHS privacy officer to report directly to the Secretary and to coordinate with the Civil Rights Officer to ensure that programs involving civil rights and privacy are addressed in an integrated and comprehensive manner and that Congress receives appropriate reports.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-350</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
