<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>262</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T06:03:41Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T06:03:41Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-01-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
        <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-01-15T22:24:58Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001070</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Casey, Robert P., Jr. [D-PA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bob</firstName>
        <lastName>Casey</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Begich</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-01-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-03-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000035</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lincoln, Blanche L. [D-AR]</fullName>
        <firstName>BLANCHE</firstName>
        <lastName>LINCOLN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AR</state>
        <middleName>LAMBERT</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-04-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Afghanistan</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Iraq</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mental health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military medicine</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military operations and strategy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National Guard and reserves</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' medical care</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-01-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-02-06T21:20:48Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Fortifying Operational Reserve Component Efforts Act of 2009 or FORCE Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to conduct a review of Department of Defense (DOD) communications to reserve members of the Armed Forces and their families on health benefits, family support, and other resources available through DOD. Requires: (1) the review to include member and family surveys on their participation in programs and activities associated with member mobilization and demobilization; and (2) the Secretary, using review results, to enhance DOD educational materials provided to such members and families on such benefits, support, and resources.</p><p>Directs: (1) the Secretary of the military department concerned (Secretary concerned) to assign to each unit of a reserve component under their jurisdiction full-time personnel to provide assistance to the family of a member during, and in connection with, the mobilization and deployment of such unit; and (2) the Secretary to ensure a minimum number of Transition Assistance Advisors in each state.</p><p>Requires: (1) the Secretary to provide a post-deployment health reassessment to each reserve member returning from deployment in Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom; and (2) the Secretary concerned to provide each reserve member an annual briefing on health benefits available to members and dependents under the TRICARE program (a DOD managed care program).</p><p>Authorizes the Secretary concerned to pay to a reserve member activated for more than 30 days a monthly stipend to cover, during the activation period, the cost of private health insurance for the spouse and dependents of such member who reside more than 50 miles from the nearest military medical treatment facility or TRICARE services provider.</p><p>Directs the Secretary to provide to reserve units comprehensive training on mental health matters.</p><p>Provides funding for mental health care for National Guard members who incurred a psychological or mental illness or injury while on active duty.</p><p>Requires the Secretary to: (1) measure the achievement of DOD objectives for reserve member participation in the Transition Assistance Program; and (2) ensure that each member of the Individual Ready Reserve who deploys as an individual is provided the same pre- and post-deployment information as provided to members who deploy as a unit.</p><p>Expresses the sense of Congress that National Guard members returning from deployment in a contingency operation or homeland defense mission of one year or longer should: (1) not be required to commence full-time National Guard duty immediately upon their return; and (2) be permitted to elect to postpone commencement of deactivation from active-duty status until at least 90 days after such return.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Fortifying Operational Reserve Component Efforts Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Fortifying Operational Reserve Component Efforts Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>FORCE Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Fortifying Operational Reserve Component Efforts Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to improve and enhance the operations of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, to improve mobilization and demobilization processes for members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-01-15T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s262is/xml/BILLS-111s262is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-01-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
