<bill session="117" type="h" number="9246" updated="2022-12-29T13:34:05Z">
  <state datetime="2022-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to disallow the deduction of certain expenses relating to ownership of single-family homes by specified large investors, to impose an excise tax on the sale of such homes by such investors, to establish the neighborhood homes tax credit, and to prohibit Federal mortgage assistance relating to certain large investors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000389"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2022-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5376" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-10T13:19:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2022 

This bill denies certain tax and other benefits to large investors whose assets exceed $100 million in a taxable year for investment in single-family housing (i.e., real property including at least one dwelling unit and not more than four units). It denies such investors a tax deduction for interest paid on a single-family home mortgage, for insuring such homes, and for the depreciation of such homes.

The bill imposes an excise tax on the sale or transfer of a single-family home by a large investor equal to the price of such home. It allows a tax credit for home sellers equal to the lesser of either the excess of reasonable development costs paid over the sale price, or 35% of the lesser of eligible development costs paid by the taxpayer, or 80% of the national median sale price for homes.

The bill prohibits large investors from obtaining certain federal mortgage assistance.</summary>
</bill>
