<bill session="110" type="s" number="1588" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:49Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Children's Access to Reconstructive Evaluation and Surgery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require that group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans provide coverage for treatment of a minor child's congenital or developmental deformity or disorder due to trauma, infection, tumor, or disease.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Access to Reconstructive Evaluation and Surgery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2007-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2007-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2007-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2007-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2008-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="1655" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Plastic surgery"/>
    <term name="Surgery"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-07-23T21:12:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Children's Access to Reconstructive Evaluation and Surgery Act or the CARES Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to require a group health plan that covers surgical benefits to also cover outpatient and inpatient diagnosis and treatment of a child's congenital or developmental deformity, disease, or injury. Requires that such coverage: (1) be subject to pre-authorization or pre-certification requirements of the plan or issuer; and (2) include any surgical treatment deemed by the treating physician to be medically necessary to approximate a normal appearance. Defines "treatment" to include reconstructive surgical procedures that are performed on abnormal structures of the body caused by congenital defects, abnormalities, trauma, infection, tumors, or disease, including: (1) procedures that do not materially affect the function of the body part being treated; and (2) procedures for secondary conditions and follow-up treatment. Excludes cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem.</summary>
</bill>
