<bill session="108" type="s" number="1953" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Deep Sea Coral Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect deep sea corals and sponges, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deep Sea Coral Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-15T16:57:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deep Sea Coral Protection Act - Prohibits the use of mobile bottom-tending fishing gear in Coral Management Areas (CMAs).

Designates CMAs according to specified coordinates. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to designate as additional CMAs areas within the exclusive economic zone that have not been fished with mobile bottom-tending gear in recent years. Authorizes the Secretary to terminate such CMA designations in specified circumstances.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) monitor fishing within the exclusive economic zone and quantify deep sea coral and sponge bycatch; (2) direct the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere to research and map deep sea corals and sponges; and (3) designate as CMAs areas identified through such monitoring and research as having deep sea coral ecosystems.

Requires the Chair of the National Research Council to review annually all available data on deep sea corals and sponges and recommend areas for CMA designation. Directs the Secretary to designate such areas after publication of a proposed rule unless a rational basis for designation is lacking.

Applies the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act's civil penalty and forfeiture requirements to persons who violate this Act's prohibition against the use of mobile bottom-tending gear. Prohibits interference with enforcement of this Act and applies the Magnuson-Stevens Act's criminal penalty scheme to violators.

Authorizes the President to permit the Secretary to identify, with foreign entities, areas in international waters that would benefit from additional protection.</summary>
</bill>
