<bill session="108" type="s" number="2580" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Technology Bond Initiative of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an income tax credit to holders of bonds financing new communications technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology Bond Initiative of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban economic development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-13T13:34:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Technology Bond Initiative of 2004 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a nonrefundable income tax credit for investment in qualified technology bonds. Defines "qualified technology bonds" as bonds issued by a State or local government for a term not exceeding 15 years, 95 percent or more of the proceeds of which are used to finance State or local projects for expanding broadband telecommunication services. Gives preference to projects for underserved urban or rural areas lacking access to high-speed Internet connections and projects reflecting partnerships and comprehensive planning between State and local governments and the private sector. Requires the inclusion in the gross income of a taxpayer amounts allowed as a tax credit under this Act.

Limits the amount of bonds that may be issued nationwide to $100 million for each of calendar years 2005 through 2009. Allows a carryover of unused bond amounts to the next calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
