<bill session="117" type="s" number="1468" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sgt. Ketchum Rural Veterans Mental Health Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to expand the Rural Access Network for Growth Enhancement Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs and to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study to assess certain mental health care resources of the Department of Veterans Affairs available to veterans who live in rural areas.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sgt. Ketchum Rural Veterans Mental Health Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2021-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2021-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2441" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-28T11:02:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sgt. Ketchum Rural Veterans Mental Health Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), during FY2022, to establish and maintain three new centers of the Rural Access Network for Growth Enhancement (RANGE) Program in areas with interest from personnel and a need for additional mental health care for rural veterans. The RANGE Program serves veterans in rural areas who are experiencing mental illness.

The bill requires the Government Accountability Office to conduct a study and report on whether the VA has sufficient resources to serve rural veterans who need mental health care that is more intensive than traditional outpatient therapy.</summary>
</bill>
