<bill session="118" type="hj" number="70" updated="2025-05-27T14:11:57Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-18T18:01:52-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-07-18T18:01:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Relating to a national emergency declared by the President on February 25, 2011.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Relating to a national emergency declared by the President on February 25, 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000596" joined="2023-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13T23:24:26-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Nunn (IA) asked unanimous consent that it be in order at any time through July 20, 2023, to consider the following joint resolutions in the House if called up by the Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or his designee: H. J. Res. 68, H. J. Res. 70, H. J. Res. 71, or H. J. Res. 74; that each such joint resolution be considered as read; that the previous question be considered as ordered on each such joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except for debate as follows: for H. J. Res. 68, 30 minutes equally divided among and controlled by Mr. McCaul, Mr. Meeks, and Mrs. Boebert or their respective designees; for H. J. Res. 70 and H. J. Res. 74, 30 minutes equally divided among and controlled by Mr. McCaul, Mr. Meeks, and Mr. Gosar or their respective designees; for H. J. Res. 71, 30 minutes equally divided among and controlled by Mr. McCaul, Mr. Meeks, and Mr. Crane or their respective designees; and that the provisions of section 202 of the                   National Emergencies Act (50 U .S.C. 1622) shall not apply                  to each such jo int resolution through July 20, 2023. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T14:24:19-04:00">
      <text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T14:25:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered pursuant to a previous order.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3662-3664" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T14:25:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant the previous order of the House of July 13, 2023, the House proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on H. J. Res. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T14:45:41-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to a previous order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T14:46:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. J. Res. 70, the Chair put the question on passage and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T17:55:51-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3682" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="334" datetime="2023-07-18T18:01:52-04:00" where="h" result="fail" state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 388 (Roll no. 334).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3662" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18T18:01:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-20T13:48:01Z" status="Introduced in House">This joint resolution terminates the national emergency concerning Libya declared by President Obama on February 25, 2011.</summary>
</bill>
