<bill session="117" type="h" number="6570" updated="2022-12-30T04:18:59Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPAIR Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPAIR Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right to Equitable and Professional Auto Industry Repair Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure consumers have access to data relating to their motor vehicles, critical repair information, and tools, and to provide them choices for the maintenance, service, and repair of their motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2022-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2022-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2022-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001203" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2022-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2022-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2022-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-11T16:18:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Right to Equitable and Professional Auto Industry Repair Act or the REPAIR Act

This bill requires a motor vehicle manufacturer to provide to a vehicle's owner certain direct, real-time, in-vehicle data generated by the operation of the vehicle that is related to diagnostics, repair, service, wear, and calibration or recalibration of parts and systems of the vehicle.

Specifically, a vehicle manufacturer may not impair an owner's access to such vehicle-generated data or impair an aftermarket parts manufacturer from producing or offering compatible aftermarket parts. A manufacturer also must make available to the vehicle's owner, and designees, vehicle-generated data through a standardized access platform. Outside of a recall, a manufacturer may not mandate or recommend the use of a particular brand or manufacturer of parts, tools, or equipment.

The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration must issue standards for access to vehicle data through the standardized access platform.

The Federal Trade Commission must establish an advisory committee to assess and report on existing and emerging barriers to vehicle repair and vehicle owners' control over their vehicle-generated data.

This bill provides authority for the commission to enforce these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
