<bill session="119" type="hr" number="382" updated="2025-07-02T14:44:55Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing a point of order in the House of Representatives during the 119th Congress against reconciliation measures that reduce benefits under the Medicaid program or the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing a point of order in the House of Representatives during the 119th Congress against reconciliation measures that reduce benefits under the Medicaid program or the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000135" joined="2025-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-05">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-02T14:40:52Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution establishes a point of order against considering budget reconciliation legislation in the House during the 119th Congress that (1) reduces enrollment or benefits for specified individuals enrolled in the Medicaid program, or (2) reduces eligibility or benefits for households that include specified&#160;individuals and participate in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP).

The&#160;individuals specified in the bill include individuals who are under the age of 19, individuals who are 65 or older, pregnant women, and individuals with a disability.&#160;

The point of order does not apply to any provision in reconciliation legislation&#160;that reduces improper payments, eliminates fraudulent billing, or enhances data verification to ensure eligibility for applicable benefits.

(Under current law, reconciliation bills are considered by Congress using expedited legislative procedures that prevent a filibuster and restrict amendments in the Senate.)</summary>
</bill>
