<bill session="117" type="h" number="9341" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IRS Funding Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide accountability for funding provided to the Internal Revenue Service and the Department of the Treasury under Public Law 117-169.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRS Funding Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5100" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-15T15:53:11Z" status="Introduced in House">IRS Funding Accountability Act 

This bill delays for a 60-day period funding for the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) enforcement activities enacted by the Inflation Reduction Act (except for eliminating return processing backlogs and reducing call wait times) until an annual spending plan for such activities is submitted to the congressional tax and appropriation committees. Congress may enact a joint resolution of disapproval of the spending plan before the end of the 60-day period requiring the IRS to submit a new spending plan.

The IRS and the Department of the Treasury must make quarterly reports to the committees on expenditures for enforcement activities. The bill requires reductions in appropriations to the IRS for any failure to submit required reports.</summary>
</bill>
