<bill session="118" type="s" number="2847" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting American Food Producers from Russia&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Market Distortions Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting American Food Producers from Russia&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Market Distortions Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the importation of agricultural products, raw materials, and food from the Russian Federation if the Russian Federation prohibits the importation of such products, materials, and food from the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-18T16:05:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting American Food Producers from Russia's Market Distortions Act of 2023

This bill prohibits the importation of certain agricultural products, raw materials, and food from Russia if the Russian government prohibits the importation of these products from the United States.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the importation of Russian products that are classified under chapters 1-24 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule (which includes, among other products, live animals, animal and vegetable products, seafood, prepared foodstuffs, and beverages). Further, the bill prohibits federal funds from being obligated or expended for the procurement of these products from Russia.

These prohibitions shall terminate on the date on which the President determines and certifies to Congress that (1) the Russian government has terminated its prohibition on the importation of these products from the United States, (2) the Russian government and its proxies have withdrawn all military and paramilitary forces from Ukraine, and (3) the President has received credible commitments from the Russian government that it will not engage in hostile action against Ukraine in the future.</summary>
</bill>
