<bill session="109" type="s" number="2348" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:52Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nuclear Release Notice Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require a licensee to notify the Atomic Energy Commission, and the State and county in which a facility is located, whenever there is an unplanned release of fission products in excess of allowable limits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nuclear Release Notice Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Release Notice Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000167"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2006-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2006-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1581-1582"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-347. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="637">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 637.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4825" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-27T19:08:04Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Nuclear Release Notice Act of 2006 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to promulgate regulations requiring certain civilian nuclear power facilities to provide notice of any release to the environment of fission products or other radioactive substances.

Directs the NRC to consider requiring licensees of such facilities to give notice of any release: (1) within 24 hours after it happens; (2) to the NRC and state and county governments in which the facility is located if an unplanned release exceeds allowable limits for normal operation, is not subject to more stringent NRC requirements or enters into the environment, and may cause drinking water sources to exceed a maximum radioactive contaminant level; and (3) to such state and county governments if the unplanned release reaches the environment by a path otherwise not allowed or recognized by the facility's operating license but falls within the allowable limits for normal operation.

Declares that this Act does not provide to any state or county that receives such notice regulatory jurisdiction over a licensee of such a facility.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-347</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
