<bill session="109" type="s" number="1883" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:48Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Empowering More Property Owners With Enhanced Rights Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 to assist property owners and Federal agencies in resolving disputes relating to private property.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EMPOWER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering More Property Owners With Enhanced Rights Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2005-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2005-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11479-11480"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-20T19:17:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Empowering More Property Owners With Enhanced Rights Act of 2005 or EMPOWER Act - Amends the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 to require a federal agency when acquiring real property to provide to a property owner with: (1) at the beginning of the negotiation process, the current contact information for the Office of the Property Rights Ombudsperson; (2) a description of available mediation and other dispute resolution alternatives; and (3) in specified cases, a copy of the appraisal.

 Establishes the Office of the Property Rights Ombudsperson to: (1) at the request of a federal or state agency, advise the agency with respect to actions that may affect property rights; (2) advise private property owners that have a legitimate potential or actual claim against a federal agency involving property rights; and (3) if appropriate, and if requested by a private property owner, mediate or arrange arbitration for disputes between private property owners and federal agencies that involve property rights, eminent domain, or relocation assistance under the Act.

Sets forth requirements for arbitration and mediation requested by a private property owner and arranged by the Property Rights Ombudsperson.

Authorizes the establishment of other federal and state offices of property rights ombudspersons.</summary>
</bill>
