<bill session="117" type="h" number="1267" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:12Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prevent Corrupting Foreign Influence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit corrupt foreign influence over the President, the Vice President, and their immediate family members, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Corrupting Foreign Influence Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001193"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Gabon"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-04T01:21:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Corrupting Foreign Influence Act

This bill establishes new statutory restrictions on the receipt or acceptance of foreign gifts or things of value by the President, Vice President, or their immediate family members.

First, the bill creates a new criminal offense to generally prohibit the President, Vice President, an immediate family member of the President or Vice President, or an entity in which any of these individuals has at least a 50% ownership interest from accepting or receiving anything of value from a foreign state or entity. A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to five years, or both.

 Second, the bill broadens the application of existing foreign gift restrictions on federal employees. Current law generally prohibits federal employees (including the President and Vice President) from receiving or soliciting foreign gifts. This bill further extends the restrictions to cover immediate family members of the President or Vice President. An immediate family member is a parent, parent-in-law, child, or sibling.</summary>
</bill>
