<bill session="116" type="h" number="6689" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accountability for Acting Officials Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to modify the provisions of that title relating to the Federal Vacancies Reform Act of 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability for Acting Officials Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2020-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4880" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8363" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-04T18:26:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Accountability for Acting Officials Act

This bill makes a series of changes with respect to the appointment, tenure, and qualifications of acting officials of executive agencies.

Among other things, the bill specifies that, for a position that requires an appointment by the President (by and with the advice and consent of the Senate),

 the first assistant to the office may temporarily fill the position only if the individual has been the first assistant for at least 30 days during the preceding year; an officer or employee of the agency who is directed by the President to temporarily fill the position may only do so if the officer or employee has served at the agency for at least the entire preceding year (rather than 90 days); and an individual who is a presidential appointee and is directed by the President to temporarily fill the position, including an acting Inspector General, must possess the requisite qualifications for the position as provided by law or regulation. The bill also limits the tenure of acting heads of agencies to no more than 120 days (rather than 210 days).</summary>
</bill>
