<bill session="118" type="s" number="3959" updated="2025-11-19T03:30:21Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation Security Screening Modernization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Security Screening Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Transportation Security Screening Modernization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Transportation Security Screening Modernization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">Transportation Security Screening Modernization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Transportation Security Administration to streamline the enrollment processes for individuals applying for a Transportation Security Administration security threat assessment for certain programs, including the Transportation Worker Identification Credential and Hazardous Materials Endorsement Threat Assessment programs of the Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2024-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2024-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2024-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2024-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-01">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-08-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="484">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 484.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6695-6696" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6695-6696" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-22T13:02:33-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-22T13:14:25-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T14:49:04-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Green (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T14:49:17-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7345-7348" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T14:49:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3959.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2024-12-18T14:58:15-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7345-7346" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T14:58:17-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-12-23" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-202" type="public" datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-202.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5840" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-03T19:50:43Z" status="Public Law">Transportation Security Screening Modernization Act&#160;of 2024

This act directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to streamline the&#160;process for individuals applying for or renewing enrollment in multiple security threat assessment (STA) programs, in particular the Transportation Worker Identification Credential (TWIC) and&#160;the Hazardous Materials Endorsement (HME) programs.

Among other things, the TSA must

permit an individual to enroll at a&#160;TSA-authorized enrollment center once and use the application, as well as information generated by TSA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s vetting, to enroll in any other programs;permit an individual to enroll in more than one STA program at the same time for a single fee that is less than the combined fee for applying to the same programs separately;provide for a streamlined and expeditious renewal process; andprovide states the expiration dates for each individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s&#160;STA to ensure commercial driver's licenses include an&#160;individual's current HME status.Additionally, the TSA must publish on its website information relating to the streamlining of the enrollment system.

If the TSA determines it is necessary to implement these changes through rulemaking, the act provides for an expedited rulemaking process.

Further, the Government Accountability Office (GAO) must audit the administration of security threat programs by the TSA and the states, including redundancies and duplications in the costs and administration of the programs. The GAO must submit a report on the audit to the TSA and Congress with recommendations for improvements to these programs. The TSA must implement the GAO recommendations and provide Congress with a written notification detailing and justifying the implementation process.</summary>
</bill>
