<bill session="117" type="h" number="175" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Penalty Free Withdrawal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand the availability of penalty-free distributions to unemployed individuals from retirement plans.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Penalty Free Withdrawal Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2021-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2021-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2021-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-09T14:06:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Penalty Free Withdrawal Act

This bill expands the exceptions in the Internal Revenue Code that permit penalty-free distributions to unemployed individuals from retirement plans.

The 10% additional tax on early distributions from retirement plans does not apply to an individual after separation from employment if (1) the individual has received federal or state unemployment compensation for 26 consecutive weeks or, if less, the maximum period available under state law; and (2) the distributions are made during the year or the succeeding year in which the compensation is paid.

The exception is limited to the lesser of (1) $50,000 from all plans of the individual over a one-year period, or (2) the greater of $10,000 or one-half of the fair market value of the individual's retirement plans and the nonforfeitable portion of the individual's defined contribution plans.

The exception does not apply to distributions that are (1) included in the existing exception for distributions to unemployed individuals for health insurance premiums, or (2) are made after the individual has been employed for at least 60 days after the separation.</summary>
</bill>
