<bill session="116" type="s" number="4050" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:10Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Health Emergency Production Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Emergency Production Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to use authorities under the Defense Production Act of 1950 to prioritize contracts necessary to promote pandemic preparedness and response, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2020-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-03T18:36:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Health Emergency Production Act of 2020

This bill modifies the administration of the Defense Production Act of 1950 and requires reporting on the use of authorities under the act during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency. (That act confers upon the President a broad set of authorities to influence domestic industry in order to provide essential materials and goods needed for the national defense.)

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must require companies to prioritize the fulfillment of federal contracts or orders necessary for pandemic preparedness and response upon finding that (1) a material is essential to the public health, and (2) public health needs cannot be met through normal distribution channels. HHS must also establish, within the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, an office responsible for Defense Production Act of 1950 activities.

Other changes include (1) eliminating a requirement to transfer any balance in excess of $750 million from the Defense Production Act Fund to the General Fund of the Department of the Treasury, and (2) enabling personnel to rotate between the Office of the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Industrial Policy and specified components of HHS.

With respect to reporting, the Defense Production Act Committee must report general information concerning the use of Defense Production Act of 1950 authorities, and the Office of the Inspector General for the Department of Agriculture must report on the use of such authorities specifically with respect to the operations of meat processing facilities, during the COVID-19 emergency.</summary>
</bill>
