<bill session="116" type="h" number="8385" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Taxpayer Protection Program to provide forgivable loans to State, territory, Tribal, and local governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000585"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-16T13:41:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Taxpayer Protection Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to establish the Taxpayer Protection Program to provide forgivable loans to state, territory, tribal, and local governments to cover revenue losses caused by the COVID-19 pandemic and for other specified purposes.

Specifically, loan amounts received under this bill may be used (1) to cover revenue losses caused by business interruptions, unemployment, or other economic hardship directly caused by the COVID-19 pandemic; and (2) for infrastructure or essential government service expenditures, including all general operating expenses. However, they may not be used for the service of any debt obligation or unfunded liability for employee retirement benefits.

The bill permits loan forgiveness if a state or local government meets specified requirements, such as a state having a truly balanced budget, sufficient rainy-day funds, and sound pension funds (i.e., pension funds that are based on generally accepted actuarial principles and that meet other specified requirements).</summary>
</bill>
