<bill session="116" type="h" number="363" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REBUILD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to authorize assignment to States of Federal agency environmental review responsibilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REBUILD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Environmental Barriers to Unified Infrastructure and Land Development Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-06T17:29:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Reducing Environmental Barriers to Unified Infrastructure and Land Development Act of 2019 Act or the REBUILD Act 

 This bill authorizes (1) the assignment to states of federal environmental review responsibilities under relevant federal environmental laws for projects funded by, carried out by, or subject to approval by federal agencies; and (2) states to assume all or part of those responsibilities.

Each responsible federal official who is authorized to assign such responsibility must promulgate regulations that establish requirements relating to information required to be contained in state applications to assume those responsibilities.

 An official may approve an application only if (1) public notice requirements have been met, (2) the state has the capability to assume the responsibilities, and (3) the head of the state agency having primary jurisdiction over the projects enters into a written agreement with an official to assume the responsibilities and to maintain the financial resources necessary to carry them out.

The officials must audit state compliance with federal laws for which responsibilities are assumed. The officials may terminate the responsibilities assigned to states after providing notice to states of any noncompliance and an opportunity to take corrective action.</summary>
</bill>
