<amendment session="110" chamber="s" number="207" updated="2022-02-03T05:24:48Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2007-01-25">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000243"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-01-25"/>
  <description>To express the sense of the Senate that Congress should repeal the 1993 tax increase on Social Security benefits and eliminate wasteful spending, such as spending on unnecessary tax loopholes, in order to fully offset the cost of such repeal and avoid forcing taxpayers to pay substantially more interest to foreign creditors.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2007-01-25" how="roll" result="pass" roll="27">
      <text>Amendment SA 207 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 0. Record Vote Number: 27.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 207 proposed by Senator Baucus to Amendment SA 100. (consideration: CR S1160-1161, S1162; text: CR S1160) To express the sense of the Senate that Congress should repeal the 1993 tax increase on Social Security benefits and eliminate wasteful spending, such as spending on unnecessary tax loopholes, in order to fully offset the cost of such repeal and avoid forcing taxpayers to pay substantially more interest to foreign creditors.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 207 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 0. Record Vote Number: 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 207 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 0. Record Vote Number: 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 207 proposed by Senator Baucus to Amendment SA 100.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1160-1161, S1162" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1160" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
