<bill session="117" type="h" number="585" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Apprenticeship Program National Scorecard Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to provide for data collection and dissemination of information regarding programs under the national apprenticeship system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apprenticeship Program National Scorecard Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000614"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H425-426"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="447" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-16T16:14:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Apprenticeship Program National Scorecard Act

This bill provides for data collection and dissemination of information regarding certain registered apprenticeship programs, youth apprenticeship programs, and pre-apprenticeship programs under the national apprenticeship system.

Specifically, the Department of Labor is required to (1) establish and support a single information technology infrastructure to support data collection and reporting from state apprenticeship agencies and offices, grantees, program sponsors, and program administrators under the national apprenticeship system; and (2) provide that such infrastructure best meets the needs of the system's stakeholders reporting data to Labor or state apprenticeship agencies, including through technical and financial assistance to ensure reporting systems are equipped to report into a single information technology infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
