<bill session="117" type="s" number="4919" updated="2023-09-12T14:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting the Border from Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Border from Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Protecting the Border from Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require an interagency strategy for creating a unified posture on counter-unmanned aircraft systems (C-UAS) capabilities and protections at international borders of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2022-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-279.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="678">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 678.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T13:47:50Z" status="Reported to Senate">Protecting the Border from Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to work with the Department of Justice (DOJ), the Federal Aviation Administration, and the Department of Defense to develop a strategy for a unified posture on counter-unmanned aircraft systems capabilities and protections at certain facilities at or near a U.S. international border (generally, facilities or assets considered high-risk or a potential target and that are related to certain DHS or DOJ missions).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-279</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
