<bill session="118" type="s" number="1019" updated="2025-11-19T04:22:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CASES Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CASES Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corruption in Argentina Stymied by Enforcing Sanctions Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to certain officials of Argentina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3067" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-08T21:12:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Corruption in Argentina Stymied by Enforcing Sanctions Act of 2023 or the CASES Act of 2023

This bill requires sanctions to be imposed on five specified Argentinian public officials if such individuals meet the criteria for such sanctions.

The specified Argentinian officials are Cristina Elisabet Fernandez de Kirchner, Maximo Kirchner, Juan Martin Mena, Oscar Isidro Jose Parrilli, and Carlos Alberto Zannini.

The bill requires the Department of State to submit an annual report to Congress containing (1) a description of each person's assets, including the net worth of immediate family members; and (2) a determination as to whether each person meets the criteria for the imposition of visa- and property-blocking sanctions related to corruption or human rights violations.

The President must impose such sanctions on any of these individuals whom the President determines meets the sanctions criteria.</summary>
</bill>
