<bill session="111" type="h" number="1264" updated="2022-02-03T06:10:43Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Multiple Peril Insurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Multiple Peril Insurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Multiple Peril Insurance Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to provide for the national flood insurance program to make available multiperil coverage for damage resulting from windstorms or floods, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000074"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001252" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000420" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001244" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001074" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000602" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001161" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2009-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001176" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2009-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-19">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 111-551.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-19" calendar="Union" number="315">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 315.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T17:09:33-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1549 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1264 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22T16:10:56-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1549 passed House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="hr" number="1549" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-08-31T18:24:25Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

 Multiple Peril Insurance Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require the national flood insurance program to enable the purchase of multiperil coverage and optional separate windstorm coverage to protect against loss resulting from physical damage or loss of real or related personal property located in the United States.

Defines windstorm as any hurricane, tornado, cyclone, typhoon, or other wind event.

Restricts multiperil coverage to areas (or their subdivisions) where an appropriate public body has adopted adequate mitigation measures, including effective enforcement provisions, which the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) finds are consistent with the criteria for construction described in the International Code Council building codes relating to wind mitigation.

Prohibits provision of multiperil coverage to any structure (or related personal property ) covered, at any time, by flood insurance under the Act.

Requires maintenance of flood insurance coverage under this Act as a prerequisite to windstorm coverage of any structure (or related personal property). States that separate windstorm coverage only covers losses from physical damages from windstorm.

Prescribes the nature and terms of coverage and actuarial rates.

(Sec. 3) Prohibits duplicative coverage.

(Sec. 4) Prohibits new multiperil coverage for property declared by a governmental authority to be in violation of state or local laws, regulations, or ordinances intended to reduce windstorm damage.

(Sec. 5) Instructs the Director to: (1) carry out studies and investigations to determine measures for wind hazard prevention; and (2) provide technical assistance to state, interstate, and local governmental agencies to encourage adoption and enforcement of laws, regulations, and ordinances relating to the orderly development and use of areas subject to damage from windstorm risks, and zoning building codes, building permits, and subdivision and other building restrictions for such areas.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-551</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
