<bill session="117" type="hr" number="1375" updated="2023-01-31T04:45:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Recognizing the history between Haiti and France, acknowledging Haiti as the first free Black nation in the Americas, recognizing how the aftermath of their freedom is directly related to their impoverished state today, and realizing the importance of this history.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the history between Haiti and France, acknowledging Haiti as the first free Black nation in the Americas, recognizing how the aftermath of their freedom is directly related to their impoverished state today, and realizing the importance of this history.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2022-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-30T18:03:23Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution recognizes the long-forgotten history between Haiti and France and its direct impact on the economic and social challenges Haiti faces today.

The resolution welcomes Haitian immigrants presently in the United States and individuals seeking to immigrate to the United States to contribute to the health, safety, diversity, and prosperity of the United States.

The resolution expresses the commitment of Congress and relevant executive agencies to promote smart and just immigration policy for Haitian immigrants presently in the United States, their families, and individuals seeking to immigrate to the United States in the future.

The resolution also commits to working with international organizations to administer assistance and policies that continue to help Haiti's economic and social recovery.</summary>
</bill>
