<bill session="117" type="s" number="1161" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Quantum Network Infrastructure and Workforce Development Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote focused research and innovation in quantum communications and quantum network infrastructure to bolster internet security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quantum Network Infrastructure and Workforce Development Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1985-1987" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1260" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-15T17:05:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Quantum Network Infrastructure and Workforce Development Act of 2021

This bill supports research in quantum networking and communications.

The Quantum Networking Working Group within the Subcommittee on Quantum Information Science of the National Science and Technology Council shall submit to Congress a report that has a plan for the advancement of quantum networking and communications technology in the United States.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall carry out research to facilitate the development and standardization of quantum networking and communications technologies and applications.

The Department of Energy shall supplement the Energy Sciences Network User Facility with dedicated quantum network infrastructure to advance development of quantum networking and communications technology.

The National Science Foundation (NSF) shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to study ways of supporting the next generation of quantum leaders.

The NSF shall prioritize the better integration of quantum information science and engineering into the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) curriculum for each grade level from kindergarten through grade 12.

The NSF shall carry out the Next Generation Quantum Leaders Pilot Program to provide funding for the education and training of the next generation of students in the fundamental principles of quantum mechanics.</summary>
</bill>
