<bill session="116" type="s" number="4577" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require online enrollment for the PreCheck Program of the Transportation Security Administration.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require online enrollment for the PreCheck Program of the Transportation Security Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2020-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-13T17:11:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to ensure that private sector entities administering the TSA PreCheck Program provide a secure end-to-end online web or mobile application enrollment capability that leverages electronic technologies to remotely capture biometrics and validate identity documents. (The PreCheck Program allows pre-approved passengers to use expedited security lanes at passenger screening checkpoints in airports.)

The TSA must also ensure that any individual who enrolled in the PreCheck Program under the Universal Enrollment Services program is eligible for renewal of the individual's enrollment under the renewal process of the Universal Enrollment Services program.

The Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice must enter into a memorandum of understanding with respect to cooperatively evaluating and approving a capability for remote collection of biometric information from a mobile device and associated vetting of individuals' criminal histories for trusted traveler enrollment programs of the TSA.

The TSA must submit a plan for the implementation of the new online enrollment capability that (1) identifies appropriate security and privacy protections; and (2) includes a strategy for ensuring that the private sector entities administering the PreCheck Program operate locations for enrollment that are geographically dispersed from locations required for enrollment under the Universal Enrollment Services program, or otherwise increase enrollment beyond existing capabilities and current geographic markets.</summary>
</bill>
