<bill session="111" type="h" number="5785" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:55Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mine Worker Safety Hotline Accessibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Mine Safety and Health Administration to provide to mine operators for distribution to miners wallet cards and similar devices containing the phone number of the Administration's national hazard reporting phone number.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mine Worker Safety Hotline Accessibility Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-23T22:02:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Mine Worker Safety Hotline Accessibility Act - Amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to require: (1) the Secretary of Labor to provide all coal and other mine operators plastic wallet cards, refrigerator magnets, and other similar devices containing the toll-free telephone number and appropriate website address of the national hazard reporting hotline; and (2) each operator to ensure that each miner and miner community receives such devices in order to facilitate the reporting of mine accidents, incidents, injuries, illnesses, possible violations of such Act or of mandatory health and safety standards or plans, or other mine safety and health concerns.</summary>
</bill>
