<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1117" updated="2022-02-03T05:20:35Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5959" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-07-16T15:06:38-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000627"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-07-16"/>
  <description>Amendment instructed the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency to submit a report on the activities of the intelligence community with regard to human rights violations of the Argentine military government from the mid-1970's until the mid-1980's. The amendment also required the inclusion of a compilation of declassified documents and consented to the inclusion of a classified annex in the report.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 7 printed in House Report 110-759 to instruct the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency to submit a report on the activities of the intelligence community with regard to human rights violations of the Argentine military government from the mid-1970's until the mid-1980's. The amendment also instructs the inclusion of a compilation of declassified documents and consents to the inclusion of a classified annex in the report.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-07-16T15:06:38-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Hinchey amendment (A007) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T15:00:36-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Hinchey.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6623-6624" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6623" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T15:00:36-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Hinchey.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6623-6624" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6623" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T15:06:38-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16T15:06:38-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Hinchey amendment (A007) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
