<bill session="117" type="s" number="3224" updated="2022-12-30T02:34:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supply Chain Emergency Response Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supply Chain Emergency Response Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a program to provide grants to owners of cargo vessels being rerouted from the western seaboard of the United States through the Panama Canal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5925" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-28T13:58:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supply Chain Emergency Response Act

This bill directs the Maritime Administration to establish a program to provide grants to certain owners of cargo vessels to cover toll costs associated with rerouting cargo vessels from ports along the western seaboard of the United States through the Panama Canal to ports along the Gulf of Mexico and the eastern seaboard of the United States.

To receive a grant, an owner of a cargo vessel shall submit documentation that such owner intends to reroute a cargo vessel and has the corresponding docking agreements.

The bill allows states and localities to use COVID-19 relief funds for costs related to rerouting cargo vessels.

Any marine terminal operator that is located along the western seaboard of the United States, and subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, may not collect port fees from a recipient of a grant who has rerouted a cargo vessel from such port due to the inability of such port to receive such vessel.

Any individual who is a member of the Chinese Communist Party or any company owned, in whole or in part, by the Chinese Communist Party may not receive a grant under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
