<bill session="118" type="s" number="1703" updated="2025-11-19T03:06:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PACE Part D Choice Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PACE Part D Choice Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure Medicare-only PACE program enrollees have a choice of prescription drug plans under Medicare part D.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3549" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3950" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8503" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-20T15:56:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">PACE Part D Choice Act of 2023

This bill allows Medicare-only beneficiaries who are enrolled in Programs of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly (PACE) to choose prescription drug plans that are not operated by PACE. (PACE is a program under Medicare and Medicaid that provides in-home and community services for certain individuals as an alternative to nursing home care.)

Specifically, the bill allows PACE enrollees who are Medicare (but not Medicaid) beneficiaries to choose a prescription drug plan that is not a Medicare Advantage plan or operated by PACE and for which annual out-of-pocket costs and federal subsidies are equal to or less than that under the applicable PACE prescription drug plan. The bill also allows for disenrollment from a chosen plan upon a change in medication or demonstration of an unexpected increase in out-of-pocket costs.

PACE programs must conduct outreach, monitor data, and coordinate benefits with respect to such options.</summary>
</bill>
