<bill session="119" type="h" number="152" updated="2025-09-17T14:47:37Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13T19:03:56-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-01-13T19:03:56-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Disaster Recovery Reform Act of 2018 to develop a study regarding streamlining and consolidating information collection and preliminary damage assessments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001103" joined="2025-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2025-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13T16:38:07-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Graves moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13T16:38:15-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H100-101" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13T16:38:16-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 152.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13T16:44:16-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13T18:56:38-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H107-108" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="9" datetime="2025-01-13T19:03:56-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 5 (Roll no. 9).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H100-101" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13T19:03:58-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4669" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-05T21:57:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to streamline disaster information collection, convene a working group on preliminary damage assessments, and provide a report to Congress.

FEMA must (1) conduct a study and develop a plan under which the collection of information from disaster assistance applicants and grantees will be made less burdensome, duplicative, and time consuming for applicants and grantees; and (2) develop a plan for the regular collection and reporting of information on federal disaster assistance awarded.

Additionally, not later than two years after enactment of the bill, FEMA must convene a working group on a regular basis to (1) identify potential areas of duplication or fragmentation in preliminary damage assessments after disaster declarations; (2)&#160;determine the applicability of having one federal agency make the assessments for all agencies; and (3) identify potential emerging technologies, such as unmanned aircraft systems (i.e., drones), to expedite the administration of preliminary damage assessments.

FEMA must submit a comprehensive report on the plans for streamlining and consolidating information collection and the findings and recommendations of the working group to Congress with a briefing. The report must be made available to the public and posted on FEMA's website.</summary>
</bill>
