<bill session="108" type="s" number="1612" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-04">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Technology Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a technology, equipment, and information transfer within the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Homeland Security Technology Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Technology Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2003-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2003-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2003-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2003-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2003-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2003-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001141" joined="2003-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2003-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2003-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11421"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="416">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 416.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>By Senator Collins from Committee on Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 108-217.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-02-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S596-597" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S596-597" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-02-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-06T12:02:19-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-06T12:21:30-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3644" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-03T19:47:55Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Homeland Security Technology Improvement Act of 2004 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include, as an element of the program to encourage technological innovation in facilitating the mission of the Department of Homeland Security, the establishment of a multi-agency homeland security technology, equipment, and information transfer program to allow for the transfer of technology, equipment, and information to State and local law enforcement agencies. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, in developing such program, to: (1) in close cooperation with the Office for Domestic Preparedness, conduct research and development of new technologies, surveys and reviews of available appropriate technologies, and tests, evaluations, and demonstrations of new and available technologies that significantly improve the capability of law enforcement agencies in countering terrorist threats; (2) in support of such activities, consult with State and local law enforcement agencies and others, work with the National Institute for Standards and Technology and any other office or agency, and enter into agreements and coordinate with other Federal agencies to maximize the effectiveness of the technologies, equipment, and information; and (3) provide a comprehensive list of available technologies, equipment, and information to the Office of Domestic Preparedness, which shall administer the technology transfer program.

 Requires the Director of the Office for Domestic Preparedness, in coordination with the Under Secretary, to: (1) make counterterrorism technology, equipment, and information available to State and local law enforcement agencies based on the list of available technologies, equipment, and information and the needs identified by the technology transfer advisory committee established by this Act; (2) consult with State and local law enforcement agencies; (3) accept applications from State and local law enforcement agencies that wish to acquire such technologies, equipment, and information to improve their homeland security capabilities and review such applications with the advisory committee; and (4) transfer the approved technology, equipment, and information and provide training to the State or local law enforcement agencies to implement such technology equipment, and information.



Allows the Director, upon approval of the Secretary, to expand the program to first responders other than law enforcement agencies and to revise the advisory committee accordingly.

Limits expenditures for administrative costs to ten percent of the program budget.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-217</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
