<bill session="117" type="h" number="987" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To establish a grant program for domestic maritime workforce training and education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program for domestic maritime workforce training and education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000587"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-16T16:31:34Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill authorizes the Department of Transportation (DOT) to award maritime career training grants to institutions of higher education and postsecondary vocational institutions for the purpose of developing, offering, or improving educational or career training programs for American workers related to the maritime workforce.

Each awarded grant may not exceed $20 million.

DOT must award grants based on

 a determination of the merits of the grant proposal submitted by the institution of higher education or postsecondary vocational institution to develop, offer, or improve maritime educational or career training programs to be made available to workers; an evaluation of the likely employment opportunities available to workers who complete a maritime educational or career training program that the institution proposes to develop, offer, or improve; an evaluation of prior demand for training programs by workers in the community served by the institution, as well as the availability and capacity of existing maritime training programs to meet future demand for training programs; and any prior designation of the institution as a Center of Excellence for Domestic Maritime Workforce Training and Education.</summary>
</bill>
