<bill session="118" type="s" number="1136" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Not One More Inch or Acre Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Not One More Inch or Acre Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the President to take such actions as may be necessary to prohibit the purchase of public or private real estate located in the United States by citizens and entities of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee)"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="344" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T20:48:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Not One More Inch or Acre Act

This bill requires the President to take actions as necessary to prohibit certain individuals and entities associated with China from purchasing real estate located in the United States and to mandate the sale of such property in certain circumstances.

The individuals and entities prohibited from purchasing U.S. real estate include (1) Chinese citizens, (2) entities acting on behalf of the Chinese government or the Chinese Communist Party, and (3) foreign individuals or entities acting on behalf of a Chinese citizen. Entities subject to this prohibition are generally those

Additionally, if the President determines that the ownership of U.S. real estate by these individuals and entities poses a national security risk, the President must take actions as necessary to require the sale of the property.

The bill also modifies an existing civil penalty for failing to satisfy a reporting requirement relating to a foreign individual or entity that acquires or transfers an interest in U.S. agricultural land. Under this bill, the civil penalty for failing to report the required information to the Department of Agriculture must be at least 10% of the fair market value of the relevant interest in agricultural land.</summary>
</bill>
