<bill session="108" type="s" number="1892" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:30Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide information and advice to pension plan participants to assist them in making decisions regarding the investment of their pension plan assets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide information and advice to pension plan participants to assist them in making decisions regarding the investment of their pension plan assets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15190" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Defined benefit pension plans"/>
    <term name="Defined contribution plans"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Retirement"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-13T20:54:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for information and advice to assist pension plan participants in making decisions regarding the investment of their pension plan assets under defined contribution plans that are individual account plans (IAPs) (401(k) and similar plans) which hold regularly tradable employment securities and permit participants or beneficiaries to exercise control over assets in the account.

Requires the plan administrator to include in the account statement a notice that the account may be overinvested in employer securities and real property, whenever assets consisting of employer securities and real property exceed 50 percent of total IAP assets. Excludes from such notice requirement: (1) assets held through pooled investment vehicles; and (2) employee stock ownership plans (ESOPs) that have no contributions subject to section 401 (k) or (m) of the Internal Revenue Code (IRC). Amends IRC to limit to $1,500 the aggregate amount which may be excluded from gross income with respect to qualified retirement planning services (QRPS) provided to any individual during a taxable year. Prohibits exclusion of any such amount if the modified adjusted gross income of the taxpayer exceeds $100,000 ($200,000 for married individuals filing a joint return). Provides that no amount (constructive receipt) shall be included in the gross income of any employee solely because the employee may choose between any QRPS provided by a qualified investment advisor and compensation which would otherwise be includable in the employee's gross income. Applies such provision to highly compensated employees only if such choice is available on substantially the same terms to each member of the group of employees normally provided education and information regarding the employer's qualified employer plan.</summary>
</bill>
