<bill session="110" type="s" number="2310" updated="2023-01-11T14:50:58Z">
  <state datetime="2007-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeowners' Defense Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Catastrophic Risks Consortium and a National Homeowners' Insurance Stabilization Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowners' Defense Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001162" joined="2008-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2007-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2008-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3355" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Casualty insurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-03-03T21:18:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeowners' Defense Act of 2007 - Establishes the National Catastrophe Risk Consortium as a nonprofit, nonfederal entity to: (1) maintain an inventory of catastrophe risk obligations held by state reinsurance funds, and state residual insurance market entities; (2) issue, on a conduit basis, securities and other financial instruments linked to catastrophe risks insured or reinsured through Consortium members; and (3) act as a centralized repository of state risk information accessible by certain private-market participants.



Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to implement a national homeowners' insurance stabilization program to make liquidity loans and catastrophic loans to qualified reinsurance programs to: (1) ensure their solvency; (2) improve the availability and affordability of homeowners' insurance; (3) provide incentive for risk transfer to the private capital and reinsurance markets; and (4) spread the risk of catastrophic financial loss resulting from natural disasters and catastrophic events.





Authorizes the Secretary to establish and collect, from qualified and precertified reinsurance programs, a reasonable fee to offset expenses of the program.

Instructs the Secretary to require full repayment of all loans made under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
