<bill session="117" type="s" number="4567" updated="2022-12-29T18:48:40Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EAGLE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EAGLE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Access to Green cards for Legal Employment Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to eliminate the per-country numerical limitation for employment-based immigrants, to increase the per-country numerical limitation for family-sponsored immigrants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2022-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3648" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-02T19:16:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Equal Access to Green cards for Legal Employment Act of 2022 or the EAGLE Act of 2022

This bill modifies requirements related to employment-based visas and addresses related issues.

The bill increases the per-country cap on family-based immigrant visas from 7% of the total number of such visas available that year to 15% and eliminates the per-country cap for employment-based immigrant visas.

The bill establishes transition rules for employment-based visas such as (1) reserving a percentage of EB-2 (workers with advanced degrees or exceptional ability) and EB-3 (skilled and other workers) visas for individuals not from the two countries with the largest number of recipients of such visas, and (2) allotting a number of visas for professional nurses and physical therapists.

The bill imposes additional requirements on an employer seeking an H-1B visa, such as prohibiting (1) an employer from advertising that a position is only open to H-1B applicants or that H-1B applicants are preferred, and (2) certain employers from having more than half of their employees as nonimmigrant visa workers.

The Department of Labor shall create a publicly available website where an employer seeking an H-1B visa must post certain information about the open position.

The bill also expands Labor's authority to review and investigate H-1B applications for fraud or misrepresentations.

The bill also allows certain aliens to obtain lawful permanent resident status if the alien (1) is in the United States as a nonimmigrant, (2) has an approved immigrant visa petition, and (3) has waited at least two years for a visa.</summary>
</bill>
