<bill session="108" type="s" number="676" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">World Trade Organization Dispute Settlement Review Commission  Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a WTO Dispute Settlement Review Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">World Trade Organization Dispute Settlement Review Commission  Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2003-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2003-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4173"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4173-4174" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Veto"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-12-30T17:29:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">World Trade Organization Dispute Settlement Review Commission Act - Establishes the World Trade Organization Dispute Settlement Review Commission to review: (1) all reports of dispute settlement panels or the Appellate Body of the World Trade Organization (WTO) in proceedings initiated by other parties to the WTO that are adverse to the United States and that are adopted by the Dispute Settlement Body; and (2) upon the request of U.S. Trade Representative or specified congressional officials, any other report of a dispute settlement panel, or the Appellate Body that is adopted by the Dispute Settlement Body.

Requires the Commission, with respect to such reports that are adverse to the United States and adopted by the Dispute Settlement Body, to conduct a review and determine whether the panel or Appellate Body: (1) exceeded its authority or its terms of reference; (2) added to the obligations, or diminished U.S. rights under the Uruguay Round Agreement that is the subject of the report; (3) acted arbitrarily or capriciously, engaged in misconduct, or demonstrably departed from the procedures specified for panels and Appellate Bodies in the applicable Uruguay Round Agreement; and (4) deviated from the applicable standard of review, including in antidumping, countervailing duty, and other unfair trade remedy cases, the standard of review set forth in Article 17.6 of the Agreement on Implementation of Article VI of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), 1994. Requires the Commission, if it makes an affirmative determination about the action of a panel or an Appellate Body, to determine further whether the action materially affected the outcome of the report.</summary>
</bill>
