<bill session="116" type="s" number="1214" updated="2022-11-01T19:47:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Privacy Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Privacy Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish and protect individual and collective privacy rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-04T14:10:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Privacy Bill of Rights Act This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to establish rules concerning the collection of personal information that are intended to increase consumer privacy. Specifically, entities that collect, use, retain, or share information that could identify a particular individual must

 provide notice about how the personal information will be used; obtain express approval to collect and use the personal information and provide the ability to withdraw approval; upon request, provide access to, and the ability to correct or delete, retained personal information; ensure that depersonalized information is not restored in a way that makes an individual identifiable; not deny service based on an individual&#8217;s refusal to approve of the collection or use of that person&#8217;s information; not offer price incentives in exchange for approval of the collection of personal information; and not disclose personal information to a third party under a written contract unless the contract prohibits the third party from using the personal information for any reason other than performing the contracted service or from disclosing the personal information to another third party. The FTC also must limit the sale or disclosure of biometric data and prohibit the use of personal information in a discriminatory manner. Individuals may bring civil claims for alleged violations of these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
