<bill session="118" type="h" number="6910" updated="2024-11-22T21:31:35Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BACKING the 2013 Brussels Agreement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BACKING the 2013 Brussels Agreement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Backing the Agreed-upon Compromises by Kosovo Imposed by the Negotiated Guarantees of the 2013 Brussels Agreement</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit United States assistance from being made available before the implementation of conditions under the 2013 Brussels Agreement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000478"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-22T21:28:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Backing the Agreed-upon Compromises by Kosovo Imposed by the Negotiated Guarantees of the 2013 Brussels Agreement or the BACKING the 2013 Brussels Agreement Act

This bill limits U.S. assistance to Kosovo until certain conditions are met. Those conditions are

Kosovo implements the conditions required in the 2013 Brussels Agreement, including the creation of an association or Serb-majority municipalities;special police are removed from northern Kosovo;new mayoral elections are held in northern Kosovo;the seizure of the private property of Serbs in Kosovo is halted; andfreedom of political expression is respected and upheld for all ethnicities in Kosovo.The State Department shall report annually on the status of Kosovo Serbs and the progress made by Kosovo in meeting the conditions mentioned above.&#160;

(The 2013 Brussels Agreement provided the first formal basis for normalized relations between Serbia and Kosovo.)</summary>
</bill>
