<bill session="116" type="s" number="1760" updated="2022-11-01T06:47:28Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">UPDATE PURPA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UPDATE PURPA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Updating Purchase Obligations to Deploy Affordable Resources to Energy Markets Under PURPA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2019-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2019-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2019-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-09T19:06:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Updating Purchase Obligations to Deploy Affordable Resources to Energy Markets Under PURPA Act or the UPDATE PURPA Act

This bill modifies (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's (FERC) rules related to cogeneration and small power production facilities, (2) the mandatory purchase obligation for electric utility companies to purchase energy from certain facilities, and (3) the one-mile rule of FERC.

FERC must modify its rules regarding certain cogeneration and small power production facilities, including to require that such facilities are responsible for the costs of any facility or network upgrades associated with delivering power to its electric customers.

The bill authorizes electric utility companies to waive the mandatory purchase obligation if additional power is not required to meet customers' electricity needs.

The bill directs FERC to publish a final rule that allows any person or entity a rebuttable presumption to the one-mile rule. Under the one-mile rule, facilities are considered to be located at the same site as the facility for which qualification is sought if they are located within one mile of such facility. Specified factors must be taken into consideration by FERC when it determines whether two facilities are located at the same site.</summary>
</bill>
