<bill session="116" type="h" number="6867" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Waiver Flexibility Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide necessary flexibility under programs for federally assisted housing to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Waiver Flexibility Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2020-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-16T21:05:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing Waiver Flexibility Act of 2020

This bill addresses the administration and funding of certain housing assistance programs in relation to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) public health emergency.

The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) may waive requirements or specify alternative requirements related to the use of funds from the Housing Trust Fund and the self-help housing assistance program, except for requirements related to fair housing, nondiscrimination, labor standards, and the environment, if doing so is necessary to respond to the COVID-19 emergency. (The Housing Trust Fund provides grants to states for housing for low-income families, while the self-help housing assistance program provides grants to organizations that facilitate home ownership.)

Furthermore, funds previously made available for the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, a program that supports local efforts to revitalize public and HUD-assisted housing, shall remain available through FY2021.

Additionally, the bill invalidates the FY2020 request for applications for funding under the Continuum of Care program, which funds efforts to address homelessness. Instead, HUD shall distribute amounts for FY2020 based on the results of the competition for FY2019.</summary>
</bill>
