<bill session="117" type="h" number="4959" updated="2023-01-01T20:19:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the right to vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Right to Vote Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right to Vote Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2021-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2615" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5746" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-04T14:30:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Right to Vote Act

This bill addresses the right to vote in federal elections.

Specifically, the bill declares that every citizen of legal voting age shall have the right to vote in federal elections that is free from any burden on the time, place, or manner of voting.

In addition, the bill prohibits federal, state, and local governments from substantially impairing the ability to vote in federal elections unless the government action furthers an important and particularized governmental interest. Further, the bill specifies that a government may not diminish the ability to vote in federal elections unless the action uses the least restrictive means to achieve such an interest.

A violation of rights created by the bill may be challenged in district court, and a prevailing plaintiff may receive attorney fees. The bill outlines judicial review standards for challenges to voting practices.</summary>
</bill>
