<bill session="117" type="s" number="1776" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Artificial Intelligence for the Military Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement recommendations relating to military training on emerging technologies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Artificial Intelligence for the Military Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-08T19:52:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Artificial Intelligence for the Military Act of 2021

This bill requires the implementation of training and education related to emerging technologies and artificial intelligence for certain military personnel.

The bill requires expansion of the curriculum for military junior leader education to incorporate training material related to focuses that include problem definition and curation and a conceptual understanding of the artificial intelligence life cycle. Such training and education should include the use of existing artificial intelligence-enabled systems and tools.

The Department of Defense (DOD) must ensure that the curriculum for professional military education is revised in each of the military services to incorporate periodic courses on militarily significant emerging technologies.

DOD must establish a short course on emerging technologies for general and flag officers and senior executive-level civilian leaders. The course must be taught on an iterative, two-year cycle and address the most recent and relevant technologies and the application of these technologies to military and business outcomes in DOD.

DOD must ensure that the military services code appropriate billets to be filled by emerging technology-qualified officers and develop a process for qualification of officers in emerging technologies.

The process for qualifying officers for emerging technology-coded billets must be modeled on a streamlined version of the joint qualification process and may include credit for serving in emerging technology-focused (1) fellowships, (2) talent exchanges, (3) government positions, and (4) education courses.</summary>
</bill>
