<bill session="117" type="h" number="5289" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to provide adjustment assistance to firms adversely affected by reduced exports resulting from tariffs imposed as retaliation for United States tariff increases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Assistance for Firms Harmed by Tariffs on Exports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assistance for Firms Harmed by Tariffs on Exports Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-25T13:55:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Assistance for Firms Harmed by Tariffs on Exports Act

This bill expands the authority of the Department of Commerce to provide trade adjustment assistance (i.e., assistance provided to companies that are adversely affected by competing imported goods and services) to firms.

Specifically, Commerce may provide such assistance to a firm that has experienced a decrease in the export of the firm's articles or services as a result of tariffs imposed on such exports by a foreign country in response to U.S. tariffs imposed on the imports of that country. Such decrease must have contributed importantly to a decline in sales or production.

Under current law, Commerce may only provide such assistance to a firm upon a determination that increases of imports of articles or services like or directly competitive with the firm's articles or services contributed importantly to a decline in sales or production.</summary>
</bill>
