<bill session="119" type="h" number="897" updated="2025-07-01T11:06:18Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Aviation-Impacted Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation-Impacted Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Aviation Administration to provide funding for noise mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-21T12:39:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Aviation-Impacted Communities Act

This bill increases access to noise mitigation&#160;measures&#160;for aviation-impacted communities.&#160;Under the bill, an aviation-impacted community is a community that is located not more than one mile from any point at which a commercial or cargo jet route is 3,000 feet or less above ground level.

The bill expands noise mitigation program funding under the Airport Improvement Program to include aviation-impacted communities that are not currently within the 65 day-night average sound level (DNL) standard.

The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must conduct outreach to aviation-impacted communities to inform them of the opportunity to be a designated community. A designated community must form a community board to provide information to airport operators and the FAA concerning aviation impacts (e.g., aircraft noise).

A community board may petition the FAA to conduct a community assessment and, based on the assessment, the FAA must devise an action plan that alleviates or addresses the community&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s concerns.

In addition, the FAA must enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study and provide the FAA with a framework and diagnostic tool for conducting community assessments.

The FAA must provide grants for necessary noise mitigation in a designated community for residences, hospitals, nursing homes, adult or child day care centers, schools, and places of worship. Further, the FAA and airport operators must provide (1)&#160;noise mitigation grants for&#160;communities subject to significant frequency of overhead flights,&#160;and (2) noise mitigation for residences impacted by significant nighttime aircraft noise.</summary>
</bill>
