<bill session="117" type="h" number="5525" updated="2023-01-01T23:51:17Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Bank Secrecy Act to expand the scope and authorities of anti-money laundering safeguards under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ENABLERS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ENABLERS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Establishing New Authorities for Businesses Laundering and Enabling Risks to Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2021-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-25T17:08:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Establishing New Authorities for Businesses Laundering and Enabling Risks to Security Act or the ENABLERS Act

 This bill expands the definition of a financial institution for purposes of reporting suspicious transactions, anti-money laundering programs, and other related measures. Specifically, the bill expands this definition to include

 persons who provide investment advice for compensation; persons who trade in works of art, antiques, or collectibles; attorneys, law firms, or notaries involved in financial or related activity on behalf of another person; certain trusts and company service providers; certified public accountants and public accounting firms; persons engaged in the business of public relations, marketing, communications, or other similar services in such a manner as to provide another person anonymity or deniability; and persons engaged in the business of providing third-party payment services. Additionally, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network must establish a task force to develop a strategy to impose anti-money laundering safeguards and enforce requirements on certain professions.

 Finally, domestic title insurance companies must obtain, maintain, and report to the Department of the Treasury information on the beneficial owners of entities that purchase or sell residential or commercial real estate in transactions involving the domestic title insurance company.</summary>
</bill>
