<bill session="112" type="s" number="2834" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:29Z">
  <state datetime="2012-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Subsidized Stafford Loan Reduced Interest Rate Extension Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Subsidized Stafford Loan Reduced Interest Rate Extension Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to extend the reduced interest rate for Federal Direct Stafford Loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001268"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3826" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4053" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4628" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4816" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="5812" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1409" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2051" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2343" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2366" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-21T21:38:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Subsidized Stafford Loan Reduced Interest Rate Extension Act of 2012 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to make the 3.4% interest rate on Direct Stafford loans first disbursed to undergraduate students between July 1, 2011, and July 1, 2012, applicable to Direct Stafford loans first disbursed to undergraduate students between July 1, 2011, and July 1, 2013.

Improper Payments Elimination and Recovery Improvement&#160;Act of 2012 - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to: (1) identify, on an annual basis, a list of high-priority federal programs for greater levels of oversight and review of improper payments; (2)&#160;coordinate with&#160;agencies responsible for administering high-priority programs to establish semi-annual or quarterly targets and actions for reducing improper payments;&#160;and &#160;(3) provide guidance to agencies for improving estimates of improper payments.

Requires federal agencies to: (1) make quarterly reports to their Inspectors General on any high-dollar improper payments identified by such agencies, and (2) review prepayment and preaward procedures and available databases to determine program or award eligibility and prevent improper payments before releasing any federal funds.&#160; Establishes a Do Not Pay List based on information from databases maintained by the federal government, including&#160;the database of the Social Security Administration (SSA) reporting deaths of Social Security recipients.

Requires the Director to: (1) determine the current and historical rates and amounts of recovery of improper payments and targets for recovering improper payments, and (2) establish a plan for at least 10 Recovery Audit Contracting programs to identify and recover overpayments and underpayments in 10 agencies.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
