<bill session="108" type="s" number="1905" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:29Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide habitable living quarters for teachers, administrators, other school staff, and their households in rural areas of Alaska located in or near Alaska Native Villages.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2003-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15291"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15291-15292" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-16">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held in Anchorage, AK. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-468.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-414.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="806">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 806.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-07T22:31:25Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2004 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to provide funds to the Alaska Housing Finance Corporation to make grants or loans to a school district located within a qualified community for: (1) construction of new housing units within the community, and the purchase and rehabilitation of existing structures to be used as such; (2) rehabilitation or leasing of housing units within a qualified community and the purchase or lease of real property on which such housing units will be constructed, purchased, or rehabilitated; (3) repayment of a loan used for such purposes or any other activities normally associated with them; and (4) funding of any remaining costs not financed by loans or other sources of funding.

Defines qualified community as a home rule or general law city incorporated under the laws of Alaska, or an unincorporated community situated outside the city limits, which: (1) has a population of 6,500 or fewer individuals; (2) is situated within or near a Native Village that includes the Metlakatla Indian Community of the Annette Islands Reserve, as determined by the Corporation; and (3) is not connected by road (except the Alaska Marine Highway System or a road through Canada) or railroad to the municipality of Anchorage, Alaska.

Requires occupants of such housing units, with certain exceptions, to be teachers, administrators, other school staff, and members of their households.

Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Agriculture to carry out this Act from FY 2006 through 2015.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-414</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
