<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4006</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:08Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:08Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-12-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP Act</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>3401</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-05-24</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-04</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 672.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-03</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001135</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Burr, Richard [R-NC]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Burr</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName>Mauze</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000560</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Coburn, Tom [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>TOM</firstName>
        <lastName>COBURN</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-12-03</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug therapy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>HIV/AIDS</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prescription drugs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-12-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-01-10T19:09:56Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP Act or the ACCESS ADAP Act - Requires specified funds to be transferred to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) from discretionary amounts appropriated under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act that remain unobligated, to be obligated during the FY2010 grant period under the AIDS Drug Assistance Program to provide assistance in reducing waiting lists and to address other cost containment measures that state AIDS Drug Assistance Programs implement after January 1, 2009. Requires amounts transferred under this Act to be used by states in a manner consistent with their state programs.</p> <p> Requires the Secretary, in allocating such funds, to: (1) give special consideration to the total scope and the basis of a state's needs, including the total number of patients on a waiting list, eligibility requirements, and other cost containment measures; and (2) ensure that funds be used only to provide treatments to individuals who were eligible to participate in the state program on the date of enactment of this Act or who would have been eligible to participate in the state program&nbsp; but were not so eligible because of the implementation of cost-containment measures after January 1, 2009.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>ACCESS ADAP Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>ACCESS ADAP Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>ACCESS ADAP Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Addressing Cost Containment Measures To Ensure the Sustainability and Success of ADAP</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the use of unobligated discretionary stimulus dollars to address AIDS Drug Assistance Program waiting lists and other cost containment measures impacting State ADAP programs.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-12-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s4006rs/xml/BILLS-111s4006rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-12-04</actionDate>
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 672.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
