<bill session="119" type="h" number="204" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-21T15:01:53-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-01-21T15:01:53-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Accurately Counting Risk Elimination Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">ACRES Act</title>
    <title type="short">Accurately Counting Risk Elimination Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="short">ACRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurately Counting Risk Elimination Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACRES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior submit accurate reports regarding hazardous fuels reduction activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ACRES Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000165"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:49:31-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:49:56-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H244-246" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:49:58-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 204.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-01-21T15:01:53-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H244-245" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T15:01:57-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-18T18:57:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Accurately Counting Risk Elimination Solutions Act or the ACRES Act

This bill establishes requirements regarding&#160;reports&#160;about hazardous fuels reduction activities and&#160;standardized procedures for tracking data for hazardous fuels reduction. Hazardous fuels reduction activities means any vegetation management activities that reduce the risk of wildfire but excludes the award of contracts to conduct hazardous fuels reduction activities.

First, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior must include in the materials submitted in support of the President's budget each fiscal year a report on the number of acres of federal land on which such activities were carried out during the preceding year.

Next, USDA and Interior must implement standardized procedures for tracking data related to such activities. The standardized procedures must include

regular, standardized data reviews of the accuracy and timely input of data used to track hazardous fuels reduction activities;verification methods that validate whether such data accurately correlates to such activities;an analysis of the short- and long-term effectiveness of such activities on reducing the risk of wildfire; andfor hazardous fuels reduction activities that occur partially within the wildland-urban interface, methods to distinguish which acres are located within and which located outside the wildland-urban interface.Finally, the Government Accountability Office must (1) conduct a study on this bill's implementation, and (2) submit a report to Congress with the results of the study.</summary>
</bill>
