<bill session="110" type="s" number="914" updated="2023-01-11T19:45:48Z">
  <state datetime="2007-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the States (and subdivisions thereof), the District of Columbia, territories, and possessions of the United States to provide certain tax incentives to any person for economic development purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Economic Development Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Development Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2007-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2007-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2007-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2007-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-04-13T18:32:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Economic Development Act of 2007 - Authorizes any state to provide to any person for economic development purposes tax incentives that otherwise would be the cause or source of discrimination against interstate commerce under the Commerce Clause of the Constitution. Disqualifies any incentive that: (1) is dependent upon the state or country of incorporation, commercial domicile, or residence of an individual; (2) requires the recipient to acquire, lease, license, use, or provide services to property created in the state; (3) is reduced or eliminated as a result of an increase in out-of-state activity by the recipient or other person or as a result of such other person not having a taxable presence in the state; (4) results in loss of a compensating tax system, because the tax on interstate commerce exceeds the tax on intrastate commerce; (5) requires that other taxing jurisdictions offer reciprocal tax benefits; or (6) requires that a tax incentive earned with respect to one tax can only be used to reduce a tax burden for, or provide a tax benefit against, any other tax that is not imposed on apportioned interstate activities.</summary>
</bill>
