<bill session="119" type="h" number="356" updated="2025-05-28T15:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Prosecutor Home Rule Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Prosecutor Home Rule Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assign the responsibility for conducting prosecutions for violations of the laws of the District of Columbia to the head of a local prosecutor's office designated under local law of the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E22"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-28T15:45:48Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia Prosecutor Home Rule Act

This bill shifts the responsibility for prosecuting all violations of the laws, ordinances, and regulations of the District of Columbia (DC) to a local prosecutor's office.

Currently, the responsibility for prosecuting such violations is shared between DC and the federal government. Generally, the local Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia prosecutes crimes committed by juveniles and criminal violations of municipal regulations, and the federal&#160;U.S. Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia prosecutes all other crimes.

The bill also specifies that current employees of the U.S. Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia who continue to be employed by the local prosecutor's office retain their eligibility as federal employees for purposes of health insurance, retirement, and&#160;other federal benefits.</summary>
</bill>
