<bill session="116" type="s" number="908" updated="2022-11-01T18:32:40Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fluke Fairness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fluke Fairness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fluke Fairness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for an equitable management of summer flounder based on geographic, scientific, and economic data and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2049-2050" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Wicker without amendment. With written report No. 116-167.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-12-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="317">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 317.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-14T16:25:05Z" status="Reported to Senate">Fluke Fairness Act of 2019

This bill directs the Mid-Atlantic Fishery Management Council to submit for approval by the Department of Commerce a modified fishery management plan for the commercial and recreational management of summer flounder, or an amendment to the plan, that

 is based on the best scientific information available; establishes commercial quotas in direct proportion to the distribution, abundance, and location of summer flounder as reflected by fishery independent surveys conducted by the National Marine Fisheries Service and state agencies; considers regional, coastwide, or other management measures that comply with national standards under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act; and prohibits the establishment of commercial catch quotas on a state-by-state basis using historical landings data that does not reflect the status of the summer flounder stock, based on the most recent scientific information. Commerce must prepare and consider a plan if the council fails to submit the modifications or amendments.

The Government Accountability Office must assess and report on whether the subsequent implementation of the approved plan or amendment complies with national standards.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-167</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
