<bill session="117" type="h" number="244" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Executive Branch Conflict of Interest Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen and enhance certain ethics requirements for the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Branch Conflict of Interest Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2021-01-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2093" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-19T14:45:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Executive Branch Conflict of Interest Act

This bill expands and establishes new prohibitions related to conflicts of interest involving certain federal government employees.

Specifically, the bill prohibits a federal government employee from accepting a bonus from a former private sector employer for entering government service.

The bill prohibits certain senior officials from using their position to participate in matters wherein a former employer or client has a financial interest, and it establishes penalties for an official who violates this prohibition. The bill also increases lobbying restrictions to two years for certain senior officials.

In addition, the bill expands prohibitions that prevent certain former officials who were responsible for specified government contracts from receiving compensation from a participating contractor, contractor's affiliate, or subcontractor. The bill also prohibits a procurement officer in the federal government from working for a company that received a contract overseen by the procurement officer during the officer's last two years in government service.</summary>
</bill>
