<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="1837" updated="2022-02-03T04:58:04Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1689" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-10-17">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-10-14"/>
  <description>To ensure that a Federal employee who takes leave without pay in order to perform certain service as a member of the uniformed services or member of the National Guard shall continue to receive pay in an amount which, when taken together with the pay and allowances such individual is receiving for such service, will be no less than the basic pay such individual would then be receiving if no interruption in employment had occurred.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-17">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12770" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2003-10-17" how="roll" result="pass" roll="390">
      <text>Amendment SA 1837 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 390.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-16">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12643, CR 10/17/2003 S12715" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12574" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Amendment SA 1837 proposed by Senator Durbin. (consideration: CR S12524-12525; text: CR S12524) To ensure that a Federal employee who takes leave without pay in order to perform certain service as a member of the uniformed services or member of the National Guard shall continue to receive pay in an amount which, when taken together with the pay and allowances such individual is receiving for such service, will be no less than the basic pay such individual would then be receiving if no interruption in employment had occurred.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-17">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1837 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 390.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-17">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 1837 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 390.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1837 proposed by Senator Durbin.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12524-12525" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S12524" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
