<bill session="112" type="h" number="4846" updated="2019-11-15T21:33:37Z">
  <state datetime="2012-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Financial Empowerment Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Senior Financial Empowerment Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud targeting seniors in the United States, to promote efforts to increas public awareness of the enormous impact that mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud have on seniors, to educate the public, seniors, their families, and their caregivers about how to identify and combat fraudulent activity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="465" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-06-21T14:17:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Senior Financial Empowerment Act of 2012 - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC): (1) to disseminate to seniors and their families and caregivers information on mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud targeting seniors, including on ways of referring complaints to appropriate law enforcement agencies; (2) in response to a request about a particular entity or individual, to provide publicly available information on any record of civil or criminal law enforcement action for such fraud; and (3) to maintain a website as a resource for such individuals on those kinds of fraud.

Directs the Attorney General (DOJ) to establish and administer a competitive grant program for mail, telemarketing, and Internet fraud prevention education programs for senior citizens.

Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to public awareness of the impact of such fraud on senior citizens and designation of a National Senior Fraud Awareness Week.</summary>
</bill>
