<bill session="118" type="s" number="1122" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prioritizing Medical Countermeasures for National Security Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prioritizing Medical Countermeasures for National Security Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the program to provide for priority review of human drug applications to encourage treatment for agents that present national security threats.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2023-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-12T19:09:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prioritizing Medical Countermeasures for National Security Act of 2023

This bill requires the Administration for Strategic Preparedness and Response (ASPR) to establish a list of categories of drugs that may be necessary to address a public health emergency or threat to the Armed Forces in order to facilitate the development of such drugs.

Specifically, ASPR must list categories and classes of drugs that may be necessary to prevent or treat diseases or conditions that are caused by chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear agents and that have the potential to cause a public health emergency that threatens national security, or that may pose a threat to the Armed Forces. ASPR must share the list with interested parties to incentivize development and speed review of relevant drug applications.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the bill's effectiveness in encouraging the development of necessary medical countermeasures.</summary>
</bill>
