<bill session="112" type="h" number="1958" updated="2019-11-15T21:43:21Z">
  <state datetime="2011-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modify the designation of accreditation organizations for orthotics and prosthetics, to apply accreditation and licensure requirements to suppliers of such devices and items for purposes of payment under the Medicare program, and to modify the payment rules for such devices and items under such program to account for practitioner qualifications and complexity of care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000362" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000652" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2011-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000573" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2011-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2011-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2125" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Allied health services"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-22T19:45:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Improvement Act of 2011 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, for application of quality standards for certain accredited suppliers of prosthetic devices, orthotics, and certain prosthetics, to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to designate and approve an independent accreditation organization with respect to such suppliers only if that organization is the American Board for Certification in Orthotics and Prosthetics, Inc. or the Board for Orthotist/ Prosthetist Certification (or a program with essentially equivalent accreditation and approval standards). Exempts from such standards any suppliers who: (1) are physicians, occupational therapists, or physical therapists licensed or otherwise regulated by the state in which they practice; and (2) receive Medicare payments. Applies to custom-fitted orthotics the special payment rules for certain prosthetics and custom&#150;fabricated orthotics.

Modifies the Medicare payment rules for orthotics and prosthetics to account for practitioner qualifications and complexity of care.

Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) HHS steps taken to ensure that the state licensure and accreditation requirements are enforced, and (2) the effects of requirements of this Act on the occurrence of Medicare fraud and abuse with respect to orthotics and prosthetics.

Requires the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to submit to Congress a projection of the effect on cumulative federal spending under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) for 2012-2016 that will result from implementation of this Act. Requires the Secretary, if the Chief Actuary projects that implementation of this Act will not result in a cumulative spending reduction of at least $250 million for 2012-2016, to issue an interim final regulation to strengthen the licensure, accreditation, and quality standards applicable to orthotics and prosthetics suppliers in order to produce such a cumulative reduction by the end of 2016. Exempts from such regulation any qualified physical therapist or qualified occupational therapist.</summary>
</bill>
