<bill session="116" type="s" number="2753" updated="2022-11-01T04:47:43Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supplemental Security Income Restoration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supplemental Security Income Restoration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVI of the Social Security Act to update eligibility for the supplemental security income program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2020-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2019-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4280" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-18T20:52:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supplemental Security Income Restoration Act of 2019

This bill modifies eligibility for, and other components of, Supplemental Security Income (SSI). This needs-based program, administered by the Social Security Administration, provides cash benefits to the aged, blind, and disabled.

Among other changes, the bill increases income and resource limits used to determine SSI eligibility. Current law excludes from income limits the first $240 of income from sources other than earnings and the first $780 of earned income. The bill increases these amounts to $1,476 and $4,788, respectively. Current law also allows SSI recipients to have $2,000 in resources if they are single or $3,000 in resources if they are married. The bill increases those amounts to $10,000 and $20,000, respectively. The bill also excludes from income and resource determinations (1) support furnished in kind, and (2) state tax refunds derived from specified state tax credits. In addition, the bill equalizes treatment of married couples when both spouses receive SSI. Under current law, such a married couple receives a lower benefit amount and is subject to lower income and resource limits than would apply to two unmarried individuals. The bill instead sets benefit amounts and limits for these married couples at a rate that is twice that of unmarried SSI recipients.

Additionally, the bill eliminates the penalty for transfers of certain resources. Under current law, SSI recipients who transfer resources for less than fair market value may lose SSI eligibility for up to 36 months. The bill repeals this loss of eligibility.

The bill also indexes annual benefit increases to a price index that reflects the spending patterns of elderly consumers.</summary>
</bill>
