<bill session="117" type="h" number="2571" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-23T14:21:13-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-06-23T14:21:13-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AMIGOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Mutual Interests and Growing Our Success Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AMIGOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Advancing Mutual Interests and Growing Our Success Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Advancing Mutual Interests and Growing Our Success Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">AMIGOS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">AMIGOS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To include Portugal in the list of foreign states whose nationals are eligible for admission into the United States as E-1 and E-2 nonimmigrants if United States nationals are treated similarly by the Government of Portugal and to otherwise modify the eligibility criteria for E visas.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To include Portugal in the list of foreign states whose nationals are eligible for admission into the United States as E&#226;&#8364;&#8220;1 and E&#226;&#8364;&#8220;2 nonimmigrants if United States nationals are treated similarly by the Government of Portugal and to otherwise modify the eligibility criteria for E visas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22T16:39:42-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Nadler moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22T16:40:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2982-2983" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2982" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22T16:40:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2571.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22T16:49:07-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23T14:21:12-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 486, proceedings on H.R. 2571 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2021-06-23T14:21:13-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 11 of H. Res. 486, and the motion offered by Mr. McGovern, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 482; H.R. 704; H.R. 961, as amended; H.R. 1314; H.R. 2571, as amended; H.R. 2679, as amended; H.R. 2694; H.R. 2922, as amended; H.R. 3182; H.R. 3239; H.R. 3241, as amended; H.R. 3723; H.R. 3752; H.R. 3841; S. 409; and S. 1340.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3026-3052" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3028" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1194" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="486" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4350" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Portugal"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-28T20:25:53Z" status="Passed House">Advancing Mutual Interests and Growing Our Success Act or the AMIGOS Act

This bill makes Portuguese nationals eligible for E-1 and E-2 nonimmigrant visas if the government of Portugal provides similar nonimmigrant status to U.S. nationals. The bill also imposes additional requirements on such visas.

An E-1 visa is for individuals entering the United States to engage in international trade, while an E-2 visa is for individuals investing a substantial amount of capital in the United States. Both are limited to nationals from countries that have a treaty of commerce and navigation with the United States.

Furthermore, under this bill, if an alien who has never received an E visa became the national of an E visa-eligible foreign country by making a financial investment in that foreign country, that alien must have been domiciled in that foreign country for a continuous period of at least three years at any point before applying for an E visa.</summary>
</bill>
