<bill session="108" type="sr" number="365" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:08Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the detention of Tibetan political prisoners by the Government of the People's Republic of China.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the detention of Tibetan political prisoners by the Government of the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2004-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5808-5809"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5808" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-16T20:32:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the Government of the People's Republic of China is in violation of international human rights standards by detaining and mistreating Tibetans who engage in peaceful activities to protest China's occupation of Tibet or promote the preservation of a distinct Tibetan identity; (2) sustained international pressure on the Government of the People's Republic of China is essential to improve the human rights situation in Tibet and secure the release of Tibetan political prisoners; (3) the Government of the United States should raise the cases of Tenzin Delek and other Tibetan political prisoners in every meeting with officials from the People's Republic of China, and work with other governments concerned about human rights in Tibet and China to encourage the release of Tibetan political prisoners and promote systemic improvement of human rights in Tibet and China; and (4) the Government of the People's Republic of China should release all Tibetan political prisoners, including Tenzin Delek.</summary>
</bill>
