<bill session="111" type="h" number="5617" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:52Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Home Energy Conservation Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for home energy conservation bonds.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home Energy Conservation Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2010-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1220"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-01T19:45:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Home Energy Conservation Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow the issuance of tax-exempt home energy conservation bonds to finance qualified residential energy efficiency assistance grants and loans and extend such grants and loans to low and very-low income taxpayers. Imposes a national home energy conservation bond limitation amount of $2.4 billion and allocates such amount to states in proportion to state population.

Defines "qualified residential energy efficiency assistance grants and loans" as any grant or loan to acquire: (1) any property which meets (at a minimum) the requirements of the Energy Star program or the Water Sense program and which is to be installed in a dwelling unit; and (2) any improvement to a dwelling unit made under a plan which is developed by a Residential Energy Services Network, Building Performance Institute, or equivalent energy efficiency expert and is certified by such expert as resulting in at least a 20% reduction in total household energy consumption related to heating, cooling, lighting, and appliances.

 Imposes dollar limitations on such grants and loans and excludes certain types of property from such grant and loan program, including equipment used in connection with a swimming pool or hot tub, any television, any device for converting a digital signal to analog, any DVD player, video cassette recorder, audio equipment, cordless phone, or other property where there is a substantial recreational use.</summary>
</bill>
