<bill session="111" type="h" number="2471" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:12Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, to authorize the Secretary of Energy to pay affected participants under a pension plan referred to in the USEC Privatization Act for benefit increases not received, to direct the Secretary of Energy to provide a plan for the re-enrichment of certain uranium tailings, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000413"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-18">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1061" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-04T16:08:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decomissioning Fund Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to reauthorize, and increase the maximum mandatory amounts in, the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund.

Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to pay any affected participant under the USEC Privatization Act a one-time sum payment of benefits in an amount to be determined by the Secretary.

Limits affected participants to persons who: (1) retired from active employment at one of the gaseous diffusion plants on or before the United States Enrichment Corporation (USEC) privatization date as vested participants in a pension; and (2) are employed by the USEC's operating contractor on or before the privatization date and are vested participants in a pension plan.

Directs the Secretary to develop, complete, and publish in the Federal Register a plan to re-enrich and sell certain cylinders of uranium tailings.</summary>
</bill>
