<bill session="115" type="h" number="6799" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Lands FIRES Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize disaster recovery assistance for areas affected by wildfires on Federal Lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands Fire-Related Incidents Recovery and Economic Stimulus Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands FIRES Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000470"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-06T14:01:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Lands Fire-Related Incidents Recovery and Economic Stimulus Act of 2018 or the Federal Lands FIRES Act of 2018

This bill authorizes the President to declare a federal lands wildfire disaster. Specifically, the President may make such a declaration for any wildfire:

 for which a request for a declaration has been made by the governor of an affected state or the chief executive of an affected Indian tribal government; that has burned 40% or more of an area that consists of federal lands; and that, in the President's determination, causes damage of sufficient severity and magnitude to warrant assistance to supplement the efforts and available resources of states, local governments, Indian tribes, and disaster relief&#160; organizations in alleviating the damage, loss, hardship, or suffering caused by the wildfire. Assistance may be provided for secondary and tertiary damages, which may not include any area more than 100 miles from the area subject to the wildfire.

The Department of Housing and Urban Development may provide assistance to states, local governments, and Indian tribes for necessary expenses for disaster relief, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, and economic revitalization in the most impacted and distressed areas resulting from a federal lands wildfire disaster.

The bill amends the Small Business Act to allow small businesses to receive economic injury disaster loans from the Small Business Administration for a federal lands wildfire disaster.</summary>
</bill>
