<bill session="118" type="s" number="850" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Quality Defense Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing a Quality Defense Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quality Defense Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to incentivize States and localities to improve access to justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-05T18:44:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Providing a Quality Defense Act of 2023 or the Quality Defense Act of 2023

This bill establishes grant programs and other resources to support the delivery of public defense services.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to state and local governments, tribal organizations, public defender's offices, and assigned counsel programs for public defense. In particular, DOJ may award a grant for (1) developing, implementing, and updating a process for collecting certain data regarding public defense attorneys and panel attorneys; or (2) hiring additional public defense attorneys and for other activities (e.g., increasing compensation or establishing a loan assistance program for public defenders).

Additionally, DOJ must award grants to eligible entities (e.g., certain tax-exempt organizations and states) to provide a comprehensive educational program to public defenders and panel attorneys that offers ongoing training, support, and programming.

The bill directs the Bureau of Justice Assistance and the Office for Access to Justice to conduct certain studies related to public defender and panel attorney caseloads and compensation.

The bill also authorizes DOJ to provide a state with an increase in Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program funds in order to collect and submit certain data related to the legal representation of defendants in criminal cases.</summary>
</bill>
