<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2138</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:21:16Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:21:16Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-06-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. RICHMOND:H.R. 2138.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:This bill is introduced pursuant to the powers granted toCongress under the General Welfare Clause (Art. 1 Sec. 8 Cl.1), the Commerce Clause (Art. 1 Sec. 8 Cl. 3), and theNecessary and Proper Clause (Art. 1 Sec. 8 Cl. 18).Further, this statement of constitutional authority is madefor the sole purpose of compliance with clause 7 of Rule XIIof the Rules of the House of Representatives and shall haveno bearing on judicial review of the accompanying bill.[Page H4037]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif14</systemCode>
            <name>Health Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2011-06-03T18:38:36Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-06-03T13:04:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif14</systemCode>
            <name>Health Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000588</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Richmond, Cedric L. [D-LA-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Cedric</firstName>
        <lastName>Richmond</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <district>2</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Homelessness and emergency shelter</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mental health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-06-30T18:21:38Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Travel Trailer Residents' Health Registry Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS Secretary) to: (1) establish and maintain a health registry for individuals exposed to formaldehyde in temporary housing units provided by the government when displaced by a major disaster that occurred between August 29, 2005, and December 31, 2009; (2) include in the registry information the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS Secretary) determines is necessary to ascertain and monitor the health effects of such exposure; (3) develop a public information campaign to inform eligible individuals about the registry; and (4) periodically notify such individuals of significant developments in the study and treatment of conditions associated with exposure.</p><p>Directs the DHS Secretary to contract with the HHS Secretary to provide health examinations, consultations, and mental health counseling free of charge to each eligible individual.</p><p>Requires the HHS Secretary to contract with an independent scientific organization to report to Congress on: (1) the effectiveness of actions taken to collect and maintain information on the health consequences of such exposure, (2) recommendations to improve such collection and maintenance, and (3) the most effective and prudent means of addressing medical needs of eligible individuals.</p><p>Requires: (1) such health consultation and mental health counseling to provide to each eligible individual information on examination results and on developments, and (2) the Secretary to commence an epidemiological study of the immediate and long-term effects of such exposure sufficient to further understand the medical needs of eligible individuals.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Travel Trailer Residents' Health Registry Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Travel Trailer Residents' Health Registry Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Travel Trailer Residents' Health Registry Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To establish a health registry to ensure that certain individuals who may have been exposed to formaldehyde in a travel trailer have an opportunity to register for such registry and receive medical treatment for such exposure, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2011-06-03T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr2138ih/xml/BILLS-112hr2138ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
