<bill session="117" type="h" number="5184" updated="2022-12-31T09:00:09Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 with respect to requirements for domestic industries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Interests Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Interests Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2022-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2021-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-20T16:19:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing America's Interests Act

This bill limits the ability of certain persons (e.g., patent or trademark holders) to bring complaints before the U.S. International Trade Commission (ITC), and it requires the ITC to consider the public interest when determining whether to exclude articles that are under investigation.

A complainant before the ITC must satisfy a domestic industry requirement obliging them to have made significant investment in the United States related to the articles that are the subject of the matter. One method to establish domestic industry is through reliance on licensing activities.

The bill requires a complainant attempting to demonstrate domestic industry through licensing activities to show that those activities led to the adoption and development of articles that incorporate the patent, copyright, trademark, mask work, or design at issue. Further, the bill prohibits a complainant from relying upon activities by a licensee to demonstrate domestic industry unless the license leads to the adoption and development of articles that incorporate the claimed patent, copyright, trademark, mask work, or design for sale in the United States.

In addition, the bill requires the ITC to determine that any exclusion of articles pursuant to an investigation is in the public interest. The ITC must also identify at the beginning of an investigation whether the matter involves a dispositive issue that is appropriate for expedited initial determination and direct the assigned judge to issue such determination not later than 100 days after the investigation is instituted.</summary>
</bill>
