<bill session="117" type="hr" number="57" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Impeaching Joseph R. Biden, President of the United States, for abuse of power by enabling bribery and other high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Impeaching Joseph R. Biden, President of the United States, for abuse of power by enabling bribery and other high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2022-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-12T19:29:37Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution impeaches President Joseph Robinette Biden for abuse of power by enabling bribery and other high crimes and misdemeanors.

Specifically, the resolution sets forth an article of impeachment stating that, in his former role as Vice President, President Biden abused the power of that office through enabling bribery and other high crimes and misdemeanors by allowing his son Hunter Biden to influence the domestic policy of a foreign nation and accept benefits from foreign nationals in exchange for favors.

The article states that, by such conduct, President Biden

 endangered the security of the United States and its institutions of government; threatened the integrity of the democratic system; interfered with the peaceful transition of power; imperiled a coordinate branch of government; and demonstrated that he will remain a threat to national security, democracy, and the Constitution if allowed to remain in office. The article also states that this conduct warrants immediate impeachment, trial, and removal from office and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit under the United States.</summary>
</bill>
