<bill session="110" type="h" number="6156" updated="2019-11-15T21:29:25Z">
  <state datetime="2008-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eastern Sierra and Northern San Gabriel Wild Heritage Act</title>
    <title type="display">Eastern Sierra and Northern San Gabriel Wild Heritage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain land as wilderness in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000508"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2008-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3069" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Snowmobiles"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-08-25T15:54:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Eastern Sierra and Northern San Gabriel Wild Heritage Act - Designates the following areas in California as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) certain lands in the Humboldt-Toiyabe and Inyo National Forests, which shall be considered as part of the Hoover Wilderness; (2) certain lands in the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest, which shall be considered to be part of the Emigrant Wilderness; (3) certain lands in the Inyo National Forest, which shall be considered to be part of the Ansel Adams Wilderness; (4) certain lands in the Inyo National Forest and lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Inyo County, which shall be considered to be part of the John Muir Wilderness; (5) certain lands in the Inyo National Forest and lands administered by BLM in Mono County, which shall be known as the White Mountains Wilderness; (6) certain lands administered by BLM in Mono County, which shall be known as the Granite Mountain Wilderness; and (7) certain lands in the Angeles National Forest, which shall be known as the Magic Mountain Wilderness and the Pleasant View Ridge Wilderness.

Releases any parts of the following areas from further study for designation as wilderness: (1) the Masonic Mountain Wilderness Study Area; (2) the Mormon Meadow Wilderness Study Area; (3) the Walford Springs Wilderness Study Area; and (4) the Granite Mountain Wilderness Study Area.

Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the following as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system: (1) the Amargosa River; (2) the Owens River; and (3) Piru Creek.

Designates certain lands in the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest as the Bridgeport Winter Recreation Area.

Requires certain lands in the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest to be managed in a manner consistent with the non-wilderness forest areas immediately surrounding acreage identified as Area X on the forest's May 20, 2008, proposed management map.

Designates certain public lands in California as the Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest.</summary>
</bill>
