<bill session="116" type="h" number="6315" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:28Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 National Service Response Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide administrative support and flexibility to the Corporation for National and Community Service to respond to the COVID-19 national emergency as declared by the President under the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) on March 13, 2020, with respect to the coronavirus.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 National Service Response Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2020-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="748" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6379" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3548" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-04T19:30:42Z" status="Introduced in House">COVID-19 National Service Response Act

This bill modifies the&#160;Corporation for National and Community Service program to respond to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) national emergency.

The corporation shall allow an individual serving in a position eligible for an educational award, who is performing limited service or whose position has been suspended or placed on hold due to COVID-19,&#160;to accrue other service hours that will count toward the number of hours needed for the individual's education award.

The bill (1) deems certain individuals who are required to exit such positions early at the direction of the corporation to have met the requirements of the position, and (2)&#160;makes certain funds available for FY2021 for the program.

The corporation may (1) permit fixed-amount grant recipients to maintain a pro rata amount of grant funds at the corporation's discretion for participants who exited, were suspended, or are serving in a limited capacity due to COVID-19; and&#160;(2) extend the term of service or waive any upper age limit for national service programs carried out by the National Civilian Community Corps for purposes of addressing disruptions,&#160;and minimizing the difficulty in returning to full operation, due to COVID-19.</summary>
</bill>
