<bill session="108" type="s" number="2027" updated="2023-01-15T09:32:49Z">
  <state datetime="2004-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Driver Education and Licensing Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23 and 49, United States Code, to improve national highway traffic safety through improved motor vehicle driver education and licensing programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Driver Education and Licensing Improvement Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000294"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-01-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S214-215"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S251-252" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Automobile drivers"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-02T18:17:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Driver Education and Licensing Improvement Act of 2004 - Modifies eligibility requirements for grants for support of alcohol-impaired driving countermeasures to require a multiple-stage graduated licensing system for young drivers that: (1) authorizes the issuance of an initial license or learner's permit no earlier than the driver's 16th birthday; (2) prohibits a person under age 21 with a blood alcohol concentration of .02 percent or greater from operating a motor vehicle; (3) provides for a learning stage and an intermediate stage of at least six months each; (4) limits the numbers of passengers; (5) limits nighttime driving, and (6) applies special penalties for violations of system restrictions and of other State motor vehicle laws.

Establishes a National Office of Driver Training in the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. Includes among the Office's functions to develop and make available to the States a recommended curriculum that incorporates best practices in driver education and licensing.

Directs the Secretary of Transportation to carry out grant programs to provide financial assistance to: (1) States to support the improvement of motor vehicle driver education programs and the establishment and improved administration of graduated licensing systems; and (2) eligible recipients to carry out campaigns to increase public awareness of, and training on, State law authority and procedures to provide for organ donation through a declaration recorded on a driver license.

Directs the Secretary to carry out a study to determine whether the establishment and imposition of nationwide minimum standards of driver education would improve national highway traffic safety.</summary>
</bill>
