<bill session="116" type="s" number="3766" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SIGHT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Seeking Inspector General's Honest Testimony Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SIGHT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the President from blocking Inspectors General from reporting to Congress and to require a report to Congress if the Department of the Treasury or the White House does not provide timely access to records, documents, and other materials relating to the implementation and execution of the CARES Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-25T22:35:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Seeking Inspector General's Honest Testimony Act or the SIGHT Act

This bill prohibits the President from blocking inspectors general from reporting to Congress regarding the implementation of the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security (CARES) Act and requires a report to Congress under specified circumstances involving denial of access to records under such act.

Specifically, if the Department of the Treasury Office of Inspector General, the Pandemic Response Accountability Committee, or the Office of the Special Inspector General for Pandemic Recovery determines that Treasury or the White House has not provided timely access or has impeded access to records regarding implementation of the CARES Act, then the office or committee shall report to Congress on the lack of access. If Treasury is responsible for the lack of access, then funding for the Office of the Secretary of the Treasury shall be rescinded until Treasury provides access to the records.</summary>
</bill>
