<bill session="116" type="h" number="4796" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mobile Workforce State Income Tax Simplification Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the authority of States to tax certain income of employees for employment duties performed in other States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mobile Workforce State Income Tax Simplification Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001214"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5674" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="604" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4318" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-10-30T15:05:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Mobile Workforce State Income Tax Simplification Act of 2019

This bill prohibits the wages or other remuneration earned by an employee who performs employment duties in more than one state from being subject to income tax in any state other than (1) the state of the employee's residence, and (2) the state within which the employee is present and performing employment duties for more than 30 days during the calendar year.

The bill exempts employers from state income tax withholding and information reporting requirements for employees not subject to income tax in the state under this bill. For the purposes of determining penalties related to an employer's state income tax withholding or reporting requirements, an employer may rely on an employee's annual determination of the time expected to be spent working in a state in the absence of fraud or collusion by such employee.

For the purposes of this bill, the term "employee" excludes professional athletes; professional entertainers; production employees who perform services in connection with certain film, television, or other commercial video productions; and public figures who are persons of prominence who perform services for wages or other remuneration on a per-event basis.</summary>
</bill>
