<bill session="116" type="h" number="7986" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:28Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native Chamorro Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Chamorro Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for contracting with Native Chamorro Organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001204"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-02T17:13:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Native Chamorro Equity Act

This bill establishes a Chamorro Registry program. It also allows eligible Native Chamorro organizations to qualify for federal contracting opportunities through their participation in certain small business programs that are administered by the Small Business Administration.

First, the bill establishes a Chamorro Registry program under the Guam Department of Chamorro Affairs. The program must keep a database to serve as a genealogy bank to verify Native Chamorro ancestry requirements.

Next, it treats businesses owned by economically disadvantaged Native Chamorro organizations as socially and economically disadvantaged small businesses for purposes of the Minority Small Business and Capital Ownership Development program, which is commonly known as the 8(a) program. Further, it allows businesses that are owned by Native Chamorro organizations to participate in the Historically Underutilized Business Zone Empowerment Contracting (HUBZone) program.

The 8(a) program and the HUBZone program each limit competition for certain government contracts to participating small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
