<bill session="109" type="s" number="1465" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:24Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ocean and Coastal Literacy in Urban and other Environments</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen programs relating to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes science training by providing coordination of efforts, greater interagency cooperation, and the strengthening and expansion of related programs administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and to diversify the ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes science community by attracting underrepresented groups.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocean and Coastal Literacy in Urban and other Environments</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2005-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8747"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8747-2851" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="National Sea Grant Program"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Urban education"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-07-27T20:46:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ocean and Coastal Literacy in Urban and other Environments - Amends the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 to rename the Federal Coordinating Council for Science, Engineering, and Technology as the National Science and Technology Council.

Establishes a National Ocean and Coastal Science Education Task Force to: (1) serve as the primary source of advice on ocean and coastal science education for the Council; and (2) improve cooperation among federal agencies with respect to ocean and coastal sciences and education budgets, programs, operations, facilities, and personnel. Requires the Task Force to maintain an Ocean and Coastal Science Education Advisory Panel.

Directs the Task Force to develop a national strategy for ocean and coastal science education and literacy.

Establishes an interagency ocean and coastal education program to improve public awareness of the role of the ocean in meeting the Nation's economic, social, and environmental needs.

Establishes National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) ocean and coastal science education programs, including: (1) a regional elementary and secondary education program; (2) an Ocean and Coastal Literacy in Urban Environments Program (Ocean CLUE Program); (3) an educational partnership program; and (4) the Teacher-at-Sea Program and the Teacher-in-the-Air Program.

Requires the Administrator of NOAA to develop a science education plan setting forth NOAA education goals and strategies for the next 20 years.

Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize appropriations for estuarine science education for FY2006-FY2011, including: (1) the educational activities of the National Estuarine Research Reserves; and (2) competitive grants for the National Estuarine Research Reserve System system-wide monitoring program data to advance ocean and coastal science literacy.</summary>
</bill>
