<bill session="117" type="h" number="4747" updated="2022-12-31T05:04:53Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Open Translation and Analysis Center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Open Translation and Analysis Center Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Translation and Analysis Center Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2021-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia, the Pacific, Central Asia and Nonproliferation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Indo-Pacific" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4037" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-22T13:18:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Open Translation and Analysis Center Authorization Act

This bill establishes the Open Translation and Analysis Center as a federally funded research and development center sponsored by the Department of State.

The center must disseminate translations and analysis of foreign language materials from China and other countries of strategic interest, with a particular focus on government materials (e.g., documents, reports, and speeches of political and military leadership).

To carry out its activities, the center must (1) select appropriate materials for translation and analysis; (2) train analysts and linguists; (3) use technologies to expedite translations; and (4) otherwise coordinate its work with federal agencies, foreign allies, and others. Specifically, the center must cooperate and consult with relevant federal agencies and stakeholders, including grantees of the United States Agency for Global Media and research organizations. The center may consult with foreign governments if the State Department certifies that the consultation serves U.S. national interests.

Additionally, the center must maintain a publicly available website of all translations and analyses that are not subject to copyright or intellectual property protections. Materials subject to those protections must be made available at no cost on a private website to federal employees and contractors and members of Congress and their staff.

The bill designates the State Department as the primary sponsor of the center. However, the State Department may enter into sponsorship agreements with other federal agencies, such as the Central Intelligence Agency.</summary>
</bill>
