<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>286</number>
    <updateDate>2021-09-29T22:07:56Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-14T21:59:02Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>SRES</type>
    <introducedDate>2004-01-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-01-21</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S122; text as passed Senate: CR S122; text of measure as introduced: CR S121)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-01-21</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.(consideration: CR S122; text as passed Senate: CR S122; text of measure as introduced: CR S121)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-01-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000439</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Frist, William H. [R-TN]</fullName>
        <firstName>WILLIAM</firstName>
        <lastName>FRIST</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TN</state>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000064</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Daschle, Thomas A. [D-SD]</fullName>
        <firstName>THOMAS</firstName>
        <lastName>DASCHLE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>SD</state>
        <middleName>ANDREW</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-01-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional legal counsel</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional officers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Members of Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Subpoena</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-01-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-02-11T21:51:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Authorizes the Senate Legal Counsel to represent certain named Senators, Senate employees, and any other Member, officer, or employee with respect to their testimony or document production in the case of United States of America v. Parviz Karim-Panahi, Crim. No. M-8374-03.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>82</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-01-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-02-11T21:53:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Authorizes the Senate Legal Counsel to represent Senators Daniel K. Akaka, Wayne Allard, Evan Bayh, Joseph R. Biden, Robert C. Byrd, Hillary Rodham Clinton, Susan M. Collins, Mark Dayton, Elizabeth Dole, John Ensign, Lindsey O. Graham, James M. Inhofe, Edward M. Kennedy, Carl Levin, Richard G. Lugar, John McCain, Bill Nelson, E. Benjamin Nelson, Mark Pryor, Jack Reed, Pat Roberts, Jeff Sessions, James M. Talent, and John W.Warner, and Senate employees Judith A. Ansley, Staff Director of the Committee on Armed Services, Scott W. Stucky, General Counsel to the Committee, June M. Borawski, Printing and Document Clerk of the Committee, Paul F.Clayman, Chief Counsel of the Committee on Foreign Relations, and Susan Oursler, Chief Clerk of such Committee, and any other Member, officer, or employee with respect to their testimony or document production in the case of United States of America v. Parviz Karim-Panahi, Crim. No. M-8374-03</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>A resolution to authorize legal representation in United States of America v. Parvis Karim-Panahi.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>A resolution to authorize legal representation in United States of America v. Parvis Karim-Panahi.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A resolution to authorize legal representation in United States of America v. Parvis Karim-Panahi.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Agreed to Senate</type>
        <date>2004-01-21T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-01-21</actionDate>
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S122; text as passed Senate: CR S122; text of measure as introduced: CR S121)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
