<bill session="110" type="s" number="1259" updated="2023-01-11T16:32:44Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Education for All Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide assistance for developing countries to promote quality basic education and to establish the achievement of universal basic education in all developing countries as an objective of United States foreign assistance policy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education for All Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2007-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2007-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2008-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2007-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2007-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2007-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2007-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2007-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2008-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2007-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2007-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5397"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11267-11268"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="2092" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-16T15:48:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Education for All Act of 2007 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to state that it is U.S. policy to work with foreign countries and international and civil society organizations to increase the global commitment to achieving universal basic education by assisting: (1) developing countries to provide all children with a quality basic education; and (2) nongovernmental and multilateral organizations working in developing countries to provide all children with a quality basic education.

Directs the President to develop a comprehensive U.S. strategy to promote universal basic education by 2015.

Authorizes the President to provide funds and other assistance to qualifying foreign countries to create the policies, processes, and infrastructure to develop national basic education plans.

Authorizes the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to establish an education fellowship program to increase the expertise of USAID personnel in promoting universal basic education.

Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish within the Department of State a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Provide Education for All in Developing Countries, who shall shall have primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of all U.S. government resources and international activities to promote universal basic education.</summary>
</bill>
