<bill session="116" type="h" number="8811" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Data Accuracy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Data Accuracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To initiate an inquiry and report on COVID-19 data quality, sharing, transparency, access, and analysis and develop a process to correct inaccurate information reported with respect to the COVID-19 public health emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2020-11-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2020-11-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4328" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-17T14:35:44Z" status="Introduced in House">COVID-19 Data Accuracy Act

This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to initiate an inquiry within seven days and report on the impact of certain changes to hospital reporting requirements for COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) on data quality, transparency, and access. The White House's Coronavirus Task Force revised the process for hospitals to report COVID-19 data on July 13, 2020; previously, hospitals reported data to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) instead of to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).

To facilitate the inquiry, HHS must provide the GAO with direct access to relevant information systems. The GAO must present its findings within 45 days, and HHS must then respond to the findings and rectify any issues identified within 7 days.

HHS must also, in coordination with the CDC, develop a process within 30 days to correct inaccuracies in the COVID-19 data.

In addition, the GAO must issue reports that address, for example, the impact of the changes to reporting requirements on federal and nonfederal entities, such as hospitals, states, and other jurisdictions, and information about how the decision to change those requirements was made.</summary>
</bill>
