<bill session="117" type="h" number="6075" updated="2023-07-07T19:30:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEADs UP Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEADs UP Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthcare Extension and Accessibility for Developmentally disabled and Underserved Population Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to expand and improve health care services by health centers and the National Health Service Corps for individuals with a developmental disability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-11-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2021-11-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-21T21:08:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthcare Extension and Accessibility for Developmentally disabled and Underserved Population Act of 2021 or the HEADs UP Act of 2021

This bill authorizes the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to support health centers that provide services for individuals with developmental disabilities, including dental care. Grant recipients must provide specialized treatment to individuals with developmental disabilities as necessary.

The bill also provides statutory authority for HHS to designate individuals with developmental disabilities as health-professional shortage population groups for the purposes of the National Health Service Corps (NHSC). The NHSC provides scholarships and student loan repayment awards to eligible providers who agree to work with designated populations or in areas that face shortages of primary care, dental care, and mental health care providers.</summary>
</bill>
