<bill session="118" type="h" number="4510" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:22Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-15T18:09:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-15T18:09:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NTIA Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Telecommunications and Information Administration Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">NTIA Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Telecommunications and Information Administration Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">NTIA Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Telecommunications and Information Administration Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NTIA Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">National Telecommunications and Information Administration Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">NTIA Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, to update the mission and functions of the agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2023-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 48 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-249.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-10-25" calendar="Union" number="199">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 199.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T14:05:27-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Latta moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T14:05:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3014-3027" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T14:05:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4510.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T14:19:36-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15T18:05:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3253-3254" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="205" datetime="2024-05-15T18:09:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 374 - 36 (Roll no. 205).</text>
      <reference ref="5/14/2024 CR H3014-3025" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15T18:09:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-07T17:22:16Z" status="Reported to House">National Telecommunications and Information Administration Reauthorization Act of 2023 or the NTIA Reauthorization Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) through FY2025 and modifies its structure and functions.

Specifically, the bill promotes the head of the NTIA to an Under Secretary of the Department of Commerce. It also provides statutory authority for two NTIA offices focused on public safety communications and international telecommunications policy, respectively.

Further, the bill provides statutory authority for the NTIA Office of Spectrum Management and otherwise revises the management of spectrum resources (electromagnetic frequencies used to transmit signals and data, including wireless internet). For example, the bill (1) sets out procedures for disclosing federal concerns and related information regarding spectrum actions, and (2) requires the NTIA to develop technologies and carry out other activities to enhance efficiency in the use of spectrum resources and facilitate sharing of the resources.

In addition, the bill expands the role of the NTIA with respect to cybersecurity. This includes requiring the NTIA to

 carry out a cybersecurity literacy campaign, report on the information and communications technology supply chain and the cybersecurity of mobile networks, and provide technical assistance and outreach to small communications providers concerning Open RAN networks and other open network architectures. The NTIA also must (1) develop and implement a strategy to close the digital divide, and (2) establish an interagency process (that replaces the Committee for the Assessment of Foreign Participation in the U.S. Telecommunications Services Sector, formerly known as Team Telecom) to consider the law enforcement and national security implications of foreign ownership interests when licensing or authorizing telecommunications systems and infrastructure.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-249</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
