<bill session="115" type="s" number="3528" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Care for Veterans Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to furnish hospital care and medical services to veterans, members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, and dependents who were stationed at Wurtsmith Air Force Base in Oscoda, Michigan, and were exposed to volatile organic compounds, to provide for a presumption of service connection for those veterans and members of the reserve components, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Care for Veterans Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6994" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-29T21:21:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Care for Veterans Act of 2018

This bill requires hospital care and medical services to be furnished to veterans that were exposed to volatile organic compounds, including trichloroethylene and benzene, while serving at Wurtsmith Air Force Base in Oscoda, Michigan. Family members of veterans who resided at Wurtsmith Air Force Base are also eligible for hospital care and medical services under this bill.

The bill also provides a presumption of service connection for veterans who were exposed to volatile organic compounds while serving at Wurtsmith Air Force Base. Under a presumption of service connection, specific conditions diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.</summary>
</bill>
