<bill session="108" type="s" number="2537" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:47Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2005, Homeland Security</title>
    <title type="popular">Homeland Security Department FY2005 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000567"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Homeland Security. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-705.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Cochran. With written report No. 108-280.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="583">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 583.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 4567 as an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-14">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 4567 in lieu of this measure by Yea-Nay Vote. 93 - 0. Record Vote Number: 184.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSAP14" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Department of Homeland Security" activity="Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4567" relation="companion"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Athletics"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Plant protection"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-02T16:30:14Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005 - Title I: Departmental Management and Operations - Makes appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for FY 2005 for: (1) the Office of the Secretary of Homeland Security and executive management; (2) the Office of the Under Secretary for Management; (3) development and acquisition of information technology equipment, software, services, and for the costs of conversion to narrowband communications; and (4) the Office of Inspector General.

Title II: Security, Enforcement, and Investigations - Makes appropriations for: (1) the Office of the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security, including for development of the U.S. Visitor and Immigrant Status Indicator Technology project; (2) enforcement of laws relating to border security, immigration, customs, and agricultural inspections and regulatory activities related to plant and animal imports and for customs and border protection automated systems; (3) immigration and customs law enforcement, including for Federal air marshals, the Federal Protective Service, and immigration and customs enforcement automated systems; (4) the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), including for explosive detection devices; (5) the Coast Guard; and (6) the Secret Service.

Title III: Preparedness and Recovery - Makes appropriations for: (1) the Office for State and Local Government Coordination and Preparedness, including for grants to State and local governments for terrorism prevention activities (sets forth specified allocations for formula-based grants, law enforcement terrorism prevention grants, discretionary grants for the use in high-threat, high density urban areas and for rail and transit security, firefighter assistance grants, and emergency management performance grants; (2) reimbursement of Federal agencies for the costs of providing support to counter, investigate, or respond to unexpected threats or acts of terrorism; (3) emergency preparedness and response, including for the Office of the Under Secretary for Emergency Preparedness and Response, the Directorate of Emergency Preparedness and Response, countering potential biological, disease, and chemical threats to civilian populations, the disaster assistance direct loan program, the Flood Map Modernization Fund, the National Flood Insurance Fund, pre-disaster mitigation grants, and an emergency food and shelter program. Limits the aggregate charges assessed during FY 2005 for the Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program.

Title IV: Research and Development, Training, Assessments, and Services - Makes appropriations for: (1) expenses for citizenship and immigration services; (2) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center; (3) the Directorate of Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection, including the immediate Office of the Under Secretary for Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection; and (4) the immediate Office of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology for management and administration of programs and activities and science and technology research.

Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 504) Deems funds made available by this Act for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress during FY 2005 until the enactment of an Act authorizing intelligence activities for FY 2005.

(Sec. 505) Directs the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to: (1) establish an accrediting body to establish standards for measuring and assessing the quality and effectiveness of Federal law enforcement training programs, facilities, and instructors; and (2) schedule basic and advanced law enforcement training at all four training facilities to ensure that all these centers are operated at the highest capacity.

(Sec. 512) Directs the Secretary: (1) to research, develop, and procure certified systems to inspect and screen air cargo on passenger aircraft at the earliest date possible; and (2) until such technology is procured and installed, to take actions to prohibit high-risk cargo from being transported on passenger aircraft.

(Sec. 514) Prohibits the obligation of funds for deployment or implementation of the Computer Assisted Passenger Prescreening System (CAPPS II), on other than a test basis, to screen aviation passengers until the General Accounting Office (GAO) has reported to the Appropriations Committees that: (1) a system of due process exists whereby passengers who are determined to pose a threat and who are either delayed or prohibited from boarding may appeal such decision and correct erroneous information contained in CAPPS II; (2) the error rate of the databases that will be used to establish identity and assign a risk level to a passenger will not produce a large number of false positives; (3) TSA has demonstrated the efficacy and accuracy of all search tools in CAPPS II and has demonstrated that CAPPS II can make an accurate predictive assessment of passengers; (4) the Secretary has established an internal oversight board to monitor the manner in which CAPPS II is being developed and prepared; (5) TSA has built in sufficient operational safeguards to reduce the opportunities for abuse; (6) substantial security measures are in place to protect CAPPS II from unauthorized access; (7) TSA has adopted policies establishing effective oversight of the system's use and operation; and (8) there are no specific privacy concerns with the technological architecture of the system. Prohibits, during the testing phase, any information gathered from passengers, air carriers, or reservation systems from being used to screen passengers or to delay or deny boarding. Requires the report by February 15, 2005.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-280</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
