<bill session="118" type="s" number="3950" updated="2024-08-22T14:50:36Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DUALS Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delivering Unified Access to Lifesaving Services Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DUALS Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide States with support to establish integrated care programs for individuals who are dually eligible for Medicare and Medicaid, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2024-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2024-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2024-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2024-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2024-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3549" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1703" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8503" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-15T19:37:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Delivering Unified Access to Lifesaving Services Act of 2024 or the DUALS Act of 2024

This bill creates a program to provide integrated care for individuals who are fully eligible for both Medicare and Medicaid (i.e., dual-eligible individuals).

The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must develop a set of models for states to provide integrated care coordination for dual-eligible individuals; states must choose one of these models and implement the model within four years of their selection. Benefits must include clinical health services, behavioral health services, and long-term services and supports. Care coordination plans must be based on individualized health risk assessments and involve interdisciplinary health care teams. Each individual must be assigned a care coordinator to help the individual with respect to benefits and health care decisions.&#160;

The bill provides funds for states and the CMS to implement this program. It also provides funds for outreach and other activities to raise awareness about the program.

The bill also modifies Programs of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly (PACE), including by allowing those under age 55 to enroll in PACE if they are eligible for Medicare. (PACE is a program under Medicare and Medicaid that provides in-home and community services for certain individuals as an alternative to nursing home care.)&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
