<bill session="117" type="h" number="8460" updated="2023-06-08T19:15:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ATF Improvement and Modernization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To remove obstacles to the ability of law enforcement officers to enforce gun safety laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000148" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2022-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4582" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-01T15:00:14Z" status="Introduced in House">ATF Improvement and Modernization Act of 2022 or the AIM Act

This bill removes limitations on the authority of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) to conduct activities related to the administration of federal firearms laws.

Specifically, the bill removes provisions that

 limit the use of firearms tracing data; prohibit consolidating or centralizing records maintained by federal firearm licensees, or FFLs (e.g., gun dealers); prohibit imposing a requirement that gun dealers conduct a physical inventory; require national instant criminal background check records to be destroyed within 24 hours; limit the disclosure of data under the Freedom of Information Act; prohibit the ATF from altering the definition of a curio or relic firearm; prohibit the denial of a federal firearms license due to lack of business activity; prohibit transferring the ATF's functions, missions, or activities to other agencies or departments; prohibit the electronic retrieval of information gathered from firearm transaction records of FFLs that go out of business; and prohibit the ATF from denying an application to import certain shotguns. Additionally, the bill

 raises the liability standard for denying or revoking a federal firearms license from a willful violation to a knowing violation of federal firearms laws or regulations, and removes the de novo standard of judicial review for appealing the denial or revocation of a federal firearms license.</summary>
</bill>
