<bill session="118" type="s" number="1572" updated="2025-11-19T04:37:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Depositor Protection Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Depositor Protection Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to address transaction account guarantees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000601"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5845" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-05T19:59:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Depositor Protection Act of 2023 

This bill expands Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) protections and the actions the FDIC is allowed to take, including in the event of an institutional failure.

First, the bill expands for two years FDIC deposit insurance for an amount up to $100,000,000 that a depositor maintains at an insured depository institution in a noninterest-bearing transaction account. (Currently, the FDIC insures deposits up to $250,000.)

The bill also increases the reciprocal deposit limit applicable to depository institutions. (Reciprocal deposits are used by institutions to increase the availability of deposit insurance by splitting large deposits using a reciprocal network of institutions.)

For 90 days after the date of enactment, the bill allows for the acquisition of distressed banks by a bank holding company without regulatory approval under certain circumstances.

The bill also allows the FDIC to facilitate a merger, sale, assumption of liabilities, or stock acquisition involving the failure of a large institution using an adjusted least-cost resolution calculation.</summary>
</bill>
