<bill session="108" type="s" number="1097" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to implement the Calfed Bay-Delta Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6859-6860"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6860-6863" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-338.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-268.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="523">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 523.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2641" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2828" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land subsidence"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Selenium"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-11-25T22:17:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act - Approves the August 28, 2000, Federal programmatic Record of Decision issued by specified Federal agencies and supported by the State of California as a framework for addressing Calfed Bay-Delta Program components. Authorizes the Secretary and the heads of such agencies to carry out Stage 1 activities (projects and programs planned for the first seven years) in the following categories if such activities have been subject to environmental review and approval under Federal and State law and have been certified by the California Bay-Delta Authority to be consistent with the Record of Decision: water storage; conveyance; water use efficiency; water transfers; the Environmental Water account; integrated regional water management plans; ecosystem restoration; watersheds; water quality; levee stability; science; program management, oversight, and coordination; and diversification of water supplies.

Requires the Federal agencies to: (1) coordinate their activities with specified California agencies; (2) cooperate with local and tribal governments and the public through a federally chartered advisory committee or other means; and (3) implement the Program using the best available scientific information and scientific review.





Directs the Secretary: (1) to report monthly on the Authority's progress in achieving the water supply targets, environmental water account requirements, and water quality targets described in the Record and on any pending actions that may affect the Authority's ability to achieve those targets and requirements; (2) to report annually on Program implementation, expenditures, and accomplishments; (3) to certify in such annual report whether the Program is progressing in a balanced manner in advancing Program components (requires the Authority to prepare a revised implementation schedule to ensure balanced progress if balance is not certified); (4) to submit annual financial reports containing a detailed accounting of all Federal and State funds received and obligated under the Program and all projects to be carried out in the upcoming year; (5) prior to December 2004, to report to Congress on the Program's accomplishments, the specific steps remaining to be undertaken, the specific funding levels and sources to accomplish such steps, and recommendations necessary to accomplish Program goals and objectives.

 Requires: (1) the President's budget to include requests for an appropriate funding level for each Federal agency to carry out its Program responsibilities; and (2) the Office of Management and Budget to submit an interagency budget crosscut report displaying the budget proposed for each such agency for the Program.

Prohibits the Federal share of the total cost of implementing Stage 1 from exceeding 33.3 percent.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-268</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
