<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="4021" updated="2022-02-03T06:04:00Z">
  <amends type="sr" number="445" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-10-07">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000444"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <description>To provide that the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Foreign Relations (if not already a member of the select Committee) shall be ex officio members of the select Committee but shall have no vote in the Committee and shall not be counted for purposes of determining a quorum.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-10-07" how="roll" result="fail" roll="203">
      <text>Amendment SA 4021 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 54. Record Vote Number: 203.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Amendment SA 4021 proposed by Senator Biden to Amendment SA 3981. (consideration: CR S10665-10669; text: CR S10665) To provide that the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Foreign Relations (if not already a member of the select Committee) shall be ex officio members of the select Committee but shall have no vote in the Committee and shall not be counted for purposes of determining a quorum.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 4021 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 54. Record Vote Number: 203.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 4021 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 54. Record Vote Number: 203.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4021 proposed by Senator Biden to Amendment SA 3981.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10665-10669" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10665" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
