<bill session="117" type="h" number="8873" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:08Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-21T17:00:43-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-09-21T17:00:43-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Presidential Election Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Election Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Presidential Election Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 3, United States Code, to reform the process for the counting of electoral votes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001109" joined="2022-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-20T16:56:06-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1372 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8873 with 1 hour of general debate. Resolution also provides one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21T14:22:48-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1372 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21T14:48:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1372.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8032-8048" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21T14:48:21-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8873 with 1 hour of general debate. Resolution also provides one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21T14:49:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 8873.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21T16:15:12-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="449" datetime="2022-09-21T17:00:43-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 203 (Roll No. 449).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8032-8036" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21T17:00:45-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1372" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-28T13:00:42Z" status="Passed House">Presidential Election Reform Act

This bill revises the process of casting and counting electoral votes for presidential elections.

The bill specifies that the choice of electors must occur in accordance with the laws of the state enacted prior to election day.

Next, the bill specifies that the voting time for a state's presidential election may only be extended due to a catastrophic event. Catastrophic event means a major natural disaster, act of terrorism, or widespread power outage if it (1) prevents a substantial portion of a state's electorate from casting a ballot on election day, or (2) causes a substantial number of ballots already cast in a state to be destroyed or rendered unreadable.

Additionally, the bill requires each state's governor to certify the appointment of electors for the state. Further, the bill provides for expedited judicial review for an action brought by an aggrieved presidential or vice-presidential candidate with respect to the issuance or transmission of a certificate of appointment.

The bill revises the framework for the joint session of Congress to count electoral votes and make a formal declaration of which candidates have been elected President and Vice President. Among other changes, the bill (1) specifies that the role of the presiding officer (the Vice President or, in the absence of the Vice President, the President pro tempore) during the joint session shall be ministerial in nature, and (2) raises the objection threshold in Congress to at least one-third of both the House of Representatives and the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
