<bill session="118" type="s" number="1630" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SOAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Simplifying Outdoor Access for Recreation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOAR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the procedures for issuing special recreation permits for certain public land units, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-23T22:01:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Simplifying Outdoor Access for Recreation Act or the SOAR Act

This bill modifies requirements regarding special recreation permits for outfitting and guiding on federal recreational lands and waters, including by categorizing permits as transitional special recreation permits or as long-term permits.

The bill requires the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to issue two-year transitional special recreation permits to a recreation provider for a new or additional reoccurring recreation service. Interior or USDA must issue a long-term special recreation permit, with a term of 5 or 10 years, to a recreation provider who has held no less than two transitional permits (or similar permits) and meets performance criteria.

The departments may provide the flexibility to a permit holder to engage in another activity similar to the permitted activity under a permit.

The departments must establish a pilot program to offer a single joint special recreation permit or commercial use authorization for a multijurisdictional trip.

The bill requires the departments to evaluate and improve the process for issuing special recreation permits.</summary>
</bill>
