<bill session="118" type="h" number="4499" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IDEA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IDEA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing and Developing Entrepreneurship Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to provide minority business enterprises access to entrepreneurship opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2023-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2023-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2023-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-18T19:09:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Increasing and Developing Entrepreneurship Access Act of 2023 or the IDEA Act of 2023

This bill requires the Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA) to establish a grant program to provide entrepreneurship opportunities for minority businesses.

These grants shall be awarded to business accelerators for providing (1) capital to minority businesses, (2) networking programs that connect such businesses to sources of capital and innovation, and (3) other appropriate assistance.

The MBDA must submit an annual report on the program that includes the number of grants provided, the number of minority businesses that have received assistance from grant recipients, and a description of any noncompliance by grant recipients.

The bill also establishes penalties (a fine or imprisonment) for a grant recipient that knowingly uses award amounts for any purpose not permitted under the program.</summary>
</bill>
