<bill session="117" type="s" number="1008" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MORE PILT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to develop a modeling tool, conduct a study, and issue reports relating to the tax equivalent amount of payments under the payment in lieu of taxes program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Obligations Right by Enlarging Payments In Lieu of Taxes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MORE PILT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2021-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2755" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-12T22:10:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Making Obligations Right by Enlarging Payments In Lieu of Taxes Act or the MORE PILT Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to develop a modeling tool that calculates the approximate market value of land covered by the payment in lieu of taxes (PILT) program and the approximate amount of local tax revenue the land would generate if privately owned. The PILT program compensates local governments for tax revenue lost due to tax-exempt federal lands within their boundaries.

Interior must annually report on the value of land covered by the PILT program, the tax revenue the land would generate if privately owned, and how PILT payments could more accurately reflect that tax revenue.</summary>
</bill>
