<bill session="117" type="h" number="8097" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 51, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to establish an initiative to conduct research, development, and demonstration on technologies capable of reducing both greenhouse gas emissions and noise emissions from aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2022-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2022-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2022-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2022-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4558" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-08T23:27:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act

This bill directs the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish an initiative to research, develop, and demonstrate new technologies and concepts to reduce emissions and noise from aviation. Emissions to be addressed include carbon dioxide (CO2), nitrogen oxides (NOx), water vapor, black carbon, and sulfate aerosols.

The goals and objectives of the initiative shall include

 ensuring U.S. leadership in research and technology innovation leading to substantial reductions in aviation noise and greenhouse gas emissions, a reduction of greenhouse gas emissions from new aircraft by at least 50% as compared to the highest-performing aircraft technologies in service as of December 31, 2021, net-zero greenhouse gas emissions from aircraft by 2050, and demonstrating new technologies developed pursuant to the initiative on regional aircraft intended to enter into service by 2030 and single-aisle aircraft designed to accommodate more than 125 passengers intended to enter into service by 2040.</summary>
</bill>
