<bill session="118" type="h" number="3364" updated="2025-11-19T03:29:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WIC Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIC Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wise Investment in Children Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to increase the age of eligibility for children to receive benefits under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2024-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2024-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001221" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2023-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1604" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-24T20:40:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Wise Investment in Children Act of 2023 or the WIC Act of 2023

This bill expands eligibility for children to receive benefits under the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC).

Specifically, the bill

 extends eligibility for the program until the period that ends on the earlier of the sixth birthday of a child or when the child enters kindergarten; extends the certification period under the program for infants to up to two years, instead of the current one year; and increases the certification time under the program for postpartum women to a period of up to two years. The bill also authorizes the Department of Agriculture to grant a waiver to a state, on request, that waives certification deadline requirements for the eligibility extensions if such state demonstrates there are unusual technological barriers to implementation, operational costs are not affordable within the nutrition services and administration grant of the state, or it is in the best interest of the program.</summary>
</bill>
