<bill session="118" type="s" number="1611" updated="2025-11-19T04:17:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Connect Grant Program Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Connect Grant Program Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to reauthorize the Community Connect Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6473" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-18T22:30:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Connect Grant Program Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 and otherwise modifies the Community Connect Program, which provides grants for high-speed broadband service in rural, economically challenged communities without such service.

In particular, the bill establishes statutory minimum broadband speeds that must be provided under the grants. (Currently, minimum speeds are defined by the Federal Communications Commission.)

Further, the bill specifies that grant funds may not be used to duplicate a service that will be provided in the future pursuant to an enforceable commitment under another broadband funding program. (Currently, grant funds may not be used to duplicate an existing service.)

The bill also makes more areas eligible for grant-funded projects by increasing the broadband service capacity that is considered inadequate.</summary>
</bill>
