<bill session="118" type="h" number="5500" updated="2024-10-03T18:33:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PLACE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Peer Learning for Agriculture Conservation Education Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLACE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an initiative to support peer learning relating to a wide range of agriculture conservation activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-03T18:32:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Peer Learning for Agriculture Conservation Education Act of 2023 or the PLACE Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish an initiative and grant program to support peer learning&#160;projects related to a wide range of agriculture conservation activities. Under the bill, peer learning means an educational experience for agricultural producers or foresters that includes (1) farmer-, rancher-, or forester- led information sharing, education, or training activities; or (2) the provision of farmer-, rancher-, or forester- led technical assistance.

As part of the initiative, USDA must provide at least five grants each fiscal year to support peer learning projects.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
