<bill session="117" type="s" number="312" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Safer Detention Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand eligibility for and provide judicial review for the Elderly Home Detention Pilot Program, provide for compassionate release based on COVID-19 vulnerability, shorten the waiting period for judicial review during the COVID-19 pandemic, and make other technical corrections.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Safer Detention Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Safer Detention Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2022-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Durbin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-06-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="68">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 68.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="929" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3669" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-25T15:48:36Z" status="Reported to Senate">COVID-19 Safer Detention Act of 2021

This bill expands statutory authority for federal prisoners to be released before completing their sentences or to be placed in the community to serve the final portion of their sentences.

First, the bill makes changes to the early release pilot program which authorizes the Bureau of Prisons to release early and place on home confinement elderly offenders and terminally ill offenders who meet eligibility criteria. This bill

 expands eligibility to offenders serving time for an offense under the laws of the District of Columbia, reduces the amount of time an offender must serve by the good time credits earned by the offender, and creates a judicial review process for prisoners. Second, the bill modifies the compassionate release process which authorizes federal courts to reduce a prisoner's sentence and impose a term of probation or supervised released in certain circumstances. This bill

 expands eligibility to prisoners sentenced before November 1, 1987; and specifies that vulnerability to COVID-19 is a basis for compassionate release. Regarding the judicial review of these release authorities, the bill also (1) authorizes federal courts to appoint counsel to assist defendants, (2) applies statutory rights for crime victims to these proceedings, and (3) shortens the waiting period during the COVID-19 pandemic.

Additionally, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to study postrelease, probation, and pretrial services, including recent changes.

Finally, the bill directs the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts to request resources to address staffing needs in each judicial district, including resources that may be necessary as a result of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
