<bill session="118" type="h" number="2975" updated="2024-08-16T13:46:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ENABLE Conservation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminating Needless Administrative Barriers Lessening Efficiency for Conservation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ENABLE Conservation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 with respect to the conservation reserve program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-16T13:45:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Eliminating Needless Administrative Barriers Lessening Efficiency for Conservation Act of 2023 or the ENABLE Conservation Act of 2023 

This bill amends the continuous enrollment procedure for the Conservation Reserve Program (CRP) of the Farm Service Agency. CRP is a land conservation program that provides an annual rental payment to farmers in exchange for removing environmentally sensitive land from agricultural production and planting species that will improve environmental health and quality.

Specifically, the bill permanently allows producers to use the continuous enrollment procedure for land that will be enrolled under the State Acres for Wildlife Enhancement (SAFE) initiative.&#160;(The SAFE initiative restores habitats to meet high-priority state wildlife conservation goals.)&#160;

The bill also allows the Department of Agriculture to grant a waiver to exclude acreage enrolled under the continuous enrollment procedure from a cap that limits the amount of cropland in a county that is permitted to be enrolled in CRP. The government of the county involved must concur with the waiver for it to be granted. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
