<bill session="108" type="s" number="2244" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:07Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Freedom to Fish Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the public's ability to fish for sport, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom to Fish Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2004-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2004-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2004-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3214"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3214-3215" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-04T17:47:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Freedom to Fish Act - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to prohibit any fishery management plan prepared by a Regional Fishery Management Council or the Secretary of Commerce from establishing areas where recreational fishing is prohibited unless: (1) there is clear indication that such fishing in the area is the cause of a specific conservation problem in the fishery; (2) no alternative conservation measures related to recreational fishing will adequately provide for conservation and management of the fishery; (3) the plan provides criteria to assess whether the prohibition provides fishery conservation benefits and requires plan periodic review; (4) the best available scientific information supports the need to close the area to recreational fishing; and (5) the prohibition is terminated as soon as the condition causing the prohibition no longer exists.

Amends the National Marine Sanctuaries Act to direct the Secretary to provide the appropriate Council with the opportunity to revise draft regulations for fishing within the exclusive economic zone as the Council may deem necessary to implement the proposed designation of a national marine sanctuary. Allows such draft regulations to regulate a fishery within a State if: (1) the governor of the State approves the regulations; or (2) the Secretary determines, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, that the State has taken, or failed to take, any action the results of which will substantially and adversely affect the fulfillment of the purposes of such Act and the goals and objectives of the proposed sanctuary designation.</summary>
</bill>
