<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="866" updated="2022-02-03T05:22:48Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3867" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2007-10-30T12:47:03-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-10-30"/>
  <description>Title IV, add at the end the following (and amend the table of contents accordingly):    SEC. __. STUDY ON EFFECTIVENESS OF HUBZONE PROGRAM IN REACHING RURAL AREAS.    The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall carry out a study on the effectiveness of the HUBZone program in reaching rural areas to determine whether there are needy areas that do not qualify under the program and whether there are areas that currently qualify under the program that are inconsistent with the program's original intent. Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study and any recommendations that the Administrator considers appropriate for alternative ways to evaluate eligibility for HUBZones in rural areas.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 110-407 to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to carry out a study on the effectiveness of the HUBZone program in reaching rural areas.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2007-10-30T12:47:03-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Welch (VT) amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T12:41:48-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Welch (VT).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12180-12181" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12180" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T12:41:48-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Welch (VT).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12180-12181" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12180" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T12:47:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30T12:47:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Welch (VT) amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-30">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
