<bill session="110" type="h" number="4158" updated="2023-01-11T20:12:12Z">
  <state datetime="2007-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to clarify and codify the authority of the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to administer the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System for Federal response to all hazards.</title>
    <title type="display">National Urban Search and Rescue Response System Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Urban Search and Rescue Response System Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000461" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001167" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2007-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="4183" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-12-26T19:34:24Z" status="Introduced in House">National Urban Search and Rescue Response System Act of 2007 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to: (1) continue to administer the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System; (2) provide for a national network of standardized search and rescue resources; (3) designate task forces to participate in the System and determine criteria for participation; and (4) enter into an agreement with the required sponsoring agency of each task force regarding participation.

Sets forth provisions regarding the composition of task forces and reimbursement.

Authorizes the Administrator to appoint a System member for a period of federal service to participate in sponsored or sanctioned exercises, pre-incident staging, major disaster and emergency response activities, and training events. Entitles a member who suffers personal injury, illness, disability, or death while acting in the scope of such appointment to be treated as an employee who sustained the injury in the performance of duty.

 Sets forth provisions regarding election of benefits, liability, employment and re-employment rights, and licenses and permits.

Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish and maintain an advisory committee; and (2) enter into an annual preparedness cooperative agreement with each agency; and (3) enter into response cooperative agreements under which the Administrator agrees to reimburse agencies for emegency response costs.</summary>
</bill>
