<bill session="117" type="s" number="3053" updated="2023-09-07T13:00:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 to require the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to develop a plan and national guidance document to improve precipitation estimates, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-07">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="596">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 596.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1437" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T20:15:00Z" status="Reported to Senate">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act or the PRECIP Act

This bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to take actions regarding precipitation estimation.

NOAA shall, no less than every 10 years, update probable maximum precipitation estimates for the United States. NOAA must include specified information in the updates and must make publicly available certain probable maximum precipitation studies developed by NOAA.

NOAA must seek to enter an agreement with the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a study on the state of practice and research needs for precipitation estimation, including probable maximum precipitation estimation.

NOAA, in consideration of the study's recommendations, shall consult with relevant partners on the development of a plan to update probable maximum precipitation estimates.

NOAA shall develop a national guidance document regarding probable maximum precipitation estimates that (1) provides best practices for federal and state regulatory agencies, private meteorological consultants, and other users that perform probable maximum precipitation studies; (2) considers the recommendations provided in the National Academies study; (3) facilitates review of probable maximum precipitation studies by regulatory agencies; and (4) provides confidence in regional and site-specific probable maximum precipitation estimates.</summary>
</bill>
