<bill session="118" type="h" number="410" updated="2025-11-19T04:16:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Care PRICE Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care PRICE Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Prices Revealed and Information to Consumers Explained Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for hospital and insurer price transparency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2023-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2840" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1130" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-08T21:30:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Care Prices Revealed and Information to Consumers Explained Transparency Act or the Health Care PRICE Transparency Act This bill provides statutory authority for requirements for hospitals and health insurance plans to disclose certain information about the costs for items and services. Specifically, hospitals must publish in their list of standard charges certain rates negotiated with insurers, discounts for cash payments, and billing codes. Further, hospitals generally must publish the standard charges for the services provided by the hospital that may be scheduled in advance. Additionally, insurance plans must publish the in-network and out-of-network charges for covered items and services and the negotiated prices for covered prescription drugs. Plans must provide a tool for consumers to search for this cost information. Consumers also may request additional information about the costs of specific items or services under their plans.</summary>
</bill>
