<bill session="117" type="h" number="5582" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:58Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require reporting of bullying to appropriate authorities and assist with equal protection claims against entities who fail to respond appropriately to bullying, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">BRAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bullying Redress And Verified Enforcement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2021-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-26T20:09:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Bullying Redress And Verified Enforcement Act or the BRAVE Act

This bill requires a local educational agency (LEA), in order to receive certain federal education funding, to collect and publish certain information about instances of bullying in schools.

Specifically, the bill requires an LEA employee who becomes aware of bullying to report information about the bullying to an LEA-designated individual within seven business days. The LEA-designated individual must, within 60 days after receiving such a report, inform all of the LEA's employees of the acts described and the response of the LEA's employees.

Additionally, the bill requires each LEA to

 review its policies on bullying on an annual basis, and publish and make available to students and parents a quarterly report that lists the number of bullying reports made since the previous quarterly report and informs the public of the right to file a complaint with the Office for Civil Rights (OCR) within the Department of Education (ED). The bill requires the OCR to (1) establish and publish complaint procedures; (2) investigate each complaint; (3) withhold certain federal funds from, issue a complaint against, or enter into a compliance agreement with any noncompliant LEA; and (4) make information about each complaint available on ED's website.</summary>
</bill>
