<bill session="117" type="s" number="5299" updated="2023-09-11T14:00:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gun Violence Prevention and Community Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gun Violence Prevention and Community Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to end the epidemic of gun violence and build safer communities by strengthening Federal firearms laws and supporting gun violence research, intervention, and prevention initiatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2022-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2022-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3509" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4238" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1825" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2325" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1808" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2377" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3480" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="736" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9624" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-11T13:45:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gun Violence Prevention and Community Safety Act of 2022

This bill makes various changes to the federal framework governing the sale, transfer, and possession of firearms and ammunition. Among other changes, the bill

 generally requires individuals to obtain a license to purchase, acquire, or possess a firearm or ammunition; raises the minimum age&#8212;from 18 years to 21 years&#8212;to purchase firearms and ammunition; establishes new background check requirements for firearm transfers between private parties; creates a statutory process for a family or household member to petition a court for an extreme risk protection order to remove firearms from an individual who poses a risk of committing violence; restricts the import, sale, manufacture, transfer, or possession of semiautomatic assault weapons and large capacity ammunition feeding devices; restricts the manufacture, sale, transfer, purchase, or receipt of ghost guns (i.e., guns without serial numbers); requires federally licensed gun dealers to submit and annually certify compliance with a security plan to detect and deter firearm theft; removes limitations on the civil liability of gun manufacturers; allows the Consumer Product Safety Commission to issue safety standards for firearms and firearm components; establishes a community violence intervention grant program; and promotes research on firearms safety and gun violence prevention.</summary>
</bill>
