<bill session="111" type="s" number="3890" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:22Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend section 310 of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009, to extend the period of time during which claims for retroactive stop-loss special pay may be submitted, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 310 of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009, to extend the period of time during which claims for retroactive stop-loss special pay may be submitted, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5449" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3889" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-09T19:42:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 to extend the period for the submission by members of the Armed Forces of claims for retroactive stop-loss special pay (paid to members whose enlistment or period of obligated service was extended, or whose eligibility for retirement was suspended, by the President in time or war or national emergency) from one to two years after the date on which implementing rules for such payments take effect. Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to include in a required report concerning such payments a plan describing DOD outreach and informational efforts to promote and increase awareness of the special pay.

Provides funding for the outreach and informational efforts, with a funding limit of $10 million.

Requires, in subsequent reports concerning the stop-loss payments, descriptions and assessments of the outreach and informational efforts.</summary>
</bill>
