<bill session="117" type="h" number="8307" updated="2022-12-29T18:05:00Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Steven&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Steven&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require certain medical information related to donors of reproductive tissue be made available to recipients of such tissue and persons conceived using such tissue, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000020"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-20T12:30:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Steven's Law

This bill establishes requirements for collecting and disclosing the medical history of reproductive tissue donors.

Through regulations, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must require reproductive tissue banks to collect, verify, and disclose certain information about a donor's medical history. As part of the regulations, HHS must (1) set out the medical information that a donor must disclose to a tissue bank, including familial medical conditions and the contact information of a medical professional who has examined the donor; and (2) require donors to waive privacy and other protections that limit disclosure of personal health information.

A tissue bank must provide, at no cost, the donor's medical information to the recipient of the donor tissue, the recipient's physician, or a person conceived using the donor tissue (if that person is either 18 years of age or older or has the consent of a parent or guardian).</summary>
</bill>
