<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3939</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:17Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:17Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-11-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssra00</systemCode>
        <name>Rules and Administration Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-11-15T21:42:23Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-11-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssra00</systemCode>
            <name>Rules and Administration Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-11-15</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7902-7907)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-11-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inhofe, James M. [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Inhofe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Budget process</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional officers and employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elections, voting, political campaign regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax credits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax deductions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax exclusion</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tariffs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-11-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-20T22:32:59Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Earmark Reform and Federal Spending Transparency and Accountability Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit, between January 1 of an odd-numbered year and December 31 of the next even-numbered year, an earmark beneficiary from making contributions aggregating more than $5,000 to any requesting candidate with respect to such earmark beneficiary. Defines &quot;requesting candidate&quot; as any Senator or Member who requested a congressionally directed spending item, limited tax benefit, or limited tariff benefit (earmark) which benefits the earmark beneficiary.</p> <p>Prohibits the employees of the personal staff of a Member of Congress, except for one designee, from attending a political fund raiser held on the Member's behalf.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives each to post on the respective public website a link to the earmark database maintained by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).</p> <p>Requires the head of each federal department and agency to post on the respective public website a link to a searchable database that lists each contract, grant, cooperative agreement, and other expenditure made by the department or agency.</p> <p>Amends Rule XLIV (Congressionally Directed Spending and Related Items) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require a Senator requesting an earmark in any legislation or an accompanying joint statement of managers to certify in the required written statement to the chairman and ranking member of the committee of jurisdiction that the earmark recipient is qualified to handle the project.</p> <p>Requires the Comptroller General, in an annual report to Congress, to use the OMB database to: (1) randomly select a percentage of each of the programs and projects funded through earmarks in the preceding fiscal year; (2) audit each selected one; and (3) provide a detailed accounting of how, if it does so, the earmark contributes to an already existing program or project.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Earmark Reform and Federal Spending Transparency and Accountability Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Earmark Reform and Federal Spending Transparency and Accountability Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reform earmarking and increase transparency and accountability for all expenditures authorized by Congress and all executive agencies of the Federal Government.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Earmark Reform and Federal Spending Transparency and Accountability Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-11-15T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3939is/xml/BILLS-111s3939is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-11-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
