<bill session="117" type="h" number="439" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Millennium Challenge Demonstration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a demonstration program to adapt the successful practices of providing foreign aid to underdeveloped economies to the provision of Federal economic development assistance to Native communities in similarly situated remote areas in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Millennium Challenge Demonstration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2021-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000396" joined="2021-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9114" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-08T19:45:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Native American Millennium Challenge Demonstration Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to establish the Native American Millennium Challenge Demonstration Project to provide economic development assistance to remote Native American communities.

Specifically, an eligible entity (e.g., a consortium of Native organizations in a noncontiguous state) must enter into a five-year binding agreement (i.e., a compact) with the United States to receive assistance. Among other elements, the agreement must contain a description of the specific objectives related to sustainable economic development and poverty reduction that the entity expects to achieve.

Further, assistance shall be provided in the form of funding agreements and may not be provided as loans. Additionally, funds may not be used for regulated gaming activities.</summary>
</bill>
