<bill session="111" type="hr" number="281" updated="2022-02-03T06:10:52Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25T15:29:45-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-03-25T15:29:45-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1404) to authorize a supplemental funding source for catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities on Department of the Interior and National Forest System lands, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a cohesive wildland fire management strategy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1404) to authorize a supplemental funding source for catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities on Department of the Interior and National Forest System lands, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a cohesive wildland fire management strategy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-52, by Mr. Polis (CO).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24T17:08:28-04:00">
      <text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The rule provides that the bill shall be considered as read. The rule waives all points of order against provisions in the bill. This waiver does not affect the point of order available under clause 9 of rule XXI. The rule makes in order only those amendments printed in this report. The amendments made in order may be offered only in the order printed in this report, may be offered only by a Member designated in this report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in this report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be suject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for a division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against the amendments except for clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-03-24" calendar="House" number="31">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 31.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25T14:13:41-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3986-3990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25T14:13:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 281.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25T14:51:28-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25T14:51:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 281, the Chair put the question on adoption of agreeing to the resolution, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25T15:20:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3991-3992" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="156" datetime="2009-03-25T15:29:45-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 248 - 175 (Roll no. 156).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3986" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25T15:29:47-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1404" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-25T08:03:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1404) to authorize a supplemental funding source for catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities on Department of the Interior and National Forest System lands, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a cohesive wildland fire management strategy.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-52</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
