<bill session="111" type="s" number="3287" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:15Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Achievements of the GI Bill Gold Medal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to award a Congressional Gold Medal in honor of the recipients of assistance under the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944 (commonly referred to as the "GI Bill of Rights") in recognition of the great contributions such recipients made to the Nation in both their military and civilian service and the contributions of Harry W. Colmery in initiating actions which led to the enactment of that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Achievements of the GI Bill Gold Medal Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4745" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-13T19:34:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Achievements of the GI Bill Gold Medal Act - Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to arrange for the presentation of a single gold medal in honor of the recipients of assistance under the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944 (commonly know as the GI Bill of Rights), in recognition of their great contributions in both their military and civilian life, and the contributions of Harry W. Colmery in initiating actions which led to the enactment of that Act. Requires the medal, following its award, to be given to the Smithsonian Institution for display. Expresses the sense of Congress that the medal should be made available for display elsewhere, particularly at appropriate locations selected by the Secretaries of Veterans Affairs (VA), Defense (DOD), or Education.</summary>
</bill>
