<bill session="118" type="s" number="1612" updated="2025-11-19T03:53:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reimburse Veterans for Domiciliary Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reimburse Veterans for Domiciliary Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to publish a rule to implement the requirement that the Secretary be permitted to waive the limitation in law on reimbursement of veterans receiving domiciliary care in State homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-217.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3368" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-20T22:05:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reimburse Veterans for Domiciliary Care Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to prescribe a rule related to the waiver of certain requirements for the payment of per diem for domiciliary care in a state home. (A state home is a home established by a state for veterans who are disabled by age, disease, or otherwise and are incapable of earning a living because of such disability. The term also includes a home that furnishes nursing home care for veterans.)

Under the bill, the VA must prescribe a rule that authorizes the waiver of certain requirements for a veteran to be eligible for per diem payments for domiciliary care at a state home if the veteran has met at least four of the current requirements or the waiver would be in the best interest of the veteran.

In prescribing the rule, the VA must ensure its authority to provide payments to state homes is retroactive to January 5, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
