<bill session="116" type="h" number="6809" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nurse Workforce Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit health care providers that receive funding through the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund from reducing employment or compensation for certain nurses employed by the provider.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nurse Workforce Protection Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2020-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-16T18:39:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Nurse Workforce Protection Act of 2020

This bill requires health care providers that receive funds made available for provider relief under certain laws enacted to address COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) to maintain nurse staffing levels and prohibits them from taking other actions with respect to nurse compensation and employment for a set period of time after receiving such funds.

Specifically, these providers must retain at least 75% of the nurses employed as of January 31, 2020, for a designated period of time. Additionally, during that period, providers may not reduce nurse pay or hours by more than 25% or require nurses to take paid or unpaid leave. The period of time begins on the date funds are disbursed and lasts two months. However, for providers that made changes with respect to staffing, compensation or leave, the relevant period begins 30 days after the date of disbursement and lasts two months.

Providers that do not meet these requirements must repay the COVID-19 funds that they received.</summary>
</bill>
