<bill session="109" type="h" number="5919" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:34Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Family Choice Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To empower parents to protect children from increasing depictions of indecent material on television.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Choice Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000165" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Subscription television"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-19T21:20:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Choice Act of 2006 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission to adopt rules to protect children from indecent video programming carried by a multichannel video programming distributor (MVPD). Gives MVPDs the option to either: (1) not transmit indecent or profane material in the expanded basic tier between 6 a.m. and 10 p.m.; (2) scramble or block any channel that a subscriber does not wish to receive; or (3) allow a subscriber to subscribe to a family tier of programming (defined as including all channels on the expanded basic tier, except those that carry programs rated TV-14 or TV-MA during those hours). Requires MVPDs that elect to scramble or block channels to issue credit to a subscriber for any channel the subscriber elects to block. Requires MVPDs that elect to provide a family tier to allow a subscriber to obtain the family tier of programming for one or more of the subscriber's reception devices while simultaneously obtaining other tiers for other of the subscriber's reception devices.</summary>
</bill>
