<bill session="109" type="h" number="5568" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:50Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1080-1081"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-06-20T20:40:00Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act - Authorizes the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard to provide financial assistance to members of the District of Columbia National Guard who satisfactorily complete initial active duty service and agree to serve for a period of not less than six years, to assist in them in covering expenses they incur while pursuing their first undergraduate, masters, vocational, or technical degree or certification at an approved institution of higher education. Limits such assistance to up to $400 per credit hour, but not to exceed $5,000 per year.</summary>
</bill>
