<bill session="110" type="h" number="4458" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:39Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Regulatory Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Regulatory Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 6 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Regulatory Flexibility Act), to ensure complete analysis of potential impacts on small entities of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2008-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001171" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2007-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 0.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-02-19T19:48:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Regulatory Improvement Act - Revises the Regulatory Flexibility Act. Defines the "economic impact" of a rule to include any direct or indirect economic effects on small entities.

Requires initial regulatory flexibility analyses of a proposed rule to contain a detailed statement describing the type of small entities to which the proposed rule will apply.

Revises provisions requiring the publication by each agency of a plan for the periodic review of its rules that have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities to determine whether they should be continued, changed, or rescinded, including to: (1) limit to two years the amount of time the period for reviewing an agency's regulations may be extended; and (2) require each agency to report annually on review results to Congress and to the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).

Requires an agency to notify the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration of any draft rules that may have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities either: (1) when the agency submits a draft rule to the such Office, if submission is required; or (2) if no submission to the Office is so required, at a reasonable time before publication of the rule by the agency.

Requires that final regulatory flexibility analyses include the agency's response to any comments filed on a rule by the Chief Counsel and a detailed statement of any changes made as a result.</summary>
</bill>
