<bill session="118" type="h" number="5043" updated="2025-07-08T19:26:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy Soils Healthy Climate Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Soils Healthy Climate Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to create permanent payments within the environmental quality incentives program for soil health practices and carbon sequestration monitoring, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2588" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-21T20:51:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Soils Healthy Climate Act of 2023

This bill modifies the Environmental Quality Incentives Program of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide permanent incentive payments to producers to adopt practices designed to increase organic carbon levels in soil.

USDA must

conduct a study regarding changes in soil health and soil organic carbon levels as a result of the adopted practices;develop ranking and scoring criteria under the program that prioritize soil health practices that score highest in soil carbon sequestration on eligible land;create a soil organic carbon conservation activity plan under the program to measure and monitor sequestration and mitigation improvement levels from the practices;provide for streamlined and coordinated procedures for the program and the Conservation Stewardship Program, including for contracting, conservation planning, conservation practices, and related administrative procedures; andestablish a program to provide grants to land-grant colleges and universities to conduct research relating to soil health and carbon science and to conduct research relating to soil health and carbon science at its agricultural research stations.</summary>
</bill>
