<bill session="118" type="s" number="3952" updated="2025-06-24T09:15:59Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fast Track To and Through College Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fast Track To and Through College Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase rates of college completion and reduce college costs by accelerating time to degree, aligning secondary and postsecondary education, and improving postsecondary credit transfer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2024-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2736" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1719" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-15T15:18:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fast Track To and Through College Act

This bill requires the Department of Education to award grants to certain partnerships with state educational agencies to suppor statewide implementation of early college fast track pathways and early high school graduation fast track pathways.

The bill defines early college fast track pathways as programs of advanced coursework resulting in credit that (1) is equivalent to at least two semesters of full-time postsecondary enrollment, and (2) satisfies the requirements for a high school diploma. In addition, the bill defines early high school graduation fast track pathways as scholarships for students who graduate high school early, do not require remedial coursework in postsecondary education, and attend a public two- or four-year institution of higher education.The bill also makes certain high school students participating in an early college fast track pathway eligible to receive Pell Grants.</summary>
</bill>
