<bill session="116" type="s" number="4245" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:38Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding Internet Freedom in Hong Kong Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Internet Freedom in Hong Kong Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to develop and deploy firewall circumvention tools for the people of Hong Kong after the People's Republic of China violated its agreement under the Joint Declaration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2020-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2020-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-08T15:34:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safeguarding Internet Freedom in Hong Kong Act of 2020

This bill authorizes and establishes programs to promote internet freedom in Hong Kong and contains other related provisions.

The Department of State may establish an interagency working group to develop a strategy to bolster internet resiliency and access in Hong Kong. The State Department shall also establish within the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor a Hong Kong internet freedom program. (The bureau has existing programs to promote internet freedom globally through technology development, digital safety, policy advocacy, and research.)

The Open Technology Fund may establish a Hong Kong internet freedom program. (The fund, an independent nonprofit organization that receives U.S. government funding, was originally a part of Radio Free Asia.)

The bureau and the fund may award grants to qualifying private organizations to promote technology and tools in Hong Kong that promote online information access, enhance digital security, and circumvent internet blocking and other online censorship.

The State Department shall report to Congress a classified strategy to (1) increase the availability of firewall circumvention technology in Hong Kong; and (2) support the preservation of an open, interoperable, reliable, and secure internet in Hong Kong.</summary>
</bill>
