<bill session="117" type="s" number="2658" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that older adults and individuals with disabilities are prepared for disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">REAADI for Disasters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REAADI for Disasters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Emergency Access for Aging and Disability Inclusion for Disasters Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2021-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4938" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-02T20:51:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Real Emergency Access for Aging and Disability Inclusion for Disasters Act or the REAADI for Disasters Act

This bill establishes programs and requirements to assist individuals with disabilities and older adults (age 50 or older) with disaster preparedness.

Among other provisions, the bill

 requires the establishment of an advisory committee that includes disabled individuals and older adults to oversee the use of funds made available by this bill; allows states to contract with Centers for Independent Living to provide services and support to disabled individuals in preparing for hazards; requires the Department of Health and Human Services to award grants to carry out projects of national significance that, among other things, create opportunities for disabled individuals and older adults to directly contribute to disaster preparedness, recovery, and mitigation; modifies and expands the membership of the National Advisory Committee on Individuals with Disabilities and Disasters to ensure that it represents the diversity of the disabled and older adult communities; and establishes the Disability and Disaster Preparedness Advisory Commission to review settlement agreements involving potential violations of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990. The Government Accountability Office must study the compliance of federal agencies with such enactments in expending funds to support disabled individuals and older adults in responding to, recovering from, and mitigating disasters.</summary>
</bill>
