<bill session="119" type="s" number="45" updated="2025-05-22T18:18:00Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce a portion of the annual pay of Members of Congress for the failure to adopt a concurrent resolution on the budget which does not provide for a balanced budget, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-22T18:17:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Balanced Budget Accountability Act

This bill withholds Members of Congress's salaries in each chamber if the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) does not certify that the chamber has adopted a balanced budget.&#160;The bill also requires that revenue increases be agreed upon by an affirmative three-fifths vote in each&#160;chamber.

Balanced budget means a concurrent budget resolution providing that for FY2035 and each succeeding fiscal year to which the resolution applies total outlays do not exceed total receipts and are not more than 18% of the projected gross domestic product for such fiscal year.&#160;

For the 119th Congress, if OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for the next fiscal year before April 16, salaries of Members of that chamber must be held in escrow until passage of a balanced budget or, if none is passed, the conclusion of the 119th Congress.

For subsequent Congresses, if OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for the next fiscal year before April 16, each Member of that chamber shall be paid at the rate of $1 annually for the remainder of the calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
