<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>429</number>
    <updateDate>2019-02-20T22:58:44Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-02-23T20:38:48Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-03-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-03-01T22:57:36Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-10</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001170</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. McCaskill, Claire [D-MO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Claire</firstName>
        <lastName>McCaskill</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aviation and airports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional officers and employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional operations and organization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Currency</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Members of Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Travel and tourism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-03-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-05-05T19:10:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Cleaning Up Congress by Providing Accountability for Congressional Foreign Travel Act - Amends the Mutual Security Act of 1954 to revise requirements with respect to the availability, use, and reporting of foreign currency by Members and employees of Congress.</p>  <p>Requires a review by current authorizing officials of specified travel-related information before approval or denial of any foreign travel authorization or appropriated dollar expenditures in connection with it.</p> <p> Requires each Member or employee provided a per diem to: (1) take necessary actions to reduce costs incurred for such travel, and (2) return to the appropriate chamber any unexpended per diem at the conclusion of the travel, which shall be used for deficit reduction.</p> <p>Prohibits, unless authorized by the appropriate chamber, the receipt of federal funds (including foreign currencies made available under this Act) by any Member of either chamber who is retiring or has been defeated for re-election in a primary. Applies such foreign travel restrictions also to Member's employees, elected officers of both chambers, and committee employees whose employment will terminate at the end of a Congress. Exempts from such restrictions travel to a military installation or a theater of operations of the Armed Forces. Allows a Member or employee to obtain a waiver of such travel restrictions by the authorizing officials.</p>  <p>Requires the chair of each congressional committee and joint committee to prepare and forward to the Clerk of the House or the Secretary of the Senate a consolidated report specifying foreign travel taken by committee Members or employees,which shall be made available on the official public websites of the Clerk and of the Secretary.</p> <p>Authorizes the chair of the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence or the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, in his or her discretion, to omit from the consolidated report any information that would identify the foreign countries in which Members and employees of that Committee traveled.</p> <p>Prescribes and/or revises requirements for Member and employee travel reports.</p> <p>Requires the Comptroller General to study the amount of appropriated funds for official foreign travel by Members, officers, and employees of both chambers, and make recommendations for determining the funding level for such travel which will promote transparency and cost savings.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Cleaning Up Congress by Providing Accountability for Congressional Foreign Travel Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Cleaning Up Congress by Providing Accountability for Congressional Foreign Travel Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Cleaning Up Congress by Providing Accountability for Congressional Foreign Travel Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to improve the reporting requirements relating to foreign travel by members of Congress and the use of foreign currency.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-03-01T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s429is/xml/BILLS-112s429is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-03-10</actionDate>
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
