<bill session="117" type="h" number="9306" updated="2023-07-03T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">States Handling Access to Reciprocity for Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">States Handling Access to Reciprocity for Employment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the use of FBI criminal history record information for administration of interstate compacts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000871"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-03T15:43:58Z" status="Introduced in House">States Handling Access to Reciprocity for Employment Act or the SHARE Act

This bill requires the Federal Bureau of Investigation to make available criminal history record information to a state occupational or professional licensing authority for background checks of individuals seeking a license under an interstate compact.

A state licensing authority may not share criminal history record information with the compact's commission, any other state entity or licensing authority, or the public, but may inform the compact's commission of completion of a background check.</summary>
</bill>
