<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>332</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:20:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:20:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-02-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-02-14T19:34:38Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-02-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-02-14</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S684-685)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-02-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000338</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hatch, Orrin G. [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>ORRIN</firstName>
        <lastName>HATCH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <middleName>GRANT</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000307</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Roberts, Pat [R-KS]</fullName>
        <firstName>PAT</firstName>
        <lastName>ROBERTS</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KS</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-02-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Immigration</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Border security and unlawful immigration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer credit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal procedure and sentencing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Detention of persons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug trafficking and controlled substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Firearms and explosives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immigrant health and welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immigration status and procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Latin America</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Poverty and welfare assistance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social security and elderly assistance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Visas and passports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water use and supply</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women's health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Immigration</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-02-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-02-23T14:38:58Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Strengthening Our Commitment to Legal Immigration and America's Security Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit an alien to be paroled into the United States or granted deferred action of a final order of removal only on a case-by-case basis for urgent humanitarian reasons or significant public benefit.<br> </p> <p>Requires an eligible state, local law enforcement agency, detention center, or correction facility enrolled in the secure communities program or enrolled to perform immigration law enforcement functions to fully comply with such requirements or functions in order to qualify for incarceration compensation.</p> <p>Makes an alien who the consular officer or the Attorney General knows or has reason to believe is a member of a known criminal organization that regularly engages in transnational criminal activity inadmissible to the United States.<br> </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to create a mandatory exit procedure for foreign visitors based upon: (1) the results of U.S. Customs and Border Protection pilot exit programs, and (2) the feasibility and benefits of the departure confirmation systems tested under such programs.</p> <p>Eliminates the diversity visa program. Expresses the sense of Congress that the diversity visa program will be discontinued unless Congress enacts legislation to authorize its continuation with changes to reduce fraud and abuse.<br> </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to report to Congress annually regarding the total amount of federal welfare benefits provided to each state and households with illegal aliens. </p> <p>Amends title XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program) (CHIP) of the Social Security Act to permit a state to continue receiving federal matching funds for covering legal immigrant children and legal immigrant pregnant woman if the state: (1) has covered at least 90% of its U.S. citizen/national children eligible for CHIP or Medicaid (title XIX of the Social Security Act) whose family incomes do not exceed 200% of the federal poverty level; and (2) will provide health benefit coverage to lawfully residing immigrant children or lawfully residing immigrant pregnant women that will not be less than the amount of such funds expended in FY2009. <br> </p> <p>Requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) with respect to an employee's inaccurate social security number to: (1) notify an employer that such a number has been discovered; (2) if the employer does not correct the number, notify the number holder and request clarification, including the possible fraudulent use of such number; and (3) notify specified federal agencies if the holder fails to reply.</p> <p>Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) increase prison penalties for cultivating or manufacturing controlled substances on federal property; and (2) prohibit a person, while cultivating or manufacturing a controlled substance on federal property, from clear cutting timber or diverting or obstructing a stream or body of water. Increases related penalties under the Federal Sentencing Guidelines, including increasing penalties if such violation involves the possession of firearms.</p> <p>Requires the Director of National Drug Control Policy to implement an action plan for keeping controlled substances off federal land.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Strengthening Our Commitment to Legal Immigration and America's Security Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Strengthening Our Commitment to Legal Immigration and America's Security Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote the enforcement of immigration laws and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Strengthening Our Commitment to Legal Immigration and America's Security Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-02-14T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s332is/xml/BILLS-112s332is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-02-14</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
