<bill session="118" type="h" number="6576" updated="2025-11-19T03:45:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Full-Service Community School Expansion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Full-Service Community School Expansion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the full-service community school program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001318" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000585" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2024-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2024-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000273" joined="2024-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2024-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2023-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3360" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-23T14:50:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Full-Service Community School Expansion Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 and expands the Full-Service Community Schools program. The program provides support for full-service community schools that serve children and their families, particularly for children who attend high-poverty elementary and secondary schools.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to award grants to eligible entities to plan, implement, expand, and support full-service community schools. An eligible entity is a consortium of (1) one or more local educational agencies; and (2) one or more community-based organizations, nonprofit organizations, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, Native Hawaiian organizations, or other entities.

A full-service community school is a public elementary or secondary school that incorporates the pillars of community schools. Among other practices, these pillars are defined by the bill as (1) integrated student supports that address out-of-school barriers to learning (e.g., medical care and assistance with housing, transportation, or nutrition); (2) expanded and enriched learning time and opportunities (e.g., before- and after-school programs); (3) student, family, and community engagement (e.g., adult education); and (4) collaborative leadership and practices, which must include a school-based leadership team, a community school coordinator, and a community-wide leadership team.

The bill directs ED to award grants to states to plan, implement, and expand full-service community schools. A state educational agency that receives a grant must meet certain requirements, such as providing subgrants to local educational agencies, establishing a state-level steering committee, and establishing goals for the implementation and expansion of full-service community schools throughout the state.</summary>
</bill>
