<bill session="111" type="h" number="2925" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Communities Building Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for community projects that will reduce the number of individuals who are uninsured with respect to health care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Communities Building Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000676"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001239" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2009-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-10T17:39:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Communities Building Access Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to public or nonprofit private entities to carry out demonstration projects for the purpose of making health care coverage available, on a cost-sharing basis, to: (1) employees through employers that have not contributed to health care benefits for employees during the prior 12 months; and (2) self-employed individuals who have been without such coverage during the prior 12 months.

Requires the Secretary to make matching grants to public or nonprofit private entities to carry out demonstration projects for the purpose of forming and maintaining networks composed of health care specialists who volunteer health services to eligible individuals.

Directs the Secretary to make an award of a grant or contract for the establishment and operation of a clearinghouse for information on demonstration projects under this Act and similar projects that are community initiated. Allows the Secretary to carry out a program to encourage public and private entities that plan or operate such projects to submit information to the clearinghouse.</summary>
</bill>
