<bill session="119" type="s" number="378" updated="2025-05-28T00:49:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expediting Hazard Mitigation Assistance Projects Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expediting Hazard Mitigation Assistance Projects Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Federal Emergency Management Agency to waive certain requirements for property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-28T00:49:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expediting Hazard Mitigation Assistance Projects Act

This bill authorizes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to waive or reduce environmental or historic preservation requirements for property acquisition and structure demolition or relocation projects receiving assistance under certain hazard mitigation programs.

Specifically, this authority applies to such projects receiving funding under FEMA's Hazard Mitigation Grant Program, Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities, or Flood Mitigation Assistance program. The bill authorizes FEMA to waive or reduce environmental and historic preservation requirements for these projects as&#160;FEMA determines appropriate, such as requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 or the National Historic Preservation Act.

Before waiving or reducing such requirements, the bill requires&#160;FEMA to consult with state and local officials, for no more than 30 days, on the necessity of the waiver or reduction. Also, before making such a determination,&#160;FEMA must consider factors including details of the acquisition and demolition or relocation project, the implications for disaster recovery, and whether the waiver or reduction could cause serious environmental issues.

FEMA must report annually to Congress for five years on topics including FEMA's use of its authority under the bill, the extent to which this authority expedited or enhanced the acquisition process under FEMA's programs, and related recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
