<bill session="117" type="h" number="6819" updated="2022-12-30T04:33:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Compact of Free Association Host Communities Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compact of Free Association Host Communities Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To address the growing unreimbursed economic impact costs on communities that receive and host Compact migrants from the Freely Associated States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000396" joined="2022-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-15T19:54:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Compact of Free Association Host Communities Support Act

This bill authorizes various financial waivers for certain U.S. jurisdictions (i.e., states, territories, or possessions) that host citizens of the Marshall Islands, Micronesia, or Palau as residents. (Under current law, citizens of these countries, known as the Freely Associated States, have the right to reside and work in the United States as nonimmigrants or habitual residents.)

Specifically, this bill authorizes a federal agency to, for the purposes of a federal grant, waive any matching funds requirements for a jurisdiction that hosts citizens of the Freely Associated States as residents.

Furthermore, the President may reduce, release, or waive amounts that such a hosting jurisdiction owes to a federal agency, at the request of the hosting jurisdiction. As a condition of receiving such a reduction, release, or waiver, a hosting jurisdiction must report to the Department of the Interior an accounting of the jurisdiction's unreimbursed economic impacts associated with receiving citizens of the Freely Associated States from 2004 through 2021.</summary>
</bill>
