<bill session="108" type="s" number="1769" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Class Action Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for class action reform, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Class Action Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000780"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2003-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2003-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-09T15:06:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Class Action Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal judicial code to require: (1) the portion of any attorney's fee paid to class counsel based on a recovery of coupons in a class action settlement to be based on the value to class members of the coupons redeemed; and (2) the attorney's fee in such a settlement otherwise to be based upon the amount of time class counsel expended working on the action, subject to court approval.

Grants a U.S. district court jurisdiction over a class action in which one-third or fewer of the members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed. Lists grounds under which a U.S. district court may decline to exercise jurisdiction over a class action in which greater than one-third but less than two-thirds of the members of the plaintiff class are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed. Bars a U.S. district court from exercising jurisdiction over a class action (with exceptions) in which: (1) two-thirds or more of the members of all proposed plaintiff classes are citizens of the State in which the action was originally filed; (2) the primary defendants are States, State officials, or other governmental entities against whom the district court may be foreclosed from ordering relief; or (3) the number of members of all proposed plaintiff classes in the aggregate is less than 100.

Allows a class action over which a district court would have jurisdiction under this Act to be removed to a U.S. district court by any: (1) defendant without the consent of all defendants; or (2) plaintiff class member who has intervened, seeks to be designated as a representative class member, and is not a named or representative class member without the consent of all members of such class.</summary>
</bill>
