<bill session="118" type="h" number="5326" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Empowering Local Curriculum Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Local Curriculum Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide rules of construction that nothing in those Acts requires the use, teaching, promotion, or recommendation of any academic discipline, program, or activity that holds that the United States is a Nation founded on white supremacy and oppression, or that these forces are at the root of American society.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001132" joined="2023-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001224" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-08T18:50:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering Local Curriculum Act

This bill specifies that nothing in federal education law shall be construed to require the use, teaching, promotion, or recommendation of any academic discipline, program, or activity that holds certain principles related to race or sex.

These prohibited principles include, for example, that

 the United States is a nation founded on White supremacy and oppression; one race or sex is inherently superior to another race or sex; the United States is fundamentally racist or sexist; any individual should feel discomfort, guilt, anguish, or any other form of psychological distress on account of the individual's race or sex; or meritocracy or traits such as hard work ethic are racist, sexist, or were created by a particular race to oppress another race.</summary>
</bill>
