<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="169" updated="2022-04-01T07:16:23Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4521" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-02-04T10:47:53-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000592"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-02-04"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 260 printed in Part D of House Report 117-241 to amend Title III by broadening Pell Grant eligibility to high-quality short term skills and job training programs and to establish a secure and privacy-protected data system that contains information about postsecondary student academic and economic outcomes.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment amends Title III by broadening Pell Grant eligibility to high-quality short term skills and job training programs and to establish a secure and privacy-protected data system that contains information about postsecondary student academic and economic outcomes.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-02-04T10:47:53-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="29">
      <text>On agreeing to the Levin (MI) amendment (A013) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 193 (Roll no. 29).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04T09:38:45-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A013) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04T09:26:41-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Levin (MI).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H952-959, H960-961" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="H952-958" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04T09:26:41-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Levin (MI).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04T10:47:53-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Levin (MI) amendment (A013) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 193 (Roll no. 29).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04T10:47:53-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Levin (MI) amendment (A013) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 193 (Roll no. 29).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04T10:47:53-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
