<bill session="111" type="h" number="5242" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:12Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Business Disaster Recovery Assistance Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish a disaster recovery assistance program for businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Business Disaster Recovery Assistance Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="General business and commerce matters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-12T20:13:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Business Disaster Recovery Assistance Act of 2010 - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a program to assist a covered entity affected by a major disaster. (Defines "covered entity" to mean a business or private nonprofit organization operating in an area with respect to which the President declared, during the 60-day period preceding the date the entity submitted a grant application, a major disaster under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.)

Authorizes the Administrator to make a grant to a covered entity to assist in: (1) the repair or replacement of the entity's property that was damaged as a direct result of a major disaster; and (2) meeting the entity's ordinary and necessary financial obligations that might not otherwise be met as a direct result of a major disaster.

Limits each grant to $28,000. Directs the Administrator to adjust the limit annually to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Department of Labor.</summary>
</bill>
