<bill session="108" type="h" number="2110" updated="2023-01-15T15:33:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency DNA Backlog Elimination and Self Defense from Serial Killers Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To give priority funding for DNA Backlog Elimination and Self Defense training, prioritizing for States and municipalities that are in the midst of combating a serial killer.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency DNA Backlog Elimination and Self Defense from Serial Killers Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000072" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000006" joined="2003-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency DNA Backlog Elimination and Self Defense from Serial Killers Act of 2003 - Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations and increase grant amounts for analysis and processing of DNA evidence kit backlogs and of DNA samples from convicted offenders and crime scenes. Directs that priority be provided to those municipalities documented by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to possess a serial killer.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2008 for grants to States that are documented by the FBI to possess a serial killer, to eliminate the backlog in carrying out DNA analyses of specified samples. Directs that grant applications include each offense under State law for which a sentence of death or imprisonment at hard labor may be imposed. Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to States documented to possess a serial killer to be used by the State to promote and develop self-defense classes, with not less than 15 percent of the grant amount used for firearms training.Requires the Director of the FBI to establish a Serial Killer Program within its General Criminal Investigative Division.</summary>
</bill>
