<bill session="112" type="h" number="2904" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:25Z">
  <state datetime="2011-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to modernize the integrated public alert and warning system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2011-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2011-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2011-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3563" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2319" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-09-23T15:46:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Modernization Act of 2011 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to modernize and implement the integrated U.S. public alert and warning system to ensure that the President can alert governmental authorities and the civilian population in areas endangered by disasters.

Directs the Administrator, consistent with the final recommendations of the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System Advisory Committee (established by this Act), to: (1) establish common alerting and warning protocols, standards, terminology, and operating procedures for such system; (2) include in such system the capability to adapt the distribution and content of communications on the basis of geographic location, risks, or personal user preferences and to alert individuals with disabilities or limited English proficiency; and (3) ensure that training, tests, and exercises are conducted for such system.

Requires the system to: (1) incorporate multiple communications technologies; (2) be designed to incorporate future technologies for communicating directly with the public, to provide alerts to the largest portion of the affected population feasible, including nonresident visitors and tourists, and to improve the ability of remote areas to receive alerts; (3) promote local and regional partnerships to enhance community preparedness and response; and (4) provide redundant alert mechanisms.</summary>
</bill>
