<bill session="117" type="h" number="154" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RESCUE Act for Black and Community Banks</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide regulatory relief for Black and community banks, to codify the Minority Bank Deposit Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reenergized Economic Sustainability for Community and Urban Entities Act for Black and Community Banks</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESCUE Act for Black and Community Banks</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2021-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2021-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2021-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-05T18:56:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Reenergized Economic Sustainability for Community and Urban Entities Act for Black and Community Banks or the RESCUE Act for Black and Community Banks

This bill establishes programs and requirements related to minority banks, Black banks, community banks, women's banks, and low-income credit unions.

The bill establishes the Office of Black and Community Banks in the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC) to oversee Black and community banks. The OCC and the Securities and Exchange Commission must exempt these banks from specified securities and federal banking regulations in certain circumstances.

The bill also establishes the Minority Bank Deposit Program. The Department of the Treasury must certify a depository institution or credit union upon successful application as a minority bank, a women's bank, or a low-income credit union. Every federal department and agency is directed to implement standards and procedures to ensure the use of such institutions to serve the financial needs of the department or agency.

The Government Accountability Office must study the use of the new markets tax credit, lower-value home mortgages, and blockchain investments.</summary>
</bill>
