<bill session="119" type="s" number="602" updated="2025-09-17T11:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildfire Resilience Through Grazing Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Resilience Through Grazing Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to support research and development of ungulate grazing land management techniques for purposes of wildfire mitigation, fuel reduction, and post-fire recovery.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2025-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2025-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-23T16:13:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wildfire Resilience Through Grazing Research Act

This bill expands the high-priority research and extension areas&#160;at the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to include&#160;the research and development of ungulate grazing land management techniques to promote wildfire mitigation, fuel reduction, and post-fire recovery. (An&#160;ungulate is a hooved grazing mammal.)&#160;

Specifically, the bill allows USDA to provide grants to land-grant institutions for supporting the&#160;research and development of wildfire-related ungulate grazing land management techniques that improve soil health and are compatible with activities that protect against adverse environmental effects. This includes compatibility with activities that&#160;protect against the spread of invasive plant species and disease, soil erosion, water quality degradation, and watershed degradation.

The grants to land-grant universities may also be used to disseminate information to public and private landowners, land managers, and livestock owners regarding these wildfire-related&#160;grazing land management techniques and compatible activities.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
