<bill session="119" type="h" number="372" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drug Testing for Welfare Recipients Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Testing for Welfare Recipients Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain welfare programs to deny benefits to persons who fail a drug test, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-20T22:04:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Drug Testing for Welfare Recipients Act

This bill requires states participating in the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program, the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, and specified public housing programs&#160;to subject&#160;applicants to substance&#160;abuse testing or screening and to deny benefits for individuals who test positive for a controlled substance.

Specifically, states administering these programs must determine whether an adult applicant for benefits has been arrested for a drug-related offense within the past five years. Applicants who have been arrested for such an offense must be tested for at least one controlled substance and must test negative to receive benefits. Applicants who have not been arrested for such an offense must be screened (via an interview, questionnaire, or other instrument) for risk of substance abuse. Applicants determined to be at high risk for substance abuse must be tested for at least one controlled substance and&#160;must test negative to receive benefits.&#160;Applicants who are determined not to be at high&#160;risk&#160;do not have to undergo testing.&#160;

Applicants who test positive for a controlled substance at any point during this process are&#160;ineligible for benefits for one year, until&#160;they complete a treatment program, or until they test negative for the substance, whichever is later.&#160;

Family members and households of individuals disqualified from receiving benefits under these provisions may generally continue to receive support.

States that fail to enforce these provisions are subject to reduced federal funding for these&#160;programs the following fiscal year.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
