<bill session="111" type="s" number="429" updated="2019-11-15T21:44:28Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Agricultural Threats: Safeguarding America's Food for Everyone (EAT SAFE) Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Ending Agricultural Threats: Safeguarding America's Food for Everyone (EAT SAFE) Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the safety of imported food products for the citizens of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2009-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2239-2240"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2240-2242" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-23T21:40:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ending Agricultural Threats: Safeguarding America's Food for Everyone (EAT SAFE) Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) establish food safety and agroterrorism training programs for appropriate federal employees and border patrol agents; (2) hire additional Food Safety and Inspection Service personnel; (3) provide notification of smuggled food products to the public and to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and (4) provide the public with notification of recalled food products.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide notification of smuggled food products to the public and to DHS.

Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to establish civil penalties for failure to present imported meat and poultry products for inspection.

Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require federal certification of food safety labs.

Amends the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 to direct the Secretary, through the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service, to establish a foodborne illness education and outreach grant program.</summary>
</bill>
