<bill session="109" type="s" number="3482" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:39Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Volunteer Vaccine and Countermeasure Corps Development Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of a volunteer corps to aid in the dissemination and distribution of vaccines and other countermeasures during a public health emergency.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Volunteer Vaccine and Countermeasure Corps Development Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-08-08T21:13:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Volunteer Vaccine and Countermeasure Corps Development Act of 2006 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Volunteer Vaccine and Countermeasures Corps to facilitate the distribution and provision of vaccines or other countermeasures to individuals under an influenza vaccination program or a countermeasure distribution program established by the Secretary or a state or local entity.

Directs that the members of the Corps shall be activated by the declaration of a public health emergency. Allows members of the Corps to be used by qualified entities to carry out activities under a national, state, or local influenza vaccination program or other countermeasure distribution program.

Allows the Secretary or a state governor to request assignment of Corps members from a state or territory to participate in a vaccination program or countermeasure distribution program of another state or territory.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a National Identification Card that describes the health-related licensure and certification information of Corps members; and (2) award grants for Corps training, recruitment and retention, and capacity building activities.

Deems a member of the Corps, when performing duties under an activation and assignment by the Secretary upon a declaration of a public health emergency, to be a federal employee for liability purposes.</summary>
</bill>
