<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="156" updated="2024-03-18T20:27:56Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-03-30T11:09:06-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000273"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 25 printed in Part B of House Report 118-30 to require each local unit of the Bureau of Land Management, National Park Service, and Forest Service to develop a plan to disseminate and advertise open civil service positions with functions relating to permitting and natural resources in their offices. Also, each plan shall include outreach to local high schools, community colleges, institutions of higher education, and any other relevant institutions.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires each local unit of the Bureau of Land Management, National Park Service, and Forest Service to develop a plan to disseminate and advertise open civil service positions with functions relating to permitting and natural resources in their offices. Also, each plan shall include outreach to local high schools, community colleges, institutions of higher education, and any other relevant institutions.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-03-30T11:09:06-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="175">
      <text>On agreeing to the Leger Fernandez amendment (A025) Agreed to by recorded vote: 323 - 109 (Roll no. 175).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1673-1674" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T19:49:31-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A025) offered by Ms. Leger Fernandez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1610-1611" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1610" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T19:49:31-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A025) offered by Ms. Leger Fernandez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1610-1611" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1610" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T11:09:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Leger Fernandez amendment (A025) Agreed to by recorded vote: 323 - 109 (Roll no. 175).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1673-1674" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T11:09:06-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T11:09:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
