<bill session="108" type="s" number="412" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Emergency Health Services Reimbursement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Balanced Budge Act of 1997 to extend and modify the reimbursement of State and local funds expended for emergency health services furnished to undocumented aliens.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Emergency Health Services Reimbursement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2003-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2004-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2003-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2003-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2492" label="text  of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="819" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health care fraud"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Local Emergency Health Services Reimbursement Act of 2003 - Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to appropriate $1,450,000,000 for each of FY's 2004 through 2008 for allotments to States for reimbursement of emergency health services furnished to undocumented aliens (presently such appropriations end after FY 2001). Sets forth formulas for the disbursement of funds by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Declares that $957,000,000 shall be allotted based on a percentage of undocumented aliens and $493,000,000 shall be allotted based on numbers of undocumented alien apprehensions (in the six States with the highest number of such apprehensions).Permits a State to receive funds on both accounts. Allows funds to go to States, local governments, hospitals, or other providers in a State, including providers of services received through an Indian Health Service facility (presently funds go only to States). Permits reimbursement to providers for the uncompensated provision of emergency health services to aliens who have been allowed to enter the United States for the sole purpose of receiving such services.Directs the Secretary to ensure that fraudulent payments are not made from allotments under this Act. Allows for the reallotment of unused funds.Declares that this Act constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts.</summary>
</bill>
