<bill session="117" type="s" number="1950" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Iran Sanctions Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose strict conditions on the lifting of sanctions imposed with respect to the Islamic Republic of Iran.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Sanctions Preservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2021-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-01T18:33:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iran Sanctions Preservation Act

This bill restricts the authority of the President to waive U.S. sanctions on Iran.

Specifically, the bill repeals the President's authority to waive sanctions on the purchase of Iranian petroleum or petroleum products or license otherwise sanctionable conduct concerning such purchases.

Furthermore, the President may not remove any Iranian person (including a financial institution) from a list of persons, organizations, and entities that have U.S. sanctions levied against them without certifying to Congress that the person has not engaged in particular conduct, such as supporting terrorism or Iran's nuclear weapons program. In addition, the bill prohibits the removal of the Central Bank of Iran from this list unless there is a Senate-approved treaty between the United States and Iran that addresses Iran's nuclear proliferation, ballistic missile program, and support for terrorism.

The President must also maintain Iran's designation as a jurisdiction of money laundering concern until certifying to Congress that Iran is not engaged in illicit financial activities, nuclear proliferation activities, or ballistic missile development.

The provisions of this bill terminate on the date the Senate approves a treaty between the United States and Iran that addresses Iran's nuclear proliferation, ballistic missile program, and support for terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
