<bill session="116" type="s" number="2915" updated="2022-10-28T02:00:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Veteran Survivors of Domestic and Sexual Violence Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Veteran Survivors of Domestic and Sexual Violence Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to improve the provision of services and benefits from the Department of Veterans Affairs for veterans who experience domestic violence, intimate partner violence, or sexual assault, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2019-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3867" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3224" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-13T15:53:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supporting Veteran Survivors of Domestic and Sexual Violence Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to take actions to improve assistance to veterans who experience domestic violence, intimate partner violence, or sexual assault.

Specifically, the bill requires the VA to implement a program to assist veterans who have experienced or are experiencing domestic violence, intimate partner violence, or sexual assault in accessing VA benefits. The VA shall carry out the program in partnership with domestic violence shelters and programs, rape crisis centers, state domestic violence and sexual assault coalitions, and other appropriate service providers. The bill authorizes the VA to establish local coordinators to provide outreach under the program to effectively assist veterans who have experienced domestic violence, intimate partner violence, or sexual assault.

The VA must consult with the Department of Justice (DOJ) and the Department of Health and Human Services to establish a national task force to develop a comprehensive national program to address domestic violence and sexual assault among veterans by integrating VA facilities, services, and benefits into existing networks of community-based domestic violence and sexual assault services.

The VA must consult with DOJ to conduct a national baseline study to examine the scope of the problem of domestic violence, intimate partner violence, and sexual assault among veterans and spouses of veterans.

Finally, the bill requires the Advisory Committee on Women Veterans to include in its biennial report an assessment of the effects of intimate partner violence on women veterans.</summary>
</bill>
