<bill session="112" type="h" number="3107" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:11Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Crop Risk Options Plan Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to provide producers with the opportunity to purchase crop insurance coverage based on both an individual yield and loss basis and an area yield and loss basis in order to allow producers to cover all or a portion of their deductible under the individual yield and loss policy, to improve the accuracy of actual production history determinations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crop Risk Options Plan Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000182"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-12-06T16:23:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Crop Risk Options Plan Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to: (1) provide an agricultural producer with the option of purchasing additional crop insurance coverage (total coverage option) based on an area yield and loss basis instead of an individual yield and loss basis, (2) trigger additional coverage when area losses reach 10% of normal levels, (3) limit indemnities to the amount of the deductible under the underlying individual policy, and (4) set premium subsidies for the additional coverage at not less than 60%.

 Revises actual production history deteminations from a 10-year average to a 7-year average with the highest and lowest production year dropped from the average.</summary>
</bill>
