<bill session="116" type="h" number="6512" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:12Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Voter Notice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require State and local election officials to conduct public education campaigns to notify individuals of changes in the administration of elections for Federal office in response to emergencies affecting public health and safety, to require the websites of such officials to be fully accessible to individuals with disabilities and to meet best practices established by the National Institute for Science and Technology for ensuring the continuing operation of such websites in the event of emergencies affecting public health and safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Notice Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Notification of Timely Information about Changes in Elections Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2020-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2020-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2020-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2020-08-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001203" joined="2020-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2020-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2020-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2020-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2020-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2020-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-20T16:30:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Voter Notification of Timely Information about Changes in Elections Act or the Voter Notice Act

This bill requires state and local election officials to conduct public education campaigns in the event of changes to federal elections (e.g., methods of voting) due to public health and safety emergencies.

Specifically, the bill requires election officials to notify individuals of changes to federal elections by (1) providing not fewer than one direct mailing to each registered voter; and (2) notifying individuals who are eligible to vote through direct mailings, newspaper advertisements, broadcasting, and social media.

Election officials must ensure their official public websites are accessible to individuals with disabilities, including the blind and visually impaired.

The bill also directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish and regularly update best practices to ensure official public websites of election officials are continuously operating during emergencies. Election officials must ensure their official public websites comply with such best practices.

 The Election Assistance Commission must make payments to states for conducting public education campaigns and operating election websites during emergencies.</summary>
</bill>
