<bill session="117" type="h" number="6171" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CNL Update Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CNL Update Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the competitive need limitation provisions under the Generalized System of Preferences program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000813"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2022-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2022-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2022-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-16T15:02:32Z" status="Introduced in House">CNL Update Act

This bill makes changes to the procedures for competitive need limitations (CNL) and de minimis waivers under the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP) program. CNLs are quantitative ceilings on GSP benefits for each product and beneficiary developing country; a beneficiary developing country loses its GSP eligibility with respect to a product if the CNLs are exceeded and no waiver is granted.

Currently, the President must terminate the duty-free treatment for a product from a beneficiary developing country if (1) imports of a product from a single country reach a specified threshold value, which increases by $5 million each calendar year; or (2) 50% or more of total U.S. imports of a product entering under the GSP come from a single country. This bill revises the annual adjustment amount from $5 million to an amount equal to 6.5%.

Further, the bill sets the annual increase in the de minimis level to 6.5%. Currently, the de minimis level is adjusted each year in increments of $500,000.</summary>
</bill>
