<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1252</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:18:37Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:18:37Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-06-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-09-20T20:39:34Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-03-24T15:24:07Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-06-11T22:03:32Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-296</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 573.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-20</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-296.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-20</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-296.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S6559-6560)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-11</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6558-6559)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000361</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rockefeller, John D., IV [D-WV]</fullName>
        <firstName>JAY</firstName>
        <lastName>ROCKEFELLER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000025</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inouye, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>INOUYE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-06-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000127</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cantwell, Maria [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Maria</firstName>
        <lastName>Cantwell</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-06-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-04-06T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1252, Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21403</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on March 24, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-04-06T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1252, Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21403</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on March 24, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Climate change and greenhouse gases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Ecology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Great Lakes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-06-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-08-18T16:19:48Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends the Oceans and Human Health Act to expand the interagency oceans and human health research program to include coasts and the Great Lakes and to direct the President, through the National Science and Technology Council, to deliver information, products, and services to reduce public health risks, including those related to climate change, and enhance health benefits from the ocean. Revises the program's scope.</p> <p>Requires (current law authorizes) establishment of an oceans and human health advisory panel to assist in the development and implementation of the Oceans and Human Health Initiative.</p> <p>Revises the focus areas of centers of excellence that strengthen the capabilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to carry out its activities related to the ocean's role in human health.</p> <p>Requires extramural research grants under existing provisions to support research to improve understanding of processes within the ocean that may affect human and marine animal health and to explore the potential contribution of marine organisms to medicine and research.</p> <p>Authorizes establishment of a competitive program to recognize highly distinguished external scientists in any area of oceans and human health research and to involve those scientists in collaborative work with NOAA's Oceans and Human Health Initiative.</p> <p>Revises requirements for dissemination of information, and for reporting on the results of the research, assessments, and findings, developed under the Initiative.</p> <p>Extends funding to carry out the Initiative.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-20</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-11-19T17:41:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Oceans and Human Health Act to expand the interagency oceans and human health research program to include coasts and the Great Lakes and to direct the President, through the National Science and Technology Council (NSTC), to deliver information, products, and services to reduce public health risks and enhance health benefits from the ocean.</p> <p>Directs the NSTC, through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, to submit to Congress, within two years after enactment of this Act and every five years thereafter, an update of the 2007 Interagency Oceans and Human Health Research Implementation Plan. Requires that such update define the roles of specified federal agencies to avoid duplication of activities and coordinate federal efforts in support of the research program.</p> <p>Adds surveillance, forecasting, mitigation, prevention, and outreach goals to federal research priorities. Extends the program's scope to atmospheric sciences, food-borne diseases, corals, and shellfish. Authorizes social, economic, and behavioral studies of human health and well-being.</p> <p>Authorizes coordination with interagency working groups of the Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology, through the NSTC, to monitor and reduce marine public health problems, including climate change. Authorizes development of new technologies for detecting and reducing hazards to human health from ocean sources, including genomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and sensors to detect distribution, concentration, toxicity, or virulence of infectious microbes, harmful algae, toxins, and chemical contaminants in ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes waters, sediments, organisms, and seafood. Requires the NSTC to submit to the President and Congress a biennial report (currently, an annual report), including funding recommendations.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Requires the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to establish an Oceans and Human Health Program (OHHP) to coordinate certain activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including forecasting long term health impacts, surveillance of public health threats, risk assessment, and development of ocean health products and services. Directs NOAA to develop a strategic implementation plan. Requires the OHHP to support: (1) centralized research coordination; (2) an external advisory panel; (3) NOAA national centers of excellence; (4) diagnostic laboratories; (5) transition of discoveries from research activities into applications; (6) research grants; and (7) distinguished scholars and training. Extends advisory group membership to public health professionals and veterinarians. Revises focus of NOAA centers of excellence to areas defined in this Act.</p> <p>Authorizes establishment of a competitive program to recognize highly distinguished external scientists in any area of oceans and human health research and to involve those scientists in collaborative work with NOAA's OHHP. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to coordinate among OHHP, the Integrated Ocean Observing System, Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia Program, and NOAA to develop specified forecasting systems and avoid duplication of activities. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on NOAA's plans to implement recommendations of its Science Advisory Board Working Group on Oceans and Health.</p> <p>Permits NOAA to: (1) accept and use federal, state, and private funds and in-kind contributions; (2) apply for and hold patents and receive royalties; and (3) accept reimbursement for sharing personnel and facilities with public and private partners.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Revises requirements for dissemination of information, and for reporting on the results of the research, assessments, and findings, developed under OHHP.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations for FY2010-FY2014.<br> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote ocean and human health and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Oceans and Human Health Reauthorization Act of 2010</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-20T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-06-11T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s1252is/xml/BILLS-111s1252is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-20</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 573.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
