<bill session="117" type="s" number="2774" updated="2022-12-31T05:35:17Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 35, United States Code, to address patent ownership, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Pride in Patent Ownership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pride in Patent Ownership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6589" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-20T16:23:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pride in Patent Ownership Act

This bill requires disclosure of certain patent-related information, including information about ownership and funding.

Under the bill, if a foreign or domestic governmental entity provides funding for fees related to a patent application or for paying an attorney (or patent agent) to prosecute the patent application, the application must disclose the amount and source of such funding.

Similarly, if any governmental entity provides funding for paying a patent's maintenance fees or for paying an attorney (or patent agent) to submit such maintenance fees, the patent owner must submit a statement disclosing the amount and source of such funding.

The bill also requires patent owners to record information about the ownership of a patent with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO). Patent owners must also update this information when certain rights or interests in the patent have been conveyed to another individual or entity. A patent owner may not receive increased monetary damages for infringement of that patent that occurred while the owner was out of compliance with this ownership information recordation requirement.

The USPTO must make this ownership information publicly available.</summary>
</bill>
