<bill session="118" type="s" number="1356" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ASSESS AI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ASSESS AI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assuring Safe, Secure, Ethical, and Stable Systems for AI Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a task force on organizational structure for artificial intelligence governance and oversight.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="778" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-29T23:13:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Assuring Safe, Secure, Ethical, and Stable Systems for AI Act or the ASSESS AI Act

This bill directs the President to appoint a task force to assess the privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties implications of artificial intelligence (AI).

The task force shall

 assess existing policy, regulatory, and legal gaps for AI applications and associated data; and make recommendations to Congress and the President for legislative and regulatory reforms to ensure that uses of AI and associated data in federal government operations comport with freedom of expression, equal protection, privacy, civil liberties, civil rights, and due process. The task force may (1) engage with representatives from a private sector organization, subject to specified requirements; and (2) recommend to Congress the creation of a similar task force focused on another emerging technology.

The task force shall terminate 18 months after its establishment.</summary>
</bill>
