<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="808" updated="2022-02-25T17:32:36Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5122" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-05-10T18:45:42-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000448"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-05-10"/>
  <description>Amendment, as modified, expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should continue to provide space-available travel on military aircraft for humanitarian reasons to Iraqi children who would otherwise have no means available to seek urgently needed medical care such as that provided by a humanitarian organization in Amman, Jordan.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 6 printed in House Report 109-459 to make certain findings concerning humanitarian support for Iraqi children in urgent need of medical care; authorizes, within the amount provided in section 301 for Operation and Maintenance, $1 million for DoD support of the Peace Through Health Care Initiative, and reduces by $1 million the amount provided for Budget Activity 4 noting the presence of operational unobligated balances.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-05-10T18:45:42-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Franks (AZ) amendment (A006) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2467" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10T18:35:48-04:00">
      <text>Franks (AZ) amendment (A006) modified by unanimous consent. In the text proposed to be inserted by the amendment, insert "due to operational unobligated balances" before the period at the end.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10T18:35:40-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Franks (AZ).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2467-2468" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2467" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10T18:35:40-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Franks (AZ).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2467-2468" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2467" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10T18:45:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Franks (AZ) amendment (A006) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2467" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10T18:45:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
