<bill session="117" type="h" number="1934" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:36Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-14T18:05:20-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-14T18:05:20-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting United States International Leadership in 5G Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting United States International Leadership in 5G Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting United States International Leadership in 5G Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Government to provide assistance and technical expertise to enhance the representation and leadership of the United States at international standards-setting bodies that set standards for equipment, systems, software, and virtually defined networks that support 5th and future generations mobile telecommunications systems and infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2021-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2021-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000479" joined="2021-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21T15:59:58-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Manning moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21T16:01:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5707-5709" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21T16:01:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1934.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21T16:11:10-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T17:57:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6605-6606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="351" datetime="2022-07-14T18:05:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 20 (Roll no. 351).</text>
      <reference ref="06/21/2022 CR H5707-5708" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T18:05:21-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="687" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1169" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3524" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4112" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-19T13:51:48Z" status="Passed House">Promoting United States International Leadership in 5G Act of 2021

This bill requires actions to increase U.S. influence in international organizations that develop and set standards for wireless telecommunications, such as fifth-generation (5G) technology, and to address the role of China's government in such standards-setting organizations. (Such organizations, with the involvement of stakeholders such as equipment manufacturers, develop and set standards for certain technologies to ensure interoperability between different companies' products.)

The President must establish an interagency working group to work with allies and international partners to increase and align their engagement in standards-setting organizations, such as the International Telecommunication Union, that address standards and issues pertaining to communications networks, including 5G technology.

The Department of State must, in coordination with the working group, develop and implement a strategy to work with allies and partners and monitor efforts by China's government (and affiliated entities) to control or influence such organizations.

The working group must provide a briefing to Congress on (1) a strategy for diplomatic engagement with allies and partners to cooperate on addressing security risks in 5G and future generation mobile telecommunications systems, and (2) the presence and activities of China's government in international standards-setting organizations.</summary>
</bill>
