<bill session="116" type="s" number="4760" updated="2023-07-07T19:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">The PASTEUR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The PASTEUR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Pioneering Antimicrobial Subscriptions To End Up surging Resistance Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program to develop antimicrobial innovations targeting the most challenging pathogens and most threatening infections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2020-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8920" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T16:36:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">The Pioneering Antimicrobial Subscriptions To End Up surging Resistance Act of 2020 or The PASTEUR Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to enter into subscription contracts for critical-need antimicrobial drugs, provides $11 billion in appropriations for activities under the bill, and contains other related provisions.

A manufacturer of a Food and Drug Administration-approved antimicrobial drug may apply to HHS to have the drug designated as a critical-need antimicrobial, and HHS may enter into a subscription contract for such a critical-need antimicrobial. The bill imposes certain requirements related to such contracts, including a mechanism to lower payments under the contract in certain instances to limit the manufacturer's revenue from the drug.

Furthermore, HHS and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall award grants to support efforts to encourage the appropriate use of antimicrobial drugs and efforts to combat antimicrobial resistance.

HHS shall also establish a Committee on Critical Need Antimicrobials. The committee shall develop a list of prioritized infections for which new antimicrobial drug development is needed, among other duties.

Within six years of the bill's enactment, the Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress a study on the bill's effectiveness in developing priority antimicrobial drugs.</summary>
</bill>
