<bill session="118" type="h" number="1364" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Science-Based Grizzly Bear Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Science-Based Grizzly Bear Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to reissue a final rule relating to removing the Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem population of grizzly bears from the Federal list of endangered and threatened wildlife and to issue a new rule removing the Northern Continental Divide Ecosystem population of grizzly bears from such list.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2023-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000633" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2023-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2023-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1419" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-03T15:57:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Science-Based Grizzly Bear Management Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to reissue the final rule relating to removing the Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem population of grizzly bears from the Federal List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife, published on June 30, 2017 (82 Fed. Reg. 30502), without regard to any other provision of statute or regulation that applies to issuance of such rule. Such reissuance shall not be subject to judicial review.

Interior shall issue a final rule removing the Northern Continental Divide Ecosystem population of grizzly bears from the Federal List of Endangered and Threatened Wildlife without regard to any other provision of statute or regulation that applies to the issuance of such rule. Such issuance shall also not be subject to judicial review.</summary>
</bill>
