<bill session="116" type="s" number="3337" updated="2022-02-08T23:22:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Aviation Accountability Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Aviation Accountability Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require more accountability in the airline industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2020-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-22T17:42:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Aviation Accountability Act of 2020

This bill addresses safety standards for the aviation industry.

Among other provisions, the bill

 directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to revise its Executive Compensation Plan to ensure that no pay, bonus, or other compensation for an officer or employee of the FAA is contingent on delivery of airplanes, the number of aircraft certified, or the number of audits completed; establishes an independent aircraft type certificate review panel to review aircraft type certificates; sets forth requirements of the aircraft certification process for domestic and international aircraft sales; extends whistleblower incentives and protections in the aviation industry for employees, contractors, and subcontractors of aircraft manufacturers, aircraft repair stations, and the FAA by providing whistleblowers with access to court for a jury trial and monetary incentives; prohibits the FAA from granting an exemption for the use of a non-motion training device to replace a full motion simulator for validation, qualification, checking, or evaluation events, and significant training leading up these events; requires the Department of Transportation to establish a commission to study and make recommendations regarding the organization designation authorization program, including the effectiveness of the program in prioritizing passenger safety; and directs the FAA to implement specific recommendations set forth in the Boeing 737 MAX Flight Control System Joint Authorities Technical Review.</summary>
</bill>
