<bill session="111" type="h" number="4261" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:58Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to provide additional procedures for congressional oversight.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to provide additional procedures for congressional oversight.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2010-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Senate Select Committee on Intelligence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-24T15:02:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to direct the President to provide to the congressional intelligence committees all information necessary to assess the lawfulness, effectiveness, cost, benefit, intelligence gain, budgetary authority, and risk of an intelligence activity.

Requires information or material concerning covert actions and actions other than covert actions to be made available to each member of such committees, unless the President requests in writing that access be limited to meet extraordinary circumstances affecting vital U.S. interests. Allows the chair and ranking member of each committee to jointly determine whether and how to limit such access. Requires information or material so limited to be made fully available to each committee member at the earliest possible time, and to include the reasons for not providing prior access.</summary>
</bill>
