<bill session="118" type="s" number="878" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness in Fentanyl Sentencing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Fentanyl Sentencing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to modify the offenses relating to fentanyl, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2023-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T17:04:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness in Fentanyl Sentencing Act of 2023

 This bill modifies the drug quantity thresholds that trigger a mandatory minimum prison term for a defendant who manufactures, distributes, imports, exports, or possesses with intent to distribute fentanyl.

Specifically, the bill reduces from 400 to 20 grams the fentanyl quantity and from 100 to 5 grams the fentanyl analogue quantity that trigger a mandatory minimum prison term for high-level first-time or repeat offenders. It also reduces from 40 to 2 grams the fentanyl quantity and from 10 to 0.5 grams the fentanyl analogue quantity that trigger a mandatory minimum prison term for low-level first-time or repeat offenders.

Additionally, the bill directs the U.S. Postal Service to increase the availability of chemical screening devices and dedicate the appropriate number of personnel to interdict fentanyl and other substances that are unlawfully imported into the United States.</summary>
</bill>
