<bill session="111" type="h" number="1479" updated="2022-02-03T06:09:03Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Reinvestment Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Insurance Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="display">Community Reinvestment Modernization Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the availability of capital, credit, and other banking and financial services for all citizens and communities, to ensure that community reinvestment requirements are updated to account for changes in the financial industry and that reinvestment requirements keep pace as banks, securities firms, and other financial service providers become affiliates as a result of the enactment of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001060" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000602" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000210" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000609" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2009-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000283" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2009-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001173" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001148" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2009-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2009-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2009-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000794" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-12T22:14:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Reinvestment Modernization Act of 2009 - Repeals specified revisions to regulations governing the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision.

Reinstates banking agency regulations in effect before the publication of such revisions.

Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (BHCA) to subject to the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (CRA) nonbank affiliates of bank holding companies that offer banking products or services, including insurance companies and securities firms.

Amends the CRA to subject to a rating reduction any regulated financial institution engaged in negative credit practices or securitization activities, including predatory and discriminatory lending.

Amends the Equal Credit Opportunity Act to require a depository institution, in connection with a small business credit application, to: (1) inquire whether the business is a women- or minority-owned business; and (2) maintain a record of the responses to such inquiry.

Requires a depository institution to maintain records of the number and dollar amounts of customer deposit accounts for each deposit taking service facility.

States that securities companies, mortgage banks, and insurance companies have a continuing affirmative obligation to meet the financial services needs in their assessment areas, including the needs of low- and moderate-income neighborhoods and persons of modest means.

Amends the BHCA to require affiliates of securities companies, mortgage banks, and insurance companies to attain satisfactory ratings in accordance with this Act.

Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to reaffirm that covered credit unions have a continuing and affirmative obligation to meet the needs of their assessment areas (including minority and low- and moderate-income neighborhoods).

 Directs the National Credit Union Administration Board (NCUAB) to prescribe regulations for evaluating a covered credit union's record of meeting such obligations.



Insurance Disclosure Act - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to: (1) establish requirements for insurers to submit information annually about noncommercial insurance, rural insurance, and investments by insurers; and (2) make such information public.

Directs the Financial Institutions Examination Council to maintain a hierarchical database containing the structure of financial holding companies, bank holding companies, depository institutions, and non-depository institutions.

Amends the BHCA to authorize certain expanded financial activities by a bank holding company only if it has neither been adjudicated in federal court, nor entered into a consent decree or settlement agreement premised upon a violation of the Fair Housing Act (antiredlining requirement).

Requires: (1) notice and public comment before establishment of a financial holding company; (2) public meetings regarding bank acquisitions and mergers; and (3) a public comment period regarding branch closures.

Amends Federal Deposit Insurance Act, the National Bank Consolidation and Merger Act, and the Home Owners' Loan Act with regard to mandatory meetings involving commenters and financial institutions.







Amends the CRA to subject regulated financial institutions, regardless of size or aggregate assets, to mandatory biennial examinations.

Amends the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 to prohibit regulatory exemptions from its reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
