<bill session="117" type="h" number="4191" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restore certain non-monetary Federal benefits to surviving spouses, eligible for the Gold Star lapel button, who remarried, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Gold Star Spouses Non-Monetary Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold Star Spouses Non-Monetary Benefits Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001054" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2021-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2021-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2022-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2021-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2021-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-22T17:48:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Gold Star Spouses Non-Monetary Benefits Act

This bill addresses certain federal benefits for surviving spouses of members of the Armed Forces, including those who have remarried.

For purposes of noncompetitive appointment to government employment, a surviving spouse of a member of the Armed Forces who was married to such member at the time they died while on active duty may be appointed as a military spouse, regardless of remarriage. Additionally, widows or widowers of certain veterans who served on active duty must be considered preference eligible for purposes of government employment, regardless of remarriage.

A surviving spouse who is eligible for the gold star lapel button is entitled to commissary and exchange privileges to the same extent and on the same basis as the surviving spouse of a retired member of the uniformed services. Such spouses are also entitled, upon request, to medical and dental care provided in facilities of the uniformed services.

A surviving spouse who is eligible for a gold star lapel button must be permitted to use commissary stores and certain retail facilities on the same basis as a dependent of a member of the Armed Forces on active duty.

In regard to Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) benefits, the remarriage of a surviving spouse of a veteran does not bar the furnishing of non-monetary benefits to a surviving spouse who is eligible for a gold star lapel button. Such surviving spouses who are eligible for a gold star lapel button are also eligible for certain VA home loan programs.</summary>
</bill>
