<bill session="118" type="h" number="10042" updated="2025-07-25T19:20:52Z">
  <state datetime="2024-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PASTURES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PASTURES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Agricultural Spaces Through Effective Ranching Strategies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the ability of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to penalize an owner of livestock for grazing by such livestock on certain Federal lands on which grazing is permitted on or after the date of enactment of this Act and subsequently prohibited, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T19:18:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Agricultural Spaces Through Effective Ranching Strategies Act or the PASTURES Act

This bill&#160;prohibits&#160;the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior from imposing penalties on livestock owners for grazing on certain public lands.&#160;

Under the bill, covered lands are National Forest System lands, lands administered by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, or public lands (1) on which&#160;grazing is allowed by a permit or lease on or after the date of the bill's enactment and is then subsequently prohibited, and (2) that border private property.

Specifically, the departments may not impose a penalty on an owner of livestock (including cattle, bison, horses, sheep, and goats) for grazing on covered lands that do not have a fence to prevent grazing.

The bill specifies that USDA or Interior, depending on the covered land, is responsible for any expense related to the construction or maintenance of a fence for the prevention of grazing by livestock.</summary>
</bill>
