<bill session="117" type="s" number="1644" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:13Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promising Pathway Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish a time-limited provisional approval pathway, subject to specific obligations, for certain drugs and biological products, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promising Pathway Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2021-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3761" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8588" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-16T15:02:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promising Pathway Act

This bill establishes a provisional approval pathway for medicines intended for serious or life-threatening diseases, including illnesses posing a threat of epidemic or pandemic. The period of the provisional approval is for two years and is potentially renewable.

The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) must establish a priority review system to evaluate completed provisional approval applications within 90 days of receipt. A provisional approval application may be approved if the FDA determines that (1) there is substantial evidence of safety for the drug; and (2) there is relevant early evidence of efficacy, based on adequate and well-controlled investigations.

During the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic, or another epidemic or pandemic, the FDA must accept and review various portions of a provisional approval application on a rolling basis.

The manufacturer of a provisionally approved drug must require patients to participate in an observational registry. A manufacturer that fails to comply with registry requirements is subject to civil penalties.

A provisionally approved drug must be labeled as such.

If a drug that receives provisional approval status is not brought to market within 180 days of the approval, the approval must be rescinded.

The bill also limits the liability of a manufacturer of a provisionally approved drug with respect to any claim under state law alleging that the drug is unsafe or ineffective.

Private health insurers and federal health care programs shall not deny coverage of a provisionally approved drug on the basis of it being experimental.</summary>
</bill>
