<bill session="117" type="s" number="3882" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:30Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP PUTIN Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP PUTIN Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Top Oil Producers and Protect Ukraine from Tyrannical Invasions Now Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the End-User Review Committee to conduct quarterly reviews with respect to the inclusion of certain Russian energy entities on the Entity List.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-28T13:56:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Top Oil Producers and Protect Ukraine from Tyrannical Invasions Now Act of 2022 or the STOP PUTIN Act of 2022

This bill requires the End-User Review Committee to review whether specified Russian energy entities should be added or removed from the Entity List. The Entity List identifies entities reasonably believed to be involved in, or to pose a significant risk of being or becoming involved in, activities contrary to the national security or foreign policy interests of the United States.

The committee must conduct the review within 15 days of this bill's enactment and every 90 days thereafter.

The bill specifies that an entity may be removed from the Entity List only by an act of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
