<bill session="119" type="h" number="1880" updated="2025-11-18T17:54:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Broadcast Freedom and Independence Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadcast Freedom and Independence Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify that the Federal Communications Commission may not take action against a broadcast licensee or any other person on the basis of viewpoint, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000381" joined="2025-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2025-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001232" joined="2025-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001226" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2025-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001230" joined="2025-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="867" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-28T13:46:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadcast Freedom and Independence Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from taking action against or imposing certain conditions on individuals on the basis of viewpoints broadcast or disseminated by the individuals or their affiliates.&#160;

Specifically, the FCC may not revoke a license or authorization of, or otherwise take action against, an individual or entity on the basis of viewpoints broadcast or otherwise disseminated by the individual or entity or an affiliate thereof. Further, the FCC may not impose conditions on its approval of certain transactions on the basis of viewpoints broadcast or otherwise disseminated by the individual or entity seeking approval of the transaction, or an affiliate thereof.&#160;

Under the bill, the FCC retains its authority to take action or impose conditions on the basis of (1) violations of certain existing laws regarding lottery information, fraud, and obscene language; or (2)&#160;the broadcast or other dissemination of content that constitutes incitement under the First Amendment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
