<bill session="116" type="h" number="9043" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Online Terrorism Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Online Terrorism Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require social media companies to establish an office dedicated to identifying and removing violent or extremist content associated with or distributed by any entity identified as a terrorist organization.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8323" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-26T16:44:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Online Terrorism Prevention Act

This bill requires each social media company to establish an office to identify and remove violent or extremist content associated with or distributed by a terrorist organization. In addition, the bill requires enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission and authorizes enforcement by state attorneys general and the Federal Bureau of Investigation.

A social media company is any person with annual revenues in excess of $10 million generated from owning, managing, or operating a website or internet medium that allows a person to establish an account or create a profile to create, share, and view user-generated content.</summary>
</bill>
