<bill session="116" type="h" number="3774" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">The Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer Improvements Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the Small Business Innovation Research program and Small Business Technology Transfer program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer Improvements Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2019-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001309" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2019-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2019-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-24T18:14:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer Improvements Act of 2019

This bill modifies the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs administered by the Small Business Administration (SBA).

Specifically, the bill

 requires the Department of Defense to report on the goals and incentives used to increase awards of SBIR and STTR contracts; prioritizes innovation in manufacturing and cybersecurity; directs federal agencies to issue Phase III awards to technology developers without requiring further competition; requires agencies' senior procurement executives to coordinate with SBIR and STTR program officers to assist small businesses; requires the SBA to conduct outreach efforts at minority institutions and Hispanic-serving institutions; makes permanent (as the Civilian Agency Commercialization Readiness Program) the pilot program that a covered agency may establish for awarding SBIR and STTR Phase II and III funds for technology development and progression toward commercialization; requires all agencies participating in the SBIR program to establish a Commercialization Assistance Pilot Program to make SBIR Phase II awards to commercialize a project undertaken by a small business with SBIR Phase I awards; authorizes specified agencies to use a percentage of STTR funds for a Proof of Concept Partnership pilot program to accelerate the creation of small businesses and the commercialization of research innovations; and authorizes all agencies participating in the SBIR program, during FY2020-FY2024, to provide a SBIR Phase II award for a project to a small business concern without regard to whether such concern was provided a Phase I award for such project.</summary>
</bill>
