<bill session="118" type="s" number="3428" updated="2025-11-19T03:51:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEFUND Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEFUND Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disengaging Entirely From the United Nations Debacle Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to terminate the membership by the United States in the United Nations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2024-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6645" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-18T01:22:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disengaging Entirely From the United Nations Debacle Act of 2023 or the DEFUND Act of 2023

This bill directs the President to terminate U.S. membership in the United Nations (U.N.) and all affiliated bodies. It also ends U.S. participation in all U.N. conventions and agreements.

Funds may be appropriated to facilitate U.S. withdrawal from the U.N. No funds may be made available for contributions or payments to any U.N. body.

The bill prohibits U.S. participation in any U.N. peacekeeping operation.

The bill also repeals diplomatic immunity for officers and employees of the U.N. and for officers and employees of foreign government missions to the U.N.

The bill repeals various acts related to the U.N., including the United Nations Participation Act of 1945, the United Nations Headquarters Agreement Act, and a joint resolution establishing U.S. membership in the World Health Organization.

The United States may not rejoin the U.N. or any affiliated body without the advice and consent of the Senate. Any agreement to rejoin the U.N. or an affiliated body must include the right of the United States to withdraw from the agreement.</summary>
</bill>
