<bill session="108" type="s" number="793" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:13Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for increased energy savings and environmental benefits through the increased use of recovered mineral component in federally funded projects involving procurement of cement or concrete.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for increased energy savings and environmental benefits through the increased use of recovered mineral component in federally funded projects involving procurement of cement or concrete.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-198.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="394">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 394.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minerals"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-12-03T22:11:40Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and each agency head to implement fully all procurement requirements and incentives, including Federal procurement guidelines, that provide for the use of cement and concrete incorporating recovered mineral component in cement or concrete projects.

Requires each agency head to give priority to achieving greater use of recovered mineral component in cement or concrete projects for which recovered mineral components historically have not been used or have been used only minimally.

Instructs the Administrator, in cooperation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Energy, to study and report to Congress on the extent to which current procurement requirements may realize energy savings and environmental benefits attainable with substitution of recovered mineral component in cement used in cement or concrete projects.

Instructs the Administrator to establish criteria (including an evaluation of whether to establish a numerical standard for concentration of lead and other hazardous substances) for the safe and environmentally protective use of granular mine tailings from the Tar Creek, Oklahoma, Mining District, known as "chat," for: (1) cement or concrete projects; and (2) transportation construction projects (including transportation construction projects involving the use of asphalt) that are carried out, in whole or in part, using Federal funds.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-198</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
