<bill session="119" type="h" number="2051" updated="2025-10-02T13:46:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coast Guard Sustained Funding Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coast Guard Sustained Funding Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 14, United States Code, to make appropriations for Coast Guard pay in the event an appropriations Act expires before the enactment of a new appropriations Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-02T13:45:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Coast Guard Sustained Funding Act of 2025 

This bill provides continuing appropriations to the Coast Guard for pay and benefits when there is a Coast Guard-specific funding lapse.

Under the bill, a&#160;Coast Guard-specific funding lapse occurs when a bill providing appropriations for the Coast Guard for a fiscal year has not been enacted before the beginning of that fiscal year, and no joint resolution providing continuing appropriations for the Coast Guard is in effect.

If a Coast Guard-specific funding lapse occurs, the bill provides appropriations to the Coast Guard for (1) pay and allowances for military members of the Coast Guard, including reserve components, who perform active service or inactive-duty training; and (2) pay and benefits for certain civilian and contract employees who are providing support to members of the Coast Guard or another Armed Force and are working during the funding lapse.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
