<bill session="116" type="s" number="3041" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:57Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VHA CRED Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Administration Caregiver Retention and Eligibility Determination Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VHA CRED Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that medical professionals employed by the Veterans Health Administration are properly credentialed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2019-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-18T18:45:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Health Administration Caregiver Retention and Eligibility Determination Act of 2019 or the VHA CRED Act of 2019

This bill requires the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to prescribe regulations, administrative guidance, and management controls applicable to the credentialing of certain appointed health care positions. Under the bill, VHA personnel who verify credentials for appointees, review qualifications for such persons, or hire such persons must undergo periodic training to review relevant law and policy regarding provider qualifications for VHA employment.

The bill requires the VHA to enroll health care appointees in continuous query of their record within the National Practitioner Data Bank. The VHA must also develop and implement a mechanism for monitoring the continuous query and updating information within the VA's credentialing system.

At least once a year, the VHA must audit its appointed health care employees who have an adverse action reported on the National Practitioner Data Bank.</summary>
</bill>
