<bill session="116" type="h" number="5607" updated="2022-02-09T01:42:25Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Food Recovery Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a grant program to make grants to eligible local educational agencies to carry out food waste reduction programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Food Recovery Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2020-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2020-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5841" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5861" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-17T14:22:40Z" status="Introduced in House">School Food Recovery Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide competitive grants and technical assistance for local educational agencies to implement food waste measurement and reporting, prevention, education, and reduction projects.

In awarding grants, USDA must give priority to agencies that agree to use grant funds for carrying out specific projects, including (1) experiential education activities that encourage children enrolled in such agencies to participate in food waste measurement and education; and (2) the establishment of food waste measurement, prevention, and reduction projects with long-term sustainability.

The federal share of project costs may not exceed 75% of the total cost of carrying out such projects.</summary>
</bill>
