<bill session="119" type="h" number="201" updated="2025-11-19T03:21:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Employee Performance and Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employee Performance and Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement a 5-year pilot program establishing a performance-based pay structure for certain Federal employees in order to enhance productivity, accountability, and employee satisfaction in public service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000478"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="359" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-10T16:22:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Employee Performance and Accountability Act of 2025

This bill establishes a pilot program making pay increases for certain federal employees contingent on job performance.

Under the bill, each executive agency must identify&#160;employees to participate in the five-year pilot program from among employees classified at or above the GS-11 level and holding positions with clearly measurable performance criteria. Each agency must select 1%-10% of these&#160;employees to participate in the program. An agency may opt out if participation potentially risks national security or public safety.

The bill provides that a participating agency

must&#160;increase an employee's pay by up to 10%&#160;if the&#160;employee significantly exceeded established performance metrics during the preceding year,&#160; may not increase the pay of an employee who met established performance metrics during the preceding year, and&#160;must reduce by 10%&#160;the pay of an employee who rates below expectations for the preceding year.Participating employees are ineligible for annual or locality-based pay increases authorized under current law during the pilot.

The&#160;bill also requires&#160;agencies to establish performance plans and evaluation systems for participating employees. Agencies must also provide training and resources to help participating&#160;employees understand and meet&#160;performance requirements.

Participating agencies must report cost savings, productivity metrics, and other information to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) every year. OMB and the Government Accountability Office must jointly report on the final outcome of the program.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
