<bill session="119" type="h" number="467" updated="2025-09-17T08:06:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foreign Medical Program Modernization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Medical Program Modernization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to eliminate the requirement of a service-connected disability to furnish veterans with medical care outside of a State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000235" joined="2025-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-28T20:21:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Medical Program Modernization Act of 2025

This bill expands eligibility for care under the Foreign Medical Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) by removing certain eligibility requirements. The program authorizes the VA to furnish care and services to veterans abroad (i.e., outside any state) for the treatment of service-connected disabilities or as part of a Veteran Readiness and Employment rehabilitation program. The bill expands eligibility for care by removing the requirement that a veteran have a service-connected disability or be participating in a rehabilitation program.

The bill also requires the VA to update its payment system to allow for reimbursements through electronic fund transfer.

Under the bill, the VA must assess the feasibility and implications of contracting with an appropriate non-VA entity to build a network of non-VA entities to provide hospital care and medical services abroad under the Foreign Medical Program.</summary>
</bill>
