<bill session="111" type="s" number="3678" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:42Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sergeant Coleman Bean National Guard and Reserves Mental Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve mental health services for members of the National Guard and Reserve deployed in connection with a contingency operation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sergeant Coleman Bean National Guard and Reserves Mental Health Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5170" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-18T17:38:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sergeant Coleman Bean National Guard and Reserves Mental Health Act - Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 to authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned (Secretary concerned) to call or order to active duty a member of the National Guard or reserves previously deployed in connection with a contingency operation, in order to perform a post-deployment mental health assessment of such member.

Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to ensure that each of the following individuals receive, at least once every 90 days, a telephone call from properly-trained DOD personnel to determine their emotional, psychological, medical, and career needs and concerns: (1) members of the Individual Ready Reserve who deployed to Afghanistan or Iraq on or after September 11, 2001, in support of a contingency operation; or (2) an individual mobilization augmentee or member of the inactive National Guard who has so deployed. Excludes from such requirement members not subjected or exposed to operational risk factors during such deployment.

Requires the person making the call to refer a member identified as being at-risk of self-caused harm to the nearest military medical treatment facility or accredited TRICARE (a DOD managed health care program) provider for immediate evaluation and necessary treatment. Authorizes the Secretary concerned to call such a member to active duty, with their consent, for such evaluation and treatment.

Requires annual reports from the Secretary to Congress on the number of members so referred, as well as their health and career status.</summary>
</bill>
