<bill session="116" type="s" number="3509" updated="2022-02-09T01:57:05Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide borrowers the right to request forbearance on mortgage loan payments due to a declared disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide borrowers the right to request forbearance on mortgage loan payments due to a declared disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2020-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-16T17:24:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill suspends foreclosures and establishes a forbearance program for certain federally backed mortgages during the coronavirus (i.e., the virus that causes COVID-19) outbreak and other disasters.

Specifically, during the coronavirus outbreak or in an area where another disaster has been declared, a federally backed mortgage servicer is (1) prohibited from initiating a foreclosure, and (2) must suspend any foreclosure procedures. These requirements are lifted 180 days after such a declaration.

Borrowers experiencing financial hardships due to the coronavirus outbreak or other disaster may request a forbearance on their federally backed mortgage payment for 180 days, which may be extended for an additional 180 days at the borrower's request. A servicer may not charge fees, interest, or other penalties in connection with the forbearance. Before the end of the forbearance period, a servicer must evaluate a borrower's ability to make regular mortgage payments. If the borrower is unable to return to making regular payments, the servicer must evaluate the borrower for certain loan modification options.</summary>
</bill>
