<bill session="108" type="s" number="1640" updated="2023-01-15T07:02:58Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide an extension of highway programs funded out of the Highway Trust Fund pending enactment of a law reauthorizing the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Extension Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="popular">TEA-21 bill</title>
    <title type="popular">TEA21 bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000162" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000154" joined="2003-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11756-11757"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with amendments. With written report No. 108-154.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="287">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 287.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3087" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Scenic byways"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-14T19:50:32Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Transportation Extension Act of 2003 - Extends Federal surface transportation programs for five months, and authorizes appropriations, through February 29, 2004.

(Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) apportion funds made available for Federal-aid highway programs under the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA21) to each State according to the ratio of the State's total FY 2003 obligation authority to the FY 2003 obligation authority for all States; and (2) ensure that each State is apportioned an amount determined according to a specified formula for the Interstate maintenance program, the National Highway System program, the bridge program, the surface transportation program, the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program, the recreational trails program, the Appalachian development highway system program, and the minimum guarantee.

 Extends the off-system bridge set-aside through February 29, 2004.

Directs the Secretary to reduce the amount that would be apportioned, but for this Act, to a State for programs for FY 2004 under a law reauthorizing the Federal-aid highway program enacted after this Act's enactment by the amount that is apportioned to each State under this Act for each such program. Authorizes the Secretary to establish procedures under which certain funds apportioned for a program category for which funds are not authorized under such a law may be restored to the Federal-aid highway program.

Makes specified funds available from the Highway Trust Fund to carry out this Act for the period of October 1, 2003, through February 29, 2004, subject to a limitation on obligations for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs.

Sets forth specified obligation limitations. Prohibits a State from obligating any funds for a Federal-aid highway program project after February 29, 2004, until the enactment of a multi-year law reauthorizing the Federal-aid highway program. Directs that any obligation of an allocation of obligation authority under this section be considered to be an obligation for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs for FY 2004 for purposes of appropriations for the Department of Transportation for FY 2004.

(Sec. 3) Authorizes a State to transfer unobligated apportionments, with transferred funds subject to the provisions of the program to which the funds are transferred. Directs the Secretary, as soon as practicable after the enactment of a multi-year law reauthorizing the Federal-aid highway program enacted after this Act's enactment, to restore any funds that a State transferred for any project that was ineligible to receive the funds except by operation of this section to the program category from which the funds were transferred. Authorizes the Secretary to establish procedures under which funds transferred from a program category for which funds are not authorized may be restored to the Federal-aid highway program.

(Sec. 4) Makes specified funds available from the Highway Trust Fund for administrative expenses of the Federal-aid highway program for FY 2004, subject to a limitation on obligations for Federal-aid highways and highway safety construction programs.

(Sec. 5) Extends the authorization of appropriations under TEA21 for: (1) Federal lands highways (Indian reservation roads, public lands highways, park roads and parkways, and refuge roads); (2) national corridor planning and development and coordinated border infrastructure programs; (3) construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities; (4) the national scenic byways program; (5) the value pricing pilot program; (6) highway use tax evasion projects; (7) the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico highway program; (8) the transportation and community and system preservation pilot program; (9) transportation infrastructure finance and innovation; (10) surface transportation research; (11) the technology deployment program; (12) training and education; (13) the Bureau of Transportation Statistics; (14) Intermodal Transportation System standards, research, operational tests, development, and deployment; (15) university transportation research; (16) metropolitan planning; (17) the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; (18) Operation Lifesaver; (19) the bridge discretionary program; (20) interstate maintenance; (21) recreational trails administrative costs; (22) railway-highway crossing hazard elimination in high speed rail corridors; (23) seat belt safety incentive grants; and (24) prevention of intoxicated driver incentive grants.

(Sec. 6) Amends the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act to extend funding through February 29, 2004, for the National Outreach and Communications Program. Makes funding available to carry out qualified projects under the Clean Vessel Act of 1992 and the Sportfishing and Boating Safety Act of 1998.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-154</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
