<bill session="109" type="h" number="3056" updated="2023-01-13T04:47:52Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Employer Health Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide for the establishment in the Department of Labor of a Small Employer Health Benefits Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Employer Health Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2005-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-07-29T15:21:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Employer Health Benefits Program Act of 2005 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish the Small Employer Health Benefits Program under which: (1) qualifying small employers are provided access to qualifying health insurance coverage for their employees; and (2) such employees may elect alternative forms of coverage offered by various health insurance issuers.

Limits such program to small employers that elect to: (1) offer health insurance coverage to each individual employed for three months or longer; and (2) pay at least half the total premium for qualifying health insurance coverage for such individual. Provides for coverage of part-time employees.

Requires the Secretary to enter into contracts with health insurance issuers for the offering of such insurance coverage.

Reduces by five percent the total premium otherwise payable by such employer if an average of fewer than 25 employees were employed during the preceding calendar year.

Requires the Secretary to provide premium subsidies (calculated according to specified formulae) to: (1) employers for coverage of employees whose individual income is at or below 200 percent of the poverty line; as well as (2) such employees.</summary>
</bill>
