<bill session="116" type="h" number="8714" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:27Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Family Friendly Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Friendly Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to local educational agencies to establish "Family Friendly School" policies at 500 elementary schools that align the school day with the work day to better support working families and to disseminate the learnings from these model schools so that other local educational agencies may adopt these practices, and to establish a supplemental 21st century community learning centers grant program to support programs and activities during summer recess when school is not in session.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2020-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2784" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-31T17:21:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Friendly Schools Act

This bill establishes a pilot program to implement policies at elementary schools that align the school day with the work day. It also establishes a grant program as a supplement to the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program to support programs and activities during summer recess.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to award five-year grants to local educational agencies for establishing policies at 500 elementary schools that align the school day with the work day. ED must report to Congress at the three-year mark and at the conclusion of the five-year grant period on best practices and recommendations for aligning school and work schedules, and for strengthening partnerships between schools and community resources.

In addition, the bill requires ED to carry out a supplemental grant program to establish or expand community learning center summer programs.</summary>
</bill>
