<bill session="117" type="h" number="1616" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Interagency Coordination for Review of Natural Gas Pipelines Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Federal and State agency coordination in the approval of certain authorizations under the Natural Gas Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Interagency Coordination for Review of Natural Gas Pipelines Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-11-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000395" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2022-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-22T18:07:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Interagency Coordination for Review of Natural Gas Pipelines Act

This bill expands the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)to act as the only lead agency for the purpose of coordinating the environmental review process under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) of natural gas pipeline project applications under the Natural Gas Act. Thus, federal, state, and local agencies involved in the environmental review process must defer to FERC's approved scope for a NEPA review.

FERC must invite and designate the other participating agencies involved in the authorization process. In addition, FERC must consult with the Transportation Security Administration regarding pipeline infrastructure security, pipeline cybersecurity, pipeline personnel security, and other pipeline security measures.

The bill establishes a deadline for agencies to complete NEPA reviews of pipeline projects and requires concurrent reviews when multiple federal or state agencies are involved.

If a federal or state agency requires the person applying for a pipeline authorization to submit data, the agency must consider any such data gathered by aerial or other remote means that the person submits.</summary>
</bill>
