<bill session="117" type="s" number="3962" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Quad Critical Minerals Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quad Critical Minerals Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a comprehensive United States strategy to address the national security threat posed by the People's Republic of China's control of nearly 2/3 of the global supply of critical minerals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2022-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2022-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2022-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-11T16:16:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Quad Critical Minerals Partnership Act

This bill requires the President to establish a comprehensive strategy to address the national security threat posed by China's dominant share of the global critical minerals market by developing a more reliable and secure supply chain of critical minerals.

The bill also requires the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation to prioritize projects that will support the strategy, including projects that will facilitate cooperation with other countries in the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue on investments related to critical minerals. (The dialogue is a coalition comprised of the United States, Japan, India, and Australia.)

The U.S. Trade Representative must initiate multilateral discussions with other countries in the dialogue to support the strategy and facilitate cooperation on investments related to critical minerals.</summary>
</bill>
