<bill session="117" type="h" number="7967" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prosecutors Need to Prosecute Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prosecutors Need to Prosecute Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act to direct district attorney and prosecutors offices to report to the Attorney General, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2022-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2022-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2022-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-10T19:20:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Prosecutors Need to Prosecute Act

This bill requires certain state and local prosecutors to report data on criminal referrals and outcomes of cases involving murder or non-negligent manslaughter, forcible rape, robbery, aggravated assault, burglary, larceny, motor vehicle theft, arson, or any offense involving the illegal use or possession of a firearm.

The reporting requirement applies to state and local prosecutors in a jurisdiction with 380,000 or more persons that receives funding under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program. The report must contain data on

 cases referred for prosecution, cases declined for prosecution, cases resulting in a plea agreement with the defendant, cases initiated against defendants with previous arrests or convictions, and defendants charged who were released or eligible for bail.</summary>
</bill>
