<bill session="108" type="h" number="923" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:56Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to allow certain premier certified lenders to elect to maintain an alternative loss reserve.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2002</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000429"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 108-153.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-12" calendar="Union" number="75">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 75.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:35:49-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Manzullo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:36:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5724-5727" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:36:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 923.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:48:55-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:11:56-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5742-5743" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="303" datetime="2003-06-24T13:18:26-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 3 (Roll no. 303).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5724-5725" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T13:18:27-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5726-5727" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-05-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-05-28" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-232" type="public" datetime="2004-05-28">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-232.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Premier Certified Lenders Program Improvement Act of 2003 - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to allow a certified development company to withdraw from its loss reserve amounts in excess of one percent of the aggregate outstanding balances of debentures to which such loss reserve relates (with an exception).Makes loss reserve requirements of lenders under the premier certified lenders (PCL) program inapplicable to PCLs that ensure that the amount of their loss reserve is: (1) not less than $100,000; and (2) sufficient, as determined by an independent auditor, for the PCL to meet its obligations to protect the Federal Government from risk of loss. Designates such PCLs as qualified high loss reserve PCLs. Requires such PCLs to certify quarterly to the SBA Administrator as to the sufficiency of such reserves. Requires: (1) the Administrator to allow the qualified high loss reserve PCL to withdraw funds in excess of the required reserve; (2) PCL recontribution when the reserve does not meet such minimum requirements; and (3) the PCL to meet specified SBA risk management benchmarks when not qualified as a high loss reserve PCL.Establishes in the SBA the Bureau of PCLP Oversight to carry out PCL Program functions designated by the Administrator.Increases the reimbursement required from a PCL to the Administrator for losses sustained by the SBA as a result of PCL default on debentures issued by the PCL and guaranteed by the SBA during any period in which the PCL elects to operate under the alternative loss reserve requirements of this Act to 15 percent of the total principal and interest on such debentures. (Currently, ten percent reimbursement is required when a PCL is operating under normal loss reserve requirements.)Directs the Administrator to contract with either a Federal agency experienced in community development lending and financial regulation or a member of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council to study and prepare a report regarding: (1) the extent to which statutory requirements have caused overcapitalization in the loss reserves maintained by certified PCLs participating in the PCL Program; and (2) alternatives for establishing and maintaining loss reserves sufficient to protect the Federal Government from the risk of loss associated with loans guaranteed under the Program. Requires the report to be transmitted to the congressional small business committees.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-153</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
