<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1157</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:22:55Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:22:55Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-06-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-06-08T16:18:42Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-08</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000555</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Gillibrand, Kirsten E. [D-NY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kirsten</firstName>
        <lastName>Gillibrand</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agricultural trade</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Business records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Food supply, safety, and labeling</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Meat</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Retail and wholesale trades</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-06-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-08-09T12:49:07Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Foodborne Illness Reduction Act of 2011 - Amends the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), In the case of any Class I recall, to distribute to each retail grocery or other establishment that sells food directly to customers in the United States a summary notice containing product information about each food or food product subject to such recall.</p> <p>Defines &quot;Class I recall' as a food recall classification that covers a health-hazard situation in which there is a reasonable probability that the use of the food or food product being recalled will cause a serious, adverse health consequence or death.</p> <p>Amends the Poultry Products Inspection Act to consider a poultry product adulterated if it is contaminated with Salmonella or Campylobacter.</p> <p>Amends the the Federal Meat Inspection Act to consider any carcass, part thereof, meat, or meat food product adulterated if it is contaminated with Salmonella, Toxoplasma gondii, or enterohemorrhagic (EHEC) Shiga toxin-producing serotypes of Escherichia coli (E. coli)</p> <p>Requires that specified slaughterhouses, processing establishments, and grinding facilities perform specified tests for the presence of E. coli in ground beef.</p> <p>Subjects imported trim, bench trim, and ground beef to the same testing requirements as domestic trim, bench trim, and ground beef. Requires domestic facilities to conduct secondary testing of such meat before processing into a final ground beef product.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary, through the Food Safety and Inspection Service (FSIS), to redesign FSIS E. coli sampling and verification programs.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Foodborne Illness Reduction Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Foodborne Illness Reduction Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to provide retail establishments with information describing recalled meat, poultry, eggs, and related food products, to require the retail establishment to communicate the recall information to consumers, to require the Food Safety Inspection Service of the Department of Agriculture to protect against certain foodborne illnesses, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Foodborne Illness Reduction Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-06-08T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1157is/xml/BILLS-112s1157is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-06-08</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
