<bill session="118" type="s" number="973" updated="2025-01-14T19:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Equal Opportunity from ESG Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Equal Opportunity from ESG Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit Federal contractors from imposing racial hiring quotas, benchmarks, or goals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-11T16:35:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Equal Opportunity from ESG Act

This bill prohibits racial hiring quotas by federal contractors.

Specifically, the bill requires each executive agency to take steps to ensure that each contract entered into by the agency includes requirements that the contractor

 certify that, during the five-year period immediately preceding the date on which the contract is entered into, the contractor did not initiate, carry out, or enforce any system of quotas, benchmarks, or goals regarding employment practices that encourage or require discrimination on the basis of race; and not, during the performance of the contract, initiate, carry out, or enforce any such system. The bill makes an exception where the Department of Labor determines that special circumstances in the national interest so require.

Labor shall have the authority to investigate potential violations and obtain compliance. The bill establishes penalties for noncompliance.</summary>
</bill>
