<bill session="112" type="s" number="3343" updated="2020-02-12T18:57:53Z">
  <state datetime="2012-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to require residential carbon monoxide detectors to meet the applicable ANSI/UL standard by treating that standard as a consumer product safety rule, to encourage States to require the installation of such detectors in homes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2012-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2012-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4326" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-07-11T22:04:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act - Directs the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to publish the American National Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms and the American National Standard for Gas and Vapor Detectors and Sensors as mandatory consumer product safety standards. Authorizes the CPSC to initiate a rulemaking to amend either standard to include any provision reasonably necessary to ensure the safe and effective operation of carbon monoxide alarms.

Requires the CPSC to establish a grant program to provide assistance to states and local governments that require approved carbon monoxide alarms to be installed in dwelling units to carry out specified carbon monoxide poisoning prevention activities.</summary>
</bill>
