<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="508" updated="2022-02-03T04:57:27Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3550" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-04-01T17:41:20-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000013"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <description>After section 4131, insert the following (and redesignate the subsequent section of subtitle A of title IV, and conform the table of contents, accordingly): \   SEC. 4132. HOURS OF SERVICE RULES FOR OPERATORS PROVIDING TRANSPORTATION TO MOVIE PRODUCTION SITES. \   Notwithstanding sections 31136 and 31502 of title 49, United States Code, and any other provision of law, the maximum daily hours of service for an operator of a commercial motor vehicle providing transportation of property or passengers to or from a theatrical or television motion picture production site located within a 100 air mile radius of the work reporting location of such operator shall be those in effect under the regulations in effect under such sections on April 27, 2003.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 17 printed in part B of House Report 108-456 to exempt motion picture and television production truck drivers from the new "hours of service" regulations that went into effect at the beginning of the year.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-04-01T17:41:20-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="109">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bachus amendment (A017) Agreed to by recorded vote: 365 - 62 (Roll no. 109).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01T16:32:17-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A017) offered by Mr. Bachus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 4/2/2004 H2028-2030, H2033-2034" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 4/2/2004 H2028" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01T16:32:17-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A017) offered by Mr. Bachus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 4/2/2004 H2028-2030, H2033-2034" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 4/2/2004 H2028" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01T17:41:20-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01T17:41:20-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01T17:41:20-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Bachus amendment (A017) Agreed to by recorded vote: 365 - 62 (Roll no. 109).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
