<bill session="118" type="s" number="891" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ATC SOAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Traffic Control Safe Operation and Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ATC SOAR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to give preferential consideration to individuals who have successfully completed air traffic controller training when hiring air traffic control specialists, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-19T15:59:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Air Traffic Control Safe Operation and Readiness Act or the ATC SOAR Act

This bill revises the hiring process for air traffic control specialists.

Specifically, the bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to

 consider for the interview stage of the hiring process candidates who score at or above the passing score on the Air Traffic Skills Assessment (AT-SA) and meet minimum qualifications established by the FAA, revise the AT-SA to ensure that all questions are supported by a peer reviewed job analysis, and revise the AT-SA to ensure that it does not incorporate any biographical questionnaire or other questions of a biographical nature.</summary>
</bill>
