<bill session="118" type="s" number="4347" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Swanson and Hugh Butler Reservoirs Land Conveyances Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Swanson and Hugh Butler Reservoirs Land Conveyances Act</title>
    <title type="display">Swanson and Hugh Butler Reservoirs Land Conveyances Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land at Swanson Reservoir and Hugh Butler Reservoir in the State of Nebraska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2024-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2024-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2024-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="623">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 623.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8413" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-05T21:20:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Swanson and Hugh Butler Reservoirs Land Conveyances Act

This bill provides for the conveyance of certain federal lands located at the Swanson Reservoir and Hugh Butler Reservoir in Nebraska to Hitchcock County and Frontier County, respectively. The counties must manage the land for substantially the same purposes for which they are being used or for (1) certain public recreation purposes, (2) public access, (3) fish and wildlife habitat, or (4) the preservation of the natural character of the land.

Within three years, the Bureau of Reclamation must enter into negotiations to transfer (1) the Swanson Permitted Cabin Land, the Swanson Permitted Concession Land, and the Lakeview Lodge Permitted Concession Land to Hitchcock County; and (2) the Red Willow Permitted Cabin Land and the Red Willow Permitted Concession Land to Frontier County. Reclamation must offer to convey the land as soon as practicable after the title transfer agreement is made. The land must be conveyed in whole and not subdivided. Additionally, the bill subjects the conveyances to certain existing rights and requirements. Further, the bill limits future conveyances of the land.

Reclamation must enter into a memorandum of agreement with each county to establish and define the roles and responsibilities for actions required to convey the land.

The counties must provide compensation to the Reclamation Fund in an amount equal to the fair market value of the land. The counties must also pay the conveyance costs in advance of the conveyance.</summary>
</bill>
