<bill session="119" type="s" number="347" updated="2025-03-07T21:09:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to reauthorize brownfields revitalization funding, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2025-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Capito without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-02-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="6">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 6.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-07T20:56:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Brownfields Reauthorization Act of 2025

This bill extends through FY2030 and modifies the Brownfields Program under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA). The Brownfields Program is administered by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to provide grants and technical assistance to states, communities, tribes, and other entities to assess, clean up, and reuse contaminated properties.

First, the bill expands eligibility for Brownfields Program resources to tax-exempt organizations defined under section 501(c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code, which are organizations that are not organized for profit and do not provide net earnings to private shareholders or individuals (e.g., chambers of commerce).

Additionally, the bill

increases to $1 million the maximum grant amount that the EPA may provide for brownfield remediation per site,removes the 5% cap that a grant recipient may use for administrative costs,reduces the cost-sharing requirement for grant recipients from 20% to 10%,requires the EPA to waive cost-sharing requirements for grant recipients located in small communities or disadvantaged areas,authorizes the use of grants by a state or Indian tribe for the implementation of a response program,modifies the criteria used to rank grant applications by requiring the consideration of whether the applicant has a plan to engage a diverse set of local groups and organizations that represent the views of the local community directly affected by the proposed brownfield project, andrequires the EPA to report on and update application ranking criteria and the approval process.</summary>
</bill>
