<bill session="118" type="s" number="331" updated="2025-11-18T22:13:32Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to make 1 percent across-the-board rescissions in non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs discretionary spending for each of fiscal years 2024 and 2025.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make 1 percent across-the-board rescissions in non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs discretionary spending for each of fiscal years 2024 and 2025.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="330" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="327" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-24T18:04:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires 1% across-the-board rescissions to FY2024 and FY2025 appropriations provided for any non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs discretionary account by any appropriations act.

For the purpose of this bill, a non-defense, non-homeland-security, and non-veterans-affairs discretionary account is a discretionary spending account other than any account

 included in a Department of Defense Appropriations Act; included in a Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act; of the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs included in a Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act; or for Department of Energy defense activities included in an Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act.</summary>
</bill>
