<bill session="116" type="s" number="4889" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:11Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act Fulfillment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act Fulfillment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to increase the dividend exclusion, to exclude certain payments to Alaska Native elders for determining eligibility for certain programs, to provide that Village Corporations shall not be required to convey land in trust to the State of Alaska for the establishment of Municipal Corporations, and to provide for the recognition of certain Alaska Native communities and the settlement of certain claims under that Act, to require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain interests in land in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2020-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-382.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8683" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2533" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4891" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8751" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8973" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-10T17:45:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act Fulfillment Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to convey specified surface estate to certain Alaska Native village corporations, allows the reversion of municipal land to village corporations, and permits the Alaska Native residents of certain Alaska Native villages to organize as Alaska Native urban corporations and to receive certain settlement land. In addition, the bill excludes certain settlement trust payments to an Alaska Native or descendant of an Alaska Native who is 65 years of age or older for purposes of determining the individual's eligibility for need-based federal programs (e.g., the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program).</summary>
</bill>
