<bill session="111" type="s" number="1144" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Transit Improvement and Flexibility Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve transit services, including in rural States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Transit Improvement and Flexibility Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-27T16:12:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Transit Improvement and Flexibility Act of 2009 - Revises the apportionment of nonurbanized formula grants for amounts remaining after apportionment for grants to Indian tribes for public transportation on Indian reservations for FY2006-FY2009. Increases from 20% to 25% the amount of remaining funds to be apportioned to a state based on its land area. Decreases correspondingly from 80% to 75% the amount of remaining funds to be apportioned to a state based on population in nonurbanized areas.

Limits to 25% of its apportionment for a formula grant for a capital project for the special needs of elderly individuals and individuals with disabilities the amount a state may use for operating costs of equipment and facilities.

Limits a grant for operating assistance from exceeding 50% of the net operating project costs. Increases such limit to 62.5% of the government share of project costs in the case of a state containing nontaxable Indian lands, individual and tribal, and public domain lands (both reserved and unreserved), national forests, and national parks and monuments.

Requires the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program for the award of grants to states to establish transit centers to improve transit service (buses and other transit vehicles) in urbanized areas with a population of less than 200,000 and in nonurbanized areas.</summary>
</bill>
