<bill session="115" type="h" number="6939" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:51Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Local Input and Access to Public Lands Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect and ensure multiple use and public access to public lands in Wyoming per the request of the respective counties, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Restoring Local Input and Access to Public Lands Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Local Input and Access to Public Lands Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001109"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-1092.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-12-20" calendar="Union" number="845">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 845.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-03T18:25:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Local Input and Access to Public Lands Act of 2018

This bill releases wilderness study areas or parts of which that are in Lincoln, Sweetwater, or Bighorn Counties in Wyoming from further study for designation as wilderness areas.

The bill prohibits the designation of any new wilderness or wilderness study area in Wyoming except by a federal statute that specifically designates such area and is enacted after enactment of this bill.

Any federal land in Wyoming that was inventoried as a "Land with Wilderness Characteristics" or identified as having wilderness characteristics under the planning process of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or the Forest Service shall no longer be inventoried or identified as such. These lands shall be managed under the multiple use and sustained yield mandate of the federal land agency concerned. The federal land agencies concerned shall no longer be bound in managing their respective lands in accordance with the non-impairment standard.

Furthermore, after this bill's enactment, no federal land in Wyoming shall be inventoried as a "Land with Wilderness Characteristics" nor shall it be identified as having wilderness characteristics under the planning process of the BLM or the Forest Service.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1092</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
