<bill session="117" type="h" number="2865" updated="2023-03-08T19:59:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to address sexual harassment involving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4690" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-19T15:45:20Z" status="Introduced in House">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2021

This bill addresses sexual harassment and sexual assault involving personnel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).

The bill specifies that NOAA's sexual harassment prevention and response policy applies to personnel such as observers, at-sea monitors, and voting members and staff of regional fishery management councils.

It also requires victim advocates at NOAA to be full-time employees whose sole job is advocacy for survivors rather than a volunteer collateral duty of an existing employee.

Additionally, the bill expands reporting requirements on sexual harassment, sexual assault, and equal opportunity employment.

The bill also provides for a restricted reporting structure that allows survivors of sexual assault to receive services without triggering an investigative process.

The Office of Marine and Aviation Operations within NOAA must develop and implement a policy to report to the Coast Guard Suspension and Revocation National Center of Expertise the names of NOAA personnel who are under investigation for an offense detrimental to good discipline and safety at sea, such as sexual harassment or sexual assault or any other offense for which suspension or revocation of a merchant mariner credential is either mandatory or sought.

Further, the bill removes the requirements that acts of assault, resistance, opposition, intimidation, sexual harassment, bribery, or interference with a fishery observer be forcible in nature and occur on a vessel to be unlawful.</summary>
</bill>
