<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>455</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:53:09Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T05:53:09Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-03-02</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-03-02T19:36:53Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Spectrum Inventory and Auction Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>911</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-03-11</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Spectrum Innovation Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1622</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-04-25</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Public Safety Spectrum and Wireless Innovation Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>28</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S146-149)</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Spectrum Optimization Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>415</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-02-17</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Spectrum Relocation Improvement Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>522</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-03-09</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Radio Spectrum Inventory Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3433</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-07-25</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Federal Wi-Net Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3439</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-07-25</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-02</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1141-1142)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-03-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000663</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Snowe, Olympia J. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Olympia</firstName>
        <lastName>Snowe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000148</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kerry, John F. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>KERRY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>FORBES</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-03-02</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal Communications Commission (FCC)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government trust funds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet and video services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet, web applications, social media</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telecommunication rates and fees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>User charges and fees</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-03-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-03-17T14:07:01Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Reforming Airwaves by Developing Incentives and Opportunistic Sharing Act or the RADIOS Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), subject to specified national security, classified information, and public safety exceptions, and in consultation with the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) and the Office of Science and Technology Policy, to: (1) biennially inventory each radio spectrum band from 300 megahertz to at least 6.5 gigahertz managed by each such agency, including information on the total spectrum authorized for each licensee or federal government user and the approximate number of deployed or authorized transmitters, end-user terminals, or receivers (excluding unintended radiators) in the band; and (2) make the information available to the public through the Internet.<br> </p> <p>Directs the FCC and NTIA to conduct a study of occupancy on the electromagnetic spectrum (between, at least, 100 megahertz and 10 gigahertz) based on the extent of the use of such spectrum.</p> <p>Directs the FCC and NTIA to determine appropriate benchmarks for assessing: (1) the utilization of each electromagnetic spectrum band, and (2) the availability of services operating in bands capable of offering substitutable services.</p> <p>Requires the FCC to study and seek public comment on means of providing greater predictability in the determination of harmful interference along the electromagnetic spectrum.</p> <p>Directs the FCC and NTIA to identify specified close proximity electromagnetic spectrum most feasible for: (1) spectrum sharing opportunities for commercial and federal government users, (2) spectrum reuse opportunities for commercial and federal government users, (3) temporary or dynamic short-term assignment and use, and (4) spectrum layering opportunities for commercial and federal government users.<br> </p> <p>Directs the FCC and NTIA to: (1) implement pilot programs (and possibly permanent programs, if deemed viable) to promote spectrum sharing and reuse activities for such identified spectrum bands, (2) examine each radio spectrum band from 2.5 to 6 gigahertz to determine spectrum sharing opportunities for high bandwidth, low-power applications and services, (3) perform a cost-benefit analysis on electromagnetic spectrum relocation opportunities to move certain federal users and services currently operating in a specific band of the spectrum to more efficient spectrum bands, and (4) establish the Spectrum Advisory Committee.</p> <p>Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to provide for the reversion of unused Spectrum Relocation Fund amounts to the Treasury after 20 years (current law provides for reversion after 8 years).</p> <p>Requires each transmission system (any telecommunications, broadcast, satellite, commercial mobile service, or other communications system that employs radio spectrum) to be designated and operated in a manner that prevents impairment by reasonably used adjacent spectrum. Directs to ensure such compliance: (1) manufacturers of transmission system products and services, and (2) each licensee or approved federal government user.</p> <p>Directs the FCC and NTIA to conduct: (1) a cost-benefit analysis on the value of improving received standards as it relates to increasing spectral efficiency, improving operation of services in adjacent frequencies, narrowing the guard bands between adjacent spectrum use, and improving overall receiver performance for the end user; and (2) a feasibility study on a more efficient spectrum incentive pricing system.</p> <p>Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to provide that, if consistent with the public interest for an eligible licensee to relinquish some or all of its spectrum usage rights in order to permit the assignment of new initial licenses or the allocation of spectrum for unlicensed use, the proceeds from the use of a competitive bidding system may be shared with any such eligible licensee. Extends the FCC's auction authority until September 30, 2017.</p> <p>Directs the NTIA to establish spectrum efficiency and utilization baselines for the use of spectrum assigned to each federal agency. Requires a federal agency that fails to meet the baseline to file a cost report and analysis (determined to be reasonable by the NTIA) as a condition to receiving funds from the NTIA and OMB to defray necessary upgrade costs. </p> <p>Requires the Department of Commerce and the FCC to triennially develop a 10-year National Strategic Spectrum Plan, as specified.</p> <p>Directs the OMB to rewrite Circular A-11 to ensure that federal agencies give more consideration to spectrum use in their management processes.</p> <p>Requires each federal agency, to the extent feasible, to share existing spectrum assignments with non-federal users.</p> <p>Requires the FCC and NTIA to issue and seek public comment on a report providing a strategy for coexistence of licensed and unlicensed use of spectrum and a determination of the amount of spectrum appropriate for unlicensed devices.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) install or retrofit wireless Internet connections in federal buildings; and (2) allow wireless neutral host providers, upon request, to install such systems in all publicly accessible federal buildings. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Reforming Airwaves by Developing Incentives and Opportunistic Sharing Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Reforming Airwaves by Developing Incentives and Opportunistic Sharing Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>RADIOS Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Reforming Airwaves by Developing Incentives and Opportunistic Sharing Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote development and opportunity with regards to spectrum occupancy and use, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-03-02T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s455is/xml/BILLS-112s455is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-03-02</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
