<bill session="108" type="h" number="3076" updated="2023-01-15T07:32:56Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-21T11:49:39-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-10-21T11:49:39-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Graduate Opportunities in Higher Education Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to ensure graduate opportunities in postsecondary education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Graduate Opportunities in Higher Education Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Graduate Opportunities in Higher Education Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Graduate Opportunities in Higher Education Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000676"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000589" joined="2003-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2003-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2003-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000508" joined="2003-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2003-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2003-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2003-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 108-307.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-10-08" calendar="Union" number="184">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 184.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T11:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hoekstra moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T11:40:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9748-9752" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T11:40:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3076.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2003-10-21T11:49:39-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9748-9749" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21T11:49:42-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4411" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban problems"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-23T21:27:39Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on October 8, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Graduate Opportunities in Higher Education Act of 2003 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to revise requirements for Graduate and Postsecondary Improvement Programs (title VII), and to reauthorize appropriations for some of such programs through FY 2009.

(Sec. 2) Revises the Jacob K. Javits fellowship program. Directs the Secretary of Education to give grant priority to institutions of higher education (IHEs) for fellowships to students in advanced linguistic studies and courses that prepare teachers to teach students with limited English proficiency. Permits IHEs to allow fellowship recipients an interruption of study due to active duty military service or a personal or family member illness. Revises requirements for allocation of fellowships. Directs the Secretary to ensure that one member of the fellowship board will be from a minority-serving institution. Reauthorizes appropriations through FY 2009.

(Sec. 3) Revises the program of graduate assistance in areas of national need. Directs the Secretary to give grant priority to IHEs to prepare mathematics, science and special education faculty who can train highly qualified mathematics, science, or special education teachers for service in elementary and secondary schools. Revises requirements relating to designation of areas of national need, stipends, and additional assistance. Reauthorizes appropriations through FY 2009.

(Sec. 4) Revises requirements for the Thurgood Marshall legal educational opportunity program. Revises activities for which the Council on Legal Education Opportunity (CLEO) is to use program contract and grant funds provided by the Secretary to include: (1) assisting students to develop analytical skills and study methods; and (2) awarding such fellowships to eligible law school students who either participated in summer institutes and are enrolled in an accredited law school or have successfully completed a comparable summer institute certified by CLEO. Revises types of program services to provide that undergraduate preparatory courses be in analytical skills and study methods. Reauthorizes appropriations through FY 2009.

(Sec. 5) Revises requirements for the Secretary's Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education program contracts and grants. Authorizes consideration of applications for projects relating to: (1) the needs of nontraditional student populations; (2) distance education delivery through communications technology; and (3) expanded opportunities to enter and reenter postsecondary institutions and pursue study programs tailored to individual needs. Includes among special projects international partnerships with postsecondary institutions abroad. Reauthorizes appropriations through FY 2009.

Eliminates continuation awards under certain parts of title VII of HEA.

(Sec. 6) Eliminates the Urban Community Service program (part C of title VII of HEA).

(Sec. 7) Revises requirements for demonstration projects to ensure that students with disabilities receive a quality higher education. Includes among authorized project activities developing innovative, effective, and efficient teaching methods and strategies to: (1) ensure such students' smooth transition from high school to postsecondary education; and (2) enable faculty and administrators to provide accessible distance education programs or classes to enhance such students' access to higher education. Requires project grant applications to describe how the IHE will work to replicate the best practices of IHEs with demonstrated success in serving students with disabilities. Reauthorizes appropriations through FY 2009.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-307</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
