<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="340" updated="2022-02-25T17:31:04Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1540" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-05-26T10:32:39-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000594"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <description>Amendment requires that the Secretary of Defense establish goals for competition in contracts for the procurement of property or services to be used outside the United States in support of a contingency operation and requires that processes be developed to measure and monitor such competition, including task order categories for services, construction, and supplies.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 134 printed in House Report 112-88 to require that the Secretary of Defense establish goals for competition in contracts for the procurement of property or services to be used outside the United States in support of a contingency operation and requires that processes be developed to measure and monitor such competition, including task order categories for services, construction, and supplies.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-05-26T10:32:39-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Runyan amendment (A040) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T10:29:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A040) offered by Mr. RUNYAN.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3690-3691" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3690" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T10:29:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A040) offered by Mr. RUNYAN.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3690-3691" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3690" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T10:32:39-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T10:32:39-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Runyan amendment (A040) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
