<bill session="117" type="h" number="6735" updated="2023-08-18T12:30:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SANE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SANE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Access to Nurse Exams Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004 to increase access to Sexual Assault Nurse Examiners, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001135" joined="2022-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2022-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3648" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3623" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-18T12:28:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Access to Nurse Exams Act or the SANE Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 and otherwise revises the Sexual Assault Forensic Exam Program. This program provides grants for training, technical assistance, education, equipment, and information relating to the identification, collection, preservation, analysis, and use of DNA samples and other evidence by medical personnel and other professionals treating victims of sexual assault.

Among other changes, the bill (1) expands the types of entities that are eligible to receive a grant under the program; (2) expands the allowable uses of these grants, including to provide full- and part-time salaries for sexual assault nurse examiners and sexual assault forensic examiners; and (3) requires the Department of Justice to establish and update annually a public website on access to forensic nurse examiners.</summary>
</bill>
