<bill session="116" type="s" number="3672" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic TANF Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic TANF Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide States and Indian Tribes with flexibility in administering the temporary assistance for needy families program due to the public health emergency with respect to the Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19), to make emergency grants to States and Indian Tribes to provide financial support for low-income individuals affected by that public health emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2020-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2020-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2020-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2020-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2020-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-05T20:51:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pandemic TANF Assistance Act

This bill temporarily suspends certain Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) program requirements and establishes a grant program in response to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency. Specifically, states, tribes, and territories may not deny, reduce, or terminate TANF assistance because a recipient does not meet specified conditions of TANF participation from October 1, 2019, to November 30, 2020. These conditions include time limits for receiving assistance, work requirements, and compliance with paternity establishment or child support procedures.

During that time period, the bill also restricts the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) from penalizing jurisdictions that fail to meet TANF requirements such as work participation standards. However, HHS may reduce grants for jurisdictions that improperly deny, reduce, or terminate TANF assistance in violation of the bill.

Additionally, HHS must award grants to states, tribes, and territories for short-term cash, noncash, and in-kind assistance and other activities to assist families meet their basic needs from April 1, 2020, to September 30, 2021. Families eligible for assistance must be impacted by COVID-19 and have monthly income at or below 200% of the federal poverty level. The bill provides funding for this purpose.</summary>
</bill>
