<bill session="109" type="s" number="4064" updated="2023-01-12T17:51:57Z">
  <state datetime="2006-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Child Left Behind Improvement Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the amendments made by the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Child Left Behind Improvement Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11069"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5709" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-12-15T21:12:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Child Left Behind Improvements Act of 2006 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to alter requirements for adequate yearly progress (AYP) assessments of student groups by: (1) lowering, from 95% to 90%, the minimum percentage of students in each group in a school that must take such assessments; (2) allowing the fractional counting of students who are in more than one group, for each such group; (3) allowing states to treat as proficient or advanced specified scores on alternate assessments for disabled students and those not proficient in English; and (4) allowing states to use alternative methods of defining AYP.

Revises criteria for local educational agency identification of schools needing improvement. Declares that only those meet such criteria that fail AYP standards, for two consecutive school years (as under current law), in the same subject for the same group of students.

Revises eligibility criteria for school transfers after a school is identified as needing improvement. Declares that only failing students in the failing group, instead of all students in such a school, may transfer. Allows such schools to provide students with supplemental services rather than transfers during that school year.</summary>
</bill>
