<bill session="116" type="hj" number="83" updated="2022-08-10T23:26:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">War Powers Reform Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the War Powers Resolution to improve requirements and limitations in connection with authorizations for use of military force and narrowings and repeals of such authorizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">War Powers Reform Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="sj" number="60" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-27T23:24:40Z" status="Introduced in House">War Powers Reform Resolution

This joint resolution repeals certain authorizations for the use of military force and provides specific requirements for any future such authorization to receive expedited consideration.

Specifically, the bill repeals the authorizations for the use of miltary force enacted in 2002 against Iraq and in 2001 in response to the September 11 terror attacks.

To receive expedited consideration, a bill or resolution that is authorizing, narrowing, or repealing the use of military force must provide

 a specific strategic objective for military action; a specification that the military force is necessary, appropriate, and proportional to the purpose of the authorization; a list of named nations, organizations, or forces engaged in active hostilities against the United States; a specification of the country, countries, or subdivisions thereof in which military force is to be authorized; and a date certain for the duration of the authorization, not to exceed two years. The bill also establishes an expedited procedure for Congress to consider such a narrowing or repeal, and it prohibits the use of appropriations to support military force in hostilities outside the parameters of an authorization.

Lastly, the resolution requires the President, when requesting an authorization for the use of military force, to provide a comprehensive justification for such request by including (1) the nations, organizations, and forces covered; (2) the countries and subdivisions of such countries covered; and (3) the duration of the request.</summary>
</bill>
