<bill session="111" type="h" number="5204" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:14Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century Full Employment and Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Full Employment Trust Fund to create employment opportunities for the unemployed.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Full Employment and Training Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2010-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-16T19:49:30Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Full Employment and Training Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish a Full Employment National Trust Fund.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a tax on certain covered securities transactions, payable by trading facilities that deal in such transactions.

Requires amounts collected to be deposited into the Fund for: (1) Employment Opportunity Grants to states, local governments, and Indian tribes for job creating activities in communities where the rate of unemployment is higher than a specified graduated percentage for a number years; and (2) the Secretary to fund Workforce Investment programs.

Directs the Secretary to convene a national employment conference to bring together leaders of small and larger business, labor, government, and other parties to discuss employment, with particular attention to structural unemployment and the plight of disadvantaged youth.</summary>
</bill>
