<bill session="116" type="s" number="1934" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Parity in Veterans Health Care Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parity in Veterans Health Care Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide benefits from the Department of Veterans Affairs for persons disabled by treatment under the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2019-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-23T15:59:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Parity in Veterans Health Care Rights Act

This bill expands eligibility for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) benefits (including dependency and indemnity compensation) in situations where a veteran has been disabled or died as a result of medical treatment or vocational rehabilitation.

Under the bill, the VA must award such benefits if a disability or death of a veteran was caused by hospital care, a medical service, or an extended care service furnished by a non-VA provider as part of the Veterans Community Care Program. The proximate cause of the disability or death in these situations must have been (1) carelessness, negligence, lack of proper skill, error in judgment, or a similar instance of fault on the part of the provider; or (2) an event that was not reasonably foreseeable.</summary>
</bill>
