<bill session="116" type="h" number="8247" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans COMPACT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Veterans COMPACT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Veterans Comprehensive Prevention, Access to Care, and Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Veterans COMPACT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Veterans Comprehensive Prevention, Access to Care, and Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans COMPACT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Comprehensive Prevention, Access to Care, and Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans COMPACT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans Comprehensive Prevention, Access to Care, and Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans Comprehensive Prevention, Access to Care, and Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make certain improvements relating to the transition of individuals to services from the Department of Veterans Affairs, suicide prevention for veterans, and care and services for women veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23T13:39:26-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23T13:39:41-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4763-4770" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23T13:39:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8247.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2020-09-23T13:59:02-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4763-4767" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23T13:59:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2020-11-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6655" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-11-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2020-11-24">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2020-12-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="116-214" type="public" datetime="2020-12-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 116-214.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4154" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5324" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7747" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2864" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-26T19:13:53Z" status="Public Law">Veterans Comprehensive Prevention, Access to Care, and Treatment Act of 2020 or the Veterans COMPACT Act of 2020

This bill implements programs, policies, and reports related to Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) transition assistance, suicide care, mental health education and treatment, health care, and women veteran care.

(Sec. 101) This section requires the VA to carry out a two-year pilot program on information sharing between the VA and designated persons regarding the assistance and benefits available to veterans.

(Sec. 102) The VA must annually report (for a period of five years) on its Solid Start program, which is an outreach program for those in their first year of separation from the military. The report must exclude any personally identifiable information regarding a veteran.

(Sec. 201) The VA must furnish or pay for emergent suicide care, including transportation costs, at a VA or non-VA facility for certain veterans. The bill requires the VA to ensure certain notification procedures occur in relation to veterans receiving emergent suicide care.

The VA must determine the eligibility of individuals receiving emergent suicide care for other VA programs and benefits. Additionally, the VA must make referrals, as appropriate, for care following the period of emergent suicide care.

(Sec. 202) The VA must establish a four-year education program for the education and training of caregivers and family members of veterans with mental health disorders.

(Sec. 203) This section requires the VA to establish the Task Force on Outdoor Recreation for Veterans to report on and make recommendations regarding the use of public lands or other outdoor spaces for medical treatment and therapy for veterans.

(Sec. 204) The VA must seek to contact covered veterans to encourage them to receive comprehensive physical, mental health, eye, and audiological examinations. A covered veteran is a veteran who is enrolled in the VA health care system and has not received health care furnished or paid for by the VA in the past two years.

Under the bill, if a covered veteran elects to receive more than one of the comprehensive examinations at a VA health care facility, the VA shall seek to furnish all such examinations on the same day. A covered veteran may also receive an examination from another specified health care provider.

The bill provides that the VA may pay for a rural covered veteran to travel to a health care facility to receive a comprehensive examination.

The VA shall seek to enter into agreements with nonprofit organizations to provide shuttle service to rural covered veterans for such examinations.

(Sec. 205) The VA must provide its police officers with annual training on the prevention of suicide among the population it serves. Each police force of a VA facility must develop a plan to enter into partnerships with local community mental health organizations and experts, local community veterans organizations, local community criminal justice organizations and experts, and local police departments.

(Sec. 301) The VA must complete an analysis and report on its programs that provide assistance to women veterans who are homeless or precariously housed to identify the areas in which such programs are failing to meet the needs of such women.

(Sec. 302) The VA must annually report on the use of VA health care by women veterans.</summary>
</bill>
