<bill session="118" type="s" number="3796" updated="2025-01-14T19:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keeping International Land Ports of Entry Open Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping International Land Ports of Entry Open Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the transfer of Department of Homeland Security staff from an international land port of entry along southwest border unless such transfer would not impact the processing of trade through such port of entry, such staff would be immediately replaced, or such staff are needed to actively engage in physical detentions to secure such border, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2024-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2024-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2024-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2024-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-27T22:48:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keeping International Land Ports of Entry Open Act

This bill prohibits&#160;Department of Homeland Security (DHS) employees from being transferred out of any land port of entry along the U.S.-Mexico border, except in specified circumstances.

The bill permits transfers only if (1) the employee&#160;is immediately replaced by an employee of similar ability; (2) the transfer would not affect the processing of trade through the port of entry;&#160;or (3) the transfer&#160;is necessary to actively engage in physical detentions to secure the U.S.-Mexico border.&#160;

Further, DHS must provide a written notice and explanation of any such&#160;transfer to the public and to specified congressional committees no later than 24 hours after the transfer. The committees are the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</summary>
</bill>
