<bill session="113" type="h" number="2848" updated="2023-01-11T13:24:13Z">
  <state datetime="2013-09-29T00:30:44-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-09-29T00:30:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of State Operations and Embassy Security Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for the Department of State for fiscal year 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of State Operations and Embassy Security Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of State Operations and Embassy Security Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2014</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State Operations and Embassy Security Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2014</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2013-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2013-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-08-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 113-226.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-09-25" calendar="Union" number="166">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 166.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T14:35:30-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Royce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T14:35:51-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5965-6075" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T14:35:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2848.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-28T15:15:15-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-09-29T00:24:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/28/2013 H6010" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="500" datetime="2013-09-29T00:30:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 384 - 37 (Roll no. 500).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/28/2013 H5965-5971" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="113" type="h" number="731" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="113" type="h" number="2099" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="113" type="s" number="978" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="General foreign operations matters"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-12-03T19:37:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of State Operations and Embassy Security Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2014 - Authorizes FY2014 appropriations for: (1) diplomatic and consular programs; (2) the Capital Investment Fund; (3) educational and cultural exchange programs; (4) conflict stabilization operations; (5) representation allowances; (6) protection of foreign missions and officials; (7) diplomatic and consular service emergencies; (8) repatriation loans; (9) the American Institute in Taiwan; (10) the Office of the Inspector General; (11) the International Chancery Center; and (12) embassy security, construction and maintenance.

 Authorizes FY2014 appropriations for Department of State: (1) contributions to international organizations, and (2) international peacekeeping activities.

 Authorizes FY2014 appropriations to the Department for: (1) the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico; (2) the International Boundary Commission, United States and Canada; (3) the International Joint Commission; (4) the International Fisheries Commissions; and (5) the Border Environment Cooperation Commission.

 Authorizes FY2014 appropriations for the National Endowment for Democracy.

 Permits funds won by the Department in a decision of an international tribunal to be used for the International Litigation Fund.

 Requires that Foreign Service positions that have been vacant for more than one assignment cycle be filled on a temporary basis.

Authorizes the establishment of the Center for Strategic Counterterrorism Communications to coordinate public communications activities directed at audiences abroad and targeted against violent extremists and terrorist organizations, especially al-Qa'ida.

 Authorizes the Secretary of State to provide for U.S. participation in the Information Sharing Centre located in Singapore, as established by the Regional Cooperation Agreement on Combating Piracy and Armed Robbery against Ships in Asia.

 Extends the passport surcharge authority through September 30, 2016.

Revises the fee for a border crossing card for minors.

 Repeals specified reporting requirements.

 Authorizes the Secretary to suspend a Foreign Service member without pay when the member's security clearance is suspended or when there is reasonable cause to believe that the member has committed a crime for which a sentence of imprisonment may be imposed.

Entitles such person to: (1) written notice stating the specific reasons for the proposed suspension; (2) reasonable time to respond orally and in writing; (3) representation; (4) a final written decision, including the specific reasons for such decision; and (5) file a grievance. Repeals the recertification requirement for Senior Foreign Service members.

 Authorizes a limited appointment extension for: (1) a person serving in the uniformed services whose limited appointment expires during such service, (2) up to 12 months in exceptional circumstances, and (3) a non-career employee who has served five consecutive years under a limited appointment for a subsequent limited appointment provided there is a one-year break in service.

 Sets maximum accrual of compensatory time off at 104 hours for travel status away from the employee's official duty station.

 Authorizes the Secretary to transfer to other Department officials or offices any authority, duty, or function assigned by statute to the Coordinator for Counterterrorism, the Coordinator for Reconstruction and Stabilization, or the Coordinator for International Energy Affairs.

 Extends the overseas comparability pay limitation through September 30, 2014.

 Directs the Secretary to: (1) submit to Congress a list of high risk, high threat diplomatic and consular posts; and (2) determine if a post should be so designated before its opening or reopening.

Directs the Secretary, before opening or reopening a high risk, high threat post, to establish a working group responsible for the geographic area in which such post is to be opened or reopened.

 Requires: (1) U.S. diplomatic mission emergency action plans to include the threat from complex attacks, and (2) rapid response procedures to include options for deployment of military resources.

Directs the Secretary to complete a strategic review of the Department's Bureau of Diplomatic Security to ensure that its mission and activities are fulfilling current and projected Department needs.

 Expresses the sense of Congress that the capital security cost sharing program should prioritize the construction of new facilities and the maintenance of existing facilities at high risk, high threat posts.

 Prohibits a project to construct a U.S. diplomatic facility from including office space or other accommodations for a federal employee if the employee's department or agency has not provided the Department with the full amount of required funding, except that a project may include office space or other accommodations for members of the U.S. Marine Corps.

 Revises requirements for local guard and protective services contracts abroad, including authorizing the Department to award contracts on the basis of best value rather than lowest price in high risk, high threat areas when necessary.

 Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) transfer to, and merge with, any appropriation for embassy security, construction, and maintenance amounts appropriated for any other purpose related to the administration of foreign affairs on or after October 1, 2013; (2) provide physical security enhancements at overseas educational facilities established for the children of U.S. government employees; and (3) reemploy through October 1, 2018, Foreign Service annuitants in emergency situations or when there is difficulty recruiting or retraining qualified personnel after an open and competitive search has failed to identify qualified, full-time persons.

 Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Overseas Security Policy Board's security standards for U.S. diplomatic and consular posts should apply to all such posts regardless of duration of occupancy, and (2) such posts should comply with requirements for attaining a waiver or exception to applicable standards if in the U.S. national interest.

 Directs the Secretary to station key personnel for sustained periods of time at high risk, high threat posts in order to: (1) establish institutional knowledge and situational awareness that would allow for a fuller familiarization with the local political and security environment, and (2) ensure that necessary security procedures are implemented.

 Requires that: (1) personnel and senior and mid-level officials serving in high risk, high threat posts receive specified security training; and (2) diplomatic security personnel assigned permanently to such posts, or who are in long-term temporary duty status at them, receive specified language training.

 Directs the Secretary to conduct an annual review of the Marine Corps security guard program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-226</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
