<bill session="117" type="s" number="5038" updated="2023-01-13T05:18:08Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Solitary Confinement Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solitary Confinement Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the use of solitary confinement and other forms of restrictive housing in the Bureau of Prisons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5549-5553" label="text"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5548-5553" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-10T20:11:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Solitary Confinement Reform Act

This bill establishes standards for the use of solitary confinement at federal prisons.

It generally limits the use of solitary confinement to situations that meet certain criteria, including confinement for the briefest term and under the least restrictive conditions practicable. It also limits the use of solitary confinement for certain categories of inmates, including pregnant women and individuals with serious mental illness.

The bill requires the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) to

 establish a transitional process for inmates in solitary confinement, provide comprehensive mental health evaluations for inmates in solitary confinement, train employees on mental illness and the psychological effects of solitary confinement, and report annually on the use of solitary confinement. It establishes, within the BOP, an Office of the Civil Rights Ombudsman.

 Finally, it establishes a solitary confinement resource center within the Department of Justice's Bureau of Justice Assistance.</summary>
</bill>
