<bill session="112" type="h" number="578" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:39Z">
  <state datetime="2011-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Parole for Sex Offenders Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that sex offenders and sexually violent predators are not eligible for parole.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Parole for Sex Offenders Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2012-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-03-18T22:11:37Z" status="Introduced in House">No Parole for Sex Offenders Act - Requires a state that is receiving funds for certain law enforcement assistance programs under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to have in effect laws and policies that prohibit parole for any individual who is convicted of a crime against a minor and who is a sexually violent predator (defined as a person who has been convicted of a sexually violent offense and who has been diagnosed by a qualified mental health professional as having a mental abnormality or personality disorder that makes the person likely to engage in predatory sexually violent offenses or who has been determined by a court to suffer from such an illness or disorder). Grants states three years to implement such laws and policies (with one additional two-year extension for states making good faith efforts at implementation).

 Directs the Attorney General to waive the requirements of this Act if compliance by a state would be unconstitutional under that state's constitution. Renders any state that does not implement such laws and policies within the required period ineligible for 10% of funding for its law enforcement assistance programs.</summary>
</bill>
