<bill session="117" type="h" number="8843" updated="2023-01-25T15:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MARINA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maintaining Access to Recreational Industry and Necessary Adjustments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MARINA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Corps of Engineers to take certain actions with respect to rental amounts and administrative fees charged to certain marinas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001108"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2022-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000612" joined="2022-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-25T15:36:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Maintaining Access to Recreational Industry and Necessary Adjustments Act or the MARINA Act 

This bill addresses rental amounts, administrative fees, and lease terms with respect to certain marinas.

The bill establishes that sales of food, beverages, fuel, boats, boat motors, and boat lifts must be capped at 1% for calculating the amount of rent charged to the operator of a marina for a lease.

It directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to establish a standardized fee schedule for administrative fees assessed to operators of marinas that specifies under what circumstances and at what time such a fee is to be assessed.

Additionally, the bill specifies that lease terms for a marina shall be at least 50 years for an initial lease or first renewal of a lease and at least 25 years for any subsequent renewal.</summary>
</bill>
