<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="429" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:56Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="23" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-03-26">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-03-26"/>
  <description>To provide additional pay and benefits for active duty, guard, and reserve forces, such as augmenting Imminent Danger Pay and Family Separation allowance, and for modernization of equipment, weapons, and technology needs of the National Guard and Reserves in recognition of those currently involved in conflict Operations and the needs of their family members left behind.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-03-26" how="roll" result="pass" roll="105">
      <text>Amendment SA 429 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 100 - 0. Record Vote Number: 105.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Amendment SA 429 proposed by Senator Landrieu. (consideration:  CR S4410-4411; text:  CR S4410) To provide additional pay and benefits for active duty, guard, and reserve forces, such as augmenting Imminent Danger Pay and Family Separation allowance, and for modernization of equipment, weapons, and technology needs of the National Guard and Reserves in recognition of those currently involved in conflict Operations and the needs of their family members left behind.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 429 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 100 - 0. Record Vote Number: 105.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 429 proposed by Senator Landrieu.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4410-4411" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S4410" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 429 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 100 - 0. Record Vote Number: 105.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
