<bill session="117" type="s" number="3144" updated="2022-12-30T08:33:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Wildfire Resiliency Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Wildfire Resiliency Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Sutton Mountain National Monument, to authorize certain land exchanges in the State of Oregon, to convey certain Bureau of Land Management land in the State of Oregon to the city of Mitchell, Oregon, and Wheeler County, Oregon, for conservation, economic, and community development purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-13T14:21:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Wildfire Resiliency Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act

This bill establishes the Sutton Mountain National Monument and authorizes land exchanges in Oregon.

The bill establishes the monument, consisting of an Upper Unit and a Lower Unit, to

 increase the wildfire resiliency of Sutton Mountain and the surrounding area; and conserve, protect, and enhance the long-term ecological health of the mountain and the surrounding area for present and future generations. The Department of the Interior shall develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-term conservation and management of the monument that fulfills such purposes.

Interior shall conduct a wildfire risk assessment of the monument. Interior shall develop, based on the wildfire risk assessment, a wildfire mitigation plan that identifies, evaluates, and prioritizes management activities that can be implemented in the Lower Unit to mitigate wildfire risk to structures and communities located near the monument.

Interior shall develop a comprehensive transportation plan for the monument.

The bill authorizes the exchange of federal and nonfederal lands involving the Bureau of Land Management.

Interior shall acquire, for approximately equal value, any land and interests in land owned by Oregon within the monument in exchange for

 the conveyance of federal land or federal mineral interests that are outside the boundaries of the monument, a payment to Oregon, or a combination of such methods.</summary>
</bill>
