<bill session="118" type="s" number="585" updated="2025-11-19T02:52:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Uyghur Human Rights Sanctions Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uyghur Human Rights Sanctions Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a determination of whether certain Chinese entities meet the criteria for the imposition of sanctions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1324" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1770" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-26T17:49:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Uyghur Human Rights Sanctions Review Act

This bill requires that certain Chinese companies be evaluated for placement on the specially designated nationals and blocked persons list, also known as the SDN list. (Being placed on the SDN list can deny the designated individual or entity access to nearly all aspects of the U.S. financial system; it can also deny access to any assets the designee has that are under U.S. jurisdiction, and U.S. persons are usually prohibited from transacting with the designee.)The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to determine if certain specified Chinese companies (such as Alibaba Group Holding, Ltd.&#160;and ByteDance Ltd.) are (1) responsible for or complicit in serious human rights abuses against Uyghurs or other predominantly Muslim ethnic groups in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region of China, or (2) meet the criteria for the imposition of sanctions under certain U.S. laws or executive orders. If the Department of the Treasury determines that a company meets either of these criteria, Treasury must place the company on the SDN list.</summary>
</bill>
