<bill session="109" type="hr" number="398" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:27Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the employees of the Department of Homeland Security, their partners at all levels of government, and the millions of law enforcement agents and emergency response providers nationwide should be commended for their dedicated service on the Nation's front lines in the war against terrorism.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the employees of the Department of Homeland Security, their partners at all levels of government, and the millions of law enforcement agents and emergency response providers nationwide should be commended for their dedicated service on the Nation's front lines in the war against terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000830"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Special months"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-10-01T20:36:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Commends the public servants of the Department of Homeland Security and other federal agencies for their outstanding contributions to our Nation's homeland security.

Salutes the dedication of state, local, territorial, and tribal government officials, the private sector, and citizens across the country for their efforts to enhance the Nation's ability to prevent, deter, protect against, and prepare to respond to potential acts of terrorism.

Expresses the Nation's appreciation for the sacrifices and commitment of our law enforcement and emergency response personnel in preventing and preparing to respond to acts of terrorism.

Supports the goals and ideals of National Preparedness Month as they relate to the threat of terrorism.

Urges the federal government, states, localities, schools, nonprofit organizations, businesses, other entities, and the people of the United States to observe National Preparedness Month with appropriate events and activities that promote citizen and community preparedness to respond to terrorist attacks.</summary>
</bill>
