<bill session="119" type="s" number="96" updated="2025-11-18T18:20:58Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FAIR PREP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR PREP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Autonomy in Independent Returns by Prohibiting Redundant and Extralegal Programs Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prohibit certain activities constituting preparation of tax returns by the Secretary of the Treasury, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="451" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-24T18:57:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fostering Autonomy in Independent Returns by Prohibiting Redundant and Extralegal Programs Act of 2025 or the FAIR PREP Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) from preparing federal tax returns or refund claims, with some exceptions. The bill specifically prohibits the preparation of federal income tax returns or refund claims through the IRS&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Direct File program. (The Direct File program currently allows qualified taxpayers in 25 participating states to prepare and electronically file free federal tax returns through a portal on the IRS&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s website.)

The bill defines prepare with respect to federal tax returns and refund claims as (1) the completion (in whole or in part) of any form or schedule for the purpose of calculating federal taxes or refunds, and (2) the filing (either electronically or on paper) of such federal tax returns or refund claims.

However, under the bill, federal and state tax returns and refund claims may be prepared through the IRS&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Free File program (a program that allows certain taxpayers to prepare and file free federal and state income tax returns&#160;using third-party tax-preparation software) or the Volunteer Income Tax Assistance grant program (through which the IRS partners with local community organizations to help low-income and disabled individuals and persons with limited English proficiency prepare and file free federal and state&#160;income tax returns).

 Further, the Department of the Treasury may not award grants or enter into contracts&#160;or other transactions for the development or operation of an electronic tax preparation service.&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
