<bill session="118" type="h" number="1673" updated="2025-01-16T11:56:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protection from Cumulative Emissions and Underenforcement of Environmental Law Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protection from Cumulative Emissions and Underenforcement of Environmental Law Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To advance environmental justice by addressing cumulative impacts and underenforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian and Insular Affairs .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-17T14:27:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Protection from Cumulative Emissions and Underenforcement of Environmental Law Act of 2023

This bill directs the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to address the cumulative public health risks associated with multiple environmental stressors and recommend measures to reduce the number of violations of environmental law in certain environmental justice communities. Environmental justice communities are communities with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or tribal and indigenous communities that experience, or are at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects, as compared to other communities.

In addition, the EPA must publish and implement a proposal for a protocol that assesses and addresses the cumulative public health risks associated with multiple environmental stressors, such as impacts associated with global climate change.

Further, the EPA must identify at least 100 communities that (1) are environmental justice communities; and (2) have had more environmental law violations than the national average, as determined by the EPA. The EPA must then identify the causes of the violations, identify measures to reduce the number of violations, and implement such measures.</summary>
</bill>
