<bill session="109" type="s" number="1388" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:26Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Regulatory Flexibility Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 6 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Regulatory Flexibility Act), to ensure complete analysis of potential impacts on small entities of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Flexibility Reform Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000121" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000560" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2005-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8220-8221"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8221-8222" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-30T19:27:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Regulatory Flexibility Reform Act of 2005 - Revises the Regulatory Flexibility Act. Defines the "economic impact" of a rule to include any economic effects on small entities.

Requires initial regulatory flexibility analyses of a proposed rule to contain a detailed statement estimating the additional cumulative economic impact of the proposed rule on small entities beyond that already imposed on the class of small entities by the agency or explaining why such an estimate is not available. Requires an agency to notify the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration of any draft rules that may have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities either: (1) when the agency submits a draft rule to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs at the Office of Management and Budget under Executive Order 12866, if that order requires such submission; or (2) if no submission to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs is so required, at a reasonable time before publication of the rule by the agency.

Requires that final regulatory flexibility analyses include the agency's response to any comments filed on a rule by the Chief Counsel and a detailed statement of any changes made as a result. Requires publication of analyses on agency websites.

Revises provisions requiring the publication by each agency of a plan for the periodic review of its rules that have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities to determine whether such rules should be continued, changed, or rescinded.</summary>
</bill>
