<bill session="116" type="h" number="2413" updated="2022-02-08T23:14:50Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nicaragua TPS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate Nicaragua under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to permit nationals of Nicaragua to be eligible for temporary protected status under such section, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nicaragua TPS Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001207" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001206" joined="2019-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-15T18:35:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Nicaragua TPS Act of 2019

This bill establishes that Nicaragua shall be treated as a designated temporary protected status (TPS) country for 18 months from the enactment of this bill. (TPS is available to nationals of certain designated countries, and such aliens shall have work authorization and not be removed from the United States while the status is in effect.)

A Nicaraguan national shall be eligible for such status under this bill if the individual has been continuously physically present in the United States since the bill's enactment, meets the admissibility standards generally applicable to TPS aliens, and registers for such status with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). DHS shall grant a TPS alien prior consent to temporarily travel abroad for emergency and extenuating consequences beyond the alien's control, and the alien shall retain such status upon return.</summary>
</bill>
