<bill session="108" type="h" number="5231" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:42Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Piedras Blancas Light Station and the surrounding public land as an Outstanding Natural Area to be administered as a part of the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-08">
      <text>comments requested from Department of Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-08T19:28:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2004 - Establishes the Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area (Outstanding Natural Area) in San Luis Obispo County, California. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage the Outstanding Natural Area as part of the National Landscape Conservation System and to complete a comprehensive management plan to provide long-term management guidance for the public lands within the Outstanding Natural Area.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with Federal, State, and local agencies to implement the management plan in the Outstanding Natural Area and to continue partnerships with local communities and the Hearst San Simeon State Historical Monument. Provides for the acquisition of State and privately held lands adjacent to the Outstanding Natural Area as additions to the Outstanding Natural Area.

Prohibits restrictions on overflights and law enforcement activities in the Outstanding Natural Area.

Directs the Secretary to ensure access to the Outstanding Natural Area by Indians and Indian tribes for cultural and religious purposes.</summary>
</bill>
