<bill session="109" type="h" number="411" updated="2022-02-03T05:35:10Z">
  <state datetime="2005-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cattleman's Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title type="display">Cattleman's Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To recognize the importance of livestock ranching to the history and continued economic vitality of the western United States and to compensate ranchers when certain Government actions result in the loss or reduction in animal unit months authorized under a grazing permit or lease issued by a Federal land management agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000574"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Sensitivity training"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-03T22:13:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Cattleman's Bill of Rights Act - Directs the National Park Service, the Forest Service, the Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Bureau of Land Management (the Federal land management agency), whenever a land exchange, special-use land designation, or a biological opinion issued pursuant to the Endangered Species Act of 1973 involving Federal land under the agency's jurisdiction results in the elimination or reduction in permitted grazing animal unit months, to: (1) make available alternative, suitable, functionally equivalent forage to the holder of the grazing permit or lease eliminated or subject to the reduction; or (2) compensate the holder of the grazing permit or lease for the value of the permit or lease lost, when alternative forage is not available.

Requires a Federal land management agency to allow the holder of a grazing permit or lease issued by the agency to sublease all or any part of the Federal land allotment covered by the permit or lease, without any fee or charge imposed by the agency, when the sublease will: (1) promote more sustainable use of forage within an area; (2) support ranchers who may be facing economic distress; or (3) promote other objectives identified by the agency.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to develop, implement, and update a training course for employees of the Federal land management agencies regarding the historical uses of the Federal land managed by such employees. Requires range managers to attend such course.</summary>
</bill>
