<bill session="116" type="s" number="3759" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Wildlife Health and Pandemic Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Wildlife Health and Pandemic Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to close high risk wildlife markets and prevent wildlife disease transmission globally, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2020-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-24T16:33:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Global Wildlife Health and Pandemic Prevention Act

This bill establishes measures to close high-risk wildlife markets and prevent outbreaks of diseases of wildlife origin.

A high-risk wildlife market is a commercial market that sells or processes wildlife for human consumption where (1) the species of wildlife or regulation of the market is a risk factor for zoonotic (i.e., naturally transmissible from vertebrate animals to humans) disease spread or is linked with the global illegal trade in wildlife, or (2) the manner of processing the wildlife is a risk factor for zoonotic disease spread.

The Department of State, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS), and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must (1) prioritize the closure of high-risk wildlife markets around the world, (2) provide support for foreign governments in their efforts to close such markets, (3) work with foreign governments and multilateral organizations to develop agreements around closing such markets, and (4) coordinate these activities with existing efforts to combat wildlife trafficking. Further, if a country is determined to be willfully harboring high risk wildlife markets, the President may impose certain sanctions, such as import bans.

The State Department, the USAID, the FWS, USDA, and the U.S. Geological Survey must leverage public health, animal health, and environmental health expertise to, among other things (1) identify high-risk wildlife markets; (2) strengthen global capacity for detection of zoonotic diseases with pandemic potential; and (3) coordinate an approach to global zoonotic disease preparedness, surveillance, and response.</summary>
</bill>
