<bill session="117" type="s" number="2884" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to provide research and extension grants to combat plant pests and noxious weeds that impact coffee plants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Coffee Plant Health Initiative Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coffee Plant Health Initiative Amendments Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2021-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6781" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5421" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-27T10:54:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coffee Plant Health Initiative Amendments Act 

This bill expands the research and extension grant program for the coffee plant health initiative. Under current law, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) may provide competitive grants under the initiative to support research and extension activities to combat the insect known as the coffee berry borer (Hypothenemus hampei).

Specifically, the bill authorizes USDA to provide competitive grants for

 developing and disseminating science-based tools and treatments to combat plant pests and noxious weeds that impact coffee plants; establishing an area-wide integrated pest management program in areas affected by, or at risk of being affected by, plant pests or noxious weeds that impact coffee plants; surveying and collecting data on coffee plant production and health; investigating coffee plant biology, immunology, ecology, genomics, and bioinformatics; and conducting research on various factors that may contribute to or be associated with coffee plant immune systems and other serious threats to coffee plants.</summary>
</bill>
