<bill session="119" type="s" number="919" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">GENIUS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Guiding and Establishing National Innovation for U.S. Stablecoins Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GENIUS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guiding and Establishing National Innovation for U.S. Stablecoins Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the regulation of payment stablecoins, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GENIUS Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000601"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2025-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Reported by Senator Scott SC, under authority of the order of the Senate of 03/14/2025 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="33">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 33.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-28T19:54:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Guiding and Establishing National Innovation for U.S. Stablecoins Act of 2025 or the GENIUS Act of 2025

This bill establishes a regulatory framework for payment&#160;stablecoins (digital assets which an issuer must redeem for a fixed value).

Under the bill, only permitted issuers may issue a payment stablecoin for use by U.S. persons, subject to certain exceptions. Permitted issuers must be a subsidiary of an insured depository institution, a federal-qualified nonbank payment stablecoin issuer, or a state-qualified payment stablecoin issuer. Permitted issuers must be regulated by the appropriate federal or state&#160;regulator. Permitted issuers may choose federal or state regulation; however, state regulation is&#160;limited to those with&#160;a&#160;stablecoin issuance of $10 billion or less.

Permitted issuers must maintain reserves backing the&#160;stablecoin on a one-to-one basis using U.S. currency or other similarly liquid assets, as specified. Permitted issuers must also publicly disclose their redemption policy and publish monthly&#160;the details of their reserves.

The bill specifies requirements for (1) reusing reserves; (2) providing safekeeping services for&#160;stablecoins; and (3) supervisory, examination, and enforcement authority over federal-qualified issuers.

The bill allows foreign issuers to offer stablecoins in the United States if the issuer has the capability to comply with lawful orders. The Department of the Treasury must establish reciprocal agreements between the United States and similarly regulated jurisdictions.

Under the bill, permitted payment stablecoins are not considered securities under securities law. However, permitted issuers&#160;are&#160;subject to the Bank Secrecy Act for anti-money laundering and related purposes.</summary>
</bill>
