<bill session="116" type="s" number="2606" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:38Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Limos Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Limos Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safety, Accountability, and Federal Enforcement of Limos Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish safety standards for certain limousines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5847-5849" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4708" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-13T14:16:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safety, Accountability, and Federal Enforcement of Limos Act of 2019 or the SAFE Limos Act 

This bill establishes safety standards for stretch limousines.

Among other requirements, the bill requires

 safety belts to be installed in stretch limousines with a gross vehicle weight rating greater than 8,500 pounds at each designated seating position, including on side-facing seats; the Department of Transportation (DOT) to develop and issue guidelines, best practices, and recommendations to assist stretch limousine alterers develop and administer a vehicle modifier plan; DOT to complete research into side impact protection, roof crush resistance, and air bag systems for the protection of occupants in stretch limousines given alternative seating positions or interior configurations, including perimeter seating arrangements; stretch limousine operators to disclose (1) the date of the most recent inspection of the limousine required under state or federal law, (2) the results of the inspection, and (3) any corrective actions taken to ensure the limousine passes inspection; and the use of event data recorders in stretch limousines.</summary>
</bill>
