<bill session="118" type="s" number="787" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Airline Operational Resiliency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airline Operational Resiliency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Comptroller General of the United States to study and report on the operational preparedness of air carriers for preparing for changing weather and other events related to changing conditions and natural hazards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-14T18:51:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Airline Operational Resiliency Act of 2023

This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to study and report on air carriers' operational preparedness for changing weather and other events related to changing conditions and natural hazards (e.g., flooding, extreme heat, storms, and fire conditions). GAO must also make recommendations for any related legislative and administrative action.

As part of the study, GAO must assess

 the extent to which air carriers are preparing for weather events and natural disasters, as well as changing conditions, that may have an impact on air carriers' operational investments, staffing levels and safety policies, and mitigation strategies; how the Federal Aviation Administration oversees air carriers' operational resilience to these types of events; and steps the federal government and air carriers can take to improve their operational resilience.</summary>
</bill>
