<bill session="108" type="s" number="692" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:27Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Consumer Right to Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Trade Commission to issue rules regarding the disclosure of technological measures that restrict consumer flexibility to use and manipulate digital information and entertainment content.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Consumer Right to Know Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4326-4327"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4327-4328" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2838"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Computer viruses"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Reporters and reporting"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Digital Consumer Right to Know Act - Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to issue rules to implement requirements that a producer or distributor of copyrighted digital content disclose the nature of restrictions that limit the practical ability of the content purchaser to play, copy, transmit, or transfer such content on, to, or between devices commonly used with respect to that type of content. Requires such disclosure in the case of limitations on: (1) the recording for later viewing or listening of certain audio or video programming; (2) the reasonable and noncommercial use of legally acquired audio or video content; (3) making backup copies of legally acquired content subject to accidental damage, erasure, or destruction; (4) using limited excerpts of legally acquired content; and (5) engaging in the secondhand transfer or sale of legally acquired content. Provides disclosure exceptions. Requires the FTC to annually review the effectiveness of such rules.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) competition among distribution outlets and methods generally benefits consumers; and (2) copyright holders selling digital content in electronic form for distribution over the Internet should offer to license such content to multiple unaffiliated distributors.</summary>
</bill>
