<bill session="118" type="s" number="3593" updated="2025-11-18T12:03:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Truckee Meadows Public Lands Management Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truckee Meadows Public Lands Management Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Truckee Meadows Public Lands Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for economic development and conservation in Washoe County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2024-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="604">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 604.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-23T17:06:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Truckee Meadows Public Lands Management Act

This bill conveys, disposes, transfers, designates, and withdraws certain federal lands in Washoe County, Nevada. Specifically, the bill

conveys certain Department of the Interior and Forest Service lands to, for example, Nevada, the city of Reno, the city of Sparks, Washoe County, and other local governmental entities;&#160;requires Interior and the Forest Service to sell certain federal lands and to evaluate such lands for affordable housing suitability;requires such sales for affordable housing to be priced at less than fair market value;requires certain Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands to be held in trust for certain Indian tribes;&#160;requires certain tribal fee lands to be held in trust for those tribes;&#160;designates certain public lands as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System;&#160;authorizes Interior to conduct management activities in the wilderness areas to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats;&#160;requires BLM to accept voluntary donations of grazing permits and leases on certain lands, terminate such permits or leases, and permanently&#160;end grazing on the land covered by such permits or leases;&#160;establishes certain National Conservation Areas; and&#160;withdraws certain federal lands from (1) entry and appropriation under public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under mining laws, and (3) operation of mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
</bill>
