<bill session="118" type="s" number="1642" updated="2025-11-19T04:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ReConnecting Rural America Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ReConnecting Rural America Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to establish the ReConnect program under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2024-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2024-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4227" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-12T14:29:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">ReConnecting Rural America Act of 2023

This bill merges the pilot ReConnect Loan and Grant Program with existing loans and grants provided by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to facilitate broadband access to rural areas that lack sufficient access to broadband. It also requires that any unobligated amounts available for the pilot program be transferred and made available, without further appropriations, to the merged program. The bill authorizes the merged program through FY2028.

The bill specifies the eligibility criteria and other requirements that apply to the merged program, some of which are the same as the criteria and requirements that currently apply to the pilot program (e.g., the required minimum upload and download speeds).

Further, the bill (1) eliminates the authority of USDA to make loan guarantees, and (2) authorizes USDA to make combinations of grants and loans.

The bill also requires that recipients of grants and loans participate in specified federal programs that assist low-income individuals access broadband and telecommunication services.</summary>
</bill>
