<bill session="111" type="h" number="4024" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:19Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Act to revise and extend that Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000014" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000611" joined="2010-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2707"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="76" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-05T19:53:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Reauthorizes for for FY2009-FY2014 and revises the Native Hawaiian Health Care Improvement Act. Requires any Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) grant to or contract with Papa Ola Lokahi (an organization of public agencies and private organizations focused on improving the health status of Native Hawaiians) to support community-based initiatives that reflect holistic approaches to health.

Requires Papa Ola Lokahi to report to Congress on the impact of federal and state health care financing mechanisms and policies on the health and well-being of Native Hawaiians. Makes Papa Ola Lokahi eligible to receive research endowments under the Public Health Service Act. Adds to authorized services the support of culturally appropriate activities enhancing health and wellness, including land-, water-, ocean-, and spiritually-based projects and programs. Allows a priority for Native Hawaiian health scholarships to be provided to employees of the Native Hawaiian Health Care Systems and the Native Hawaiian Health Centers. Allows the provision of financial assistance to a scholarship recipient during the period of obligated service in any of such health care systems or health centers. Authorizes Papa Ola Lokahi to provide fellowships to Native Hawaiian health professionals. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to allocate funds to carry out Native Hawaiian demonstration projects of national significance, including the establishment of specified Native Hawaiian Centers of Excellence. Deems the Papa Ola Lokahi as a qualified Center of Excellence.</summary>
</bill>
