<bill session="116" type="s" number="1629" updated="2022-11-01T06:02:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to regulate certain pay-to-win microtransactions and sales of loot boxes in interactive digital entertainment products, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate certain pay-to-win microtransactions and sales of loot boxes in interactive digital entertainment products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Games and hobbies"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-02T16:03:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill prohibits the publication or distribution of interactive video games and digital entertainment products that (1) include pay-to-win features and (2) are targeted to minors under the age of 18.

Pay-to-win features include making available for purchase assistance, advantages, or other awards that a reasonable user would perceive provides a competitive advantage in the progression of the game or product over those users who do not make such purchase. Pay-to-play features do not include purchases (1) that alter only the appearance of the game, (2) of game modes that make game-play progression more difficult that without such purchase, or (3) of add-ons that do not assist in the progression of the underlying game or product. Additionally, game publishers and distributors are prohibited from including pay-to-play features in games and digital entertainment products that are not targeted to minors but where the publisher or distributor reasonably should know that minors use such games or products.</summary>
</bill>
