<bill session="118" type="s" number="3147" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Flood Protection and Infrastructure Resilience Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Protection and Infrastructure Resilience Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify Department of Agriculture programs to improve flood protection and infrastructure resiliency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3972" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5250" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-18T15:15:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Flood&#160;Protection and Infrastructure Resilience Act of 2023

This bill modifies Department of Agriculture&#160;(USDA) watershed programs.

The bill modifies the Emergency Watershed Protection (EWP) Program to allow USDA to undertake certain measures that go beyond addressing the immediate impairment of the watershed. Specifically, USDA may undertake measures that increase the level of protection of the watershed if USDA determines that the restoration is in the best interest of the long-term health and the protection of the watershed from repetitive impairments. (The EWP Program assists sponsors, landowners, and operators in implementing emergency recovery measures for runoff retardation and erosion prevention to relieve imminent hazards to life and property created by natural disasters.)&#160;

In addition, for Watershed Rehabilitation Program (REHAB) projects that serve a limited resource area, the bill increases the federal cost-share to up to&#160;90% of the total rehabilitation costs. Currently, the federal cost-share for all projects is 65% of the total rehabilitation costs. (REHAB assists project sponsors in rehabilitating aging watershed dams that are reaching the end of their design life or no longer meet certain federal or state standards.)

Further, the purpose of the Regional Conservation Partnership Program (RCPP) is amended&#160;to include the prevention and mitigation of the effects of flooding and drought and the improvement or expansion of flood resiliency. (Under the RCPP, USDA enters into agreements with eligible partners to deliver conservation projects in specific geographical areas. Within an RCPP project, producers enter into contracts and agreements with USDA to carry out eligible conservation activities.)</summary>
</bill>
