<bill session="119" type="s" number="841" updated="2025-09-23T16:41:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Romance Scam Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Romance Scam Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Romance Scam Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require online dating service providers to provide fraud ban notifications to online dating service members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2025-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cruz with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 119-58.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-09-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="145">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 145.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2481" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-27T15:33:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Romance Scam Prevention Act

This bill requires online dating service providers (i.e., mobile applications or websites) to provide users with&#160;a fraud ban notification if the user has established an account with the service and received a message through the service from a banned user of the service.

The fraud ban notification must include (1) the username or other profile identifier of the banned user and the most recent time when the user who is receiving the notification sent or received a message through the service&#160;to or from the banned user, (2) a statement that the banned user may have been using a false identity or&#160;attempting to defraud other users, (3) a statement that the user should not send cash (or another form of currency) or personal financial information to another user, (4) information about avoiding online fraud (e.g., a link to another website or a disclosure) and (5) contact information for the provider's customer service department.

The bill provides for enforcement of these requirements by the Federal Trade Commission and state attorneys general.&#160;&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-58</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
