<bill session="118" type="h" number="413" updated="2025-01-16T11:48:07Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TOTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TOTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency Over Toys Spying Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish requirements for the labeling and user agreements of internet-connected toys for children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2023-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000308" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2023-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2023-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-27T12:33:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency Over Toys Spying Act or the TOTS Act

This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission to issue rules requiring internet-connected toys to include a label indicating that the toy has the ability to connect to the internet and collect and transmit personal information of the user. The label must also indicate whether personal information collected by the toy is retained in the toy or by the manufacturer or another entity. Further, any user agreement or privacy policy associated with the toy must prominently state specified information about how personal information may be collected and used by the manufacturer or other entity.

Internet-connected toys include entertainment devices that are targeted to, or likely to be operated by, children and are able to connect to the internet and collect and transmit personal information.

The bill also authorizes the commission to enforce these rules.</summary>
</bill>
