<bill session="109" type="h" number="905" updated="2019-11-15T21:28:57Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Leasing Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Coal Leasing Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to provide for the development of Federal coal resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000962"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Sulphur dioxide"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-24T22:12:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Coal Leasing Amendments Act of 2005 - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to repeal the 160-acre limitation placed upon coal leases. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to establish a mining plan period of more than 40 years upon a determination that the longer period: (1) will ensure the maximum economic recovery of a coal deposit; or (2) the longer period is in the interest of the orderly, efficient, or economic development of a coal resource.Revises the statutory formula for the payment of advance royalties. Extends from ten years to twenty years the lease term for which advance royalties may be accepted in lieu of the condition of continued operation.Eliminates the deadline for submission of a coal lease operation and reclamation plan.Prohibits the Secretary from requiring a surety bond or any other financial assurance to guarantee payment of deferred bonus bid installments with respect to any coal lease issued based upon a cash bonus bid.Requires the Secretary to review and identify for Congress coal assessments on public lands and the restrictions or impediments to development of those resources.</summary>
</bill>
