<bill session="118" type="s" number="279" updated="2025-11-18T20:24:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preserving the Gulf Test Range to Ensure Military Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving the Gulf Test Range to Ensure Military Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a moratorium on energy development in certain areas of the Gulf of Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="970" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-14T18:11:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preserving the Gulf Test Range to Ensure Military Readiness Act

This bill establishes a moratorium on energy development (e.g., offshore wind development) in specified areas of the Gulf of Mexico until June 30, 2032.

Until that date, the Department of the Interior may not conduct certain energy development activities in any area east of the Military Mission Line in the Gulf of Mexico. The moratorium also applies to other areas of the Outer Continental Shelf&#8212;the South Atlantic Planning Area, the Straits of Florida Planning Area, or any area west of the Military Mission Line in the Eastern Gulf of Mexico Planning Area&#8212;if energy exploration, leasing, or development in that area has been identified as having any adverse effect on national security, military readiness, or the Department of Defense's testing capabilities.

However, Interior may issue leases in those areas for environmental conservation purposes, including the purposes of shore protection, beach nourishment and restoration, wetlands restoration, and habitat protection.</summary>
</bill>
