<bill session="116" type="s" number="4512" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Equal Access to Information Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Access to Information Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish requirements for Federal agencies to ensure that individuals with limited English proficiency and people with disabilities can access the services, activities, programs, and the benefits of those agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8682" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-16T18:28:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Equal Access to Information Act of 2020

This bill requires federal agencies to take specified steps to ensure that individuals with limited English proficiency and people with disabilities can access the services, activities, programs, and benefits of those agencies, particularly during national or public health emergencies or under other specified circumstances.

Specifically, each federal agency shall, within specified timeframes

 conduct demographic assessments of individuals with limited English proficiency and individuals with disabilities who are eligible to be served or likely to be encountered by that agency, establish within the agency a Language Access Working Group, prepare and submit to the Department of Justice (DOJ) an access plan for federally conducted programs and activities, and issue guidance for recipients of federal financial assistance under the agency's jurisdiction. DOJ shall review (1) each plan submitted within 120 days after receipt of the plan, and (2) the most recently submitted plan from each relevant agency not later than 7 days after an emergency has been declared.

Agencies shall ensure stakeholder input to ensure meaningful access.</summary>
</bill>
