<bill session="119" type="h" number="357" updated="2025-05-27T21:27:51Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Back to Work Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Back to Work Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide limitations on Federal teleworking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2025-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-27T21:26:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Back to Work Act

This bill limits&#160;federal agency employees' telework to up to 40% of the work days&#160;in any pay period and eliminates certain pay increases for teleworking employees.

Under current law, executive agencies must maintain policies detailing how their employees may work remotely and enter into telework agreements with participating employees. The bill requires telework agreements to cap employees' telework at 40% of the work days&#160;in a pay period, specify&#160;that the agency will monitor employees' telework via remote technical methods, and make telework&#160;subject to annual review by the agency.&#160;The bill also&#160;eliminates locality-based and automatic annual pay adjustments for employees with telework agreements.

The bill authorizes agencies to further restrict the amount of telework permitted based on an employee's specific role or other circumstances (e.g., working with classified information). Agencies may also waive the limitation for inclement weather or&#160;exigent circumstances or for an employee who (1) is married to a member of the Armed Forces or federal law enforcement officer; (2) holds a position requiring highly specialized experience or frequent travel; or (3) holds a&#160;position that is difficult to fill.

Additionally, the bill requires annual agency reports to Congress&#160;describing the effectiveness of agency telework policies. The Government Accountability Office must evaluate the accuracy and thoroughness of each report&#160;in an accompanying report to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
