<bill session="119" type="h" number="2524" updated="2025-05-14T15:10:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPEAL CBO Requirements Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPEAL CBO Requirements Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Replacing Exploitative Partisan Estimates with Alternatives by Liquidating Congressional Budget Office Requirements</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to provide that Congress may request estimates of legislation from reputable accounting firms for purposes of budget enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001129" joined="2025-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-14T15:10:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Replacing Exploitative Partisan Estimates with Alternatives by Liquidating Congressional Budget Office Requirements or the REPEAL CBO Requirements Act

This bill allows&#160;certain&#160;congressional committees to obtain cost estimates for legislation from private reputable accounting firms rather than the Congressional Budget Office (CBO).

Under current law, CBO is generally required to produce cost estimates for most bills that are reported by congressional committees. This bill allows chairs of congressional committees (except the appropriations committees) to obtain estimates for reported legislation from a private reputable accounting firm instead of&#160;CBO. Under the bill, a private reputable accounting firm means any of the 10 public accounting firms registered with the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board with the largest net revenue during the previous year.

If a committee chair obtains an estimate from a private accounting firm pursuant to this bill, (1) the estimate must be used for budget enforcement purposes, and (2) CBO may not prepare an estimate for the applicable measure.</summary>
</bill>
