<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>718</number>
    <updateDate>2025-01-14T18:22:18Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2025-01-14T18:22:18Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2023-03-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>118</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssbu00</systemCode>
        <name>Budget Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2023-03-08T20:29:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-03-08</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssbu00</systemCode>
            <name>Budget Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-03-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001310</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Braun, Mike [R-IN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Braun</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IN</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        <updateDate>2023-05-25T19:00:53Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2023-03-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2024-01-19T18:51:24Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;This bill establishes a Federal Rainy Day Fund to fund emergency spending. Under the bill, an &lt;em&gt;emergency &lt;/em&gt; is any occasion or instance for which federal assistance is needed to supplement state and local efforts and capabilities to save lives and to protect property, public health, and safety or to lessen or avert the threat of a catastrophe in any part of the United States.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The bill authorizes annual appropriations to the fund that are equal to 2% of the previous year's nonemergency discretionary spending. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In addition, the bill modifies or establishes various budget enforcement procedures to address spending from the fund. For example, the bill &lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;establishes a point of order to prohibit the fund from being used for nonemergency spending,&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;establishes a point of order against provisions that provide emergency spending from the general fund of the Treasury when unobligated funds are available in the rainy day fund, and &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;repeals a provision that currently requires adjustments to discretionary spending limits to accommodate emergency spending. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;The bill also requires an affirmative vote of two-thirds (currently three-fifths) of the Senate to waive a budget point of order that is raised in the Senate against legislation because it would cause a committee's spending allocation to be exceeded. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on the relationship between emergency, disaster, and wildfire spending, including any recommendations to modify the spending that qualifies as emergency spending. &lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>A bill to establish the Federal Rainy Day Fund to control emergency spending.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to establish the Federal Rainy Day Fund to control emergency spending.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-03-30T14:49:52Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to establish the Federal Rainy Day Fund to control emergency spending.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-03-21T02:13:46Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2023-03-08T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-118s718is/xml/BILLS-118s718is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2023-03-08</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
