<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="921" updated="2022-02-03T06:00:29Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3582" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-02-02T17:00:21-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-02-02"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require that, in addition to preparing cost estimates for each bill or resolution reported by any committee of the House, the Congressional Budget Office must also prepare an estimate of the number of jobs which would be created, sustained, or lost in carrying out the measure--including regional and State level estimates.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 8 printed in Part B of House Report 112-383 to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require that, in addition to preparing cost estimates for each bill or resolution reported by any committee of the House, the Congressional Budget Office also prepare an estimate of the number of jobs which would be created, sustained, or lost in carrying out the measure--including regional and State level estimates.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-02-02T17:00:21-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="28">
      <text>On agreeing to the Cicilline amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 174 - 245 (Roll no. 28).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02T16:04:28-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Cicilline.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H412-413, H416" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H412" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02T17:00:21-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Cicilline amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 174 - 245 (Roll no. 28).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02T16:04:28-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A008) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Cicilline.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H412-413, H416" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H412" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02T17:00:21-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02T17:00:21-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-02">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
