<bill session="118" type="h" number="4382" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agricultural Access to Addiction and Mental Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Access to Addiction and Mental Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct a study on the accessibility of addiction and mental health care providers and services for farmers and ranchers who have been impacted by severe and persistent drought, extreme weather events, instability in the commodities market, misinformation targeting consumers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T21:47:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Agricultural Access to Addiction and Mental Health Care Act

This bill directs the National Institute of Food and Agriculture (NIFA) to study the accessibility of addiction and mental health care providers and services for farmers and ranchers impacted by severe and persistent drought, extreme weather events, instability in the commodities market, and misinformation targeting consumers.

For example, the study must examine (1) best practices and successful programs at the state and local level that can be replicated at the federal level to address addiction and mental health care needs in agricultural communities, and (2) recommendations for improving the accessibility of care.

In conducting the study, NIFA must collaborate and consult with relevant federal agencies, state departments of agriculture, and mental health and agricultural organizations.</summary>
</bill>
