<bill session="116" type="s" number="2580" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:49Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">An original bill making appropriations for the Department of the Interior, environment, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Department of the Interior, environment, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Murkowski. With written report No. 116-123.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-09-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="227">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 227.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1865" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3052" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-10-01T11:53:35Z" status="Reported to Senate">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020

This bill provides FY2020 appropriations for the Department of the Interior, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to Interior for

 the Bureau of Land Management, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the National Park Service, the U.S. Geological Survey, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement, the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Bureau of Indian Education, Departmental Offices, and Department-Wide Programs. The bill provides appropriations to the EPA and the Forest Service.

Within the Department of Health and Human Services, the bill provides appropriations for

 the Indian Health Service, the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, and the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry. The bill provides appropriations to several related agencies, including

 the Executive Office of the President for the Council on Environmental Quality and the Office of Environmental Quality; the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; the Smithsonian Institution; the National Gallery of Art; the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars; the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities, including the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Endowment for the Humanities; the Commission of Fine Arts; the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; the National Capital Planning Commission; the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum; the Dwight D. Eisenhower Memorial Commission; the Women's Suffrage Centennial Commission; the World War I Centennial Commission; and the Alyce Spotted Bear and Walter Soboleff Commission on Native Children. Additionally, the bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-123</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
