<bill session="118" type="s" number="2706" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to require the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into cooperative agreements relating to drought prevention, preparedness, response, and mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to require the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into cooperative agreements relating to drought prevention, preparedness, response, and mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-27T10:45:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to enter into multiyear cooperative agreements with a policy research center to conduct research and education programs that focus on drought prevention, preparedness, response, and mitigation.

An eligible policy research center includes a state agricultural experiment station, college or university, or other public research institution or organization that has a history of providing objective, scientific information to federal agencies and the public to support and enhance efficient, accurate implementation of federal drought preparedness and drought response programs.

A&#160;center must also conduct research and education programs that concern the effect of public policies and trade agreements on (1) the farm and agricultural sectors; (2) the environment; (3) rural families, households, and economies; and (4) consumers, food, and nutrition.

In awarding agreements, USDA must give a preference to centers that have information, analysis, and research relating to drought mitigation.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
