<bill session="116" type="h" number="7472" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Secure Data and Privacy for Contact Tracing Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to award grants to eligible State, Tribal, and territorial public health agencies to develop and administer a program for digital contact tracing for COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Data and Privacy for Contact Tracing Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2020-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="5027" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-12T20:35:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure Data and Privacy for Contact Tracing Act of 2020

This bill requires the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to award grants to public health agencies in states, tribes, and territories to incorporate digital contact tracing technology in COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) contact tracing programs.

This technology must meet requirements with respect to contact tracing functions, data security and privacy, and voluntary use. Grantees that develop or procure technology that does not meet these requirements lose eligibility for this funding and future funding for COVID-19 contact tracing technology.

Furthermore, as a condition of receiving funding, grantees must (1) undertake an independent security assessment, and (2) develop a plan that delineates how the technology augments existing COVID-19 contact tracing and response efforts and addresses interoperability and protections to limit access to the data.

In addition, the bill expressly applies federal privacy standards for the use and disclosure of personal health information by health care providers, health plans, health clearinghouses, and their business associates to contact tracing technology and its use. Current law provides an exception to these standards for personal health information used by, or disclosed to, a public health authority that is legally authorized to collect the information. The bill also prohibits the use of data derived from the contact tracing technology in legal proceedings or for immigration enforcement.

The Government Accountability Office must evaluate this program within 90 days.</summary>
</bill>
