<bill session="108" type="s" number="1945" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bipartisan Patient Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to protect consumers in managed care plans and other health coverage.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bipartisan Patient Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2004-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000286" joined="2003-11-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000352" joined="2003-11-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-11-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2004-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2083" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health care industry"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Mastectomy"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-08-30T14:33:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bipartisan Patient Protection Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act (PHSA) and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) with respect to health care coverage. Provides for patient protection and quality care standards for individual and group health plans under PHSA and ERISA. Applies such standards, as well, to: (1) all Federal health care programs, as defined under the Social Security Act; and (2) the Federal employee health benefits program. Requires group health plans and health insurance issuers providing health insurance coverage to have approved utilization review programs, claims procedures, and appeal procedures concerning claims denials.Sets forth provisions concerning group health plans and health insurers and the provision of certain advice and care, including: (1) emergency care; (2) obstetric and gynecological care; (3) specialists care; (4) prescription drugs; (5) participation in approved clinical trials; and (6) health plan information.Restricts interference by health plans and insurers with the doctor-patient relationship.Prohibits health plans and insurers from discriminating against a licensed health care professional with respect to participation or indemnification. Sets forth limitations on certain class action litigation and other actions. Makes certain civil remedies available. Declares that courts should consider the loss of a nonwage earning spouse or parent as an economic loss to be fully compensated in certain ERISA cases.

Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) men and women battling life-threatening, deadly diseases, including advanced breast or ovarian cancer, should have the opportunity to participate in a federally approved or funded clinical trial; (2) a child battling a rare cancer should be allowed to go to a cancer center capable of providing high quality care for that disease; and (3) every patient who is denied care by a health maintenance organization or other health insurance company should have a fair, speedy, and impartial appeal to a review organization that has not been selected by the health plan.</summary>
</bill>
