<bill session="118" type="s" number="3018" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 and the National Labor Relations Act to clarify the standard for determining whether an individual is an employee, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 and the National Labor Relations Act to clarify the standard for determining whether an individual is an employee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2023-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2023-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5513" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-26T16:22:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill specifies a legal standard for determining whether an individual is considered an independent contractor rather than an employee for the purposes of federal labor laws that address issues such as the federal minimum wage, overtime compensation, and collective bargaining. The rights and protections provided by these laws exclusively apply to employees.

Under the bill, an individual is considered an independent contractor if (1) another individual or entity does not exercise significant control over the details of how the individual's work is performed, without regard to any control the other individual or entity may exercise over the final result of the work performed; and (2) while performing such work, the individual has opportunities and risks inherent with entrepreneurship (for example, the discretion to exercise professional judgment).

The bill also sets forth factors that may not be used to determine whether an individual is an employee. Specifically, factors such as whether another individual or entity requires the individual to meet certain legal, health and safety, insurance, or performance requirements may not be used to make such a determination.</summary>
</bill>
