<bill session="117" type="s" number="651" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STAT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend SAFETEA-LU to improve the Intelligent Transportation System Program Advisory Committee, to require information and resources for the development of local smart communities, to help establish a 21st century transportation workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smart Transportation Advancement and Transition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-29T17:52:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Smart Transportation Advancement and Transition Act or the STAT Act

This bill revises and permanently reauthorizes the Intelligent Transportation Systems Advisory Committee of the Department of Transportation (DOT).

DOT, in coordination with the advisory committee, must report on its efforts to engage local communities, metropolitan planning organizations, regional transportation commissions, and multi-jurisdictional groups, including in rural areas, on advancing data and intelligent transportation systems technologies and other smart cities solutions.

Additionally, DOT must create, publish, and maintain a resource guide that is designed to assist states and local communities in developing and implementing intelligent transportation technology or smart community transportation programs. DOT and the advisory committee must issue a revised community resource guide at least once every three years.</summary>
</bill>
