<bill session="118" type="h" number="7723" updated="2024-12-16T20:37:38Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit the solicitation and acceptance of a recurring contribution or donation in a campaign for election for Federal office by any method which does not require the contributor or donor to give affirmative consent to making the contribution or donation on a recurring basis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit the solicitation and acceptance of a recurring contribution or donation in a campaign for election for Federal office by any method which does not require the contributor or donor to give affirmative consent to making the contribution or donation on a recurring basis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000598" joined="2024-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2024-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2024-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-09T12:39:56Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill places restrictions on recurring political contributions or donations.

Specifically, the bill prohibits any person from soliciting a recurring contribution or donation for a political committee, an independent expenditure, or an electioneering communication by any method that does not require the affirmative consent of the contributor or donor. In addition, the bill prohibits a political committee, a person funding an independent expenditure, or a person funding an electioneering communication from accepting a recurring contribution or donation unless the contributor or donor gave affirmative consent. This affirmative consent cannot be a passive action by the contributor or donor, such as failing to uncheck a prechecked box.

Further, any person who accepts a recurring contribution or donation must (1) provide a receipt for the initial contribution or donation and for each recurrence that clearly and conspicuously discloses all material terms, (2) provide all information needed to cancel the recurring contribution or donation in each communication with the contributor or donor, and (3) immediately cancel recurring contributions or donations upon request of the contributor or donor.</summary>
</bill>
