<bill session="117" type="h" number="2585" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIRE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To conduct fire salvage on certain National Forest System lands burned by wildfire, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forestry Improvements to Restore the Environment Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000301"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001109" joined="2021-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-15T00:25:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Forestry Improvements to Restore the Environment Act of 2021 or the FIRE Act of 2021

This bill provides for salvage activities after a wildfire is contained on certain National Forest System lands.

No later than 60 days after a wildfire is contained on such lands (1) the Forest Service, to the maximum extent practicable, shall complete a survey of the lands that were impacted by such wildfire; and (2) the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall convert the timber sales applicable to such lands that were impacted by such wildfire to salvage sales.

The bill designates a categorical exclusion for forest management activities where the primary purpose of the activity is for roadside salvage activities that allow for the removal of hazard trees that are within 200 feet of a roadway center line.

Activities carried out pursuant to this bill shall be subject to judicial review in the same manner as authorized hazardous fuels reduction projects.

A court may not order a preliminary injunction enjoining the USDA from proceeding with timber sales authorized under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
