<bill session="119" type="s" number="444" updated="2025-05-28T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Emergency Mobilization Accountability (FEMA) Workforce Planning Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Emergency Mobilization Accountability (FEMA) Workforce Planning Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the development of a workforce plan for the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-28T19:32:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Emergency Mobilization Accountability (FEMA) Workforce Planning Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to develop and submit to Congress every three years a human capital operating plan to shape and improve FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s workforce, and it requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to submit a report analyzing the plan.

Specifically, the bill lists contents FEMA must include in the plan, such as performance measures to track staffing and training, strategies for increasing cost-efficiency, and a plan of action to address gaps in critical and emerging skills in FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s workforce. The plan must discuss the membership and training of the Surge Capacity Force, through which federal employees deploy in response to a catastrophic disaster. FEMA must submit the first plan within one year after the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment and subsequent plans at least once every three years.

The bill also requires GAO to submit a report analyzing whether FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s plan meets the requirements of the bill, including any recommendations to ensure subsequent plans meet the requirements.</summary>
</bill>
