<bill session="108" type="s" number="1435" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:49Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-09-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the analysis of the incidence and effects of prison rape in Federal, State, and local institutions and to provide information, resources, recommendations, and funding to protect individuals from prison rape.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-07-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9659-9664" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S9659-9664" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T09:02:01-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22T22:49:11-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T18:39:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7764-7771" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T18:39:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2003-07-25T18:40:13-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7766-7771" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T18:40:15-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-09-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-09-04" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-79" type="public" datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-79.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Legislative Interest, Legislative Interest, Legislative Interest"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1765" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1707" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Criminology"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee crimes"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prison violence"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Psychotherapy"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Punishment"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Social science research"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-31T00:02:58Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.)

Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Bureau of Justice Statistics to carry out, annually, a comprehensive statistical review and analysis of the incidence and effects of prison rape. Requires: (1) the review and analysis to be based on a sample of not less than ten percent of all Federal, State, and county prisons, and a representative sample of municipal prisons, that includes at least one prison from each State; and (2) Federal, State, or local officials or facility administrators that receive a request from the Bureau to participate in the national survey and provide access to any inmates under their legal custody.

Establishes within the Department of Justice the Review Panel on Prison Rape to carry out, for each calendar year, public hearings concerning the operation of the three prisons with the highest incidence of prison rape and the two prisons with the lowest incidence in each category of facilities identified. Declares that the purpose of these hearings shall be to collect evidence to aid in the identification of common characteristics of: (1) victims and perpetrators of prison rape; (2) prisons and prison systems with a high incidence of prison rape; and and (3) prisons and prison systems that appear to have been successful in deterring prison rape.



Requires the Attorney General to submit an annual report to Congress and the Secretary of Health and Human Services on Bureau and Panel activities regarding prison rape. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2010. (Sec. 5) Establishes within the National Institute of Corrections (NIC) a national clearinghouse for the provision of information, assistance, and training to Federal, State, and local authorities for the prevention, investigation, and punishment of prison rape. (Sec. 6) Directs the Attorney General to make grants to to assist States in ensuring that budgetary circumstances do not compromise efforts to protect inmates and to safeguard the communities to which inmates return. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2010, with a limitation. (Sec. 7) Establishes the National Prison Rape Reduction Commission to: (1) study the impact of prison rape on Federal, State, and local governments and on communities and social institutions; and (2) report recommended national standards for enhancing the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape. (Sec. 8) Directs the Attorney General, within one year after receiving such report, to publish a final rule adopting national standards. Provides for a five percent reduction of any amount of grant funds for prisons that a State would otherwise receive for a fiscal year, unless the chief executive of the State submits to the Attorney General: (1) a certification that the State has adopted, and is in full compliance with, the national standards; or (2) an assurance that not less than five percent of such amount shall be used only to enable the State to adopt and achieve full compliance with such standards, so as to ensure that such certification may be submitted in future years. Requires the Attorney General to publish an annual report listing each grantee that is not in compliance with the standards. (Sec. 9) Prohibits the receipt of Federal grants by penal facility accredication organizations that fail to adopt accreditation standards for the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape.</summary>
</bill>
