<bill session="111" type="h" number="4828" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Nondiscrimination Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Housing Act to prohibit housing discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity, to amend the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to prohibit such discrimination in public accommodations and public facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Nondiscrimination Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000326"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4820" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4988" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-06T17:35:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing Nondiscrimination Act of 2010 - Amends the Fair Housing Act to prohibit discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity in housing sales and rentals, residential real estate-related transactions, and brokerage services.

Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1968 to: (1) prohibit the intimidation, interference, or injury of individuals because of their sexual orientation or gender identity; and (2) state that nothing in that Act or in the Civil Rights Act of 1964 shall be construed to require any person to disclose a personal sexual orientation or gender identity.

Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to prohibit discrimination or segregation on the grounds of sexual orientation or gender identity in the use of public accommodations or public facilities.</summary>
</bill>
