<bill session="117" type="s" number="585" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Anti-Doping Agency Reauthorization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the United States Anti-Doping Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Anti-Doping Agency Reauthorization Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="172" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-13T21:04:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Anti-Doping Agency Reauthorization Act of 2021

This bill authorizes appropriations for the U.S. Anti-Doping Agency (USADA) through FY2030.

The bill adds requirements that USADA

 be responsible for certifying in advance any testing conducted by international organizations under the World Anti-Doping Code for international amateur athletes and athletic competitions occurring within the jurisdiction of the United States; and promote a positive youth sport experience by using a portion of its funding to provide educational materials on sportsmanship, character building, and healthy performance for those participating in youth sports. The bill requires any action taken by USADA to enforce a policy, procedure, or requirement against a person with respect to a violation of federal law, including an investigation, disciplinary action, sanction, or any other administrative action, to be carried out in a manner that provides due process protection.

The Department of Justice, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Food and Drug Administration&#160;must provide to USADA information relating to the prevention of the use of performance-enhancing drugs or the prohibition of performance-enhancing methods.</summary>
</bill>
