<bill session="115" type="h" number="4640" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:15Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate public colleges and universities that provide research, data, and recommendations on physical science, social science, economic analysis, policy analysis, risk analysis, monitoring, predicting, and planning for coastal flooding as National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000477"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2017-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2017-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY18" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-29T20:23:09Z" status="Introduced in House">National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education Act

This bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to designate public colleges and universities as National Centers of Excellence in Coastal Flood Research and Education.

The purposes of such designations are to: (1) recognize those institutions of higher education that have exhibited national leadership in research and education in coastal flooding, and (2) identify such centers as sources for expert advice and guidance for federal agencies engaged in coastal flooding research and education issues and projects.

NOAA shall require the designated public colleges or universities to enter into an agreement with NOAA to: (1) collaborate on federal flood-related issues with federal agencies; and (2) collaborate and share with specified entities best practices on regional, state, and locally specific flooding and flood-related issues.</summary>
</bill>
