<bill session="116" type="s" number="3891" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing Artificial Intelligence Research Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Artificial Intelligence Research Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to advance the development of technical standards for artificial intelligence, to establish the National Program to Advance Artificial Intelligence Research, to promote research on artificial intelligence at the National Science Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2020-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2020-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-27T13:28:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Advancing Artificial Intelligence Research Act of 2020

This bill requires the development of standards for artificial intelligence and establishes the National Program to Advance Artificial Intelligence Research.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) shall have the mission, among other things, of advancing frameworks, standards, guidelines, and associated methods and techniques for artificial intelligence. NIST shall also participate in the development of standards and specifications for artificial intelligence.

The bill provides for a research program with a national scope to advance use-inspired artificial intelligence research and its use to serve the needs of the United States, NIST, and specified stakeholders.

The National Science Foundation (NSF) shall establish at least six National Artificial Intelligence Research Institutes to serve the needs of the United States and other specified stakeholders by (1) conducting research on longer-time-horizon challenges in artificial intelligence research, and (2) creating and developing processes to advance use-inspired artificial intelligence research and its deployment.

The NSF shall award grants to establish traineeship programs and support trainees in topics of national importance selected by the NSF, including the selection of artificial intelligence as the initial topic.

The NSF shall establish a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of awarding grants to conduct research in rapidly evolving, high priority topics (i.e, of high importance to the economy and security of the United States). It shall select artificial intelligence as the initial topic for the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
