<bill session="108" type="s" number="2319" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize and facilitate hydroelectric power licensing of the Tapoco Project.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4097-4099"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-600.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-299.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="618">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 618.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9342-9344" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9342-9344" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:04:21-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T12:34:24-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:25:59-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:26:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7954-7955" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:26:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2319.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2004-10-04T14:28:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7954" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T14:28:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-10-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-343" type="public" datetime="2004-10-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-343.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4667" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-25T15:04:42Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on July 7, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Tapoco Project Licensing Act of 2004 - (Sec. 3) Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to engage in a simultaneous land exchange with Alcoa Power Generating Inc. (APGI) upon conveyance by APGI of acceptable title to certain land adjacent to the APGI power line within the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, generally depicted on the map as "proposed Property Transfer from APGI to National Park Service."

Identifies the land to be conveyed by the Secretary as approximately 110 acres within the Park: (1) adjacent to or flooded by the Chilhowee Reservoir; and (2) within the boundary of the Tapoco Hydroelectric Project as of February 21, 2003.

Prescribes procedural requirements, including reservation of a conservation easement over any land transferred to APGI that: (1) specifically prohibits development of the land by APGI which is not necessary for the continued operation and maintenance of the Chilhowee Reservoir; (2) authorizes public access to the easement area, subject to National Park Service regulations; and (3) authorizes the National Park Service to enforce Park regulations on the land and in and on the waters of Chilhowee Reservoir lying on the land.

Requires the deed to require reversion of the title to the United States if the Chilhowee Reservoir ceases to exist, or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) issues a final order decommissioning the Tapoco Project from which no further appeal may be taken.

(Sec. 4) Grants FERC jurisdiction to license the Tapoco Project upon completion of the land exchange.

(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire for the United States any land or interest in land identified as specified easements that may be transferred by APGI to a nongovernmental organization pursuant to a specified Settlement Agreement.

Prescribes implementation requirements for land acquired by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, respectively.

(Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-299</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
