<bill session="117" type="h" number="2702" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SURE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to include requirements for declaring an unlawful act or practice, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Statement on Unfairness Reinforcement and Emphasis Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SURE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-21T18:51:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Statement on Unfairness Reinforcement and Emphasis Act or the SURE Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the factors that the Federal Trade Commission must consider when determining whether a practice causes or is likely to cause a substantial injury to consumers (the factors generally mirror the current policy of the commission).

For example, the commission must consider whether the practice results in monetary harm, unwarranted health or safety risk, and only emotional or subjective harm. Further, to be considered an unfair practice, the net effects (including consideration of the costs for a remedy and the resulting burden on society from making the practice unlawful) must cause injury.

The commission also must consider an economic analysis from the Bureau of Economics.</summary>
</bill>
