<bill session="111" type="h" number="3913" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-28T14:39:53-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-06-28T14:39:53-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia to establish a District of Columbia National Guard Educational Assistance Program to encourage the enlistment and retention of persons in the District of Columbia National Guard by providing financial assistance to enable members of the National Guard of the District of Columbia to attend undergraduate, vocational, or technical courses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Major General David F. Wherley, Jr. District of Columbia National Guard Retention and College Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2612-2613"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28T14:30:04-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Norton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28T14:30:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4883-4885" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28T14:30:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3913.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2010-06-28T14:39:53-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4883-4884" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-06-28T14:39:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA03" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO25" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2333" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3323" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-02T16:29:40Z" status="Passed House amended">(Sec. 1) Amends the District of Columbia Code to direct the Mayor of the District of Columbia, in coordination with the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard, to establish a program that allows the Mayor to provide educational assistance to members of the District of Columbia National Guard who have satisfactorily completed their initial active duty service and agree to serve for at least six years.

Requires such assistance to be used by members for expenses incurred in pursuing their first undergraduate, master's, vocational, or technical degree or certification at an approved institution of higher education.

Limits such assistance to no more than $400 per credit hour and no more than $6,000 per year for each eligible member of the District of Columbia National Guard.

Prohibits members who are receiving a Reserve Officer Training Corps scholarship from receiving this Act's assistance; though permits recipients of this Act's assistance to receive educational assistance under other programs.

Authorizes appropriations.



Allows the Mayor to accept donations of services or property for the program.



(Sec. 2) Provides that the budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled "Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation" for this Act, submitted by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted before vote on passage.</summary>
</bill>
