<bill session="109" type="h" number="2942" updated="2023-01-13T04:47:55Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sexual Predator Sentencing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect potential victims of sex crimes by strengthening the sentencing provisions for sex offenders.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sexual Predator Sentencing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000361" joined="2005-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000072" joined="2005-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000652" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2005-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000358" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2005-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-28T14:32:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Sexual Predator Sentencing Act - Amends the federal criminal code to increase penalties, and set mandatory minimum terms of imprisonment, for aggravated sexual abuse, sexual abuse, sexual abuse of a minor or ward, abusive sexual contact, and sexual abuse resulting in death. Increases the mandatory minimum term of imprisonment for repeat sex offenses to life imprisonment unless the death penalty is imposed. Prohibits a term of imprisonment imposed for sex offenses from running concurrently with any other term of imprisonment for such an offense.

Increases penalties, and sets a mandatory minimum term of imprisonment, for coercing or enticing any individual to travel in interstate or foreign commerce to engage in prostitution or in any sexual activity for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense. Doubles the minimum and maximum terms of imprisonment for subsequent offenses. Prohibits a term of imprisonment imposed for sex offenses from running concurrently with any other term of imprisonment for such an offense.</summary>
</bill>
