<bill session="118" type="h" number="1710" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Office of Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation Policy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation Policy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Office of Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation Policy and strategic national manufacturing policy for the United States, to provide manufacturing and industrial perspective and advice to the President, to provide for a comprehensive survey and cross administration management of efforts to ensure global leadership in manufacturing critical to the long-term economic health and national security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000619" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1319"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-16T18:23:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Office of Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation Policy Act of 2023

 This bill addresses the manufacturing capacity of the United States.

The bill establishes the Office of Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation Policy, led by the Chief Manufacturing Officer, to serve as a source of manufacturing and industrial innovation analysis and judgment for the President with respect to the major policies, plans, and programs of the federal government. The office must establish a national strategic plan for manufacturing and industrial innovation that identifies critical needs to the manufacturing sector, including emergency readiness and resilience.

Additionally, the bill establishes the President's Advisory Committee on Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation to promote regular communication between the federal government and the U.S. manufacturing sector.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the efforts of the office along with recommendations for improvements.

The bill also establishes the Federal Strategy and Coordinating Council on Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation within the executive branch to be chaired by the President to coordinate manufacturing and industrial innovation policy.

Further, the bill establishes the Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation Policy Institute to assemble information relating to significant manufacturing and industrial development and trends in research and applications.

Finally, the bill establishes the National Medal of Manufacturing and Industrial Innovation to be awarded for outstanding contributions to knowledge in manufacturing and industrial innovation.</summary>
</bill>
