<bill session="111" type="s" number="1138" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Expansion Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to expand the Bay Area Regional Recycling Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Expansion Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5844"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5844-5845" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-619.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2442" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-19T17:30:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Expansion Act of 2009 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of: (1) recycled water distribution systems in California in cooperation with the Central Contra Costa Sanitary District and the Ironhouse Sanitary District; and (2) recycled water system facilities in California in cooperation with the Dublin San Ramon Services District, the city of Petaluma, Redwood City, and the city of Palo Alto. Limits the federal share of each project to 25%. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds for project operation and maintenance.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into individual agreements with the San Francisco Bay Area Regional Water Recycling implementing agencies to fund specified projects under such Act through the Bay Area Clean Water Agencies; and (2) include in such agreements a provision for the reimbursement of construction costs.

Increases the authorization of appropriations for the design, planning, and construction of: (1) recycled water system facilities in cooperation with the city of Antioch, California; and (2) recycled water treatment facilities in cooperation with the city of San Jose, California, and the Santa Clara Valley Water District.</summary>
</bill>
