<bill session="118" type="s" number="3617" updated="2025-11-19T03:23:12Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cape Fox Land Entitlement Finalization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cape Fox Land Entitlement Finalization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cape Fox Land Entitlement Finalization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Cape Fox Land Entitlement Finalization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide equitable treatment for the people of the Village Corporation established for the Native Village of Saxman, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2024-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="606">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 606.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7218" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7219--7220" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-20T16:53:27-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-20T17:04:21-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7022" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-12T15:34:51Z" status="Passed Senate">Cape Fox Land Entitlement Finalization Act of 2024

This bill waives a statutory core township selection requirement for the Cape Fox Corporation and allows Cape Fox to receive&#160;other lands to fulfill its remaining land entitlement. Cape Fox is an Alaska Native village corporation for the Alaska Native village of Saxman, Alaska.

Specifically, the bill states that Cape Fox shall not be required to receive its previously selected land of approximately 185 acres located within the township in which the Alaska Native village of Saxman, Alaska, is located. Instead, the bill allows Cape Fox to receive&#160;land outside of Cape Fox's current exterior selection boundary upon written notice of the new selection to the Department of the Interior.&#160;

In particular, if Cape Fox submits written notice of its selection of approximately&#160;180 acres of surface land within the&#160;Tongass National Forest in Alaska to Interior within 90 days of the bill's enactment, then Interior must convey the federal land to Cape Fox. Upon conveyance of the surface estate of the federal land to Cape Fox, Interior must convey the subsurface estate of the federal land to Sealaska Corporation (the Alaska Native regional corporation representing southeastern Alaska).

The bill reserves a public access easement on the federal land conveyed to Cape Fox and Sealaska.</summary>
</bill>
