<bill session="116" type="s" number="2456" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:05Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Water Through Green Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Water Through Green Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish centers of excellence for innovative stormwater control infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4266" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-12T20:39:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Water Through Green Infrastructure Act

This bill establishes grant programs for innovative stormwater control infrastructure, which means any green stormwater management technique that (1) uses systems that mimic natural processes to infiltrate, evapotranspire, or capture stormwater; and (2) preserves, enhances, or mimics natural hydrology to protect or restore water quality.

Specifically, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must provide grants to eligible institutions of higher education or research institutions to establish and maintain between three and five centers of excellence for innovative stormwater control infrastructure. Among other things, the centers must research such infrastructure and provide technical assistance to state, tribal, and local governments to assist with stormwater control infrastructure projects. One of the centers must be the national electronic clearinghouse center. That center must operate a website and a public database on the infrastructure.

In addition, the EPA must provide grants to state, tribal, or local governments or entities that manage stormwater, drinking water resources, or wastewater resources for innovative stormwater control infrastructure projects.</summary>
</bill>
