<bill session="108" type="s" number="2148" updated="2023-01-15T10:47:54Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">U.S.A. Jobs Protection Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect American workers from competition of foreign workforces for performance of Federal and State contracts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">U.S.A. Jobs Protection Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-18T20:21:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">U.S.A. Jobs Protection Act of 2004 - Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to prohibit a contract that is entered into by the head of an executive agency from being performed outside the United States except to meet a requirement of that agency for the contract to be performed specifically at a location abroad.

Prohibits funds appropriated for financial assistance for a State from being disbursed to or for such State during a fiscal year unless that State's chief executive has transmitted to the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, by April 1 of the preceding fiscal year, a written certification that (except as provided above) none of those funds will be expended for the performance of State contracts outside the United States. Makes an exception where the State's chief executive certifies in advance to the Administrator that such expenditure is for a contract that cannot be performed within the United States.

Makes this Act inapplicable to disbursements of funds to a State during the first two fiscal years of its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
