<bill session="118" type="s" number="289" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Genomics Data Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Genomics Data Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve national security at the National Institutes of Health, to address national security issues in the licensure of biological products, to address national security considerations in research at the Department of Health and Human Services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-24T14:40:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Genomics Data Security Act

This bill establishes requirements and otherwise directs the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to take actions to address national security concerns in genomic and other research.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the use of NIH funds by any Chinese company (or its subcontractors or subsidiaries). This includes companies (1) over which the Chinese government, a Chinese national, or an entity organized under Chinese law exercises control; or (2) in which the Chinese government has a substantial interest. It also requires, as a condition of certification, that clinical laboratories that have access to U.S. health data disclose ties to the Chinese government.

In addition, the NIH must incorporate national security issues in its strategic plan and report annually on any improperly disclosed, vetted, or approved ties that NIH-funded researchers have to foreign governments.

Furthermore, the Department of Health and Human Services must establish a working group to update the NIH's Genomic Data Sharing Policy with respect to intellectual property, national security, and privacy concerns.</summary>
</bill>
