<bill session="118" type="s" number="2314" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRESERVE Online Speech Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRESERVE Online Speech Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Restrictions and Empowering Speakers to Enable Robust and Varied Exchanges in Online Speech Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require providers of interactive computer services to publicly disclose information relating to requests or recommendations made by government entities to moderate content, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-02T10:32:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Restrictions and Empowering Speakers to Enable Robust and Varied Exchanges in Online Speech Act of 2023 or the PRESERVE Online Speech Act of 2023

This bill requires interactive computer services (e.g., social media companies) to issue a public disclosure containing specified information related to a request or recommendation by a government entity that the service moderate content on its platform. Examples of such moderation include eliminating the ability of a user to comment upon information or terminating or limiting a user's account.

Failure to comply with this requirement shall result in a fine of $50,000 per day, which shall be deposited in the Rural Digital Opportunity Fund. The Federal Communications Commission must submit an annual report that includes the contents of each such public disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
