<bill session="118" type="h" number="3306" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Broadband Permit Coordination Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Broadband Permit Coordination Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate Federal broadband permit coordination, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-17T22:02:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Broadband Permit Coordination Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior to coordinate with specified federal entities and other stakeholders to expedite permits for broadband projects (i.e., projects to install fiber optic lines, communications towers, and related infrastructure). It also allows the departments to establish teams to support the coordination efforts.

Specifically, USDA and Interior must enter into agreements with the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to coordinate and expedite the permits. In developing the agreements, USDA and Interior (1) must consult with organizations representing state and tribal historic preservation officers, and (2) may request that states and Indian tribes with broadband projects in their jurisdictions enter the agreements.

After entering an agreement, USDA and Interior may designate employees with expertise in planning, environmental analyses, and other relevant topics to work as part of a team in a state or regional office that has been delegated responsibility for issuing broadband permits.</summary>
</bill>
