<bill session="108" type="s" number="1508" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Enterprise Regulatory Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address regulation of secondary mortgage market enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Enterprise Regulatory Reform Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2003-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2004-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2003-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001078" joined="2003-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10623"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10623-10631" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1656" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-11-25T20:10:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Enterprise Regulatory Reform Act of 2003 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to establish in the Department of the Treasury the Office of Federal Enterprise Supervision. Transfers to the Director of such Office supervisory and regulatory authority over specified government sponsored enterprises (Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac) from the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and from the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development. Prohibits merger or consolidation of such Office or its functions.

Requires: (1) the Director to ensure that the enterprises operate in a financially safe manner and remain adequately capitalized; and (2) that each enterprise have prior approval of the Director before implementing a new program.

Sets forth operating, administrative, and regulatory provisions of the Director, including provisions respecting: (1) assessment authority; (2) authority to limit nonmission-related assets; (3) minimum and critical capital levels; (4) risk-based capital test; (5) capital classifications and undercapitalized enterprises; (6) enforcement actions and penalties; and (7) reporting.

Sets forth certain retained authorities of the Secretary.

Abolishes the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight. Sets forth related transfer of personnel and facility and property provisions.</summary>
</bill>
