<bill session="117" type="sj" number="16" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:32Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Securities and Exchange Commission relating to "Procedural Requirements and Resubmission Thresholds Under Exchange Act Rule 14a-8".</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Securities and Exchange Commission relating to "Procedural Requirements and Resubmission Thresholds Under Exchange Act Rule 14a-8".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hj" number="36" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-20T18:10:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This joint resolution nullifies the final rule issued by the Securities and Exchange Commission titled Procedural Requirements and Resubmission Thresholds Under Exchange Act Rule 14a-8 and published on November 4, 2020.

The rule provides additional requirements for the inclusion of shareholder proposals in proxy statements, such as increasing the securities ownership requirements for submitting a proposal and increasing the level of support a proposal must receive to be eligible for resubmission at a future shareholder meeting. (Proxy statements must be filed by a publicly traded company and provided to shareholders before shareholder meetings. Proxy statements contain information regarding matters such as the election of directors and shareholder proposals.)</summary>
</bill>
