<bill session="116" type="s" number="44" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:25Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce a portion of the annual pay of Members of Congress for the failure to adopt a concurrent resolution on the budget which does not provide for a balanced budget, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="298" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-01T14:34:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Balanced Budget Accountability Act

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), upon adoption by a chamber of Congress of a concurrent budget resolution for a fiscal year, to certify to the Speaker of the House of Representatives or the President pro tempore of the Senate whether that chamber has adopted a balanced budget.

Balanced budget means a concurrent budget resolution providing that for FY2027 and each succeeding fiscal year to which the resolution applies total outlays do not exceed total receipts and are not more than 18% of the projected domestic product for such fiscal year.

The bill requires the salary of Members of Congress to be held in escrow if OMB determines a chamber has not adopted a balanced budget for FY2020 before April 16, 2019, and for FY2021 before April 16, 2020. The bill also provides for the release of such funds to the Members.

Beginning in FY2022, if OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget before April 16 of the prior fiscal year, each Member of that chamber shall be paid at the rate of $1 annually for pay periods after that date in the same calendar year.

 This bill requires legislation in either chamber that increases revenue to be agreed upon only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members of that chamber.</summary>
</bill>
