<bill session="116" type="s" number="779" updated="2022-11-01T17:47:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to end offshore corporate tax avoidance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2019-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1711" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2140" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1712" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-11T21:40:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Tax Haven Abuse Act

 This bill authorizes the Department of the Treasury to impose restrictions on foreign jurisdictions or financial institutions to counter money laundering and efforts to significantly impede U.S. tax enforcement.

The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to

 expand reporting requirements for certain foreign investments and accounts held by U.S. persons, establish a rebuttable presumption against the validity of transactions by institutions that do not comply with reporting requirements under the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act, treat certain foreign corporations managed and controlled primarily in the United States as domestic corporations for tax purposes, treat swap payments sent offshore as taxable U.S. source income, require reporting of United States beneficial owners of foreign-owned financial accounts, impose additional requirements for third party summonses used to obtain information in tax investigations that do not identify the person with respect to whose liability the summons is issued (i.e., John Doe summons), and modify the rules for the taxation of inverted corporations (U.S. corporations that acquire foreign companies to reincorporate in a foreign jurisdiction with income tax rates lower than the United States). The bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to (1) require corporations to disclose certain financial information on a country-by-country basis, and (2) impose penalties for failing to disclose offshore holdings.

The bill makes investment advisers and persons engaged in forming new business entities subject to new anti-money laundering requirements.</summary>
</bill>
