<bill session="118" type="s" number="1331" updated="2025-11-19T03:55:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PSLF Payment Completion Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PSLF Payment Completion Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Service Loan Forgiveness Payment Completion Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that borrowers who have performed qualifying public service are eligible for Public Service Loan Forgiveness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Economic Policy. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity=""/>
    <committee code="SSBK12" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Policy" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2949" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-10T11:30:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Service Loan Forgiveness Payment Completion Fairness Act or the PSLF Payment Completion Fairness Act

This bill removes the requirement that a borrower must be employed in a public service job at the time of loan forgiveness under the Public Service Loan Forgiveness (PSLF) program.

Under the current PSLF program, the Department of Education must cancel the balance of interest and principal due on a borrower's Federal Direct Loans after the borrower makes 120 monthly loan payments while employed in a public service job and, at the time of loan forgiveness, the borrower is employed in a public service job. This bill removes the requirement that the borrower must be working in a public service job at the time of loan forgiveness.</summary>
</bill>
