<bill session="109" type="sr" number="530" updated="2018-02-03T18:42:48Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-14">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution calling on President George W. Bush and other leaders attending the 2006 Group of Eight (G-8) Summit in St. Petersburg, Russia, to engage in a frank dialogue with the President of Russia concerning actions of the Government of the Russian Federation that appear inconsistent with the Group's objectives of protecting global security, economic stability, and democracy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on President George W. Bush and other leaders attending the 2006 Group of Eight (G-8) Summit in St. Petersburg, Russia, to engage in a frank dialogue with the President of Russia concerning actions of the Government of the Russian Federation that appear inconsistent with the Group's objectives of protecting global security, economic stability, and democracy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000121" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000439" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2006-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2006-07-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7563-7564" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7563-7564" label="text"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7562" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Antisemitism"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Caucasus"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Journalism"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Racism"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Summit diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-30T19:49:12Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) in order to preserve the integrity of the G-8 as a forum of the leading industrialized democracies of the world, President George W. Bush and other heads of state attending the G-8 Summit should engage Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin in a dialogue about the anti-democratic behavior of the government of the Russian Federation; (2) the United States and other democratic countries should reaffirm their support for civic and non-governmental organizations working to promote democracy and the rule of law in Russia; (3) the government of the Russian Federation should take action to ensure that it guarantees the full range of civil and political rights to its citizens, as it is obligated to do under the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights; (4) consistent with its obligations under the International Covenant, the government of the Russian Federation should take steps to cease its interference with foreign news organizations, including the Voice of America and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty; (5) the government of the Russian Federation should take action to combat rising racism, anti-Semitism, and xenophobia in Russian society; and (6) the United States and countries of the G-8 should reaffirm their support for new democracies on the borders of Russia and, where applicable, expedite their integration into Euro-Atlantic institutions to provide a bulwark for democracy in eastern Europe and the Caucuses.</summary>
</bill>
