<bill session="109" type="h" number="3175" updated="2023-01-13T04:47:49Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Answer Africa's Call Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement measures to help alleviate the poor living conditions in Africa.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Answer Africa's Call Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000404"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000714" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA19" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Mauritius"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-07T17:20:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Answer Africa's Call Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an additional income tax (surcharge) on adjusted gross incomes exceeding certain threshold levels (in order to fund the U.S. International Finance Facility).

Establishes the United States International Finance Facility Trust Fund in the Treasury consisting of such amounts appropriated or credited to the Trust Fund, including amounts collected from the surcharge).

Makes such Fund amounts available without further appropriation for expenditures in connection with U.S. commitments to the International Finance Facility.

Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to modify the preferential trade treatment for agricultural products of beneficiary sub-Saharan African countries. Removes the limitation on eligibility for duty-free treatment of an agriculture product subject to a tariff-rate quota exceeding the in-quota amount, if the over-quota import is the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary sub-Saharan African country. Requires the President to: (1) assess a duty on such an over-quota product if its unit import price is less than the annual trigger price; (2) establish an annual trigger price for each such product; and (3) notify the beneficiary sub-Saharan African country concerned of such additional duty.

Amends the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) to revise criteria for preferential treatment of apparel articles wholly assembled from fabric or yarn not available in commercial quantities in the United States to make certain yarn or fabrics eligible for use in the production of specified cut or knit-to-shape apparel articles.

Modifies AGOA special rules for lesser developed countries with respect to preferential treatment for apparel articles wholly assembled, or knit to shape and wholly assembled, or both, in one or more lesser developed beneficiary sub-Saharan African countries regardless of the country of origin of the fabric or yarn used. Extends through FY 2015 the applicable percentage component of the preferential treatment formula established for FY 2005.

Includes Mauritius in such extension, with no change in its current limitation of 5% of such applicable percentage.</summary>
</bill>
