<bill session="117" type="h" number="4113" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to fix the consumer report dispute process, to ban misleading and unfair consumer reporting practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Improving Credit Reporting for All Consumers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Credit Reporting for All Consumers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4120" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-03T15:39:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Credit Reporting for All Consumers Act 

This bill generally modifies requirements related to consumer credit reporting. Specifically, it revises the dispute process for consumers challenging information contained on their credit report, establishes an appeals process for disputed information, and establishes the right to injunctive relief.

The bill also requires additional disclosures from credit reporting agencies and furnishers of credit information, prohibits automatic renewals for promotional consumer credit products and services, and makes other related changes.

Additionally, the bill directs the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to issue rules under this bill, including rules to provide for (1) accuracy and completeness in credit reports; (2) access to consumer reporting information for nonnative English speakers, the visually impaired, and the hearing impaired; and (3) the registration of consumer reporting agencies.</summary>
</bill>
