<bill session="117" type="h" number="2500" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forest TECH Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to assess the use of new technologies across reforestation activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest TECH Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Technology Enhancements for Conservation and Habitat Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2021-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2021-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2021-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2021-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2021-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2021-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2639" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-26T19:53:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Forest Technology Enhancements for Conservation and Habitat Improvement Act or the Forest TECH Improvement Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to either establish a research and development pilot program or expand an applicable existing program to

 assess new technologies, including unmanned aircraft system, geospatial, or remote sensing technologies, across all reforestation activities; accelerate the deployment and integration of such technologies into the operations of USDA and the Department of the Interior; collaborate and cooperate with state, tribal, and private geospatial information system organizations with respect to such technologies. USDA and Interior shall enter into an agreement to develop consistent protocols and plans for the use of unmanned aircraft system technologies for reforestation activities.

Any unmanned aircraft system technology or component of such technology that is used pursuant to this bill shall be made and manufactured in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
