<bill session="117" type="h" number="3204" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:47Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">One In, Two Out Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require each agency to repeal two existing regulations before issuing a new regulation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">One In, Two Out Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2021-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-02T13:06:34Z" status="Introduced in House">One In, Two Out Act

 This bill requires federal agencies to repeal certain existing rules prior to issuing a new rule.

Specifically, the bill prohibits an agency from issuing a rule that imposes a cost or responsibility on a nongovernmental person or a state or local government unless it repeals two or more related rules. Additionally, an agency may not issue a major rule that imposes such a cost or responsibility unless (1) the agency has repealed or revised two or more related rules, and (2) the cost of the new rule is less than or equal to the cost of the rules being repealed or revised. (Generally, a major rule is one likely to result in an annual economic impact of $100 million or more, a major increase in costs, or significant adverse effects on competition or investment.)

Any such repealed or revised rule must be published in the Federal Register.

This bill does not apply to a rule or major rule that (1) relates to an internal agency policy, (2) procurement by the agency, or (3) is being revised to be less burdensome by decreasing requirements imposed or compliance costs.</summary>
</bill>
