<bill session="118" type="h" number="822" updated="2024-06-12T08:05:22Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Mental Health Helpline Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Mental Health Helpline Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, to award grants to eligible entities to establish or maintain a student mental health and safety helpline, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2024-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09T10:52:00-05:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Ms. Bonamici asked unanimous consent that she may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 822, a bill originally introduced by Representative Stewart, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Unknown, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-17T14:11:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Mental Health Helpline Act

This bill authorizes grants to support student mental health and safety helplines (i.e., a free, confidential service that is accessible via telephone and other communication platforms that assists students facing challenges with abuse, bullying, depression, self-harm, and related issues). The Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) may award the grants to agencies or other subdivisions of a state, Indian tribe, or local government that are primarily responsible for health, public health, or education.

Recipients must use funds to establish or maintain a helpline that provides information to school officials (to the extent permitted by federal privacy standards for health information) about student mental health and safety concerns and related activities.

The bill also requires SAMHSA to report on the feasibility of setting up a nationally available student mental health and safety helpline.</summary>
</bill>
