<bill session="116" type="h" number="5495" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:14Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Electronic Equipment Donation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct Federal agencies to transfer excess Federal electronic equipment, including computers, computer components, printers, and fax machines, to educational recipients, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Electronic Equipment Donation Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2019-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-22T18:51:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Electronic Equipment Donation Act of 2019

This bill directs federal agencies to transfer excess federal electronic equipment, including computers and related peripheral tools, to educational recipients.

Each agency shall identify useful electronic equipment determined to be excess to the needs of the agency (excluding research equipment) and

 report such equipment to the General Services Administration (GSA) for processing for transfer to an educational recipient; transfer such equipment directly to an educational recipient, through an arrangement made by the GSA; or report such equipment to the GSA as excess property if such transfers are not practicable. Each agency shall report to the GSA the availability of useful federal electronic equipment as far as possible in advance. If the equipment is not classroom-usable, the transferring agency shall convey the equipment initially to a nonprofit refurbisher for upgrade before transfer.

The transferring agency shall (1) remove data using a means that does not render the equipment or components unusable, and (2) give the highest preference to educational recipients located in a persistent poverty county or other specified areas.

A state's plan for distributing donated federal equipment must give the highest preference for electronic equipment to institutions that are located in an enterprise community, an empowerment zone, or specified high poverty areas.</summary>
</bill>
