<bill session="117" type="h" number="4655" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:27Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program to promote public-private partnerships among apprenticeships or other job training programs, local educational agencies or area career and technical education schools, and community colleges, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Workforce Investment in Next Generation of Students Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Workforce Investment in Next Generation of Students Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000560"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2021-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-28T17:09:16Z" status="Introduced in House">American Workforce Investment in Next Generation of Students Act

 This bill directs the Secretary of Education to award grants to eligible entities to carry out a program for students to

 enroll in and complete science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) courses, STEM-focused career and technical education courses, and other career pathway courses during grades 11 and 12 at a secondary school served by a local educational agency (LEA) partner; enroll in a course of study related to such a career pathway or in a youth apprenticeship program at a partner community college upon graduating from the secondary school; enroll, for a two-year period, in the youth apprenticeship program or the joint-labor management training program upon receiving an associate's degree from a partner community college; receive assistance from a student career workforce navigator; and receive work training and job placement through a workforce development consortium employer established under the bill. An eligible entity is a partnership (1) among at least one LEA, at least one community college, and at least one youth apprenticeship program or joint labor-management training program; and (2) that works with an employer in a state-identified high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sector or occupation that is serving, or seeking to expand its capacity to serve, youth apprenticeship programs.</summary>
</bill>
