<bill session="119" type="hj" number="131" updated="2025-11-23T17:44:20Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-18T20:52:55-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-11-18T20:52:55-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to "Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Record of Decision".</title>
    <title type="official">Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Record of Decision.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to "Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Record of Decision".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001323"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-17T20:02:19-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 879 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 80, H.J. Res. 130, H.J. Res. 131, H. Con. Res. 58, H.R. 1949, H.R. 3109, H.R. 5107 and H.R. 5214. The resolution provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 80, H.J. Res. 130, H.J. Res. 131, H. Con. Res. 58, H.R. 1949, H.R. 3109, H.R. 5107, and H.R. 5214 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution also provides for one motion to recommit on H.J. Res. 130, H.J. Res. 131, H.R. 1949, H.R. 3109, H.R. 5107, and H.R. 5214, and one motion to commit S.J. Res. 80.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T17:22:47-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 879.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4750-4753" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T17:22:52-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 80, H.J. Res. 130, H.J. Res. 131, H. Con. Res. 58, H.R. 1949, H.R. 3109, H.R. 5107 and H.R. 5214. The resolution provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 80, H.J. Res. 130, H.J. Res. 131, H. Con. Res. 58, H.R. 1949, H.R. 3109, H.R. 5107, and H.R. 5214 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate on each measure. The resolution also provides for one motion to recommit on H.J. Res. 130, H.J. Res. 131, H.R. 1949, H.R. 3109, H.R. 5107, and H.R. 5214, and one motion to commit S.J. Res. 80.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T17:23:07-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 131.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T17:44:09-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T17:44:14-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.J. Res. 131, the Chair put the question on passage of the joint resolution and by voice vote announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Huffman demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T20:46:47-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4760" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="295" datetime="2025-11-18T20:52:55-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 217 - 209 (Roll no. 295).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4750" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18T20:52:56-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="879" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="sj" number="91" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-18T15:02:38Z" status="Introduced in House">This joint resolution nullifies the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), issued on December 9, 2024, and related to the record of decision (ROD) for the program that leases, develops, produces, and transports oil and gas in and from the Coastal Plain program area within the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge.

The 2024 ROD that is being nullified by this resolution&#160;replaced the 2020 ROD that made all of the approximately 1.6 million acres of the program area available for oil and gas leasing. The 2024 ROD adopted Alternative D2 in the 2024 Coastal Plain Oil and Gas Leasing Program Final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement, which made approximately&#160;1.2 million&#160;acres unavailable for leasing or exploration in order to protect and conserve resources and certain uses in these areas. However, the 2024 ROD requires the statutory minimum of 400,000 acres to be made available for oil and gas leasing in a specified lease sale, subject to certain stipulations and operating procedures. Under current&#160;law, those acres must be located in the areas with the highest potential for the discovery of hydrocarbons.</summary>
</bill>
