<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="777" updated="2022-02-03T05:33:55Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5020" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-04-26T16:17:55-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-04-26"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill, add the following new section: ?   SEC. 510. REPORT ON AUTHORIZATION TO OVERTHROW DEMOCRATICALLY ELECTED GOVERNMENTS. ?   Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a report describing any authorization granted during the 10-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this Act to engage in intelligence activities related to the overthrow of a democratically elected government.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 109-438 to require a report to House and Senate Intelligence committees describing an y authorization granted during the past 10 years to engage in intelligence activities related to the overthrow of a democratically elected government.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-04-26T16:17:55-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lee amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26T16:11:13-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1803-1804" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1803" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26T16:11:13-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1803-1804" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1803" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26T16:17:55-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26T16:17:55-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lee amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
