<bill session="110" type="h" number="4034" updated="2023-01-11T20:22:31Z">
  <state datetime="2007-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a land exchange involving State land and Bureau of Land Management land in Chaves and Dona Ana Counties, New Mexico, and to establish the Lesser Prairie Chicken National Habitat Preservation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Lesser Prairie Chicken National Habitat Preservation Area Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lesser Prairie Chicken National Habitat Preservation Area Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3930" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-02-25T21:06:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Lesser Prairie Chicken National Habitat Preservation Area Act of 2007 - Requires the exchange of certain federal and non-federal lands in New Mexico concerning the establishment under this Act of the Lesser Prairie Chicken Habitat Preservation Area in the County of Chaves, New Mexico.

Establishes the Preservation Area for the protection, conservation, and enhancement of habitat for the lesser prairie chicken. Provides for such area to comprise certain public land in the county, as well as those non-federal lands acquired under the land exchange.

Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) only allow uses of the Preservation Area that will further the purposes for which it is established; and (2) acquire non-federal land in the Preservation Area only from a willing seller or through purchase, exchange, or donation.

Requires the Secretary to develop a plan for the long-range protection and management of the Preservation Area.</summary>
</bill>
