<bill session="112" type="h" number="3379" updated="2021-04-19T19:15:51Z">
  <state datetime="2011-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regional Haze Federalism Act</title>
    <title type="display">Regional Haze Federalism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to provide States increased flexibility in implementing standards through State implementation plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001272"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2012-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000528" joined="2011-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2011-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2011-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2011-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-03-20T22:10:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Regional Haze Federalism Act - Amends the Clean Air Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate a federal implementation plan in place of a state implementation plan to remedy any impairment to visibility in designated class I areas (international parks, wilderness areas and memorial parks that exceed 5,000 acres, and national parks that exceed 6,000 acres) only if: (1) such state failed to consider the costs of, the time necessary for, and and the energy and non-air quality environmental impacts of compliance with such plan and the remaining useful life of any existing air pollution source; and (2) compliance with federal implementation plan requirements is not required earlier than five years after the date of promulgation.

Requires: (1) the Administrator to revoke an existing federal or state implementation plan for a state regarding visibility or any determination made in 2010 or 2011 of best available retrofit technology for a source upon receipt of a request by such state; and (2) such state to submit to the Administrator a visibility plan or a revised retrofit technology determination within a reasonable period of time.

Provides that states have sole discretion, after considering certain economic factors, in determining emission limits, schedules of compliance, and other measures for each applicable implementation plan for a state for any area that is listed as contributing to impairment of visibility.

Requires the state, in determining best available retrofit technology (or the Administrator in determining emission limitations that reflect such technology), to consider, in addition to other factors, the economic impacts to the state and the degree of improvement in visibility that may reasonably be anticipated to result from measures described in the applicable implementation plan. Provides that a state's determination of such technology for any source may be subject to review by the Administrator or an administrative entity or federal or state court only pursuant to a clearly erroneous standard of review.</summary>
</bill>
