<bill session="119" type="h" number="440" updated="2025-11-21T12:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">READY Accounts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">READY Accounts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001232" joined="2025-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001217" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000622" joined="2025-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2025-08-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1940" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-19T19:25:19Z" status="Introduced in House">READY Accounts Act

This bill establishes a new Residential Emergency Asset-accumulation Deferred Taxation Yield (READY) account, allows individuals to make tax-deductible contributions of up to $4,500 per year to such accounts (adjusted annually for inflation), and allows individuals to take tax-free distributions from such accounts to pay for qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses related to a principal residence owned by the taxpayer.

Under the bill, qualified home disaster mitigation expenses include expenses certified by a qualified industry professional as meeting criteria to mitigate damage from a natural or other disaster, including

installing a roofing underlayment to sheathing, impact-resistant windows, impact-resistant entry doors, or ground anchors;replacing a roof covering;applying a foam adhesive to reinforce the roof structure;strengthening the connection of the&#160;roof deck to roof framing, roof-to-wall connections, soffits, or attic ventilation openings;elevating a residence; orachieving the current building code standard.Qualified home disaster recovery expenses include costs for&#160;repairing damage to a residence resulting from fire, storm, or other casualty (provided such costs are not reimbursed).

Distributions from a READY account used for anything other than qualified home disaster mitigation and recovery expenses must be included in gross income and are subject to a 20% penalty. (Some exceptions apply.)

Finally, the bill imposes a 6% tax on contributions in excess of the annual limit. (Some exceptions apply.)&#160;</summary>
</bill>
