<bill session="119" type="s" number="267" updated="2025-11-19T04:56:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Access to Mountain Homes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Access to Mountain Homes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make certain repairs, replacements, and restorations of private roads and bridges eligible for reimbursement under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="760" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-20T17:34:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Access to Mountain Homes Act

This bill authorizes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide Public Assistance (PA) grant funding, under certain conditions, to reimburse government entities covered under the major disaster declaration for North Carolina relating to Tropical Storm Helene for the costs of repairing, replacing, or restoring private roads and bridges damaged by Helene.

Under current law, the PA program provides grants for repairing disaster damage to infrastructure owned or legally maintained by government entities (or certain&#160;nonprofits). The bill authorizes PA funding for permanent repair work on privately&#160;owned and maintained roads and bridges significantly damaged by Helene in North Carolina, as costs incurred by state, tribal, or local governments for such work are eligible for reimbursement. &#160;&#160;

Also, under current law, the costs of repairing damage that existed before the disaster are generally ineligible for PA. The bill makes the repair, replacement, or restoration costs eligible for reimbursement under PA regardless of pre-existing condition.

Additionally, the bill contains criteria and conditions for reimbursement, including that to be eligible a road or bridge must be used as the sole means of accessing primary residences or essential community services. Reimbursement is under PA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s alternative procedures, and the bill requires&#160;FEMA to determine eligible costs based on estimates prepared by engineers.

Recipients of funds from&#160;FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Individuals and Households Program (IHP) before the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment may use IHP funds for repairs eligible under the bill without those costs counting against their maximum amount of IHP assistance.</summary>
</bill>
