<bill session="109" type="s" number="2993" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:13Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strategic Energy Fund Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a temporary oil profit fee and to use the proceeds of the fee collected to provide a Strategic Energy Fund and expand certain energy tax incentives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategic Energy Fund Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6593"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Excess profits tax"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Geophysical prediction"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Sugar"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-06-15T18:45:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strategic Energy Fund Act of 2006 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish in the Treasury the Strategic Energy Fund. Transfers revenues from the excess profits tax imposed by this Act to such Fund to finance clean energy research and alternative fuel projects.

Modifies the tax credit for investment in alternative fuel vehicle refueling property to: (1) increase the rate of such credit from 30 to 50%; (2) increase to $50,000 the allowable amount of such credit for commercial refueling properties; and (3) extend such credit to the earlier of December 31, 2014, or until 20,000 refueling properties have been installed through the use of such credit.

Expands eligibility for the small ethanol producer tax credit for producers of sucrose or cellulosic ethanol.

Extends through 2014: (1) income and excise tax credits for biodiesel used as fuel; (2) tax credits for investment in solar energy and fuel cell property; (3) the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial property; and (4) the tax credit for new energy efficient homes.

Allows new tax credits for: (1) the manufacture of flexible fuel and advanced technology motor vehicles; (2) investment in fuel-efficient motor vehicle fleets; (3) investment in wind energy property; and (4) captured carbon dioxide processes to enhance oil and natural gas recovery.

Extends through 2017 the tax credit for producing electricity from renewable resources.

Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish the position of Assistant Secretary for Advanced Energy Research, Technology Development, and Deployment.

Imposes for taxable years beginning in 2006 or 2007 a 50% excise fee on the excess profits of integrated oil companies and producers or refiners of crude oil with gross receipts exceeding $100 million. Eliminates certain tax benefits for such oil companies, producers, and refiners, including: (1) the tax deductions for intangible drilling and development costs and for income attributable to domestic production of oil, natural gas, or related products; (2) amortization of geological and geophysical expenditures; and (3) foreign tax credits and deferrals. Requires such companies, producers, and refiners to revalue their LIFO inventories of crude oil, natural gas, and other petroleum products according to a specified formula.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to suspend royalty relief programs for producers of oil and natural gas on federal lands during periods when the price of oil and natural gas exceeds certain levels and to renegotiate existing leases for production of oil and natural gas on federal lands.

Places limits on the depreciation of certain non-farm heavy passenger motor vehicles.</summary>
</bill>
