<bill session="119" type="h" number="960" updated="2025-06-09T16:52:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Our Clothes from PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Clothes from PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 62 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to modify the requirements for a garment to be considered water resistant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001238" joined="2025-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001213" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-23T14:20:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Our Clothes from PFAS Act

This bill revises requirements for a garment to be considered water resistant under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS). The HTS sets out the tariff rates and statistical categories for all merchandise imported into the United States.

Currently, garments that are classified under specified subheadings under chapter 62 of the HTS (e.g., water resistant trousers) must have a water resistance such that, under a head pressure of 600 millimeters, not more than 1.0 gram of water penetrates after two minutes when tested in accordance with a specified test method. Further, the water resistance must be the result of a rubber or plastics application to the outer shell, lining, or inner lining. This bill removes the requirement that the water resistance must be the result of a rubber or plastics application to the outer shell, lining, or inner lining.</summary>
</bill>
