<bill session="118" type="h" number="4556" updated="2025-11-19T04:21:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">General Aviation Airport Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">General Aviation Airport Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to increase access to general aviation airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1847" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T21:40:24Z" status="Introduced in House">General Aviation Airport Access Act

This bill requires public use airports that have received certain federal grants or property conveyances to provide transient general aviation aircraft parking on or near the existing apron in specific circumstances. A transient general aviation aircraft is an aircraft that is not owned or operated by an air carrier and is seeking to park temporarily at an airport.

Specifically, transient general aviation aircraft parking must be provided on or near the existing apron when a pilot or owner of the aircraft does not need or request fuel or use other related services from the airport or a fixed-base operator at the airport. A fixed-base operator is a business that is operating on an airport or heliport and provides aeronautical services, such as fueling, rentals, and parking.

A public use airport may assess a fee on a transient general aviation aircraft for using the transient apron; the fee must be fair, reasonable, transparent, and publicly available. It must also exclude any extraneous or hidden costs. A controlled access airport or a fixed-base operator at the airport may not charge a fee for a pilot or passenger to transit between their transient general aviation aircraft parked on the transient apron and a place outside the airport's perimeter fence, whether or not the individual must pass through a building.</summary>
</bill>
