<bill session="117" type="h" number="1828" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Success in the Middle Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to States to ensure that all students in the middle grades are taught an academically rigorous curriculum with effective supports so that students complete the middle grades prepared for success in secondary school and postsecondary endeavors, to improve State and local educational agency policies and programs relating to the academic achievement of students in the middle grades, to develop and implement effective middle grades models for struggling students, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Success in the Middle Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2021-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-14T17:41:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Success in the Middle Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to establish a grant program and take other specified actions to improve student learning and academic achievement for students in the middle grades (i.e., grades 5-8).

Specifically, the bill directs ED to

 make formula grants to states, based on their proportion of children aged 5 to 17 living below the poverty line, to implement state middle grades need analyses and, on the basis of such analyses, create statewide improvement plans to improve student academic achievement in the middle grades; and award competitive subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or designated LEA partnerships to implement a comprehensive middle school improvement plan for each eligible school (based on graduation rates and specified risk factors). Among other activities, ED must also (1) study and identify promising practices for the improvement of middle grades education, (2) create a national clearinghouse and national middle grades database, (3) establish an educational research and development center, and (4) provide grants to turn around low-performing schools that serve middle grade students.</summary>
</bill>
