<bill session="119" type="h" number="206" updated="2025-04-22T08:05:24Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Landlord Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Landlord Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Housing Act to prohibit discrimination based on use of section 8 vouchers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2025-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-12T21:45:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Landlord Accountability Act of 2025

This bill prohibits housing discrimination based on income, provides protections to tenants of certain federally assisted housing, and establishes a low-income housing maintenance tax credit for eligible landlords.

Specifically, the bill prohibits discrimination in rental housing and residential real estate transactions based on an individual's source of income and provides for penalties. Protected income sources include

housing vouchers and rental assistance,rental and homeownership subsidies,Social Security and disability income assistance, andspousal and child support.Additionally, landlords are prohibited from taking or failing to take certain actions with the intent to make a unit ineligible to receive Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) assistance. Landlords that violate this prohibition are subject to penalties and may be sued by harmed tenants. The bill further prohibits property owners of certain multifamily housing projects from intentionally leaving a unit vacant for more than 60 days. Property owners that violate this prohibition are subject to penalties.

The bill also provides protections to tenants of multifamily housing projects, which includes requiring HUD to increase the staffing level for the Multifamily Housing Complaint Line and create a Multifamily Housing Complaint Resolution Program.

In addition, HUD may provide grants to develop, expand, and assist tenant harassment prevention programs.

Finally, the bill establishes a tax credit for qualifying landlords that is equal to the landlord's annual low-income housing maintenance expenses. To qualify, a landlord must have addressed within 30 days any relevant complaints filed under the complaint resolution program.</summary>
</bill>
