<bill session="117" type="h" number="7602" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent organizational conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2022-08-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 17.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3905" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-11T22:21:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act

This bill addresses conflicts of interest in federal acquisitions.

Specifically, the bill directs the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to (1) identify contracting methods, types, and services that raise heightened concerns for potential organizational conflicts of interest beyond those currently addressed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR); and (2) revise the FAR to address organizational conflicts of interest and require executive agencies to take certain actions.

The council must revise the FAR to

 provide and update definitions related to organizational conflicts of interest, to include specified contractor relationships; provide executive agencies with solicitation and contract provisions that require contractors to disclose information relevant to potential organizational conflicts of interest and limit future contracting with respect to potential conflicts; and require executive agencies to establish or update agency conflict of interest procedures to implement these FAR revisions and address agency-specific conflict of interest issues.</summary>
</bill>
