<bill session="117" type="h" number="8825" updated="2022-12-29T12:33:50Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide authority for small cultivators of marijuana and small manufacturers of marijuana products to ship marijuana and marijuana products using the mail, and for other purpose.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2022-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Biotechnology, Horticulture, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-12T14:09:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2022 

This bill provides authority for small cultivators of marijuana and small manufacturers of marijuana products to ship and sell the marijuana or marijuana products using the U.S. Postal Service or a private or commercial interstate carrier.

Specifically, marijuana or a marijuana product may be shipped or sold to individuals within a state or another state in which the possession of it is lawful by such individuals.

The bill takes effect on the date on which marijuana is removed from the list of scheduled substances under the Controlled Substances Act and federal criminal penalties for an individual who manufactures, distributes, or possesses marijuana, are eliminated.</summary>
</bill>
