<bill session="119" type="s" number="1207" updated="2025-06-09T15:45:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Feral Swine Eradication Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feral Swine Eradication Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 to reauthorize the feral swine eradication and control pilot program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2025-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T15:44:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Feral Swine Eradication Act

This bill reauthorizes&#160;the Feral Swine Eradication and Control Pilot Program through FY2030&#160;and removes the pilot program designation. This Department of Agriculture (USDA) program responds to the threat feral swine pose to agriculture, native ecosystems, and human and animal health.

In addition, USDA must require&#160;the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) and the Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS)&#160;to&#160;continue monitoring an&#160;area for reoccurrence of feral swine for one year after USDA determines that feral swine has been eradicated from&#160;an eligible&#160;area.

The bill requires 60% of the funds provided for the program to be allocated to APHIS and 40% of the funds to be allocated to the NRCS. (Under current law, the funds are divided evenly between APHIS and&#160;the NRCS).&#160;

Further, the bill includes new reporting requirements, which direct APHIS and the NRCS to submit a joint report to Congress on the program. This report must be publicly available on USDA's website.</summary>
</bill>
