<bill session="117" type="h" number="2587" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SERVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the ability of veterans with medical training to assist the United States in response to national emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SERVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Education Recognition for Veterans during Emergencies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4156" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-29T15:04:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Education Recognition for Veterans during Emergencies Act or the SERVE Act

This bill addresses opportunities for certain veterans with medical experience.

The bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to update its web portals to allow the identification of veterans who had a medical occupation as a member of the Armed Forces. Specifically, the bill authorizes veterans to elect to provide their contact information and a history of their medical experience and trained competencies.

The VA, the Department of Defense (DOD), and the Department of Labor must establish a program to share the veteran's provided information with specified entities (e.g., state credentialing bodies) for purposes of facilitating civilian medical credentialing and hiring of veterans seeking to respond to a national emergency, including a public health emergency.

The VA must implement a program to train and certify veterans who served as basic health care technicians during their service to work as VA intermediate care technicians, specifically at VA medical center locations with staffing shortages. Additionally, the VA must prepare a communications campaign under the Transition Assistance Program to convey opportunities related to the intermediate care technician program to members of the Armed Forces who are separating from active duty.

Finally, the bill requires the VA and DOD to notify veterans service organizations and members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces about the opportunities for veterans provided under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
