<bill session="118" type="s" number="199" updated="2025-11-19T03:39:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Root and Stem Project Authorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Root and Stem Project Authorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Root and Stem Project Authorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to codify the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to conduct certain landscape-scale forest restoration projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin without amendment. With written report No. 118-50.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="122">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="674" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1456" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-25T19:21:48Z" status="Reported to Senate">Root and Stem Project Authorization Act of 2023

This bill authorizes the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to conduct certain forest restoration projects.

Specifically, the Forest Service or BLM may enter into an agreement for a project on federal land that was developed through a collaborative process that meets local and rural community needs if

 the party with whom it enters into an agreement initially provides the Forest Service or BLM with a portion of the funding necessary to complete any analysis deemed necessary under federal law for consideration of the proposed project; the Forest Service or BLM uses the funding to pay a contractor included on a list of contractors that it maintains to conduct the analysis; upon completion of the analysis, the Forest Service or BLM solicits bids to carry out the project and enters into a contract or agreement under the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to carry out the project; and using certain receipts from the project, the Forest Service or BLM repays the initially provided funding. For purposes of a civil action relating to such a project, any person that participated in the collaborative process to develop the proposal for the project shall be (1) entitled to intervene, as of right, in any subsequent civil action; and (2) considered to be a full participant in any settlement negotiation relating to the project.

The authority to enter into an agreement and the requirement to maintain a list of contractors shall expire on January 1, 2033.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-50</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
