<bill session="117" type="h" number="8525" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001125"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2022-07-27" withdrawn="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2022-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-23T17:07:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Delivering Equity and Justice for Disaster Survivors Act of 2022

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish, as a subcommittee of the National Advisory Council, the Disaster Equity and Justice Subcommittee.

The subcommittee must develop recommendations for improving equitable and just policy and program delivery before, during, and after disasters, including recommendations related to

 the accessibility, utilization, and receipt of FEMA grants and assistance by underserved, under resourced, and underrepresented populations and communities; strategies and policy recommendations to address the inequitable delivery of disaster assistance, grant programs, technical assistance, and training; and strategies to address any disparate impacts climate change will have on culturally, socially, or economically vulnerable communities.</summary>
</bill>
