<bill session="117" type="h" number="9506" updated="2023-08-14T15:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Budgetary Quid Pro Quo Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Budgetary Quid Pro Quo Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the consideration in the House of Representatives and Senate of legislation which includes a provision authorizing the appropriation of an amount of funds for a program which does not include a provision reducing by at least the same amount the amount otherwise authorized to be appropriated for the same program or for any other program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2022-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-14T15:06:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Budgetary Quid Pro Quo Act

This bill generally prohibits Congress from considering legislation that authorizes appropriations for a program unless the legislation also includes a provision that reduces an authorization of appropriations for the program or another program by at least the same amount.

The bill also requires the Government Publishing Office to establish and maintain an online portal through which members of the public may access information about authorizations of appropriations, including (1) specified details about laws enacted during a Congress that authorize appropriations, and (2) a statement of the total amount of funds authorized to be appropriated during a Congress.</summary>
</bill>
