<bill session="108" type="s" number="2155" updated="2023-01-15T10:47:53Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Growing Our Manufacturing Employment (GoME) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a manufacturer's jobs credit, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Growing Our Manufacturing Employment (GoME) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2004-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2024-2025"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-30T12:13:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Growing Our Manufacturing Employment (GoME) Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish as a general business tax credit a manufacturer's jobs credit equal to a certain percentage of wages paid to the employees (including employees eligible for a trade readjustment allowance) of a taxpayer that has a certain level of domestic production gross receipts in the current and preceding taxable years and that is not disqualified as an inverted domestic corporation (a foreign corporation that manipulates its structure to evade U.S. taxes).

Allows an income tax deduction for: (1) nine percent of income allocable to domestic production activities; (2) up to $10,000 of reforestation expenditures in the current taxable year.

Permits a taxpayer to revoke a prior election to treat the cutting of timber as a sale or exchange. Qualifies the outright sale of timber for capital gains tax treatment. Repeals the investment tax credit for reforestation expenditures.

Sets forth requirements for transactions to qualify for tax benefits under the economic substance doctrine, including special rules for transactions with tax-indifferent parties.

 Sets forth rules for the tax treatment of inverted domestic corporations (a foreign incorporated entity that acquires substantially all of the properties of a domestic corporation or partnership, that retains 80 percent of stock ownership identity, and that does not have substantial business activities in the foreign country under whose law the entity is created, for the purpose of avoiding U.S. taxation). Treats a foreign corporation deemed to be an inverted domestic corporation as a domestic corporation for U.S. tax purposes.</summary>
</bill>
