<bill session="117" type="h" number="3016" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commuter Parkway Safety and Reliability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to direct the Director of the National Park Service to provide funding for high-commuter corridors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commuter Parkway Safety and Reliability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-03T19:22:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Commuter Parkway Safety and Reliability Act

This bill requires the National Park Service (NPS) to carry out a program under the federal lands transportation program to provide funding for high-commuter corridors. High-commuter corridor is defined as a federal lands transportation facility administered by the NPS that has average annual daily traffic of not less than 20,000 vehicles.

If the NPS determines that a high-commuter corridor requires additional investment it must submit to the state

 information on the condition of pavements and bridges; an estimate of the amounts needed to bring such corridor into a state of good repair, taking into consideration any planned future investments; and at its discretion, a request that the state provide funding to address the condition of the corridor. The bill sets forth the criteria the NPS must consider when making a determination of whether a a high-commuter corridor requires additional investment.</summary>
</bill>
