<bill session="117" type="h" number="7686" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide information on certain persons under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons to the Mayor of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E457"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6962" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-13T18:26:12Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia Code Returning Citizens Coordination Act

This bill requires the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) to provide, every 90 days, specified information (e.g., the scheduled release date) to the Mayor of the District of Columbia for each person under the jurisdiction of the BOP pursuant to the National Capital Revitalization and Self-Government Improvement Act of 1997. The BOP must also provide, upon the request of the Mayor, such information to the Court Services and Offender Supervision Agency for the District.

The Mayor of the District of Columbia may not disclose the provided information outside of the District government or to any District of Columbia law enforcement agency, but may disclose such information to counsel for the detained individuals, and to organizations that provide legal representation to individuals in criminal or post-conviction matters, or in matters related to re-entry.</summary>
</bill>
