<bill session="118" type="s" number="3836" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CRAWDAD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CRAWDAD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crawfish Recovery Assistance from Weather Disasters And Droughts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve drought-related disaster assistance programs of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-31T16:30:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Crawfish Recovery Assistance from Weather Disasters And Droughts Act or the CRAWDAD Act

This bill modifies access to the Emergency Assistance for Livestock, Honey Bees, and Farm-Raised Fish Program (ELAP) and the Livestock Forage Disaster Program (LFP).&#160;ELAP and LFP are Farm Service Agency (FSA) administered programs.

The bill expands coverage under ELAP for losses caused by adverse weather or drought. The bill includes under ELAP the loss of a crawfish harvest due to adverse weather or drought. (ELAP provides payments to producers of livestock, honey bees, and farm-raised fish as compensation for losses due to disease, adverse weather, feed or water shortages, or other conditions that are not covered under other programs.)

The FSA must&#160;establish ELAP documentation standards for (1) collecting data, (2) the production of crawfish,&#160;and (3) defining loss conditions due to drought.

The bill also specifies that eligibility under LFP for livestock producers applies to producers with weaned or unweaned livestock.&#160;(LFP makes payments to eligible livestock producers who have suffered grazing losses on drought-affected pastureland, including cropland planted specifically for grazing. Currently, unweaned livestock are not eligible for the program.)&#160;</summary>
</bill>
