<bill session="108" type="h" number="5339" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:39Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">La Cura Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize increased funding for research at the National Institutes of Health relating to Alzheimer's disease, to amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize an education and outreach program to promote public awareness and risk reduction with respect to Alzheimer's disease (with particular emphasis on education and outreach in Hispanic populations), and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cure and Understanding through Research for Alzheimer's Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">La Cura Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000359" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2004-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000170" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000568" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001153" joined="2004-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2004-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-01T16:41:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Cure and Understanding through Research for Alzheimer's Act of 2004 or La Cura Act of 2004 - Authorizes appropriations for conducting and supporting research on Alzheimer's disease at the National Institutes of Health (NIH).

Requires the Director of NIH to ensure sufficient resources for activities relating to Alzheimer's disease and Hispanic communities, including by: (1) increasing efforts in epidemiological work in Hispanic subgroups; (2) allocating resources to the National Institute on Aging Alzheimer's disease research centers and other academic centers involved in such research to increase participation of Hispanics in research and clinical trials in sufficient numbers to draw valid conclusions; and (3) conduct social, behavioral, and health services research to understand the underlying reasons why Hispanic individuals delay diagnosis and underutilize services and to identify culturally and linguistically appropriate approaches to address such delays and underutilization.

Requires the Director to expand and intensify NIH efforts to educate communities about the importance of research relating to Alzheimer's disease and to respond effectively to cultural concerns about participation in such research.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for a program of grants to States to carry out demonstration programs related to Alzheimer's disease.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to conduct an aggressive, evidence-based education and outreach program to promote public awareness and risk reduction with respect to Alzheimer's disease, particularly to Hispanic populations.</summary>
</bill>
