<bill session="119" type="h" number="1048" updated="2025-09-03T14:21:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-27T10:54:47-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-27T10:54:47-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="display">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to strengthen disclosure requirements relating to foreign gifts and contracts, to prohibit contracts between institutions of higher education and certain foreign entities and countries of concern, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2025-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001314" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001093" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000307" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001233" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000177" joined="2025-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000619" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2025-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2025-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Workforce. H. Rept. 119-16.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-14" calendar="Union" number="9">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24T19:43:25-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 242 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 24, H.J. Res. 75 and H.R. 1048. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 24 and H.J. Res. 75 under a closed rule, and provides for consideration of H.R. 1048 under a structured rule. Also, the resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T14:28:50-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 242 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T14:29:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 242.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1241-1260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T14:29:15-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 24, H.J. Res. 75 and H.R. 1048. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J. Res. 24 and H.J. Res. 75 under a closed rule, and provides for consideration of H.R. 1048 under a structured rule. Also, the resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T14:30:26-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 242 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T14:30:27-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Pat Harrigan to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T14:30:52-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1048.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:10:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 242, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:21:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 242, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:26:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 242, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Scott (VA) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:35:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Scott (VA) amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Scott (VA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:35:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 242, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Self amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:39:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Self amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Scott (VA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:39:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 242, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tlaib amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:48:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tlaib amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Tlaib demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:48:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 242, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tlaib amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:58:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tlaib amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Tlaib demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:58:53-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walberg moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:59:08-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25T15:59:21-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1048 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27T10:26:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1312-1316" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27T10:26:25-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27T10:46:40-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1048.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27T10:47:44-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27T10:47:55-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gros as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="83" datetime="2025-03-27T10:54:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 169 (Roll no. 83).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27T10:54:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="938" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1023" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1018" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="242" relation="procedurally related"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1296" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1999" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h15"/>
    <amendment number="h14"/>
    <amendment number="h13"/>
    <amendment number="h12"/>
    <amendment number="h11"/>
    <amendment number="h10"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-03-19T14:59:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act or the DETERRENT Act

This bill expands oversight and disclosure requirements related to foreign sources and institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to annually disclose to the Department of Education (ED) any year in which the IHE

receives a gift from a foreign country of concern (e.g., China or Russia) or foreign entity of concern of any dollar amount;receives a gift or contract from a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) that is valued at $50,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts or contracts within a calendar year (current disclosure threshold is $250,000 or more), or which has an undetermined monetary value;enters into a contract with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern after receiving a waiver for such contract; oris substantially controlled by a foreign source.Additionally, the bill

prohibits IHEs from entering into contracts with a foreign country of concern or with a foreign entity of concern without obtaining a waiver,requires certain IHEs to disclose gifts or contracts between covered individuals (e.g., researchers) and foreign sources, andrequires private IHEs with specified assets or investments to file annual investment disclosure reports.The bill requires ED to investigate possible violations of this bill and outlines the various penalties for each violation. Penalties may include losing eligibility for federal student financial aid.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-16</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
