<bill session="117" type="h" number="8406" updated="2023-08-10T16:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COREY Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Operational Reporting of Emergencies Involving Teens and Young Adults Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COREY Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require reporting of certain incidents resulting in serious physical injuries or death at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2022-08-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2022-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2022-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2022-08-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2022-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000929" joined="2022-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001135" joined="2022-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-10T16:16:57Z" status="Introduced in House">College Operational Reporting of Emergencies Involving Teens and Young Adults Safety Act of 2022 or the COREY Safety Act of 2022

This bill expands reporting requirements included in the annual security report provided to current and prospective students and employees of each institution of higher education (IHE).

Specifically, the bill requires each IHE to include in its report information about the number of incidents that result in serious physical harm or death involving (1) transportation on foot or via bikes, scooters, skateboards, longboards, or motor vehicles; (2) ground level and high height slips and falls; (3) alcohol or drug overdoses; and (4) choking or drowning. Further, the IHE must also include in the report a statement containing the name, address, and distance from campus of the closest Level I trauma center.

Additionally, the bill changes the name of the report from annual security report to annual campus safety report.</summary>
</bill>
