<bill session="115" type="s" number="2742" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:39Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SARMs Control Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to more effectively regulate selective androgen receptor modulators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SARMs Control Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Selective Androgen Receptor Modulators Control Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2018-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-23T23:00:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Selective Androgen Receptor Modulators Control Act of 2018 or the SARMs Control Act of 2018

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) to add SARMs (selective androgen receptor modulators) to schedule III. A SARM is a synthetic drug or substance that has effects similar to testosterone. A schedule III controlled substance (e.g., an anabolic steroid) has less potential for abuse than a schedule I or II substance, has a currently accepted medical use, and has low or moderate risk of dependence if abused.

The bill also:

 authorizes, and establishes procedures for, the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) to temporarily and permanently add a drug or substance to the definition of a SARM; specifies that a felony drug offense includes an offense related to SARMs; and makes it unlawful to import, export, manufacture, distribute, dispense, or possess with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, a SARM that is not clearly labeled. The bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Food and Drug Administration to notify the DEA when it determines that a new dietary ingredient in a dietary supplement may contain a SARM or SARM analogue.</summary>
</bill>
