<bill session="117" type="s" number="2464" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Economic Development, to establish a RECOMPETE grant program to provide flexible, 10-year block grants for purposes of creating quality jobs, providing resources to help local residents access opportunities and attain and retain employment, increasing local per capita income and employment rates, and supporting long-term, sustained economic growth and opportunity in persistently distressed areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">RECOMPETE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuilding Economies and Creating Opportunities for More People to Excel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RECOMPETE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4651" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-28T18:51:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rebuilding Economies and Creating Opportunities for More People To Excel Act or the RECOMPETE Act

This bill establishes a grant program to assist economically distressed local communities and labor markets that meet specified economic criteria, including employment criteria.

The Economic Development Administration (EDA) must award 10-year grants to a local government, tribal government, economic development district, or consortium of local government units located in such areas. Each grant recipient must develop and implement a comprehensive strategy to address the economic challenges specific to the area. The grants may be used to increase employment opportunities, increase local per capita income, support economic development, and develop infrastructure and housing.

Additionally, the EDA must periodically evaluate each grant recipient based on certain benchmark criteria and annually report on the implementation of the program.

The bill specifies formulas for determining the grant amount for each community or market and the federal share of the cost of each program or activity conducted under the program.</summary>
</bill>
