<bill session="117" type="h" number="8366" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Land Restoration and Resiliency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land Restoration and Resiliency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to enter into an agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation to establish the Community Resilience and Restoration Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5118" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-19T22:42:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Land Restoration and Resiliency Act of 2022

This bill directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to enter into cooperative agreements with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation to establish the Community Resilience and Restoration Fund at the foundation, for purposes including to

 improve community safety in the face of climactic extremes through conservation and protection of restoration and resilience lands; protect, conserve, and restore restoration and resilience lands in order to help communities respond and adapt to natural threats, including wildfire, drought, extreme heat, and other threats posed or exacerbated by the impacts of global climate; and protect and enhance the biodiversity of wildlife populations across restoration and resilience lands. The bill defines restoration and resilience lands as fish, wildlife, and plant habitats, and other important natural areas in the United States, on public lands, private land (after obtaining proper consent from the landowner), or land of Indian tribes, including grasslands, shrublands, prairies, chaparral lands, forest lands, deserts, and riparian or wetland areas within or adjacent to these ecosystems.

To the extent amounts are available in the fund, the foundation shall award grants to eligible entities (e.g., a federal agency, a unit of local government, an Indian tribe, or a nonprofit organization) through a competitive grant process to carry out eligible projects and activities.</summary>
</bill>
