<bill session="117" type="s" number="866" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Repairing Existing Public Land by Adding Necessary Trees Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Repairing Existing Public Land by Adding Necessary Trees Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPLANT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 to promote reforestation following unplanned events on Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2021-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2021-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2049" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-27T21:13:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Repairing Existing Public Land by Adding Necessary Trees Act or the REPLANT Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) annually for each of the 10 years after enactment of this bill to transmit to Congress an estimate of the sums necessary to be appropriated, in addition to the funds available from other sources, to replant and otherwise treat an acreage equal to the acreage to be cut over that year, plus a sufficient portion of the backlog of lands found to be in need of treatment to eliminate the backlog within the 10-year period.

After such 10-year period, USDA shall transmit annually to Congress an estimate of the sums necessary to replant and otherwise treat all lands being cut over and maintain planned timber production on all other forested lands in the National Forest System to prevent the development of a backlog of needed work larger than the needed work at the beginning of the fiscal year.

Each reforestation activity included in a renewable resource assessment shall be carried out in accordance with applicable Forest Service management practices and definitions, including definitions relating to silvicultural practices and forest management.

The Forest Service shall, based on recommendations from regional foresters, create a priority list of reforestation projects that primarily take place on priority land, promote effective reforestation following unplanned events, and may include activities to ensure adequate and appropriate seed availability.

USDA shall give priority to projects on the priority list.</summary>
</bill>
