<bill session="117" type="h" number="1495" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jim Ramstad Legacy of Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide coverage under the Medicaid program for services for the treatment of psychiatric or substance use disorders furnished to certain individuals in an institution for mental diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jim Ramstad Legacy of Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-21T22:12:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Jim Ramstad Legacy of Recovery Act

This bill allows states to receive federal Medicaid payment for psychiatric and substance-use disorder services provided in institutions for mental diseases (IMDs) to patients who are enrolled with a Medicaid managed care organization (MCO) or in a prepaid inpatient health plan (PIHP).

Current law generally prohibits federal payment under Medicaid for services provided in IMDs for individuals under the age of 65. However, states may receive federal Medicaid payment for monthly capitation payments to MCOs and PIHPs for services provided in IMDs to enrollees aged 21 to 64. Such services must be provided for no longer than 15 days per month and in lieu of other services covered under the state Medicaid program.</summary>
</bill>
