<bill session="112" type="h" number="3089" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:11Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RELIEF Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to make grants to local governments for flood mitigation projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuilding the Economy and Limiting the Impacts of Expected Flooding Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RELIEF Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2011-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-11-04T13:46:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Rebuilding the Economy and Limiting the Impacts of Expected Flooding Act of 2011 or the RELIEF Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to make grants to local governments for flood mitigation projects. Directs the Administrator to give priority to: (1) projects that will resolve the greatest safety and property hazards, and (2) projects with significant capacities for job creation. Allows the Administrator to provide such grant assistance to a local government without regard to its eligibility to receive financial assistance for the project under another federal program.</summary>
</bill>
