<bill session="108" type="s" number="2227" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:07Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-08">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Anticounterfeiting Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent and punish counterfeiting and copyright piracy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Anticounterfeiting Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anticounterfeiting Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000121" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000725" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000180" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2004-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3001-3002"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3002-3003" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-08">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12028-12029" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-12-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12028-12029" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2242" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3632" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-18T19:52:53Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Anticounterfeiting Act of 2004 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit trafficking in an "illicit authentication feature." Defines that term to mean an authentication feature that: (1) has been tampered with or altered without authorization so as to facilitate the reproduction or distribution of a phono-record, a copy of a computer program, motion picture or other audiovisual work, or documentation or packaging, in violation of the rights of the copyright owner; (2) is genuine, but has been distributed or is intended for distribution without authorization; or (3) appears to be genuine but is not.

Authorizes a copyright owner who is injured by a violation of this Act or is threatened with injury to bring a civil action in an appropriate U.S. district court. Allows the court to: (1) grant temporary or permanent injunctions to prevent or restrain violations; (2) order the impounding of an article in the custody or control of the alleged violator that the court has reasonable cause to believe was involved in a violation; and (3) award to the injured party reasonable attorney fees and costs, actual damages and any additional profits of the violator, or statutory damages. Authorizes: (1) the injured party to elect to recover, instead of actual damages and profits, an award of statutory damages of between $2,500 and $25,000 for each violation; and (2) the court to increase a damage award by three times the amount that would otherwise be awarded upon finding that a person has violated this Act within three years after a final judgment was entered for a previous violation. Sets a three-year statute of limitations from discovery of the violation.</summary>
</bill>
