<bill session="116" type="h" number="6230" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:31Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PSLF Administrative Improvements Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Service Loan Forgiveness Program under the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require an on-line portal, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PSLF Administrative Improvements Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001296"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-02T16:18:25Z" status="Introduced in House">PSLF Administrative Improvements Act

This bill revises provisions related to the Public Service Loan Forgiveness (PSLF) program.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish a publicly accessible database of public service employers, which must include information required for the completion of employment certification forms. Such forms must also be available in languages other than English.

ED must annually provide certain notices of PSLF program requirements to public service employers and institutions of higher education. In addition, ED must determine whether a borrower who was denied loan cancellation under the PSLF program qualifies for loan cancellation under the Temporary Expanded Public Service Loan Forgiveness program.

The bill requires ED to enter into data matching agreements with relevant federal agencies. In addition, the Department of Labor, the Internal Revenue Service, and the Social Security Administration must disclose any relevant records to ED. ED must notify borrowers of receipt of employer or employment information.

Additionally, it requires ED to ensure that (1) borrowers have access to an online portal that provides borrowers with certain instructions and information, including the number of monthly payments on qualifying loans; and (2) employers have the ability to electronically sign and submit forms associated with loan cancellation.

It also requires ED to develop and make publicly available procedures for determining whether a borrower meets the requirements for loan cancellation under the PSLF program.</summary>
</bill>
