<bill session="117" type="s" number="2366" updated="2023-01-01T23:43:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library to replace the bust of Roger Brooke Taney in the Old Supreme Court Chamber of the Capitol with a bust of Thurgood Marshall to be obtained by the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library and to remove certain statues from areas of the Capitol which are accessible to the public, to remove all statues of individuals who voluntarily served the Confederate States of America from display in the Capitol, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to direct the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library to replace the bust of Roger Brooke Taney in the Old Supreme Court Chamber of the Capitol with a bust of Thurgood Marshall to be obtained by the Joint Committee of Congress on the Library and to remove certain statues from areas of the Capitol which are accessible to the public, to remove all statues of individuals who voluntarily served the Confederate States of America from display in the Capitol, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2022-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4216" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3005" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1248" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="366" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5229" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-19T16:23:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides for the removal of certain statues and busts from display in the Capitol.

The bill directs the Joint Committee on the Library to remove the bust of Roger Brooke Taney in the Old Supreme Court chamber of the Capitol and replace it with a bust of Thurgood Marshall.

The committee must remove the statues of Charles Brantley Aycock, John Caldwell Calhoun, and James Paul Clarke and the bust of John Cabell Breckinridge from areas of the Capitol accessible to the public. The Architect of the Capitol (AOC) must store the statues and bust until it arranges their return to the states that provided them.

Additionally, the bill

 prohibits the display of statues in National Statuary Hall of persons who served as officers or voluntarily with the Confederate States of America or of the military forces or government of a state while it was in rebellion against the United States; requires the AOC to identify such statues and arrange for their transfer and delivery from the Capitol to the Smithsonian Institution; requires the Smithsonian to follow its preexisting policies and procedures regarding the storage and display of such transferred statues; requires each statue to be returned to the providing state, including its ownership, if the state requests and agrees to pay any transportation-related costs; and permits a state that has a statue removed to replace the statue.</summary>
</bill>
