<bill session="116" type="s" number="1033" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Health Options and Insurance Competition Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a public health insurance option, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2019-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2019-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2085" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-27T14:24:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Health Options and Insurance Competition Enhancement Act or the CHOICE Act This bill requires the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) to develop a public health insurance option that meets all federal plan requirements and is available on state and federal health insurance exchanges. Specifically, the CMS must offer silver and gold plans, may offer bronze plans, and must include all essential benefits, consumer protections, and cost-sharing limitations in each plan. The CMS may contract with a third party to administer the public option plans and states may establish advisory councils to make recommendations to the CMS about the operation and policies of such plans. Further, the CMS must establish geographically adjusted premiums and negotiate provider payment rates for services and prescription drugs covered the plans. If a payment rate cannot be negotiated, the CMS must pay the amount for such service as required under traditional Medicare. Medicare and Medicaid providers are automatically participants in public option plans unless they opt out, and providers not participating in Medicare or Medicaid may opt in.</summary>
</bill>
