<bill session="116" type="hr" number="767" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:52Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-18T11:57:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-18T11:57:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 755) impeaching Donald John Trump, President of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 755) impeaching Donald John Trump, President of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-355, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T21:45:09-05:00">
      <text>The question of adoption of the resolution, as amended shall be divided between the two articles. The amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted After adoption of H. Res. 755, it shall be in order without intervention of any point of order to consider in the House a resolution appointing and authorizing managers for the impeachment trial if offered by the chair of the Committee on the Judiciary or his designee.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-12-17" calendar="House" number="63">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18T10:02:09-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12115-12130" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18T10:05:32-05:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Scalise rose to raise a point of order against H.Res. 767 on the ground that the report accompanying the resolution fails to specify the waiver of a particular point of order, and is thus in violation of clause 6(g) of rule 13. The Chair advised the gentleman that he was not stating a proper point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18T10:06:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 767.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18T11:48:32-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 197 (Roll no. 693).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12129-12130" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="694" datetime="2019-12-18T11:57:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 228 - 197 (Roll no. 694).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12115" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18T11:57:04-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="798" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="755" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-21T14:41:54Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of H.Res. 755 (impeaching the President for high crimes and misdemeanors).

 The resolution (1) designates certain individuals to be admitted to the Hall of the House of Representatives, during consideration of H.Res. 755; (2) after adoption of H.Res. 755, makes it in order to consider in the House a resolution appointing and authorizing managers for the impeachment trial, if offered by the chair of the House Committee on the Judiciary; and (3) prohibits any other resolution incidental to impeachment relating to H.Res. 755 from being privileged during the remainder of the 116th Congress.

The chair of the Committee on the Judiciary may insert in the Congressional Record, within five legislative days after its adoption, such materials as the chair may deem explanatory of (1) H.Res. 755, and (2) the resolution appointing and authorizing managers for the impeachment trial.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-355</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
