<bill session="118" type="h" number="4820" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-24">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Departments of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-24">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-154, by Mr. Cole.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-24" calendar="Union" number="122">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T08:19:30-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 838 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4821, H.R. 4820 and H.R. 6126. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4821 and H.R. 4820 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate for each bill. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6126, under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate. Each measure has one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:29:54-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 838.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5420-5425" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5427-5451" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:29:59-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4821, H.R. 4820 and H.R. 6126. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4821 and H.R. 4820 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate for each bill. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6126, under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate. Each measure has one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:30:37-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 838 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:30:40-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Don Bacon to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:30:53-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:57:04-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed with debate on H.R. 4820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T18:15:54-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cole moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T18:16:12-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T18:16:31-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4820 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:15:46-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5427-5462" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:15:59-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:19:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Cole amendment en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:30:18-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lawler amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:36:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Escobar amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:42:46-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Escobar amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Escobar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:43:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T19:52:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:00:21-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:00:53-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:10:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:18:02-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:21:38-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:36:45-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 25, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:37:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:45:30-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 29, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:46:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:51:55-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 30, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:52:24-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cole moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:52:43-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T20:52:57-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4820 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T14:11:07-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5490-5494" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T14:11:27-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T14:11:28-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on agreeing to amendments to H.R. 4820, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T14:30:43-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cole moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T14:31:02-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T14:31:12-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4820 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T15:59:49-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5503-5530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:00:10-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:02:12-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Strong amendment No. 31.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:10:59-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:15:50-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:26:30-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 34, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:28:16-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blunt Rochester amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:35:44-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blunt Rochester amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Ms. Blunt Rochester demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:36:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:45:56-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 37, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:46:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:53:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schweikert amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:58:56-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schweikert amendment No. 46, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T16:59:32-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schweikert amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:07:54-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schweikert amendment No. 47, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:08:58-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burlison amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:17:23-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cammack amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:23:37-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fry amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:31:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gooden (TX) amendment No. 52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:39:28-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:44:03-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T17:54:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Green (GA) amendment No. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:04:48-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 57.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:11:53-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 57, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:12:40-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:17:51-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Massie amendment No. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:27:34-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Massie amendment No. 59, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:28:08-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Massie amendment No. 60.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:40:26-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Massie amendment No. 60, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:41:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:47:38-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:50:56-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 62, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:52:08-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:55:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:58:33-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 64, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T18:59:20-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:05:35-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:11:54-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 66, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:12:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:15:03-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:17:26-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 69.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:22:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:30:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:38:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:45:58-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Santos amendment No. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:52:07-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Santos amendment No. 73, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T19:52:50-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Self amendment No. 74.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T20:01:14-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Self amendment No. 74, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Quigley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T20:01:38-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cole moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T20:01:53-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T20:02:16-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4820 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T21:00:42-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5531-5540" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T21:00:57-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T22:18:47-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4820.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T22:19:28-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07T22:20:38-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced further proceedings on H.R. 4820 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2437" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="838" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4366" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1061" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae)"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Iceland"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on Homelessness"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB)"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Norway"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h655"/>
    <amendment number="h654"/>
    <amendment number="h653"/>
    <amendment number="h652"/>
    <amendment number="h651"/>
    <amendment number="h650"/>
    <amendment number="h649"/>
    <amendment number="h648"/>
    <amendment number="h647"/>
    <amendment number="h646"/>
    <amendment number="h645"/>
    <amendment number="h644"/>
    <amendment number="h643"/>
    <amendment number="h642"/>
    <amendment number="h641"/>
    <amendment number="h640"/>
    <amendment number="h639"/>
    <amendment number="h638"/>
    <amendment number="h637"/>
    <amendment number="h636"/>
    <amendment number="h635"/>
    <amendment number="h634"/>
    <amendment number="h633"/>
    <amendment number="h632"/>
    <amendment number="h631"/>
    <amendment number="h630"/>
    <amendment number="h629"/>
    <amendment number="h628"/>
    <amendment number="h627"/>
    <amendment number="h626"/>
    <amendment number="h625"/>
    <amendment number="h624"/>
    <amendment number="h623"/>
    <amendment number="h622"/>
    <amendment number="h621"/>
    <amendment number="h620"/>
    <amendment number="h619"/>
    <amendment number="h618"/>
    <amendment number="h617"/>
    <amendment number="h616"/>
    <amendment number="h615"/>
    <amendment number="h614"/>
    <amendment number="h613"/>
    <amendment number="h612"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-09-06T10:24:20Z" status="Reported to House">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024

This bill provides FY2024 appropriations to the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to DOT for

 the Office of the Secretary, the Federal Aviation Administration, the Federal Highway Administration, the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Federal Railroad Administration, the Federal Transit Administration, the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation, the Maritime Administration, the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, and the Office of Inspector General. The bill provides appropriations to HUD for

 Management and Administration, Public and Indian Housing, Community Planning and Development, Housing Programs, the Federal Housing Administration, the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae), Policy Development and Research, Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, the Information Technology Fund, and the Office of Inspector General. The bill also provides appropriations to several related agencies, including

 the Access Board, the Federal Maritime Commission, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) Office of Inspector General, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, the Surface Transportation Board, and the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. Additionally, the bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-154</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
