<bill session="112" type="s" number="3203" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:07Z">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Health Care Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to limit increases in the certain costs of health care services under the health care programs of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Military Health Care Protection Act of 2012</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2012-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2012-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2012-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2012-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="6266" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-07-26T18:52:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Health Care Protection Act of 2012 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) career military personnel and their families endure unique and extraordinary demands and make extraordinary sacrifices over the course of a 20-30 year career, and (2) those decades of sacrifice constitute a significant pre-paid premium for health care during a career member's retirement that is over and above what the member pays with money.

Prohibits any cost-sharing requirement under the Department of Defense (DOD) pharmacy benefits program, as well as deductibles under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS), from being increased by a percentage greater than that year's percentage increase in retired pay. Prohibits CHAMPUS inpatient charges from exceeding 25% of their total cost or $708 per day. Prohibits, beginning with FY2013, the maximum annual limit on charges under CHAMPUS from being increased by a percentage greater than that year's percentage increase in retired pay.

Prohibits former members of the Armed Forces who are entitled to retired pay, as well as dependents of members who died while on active duty or from an injury, illness, or disease incurred while on active duty, from being charged an enrollment fee for CHAMPUS coverage or from being subject to denial of claims for coverage based on failure to enroll.</summary>
</bill>
