<bill session="118" type="h" number="1353" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-26T14:19:45-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-04-26T14:19:45-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advanced, Local Emergency Response Telecommunications Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Advanced, Local Emergency Response Telecommunications Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Advanced, Local Emergency Response Telecommunications Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced, Local Emergency Response Telecommunications Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short">Advanced, Local Emergency Response Telecommunications Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short">ALERT Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to issue rules for the provision of emergency connectivity service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2023-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 0 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 46 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-24">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-39.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-04-24" calendar="Union" number="25">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25T16:01:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Latta moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25T16:01:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1921-1924" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25T16:01:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1353.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25T16:01:36-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26T14:11:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1978-1979" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="197" datetime="2023-04-26T14:19:45-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 422 - 1 (Roll no. 197).</text>
      <reference ref="4/25/2023 CR H1922-1923" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26T14:19:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-02T13:11:20Z" status="Passed House">Advanced, Local Emergency Response Telecommunications Parity Act or the ALERT Parity Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to facilitate the provision of emergency communication services (e.g., 9-1-1 calls and emergency alerts) in unserved areas. An unserved area is one that has no commercial mobile service capable of providing emergency services because of a lack of infrastructure, destruction of infrastructure, a power outage, or other reason.

The FCC must establish a process for companies to apply for approval to access the electromagnetic spectrum in order to provide emergency services in unserved areas. To obtain approval, a company must demonstrate that it (1) has a technical proposal for providing services, (2) will not use the spectrum to provide additional services, and (3) has the capability to provide the services rapidly. The company must also demonstrate that the services can withstand earthquakes, hurricanes, and other major disasters. The FCC must publish a list of approved providers online.

Additionally, the bill provides protections for authorized users of the spectrum. For example, a provider with FCC approval to provide emergency services to an area under this bill may only access the spectrum if (1) the entity that is typically authorized to use it expressly consents in writing to the approved provider's use, and (2) the approved provider's use does not interfere with the authorized entity's use. Authorized entities that receive a request for consent must reasonably engage with the provider submitting the request.

The bill also limits the liability of an approved provider for certain harms resulting from the transmission of (or failure to transmit) emergency alerts or the release of subscriber information when delivering an alert.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-39</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
