<bill session="111" type="s" number="2793" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:05Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SURE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for clarification on the use of funds relating to certain homeland security grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening and Updating Resources and Equipment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SURE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2009-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2009-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11495"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11495" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3837" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-02T17:10:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening and Updating Resources and Equipment Act or the SURE Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act to permit grants awarded under the State Homeland Security Grant Program or the Urban Area Security Initiative to be used for maintenance agreements, user fees, or sustainment costs for purchased equipment related to preventing, preparing for, protecting against, and responding to acts of terrorism.

Prohibits the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) from imposing: (1) a limit on the amount of any such award that may be used to pay for equipment purchase and maintenance costs; and (2) any additional limitation, including any fiscal year limitation, on the amount of any such award that may be used for a specific type, purpose, or category of equipment purchase or maintenance cost.</summary>
</bill>
