<bill session="116" type="h" number="2820" updated="2022-11-01T06:17:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dream Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain individuals who are long-term United States residents and entered the United States as children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Dream Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dream Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000486"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-98.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-30" calendar="Union" number="73">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 73.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2821" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="874" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-12T13:46:50Z" status="Reported to House">Dream Act of 2019 

This bill provides certain aliens with a path to receive permanent resident status and contains other immigration-related provisions.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) or the Department of Justice (DOJ) shall provide conditional permanent resident status for 10 years to a qualifying alien who entered the United States as a minor and (1) is deportable or inadmissible, or (2) has deferred enforced departure status or temporary protected status. The bill imposes various qualifying requirements, such as the alien being continuously physically present in the United States since four years before this bill's enactment, passing a background check, and being enrolled in or having completed certain educational programs.

DHS shall remove the conditions placed on permanent resident status granted under this bill if the alien applies and meets certain requirements, such as completing certain programs at an educational institution, serving in the military, or being employed.

An alien shall have the right to administrative and judicial review of the denial or revocation of an immigration status granted under this bill. Furthermore, an alien shall be appointed counsel upon request when seeking judicial review of a provisional denial of an application for permanent resident status under this bill.

DHS may not use information from applications filed under this bill or for Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals status for immigration enforcement purposes.

DHS shall establish a grant program for nonprofit organizations that assist individuals with certain immigration-related issues.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-98</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
