<bill session="117" type="h" number="1107" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PLAN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure the ability to enforce State and local law relating to leasing and renting of real property, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Local Authority and Neighborhoods Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000396" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2021-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-03T17:17:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Local Authority and Neighborhoods Act or the PLAN Act

This bill limits liability protection that applies to a provider of an interactive computer service that facilitates the lease or rental of real property (e.g., Airbnb) in violation of a state law or contractual agreement, such as a lease provision prohibiting short-term rentals.

Current law protects providers and users of such services from liability for information provided by third parties, subject to specified exceptions. This bill removes that protection for providers that facilitate certain real estate transactions if the provider (1) receives written notice that a lease or rental violates a law or contractual agreement, and (2) subsequently facilitates the lease or rental in a manner restricted by the applicable law or contractual agreement.

The bill also expressly preserves the authority of a state or locality to enforce laws that restrict a provider of an interactive computer service from booking, or providing ancillary services for, a transaction for the lease or rental of real property.</summary>
</bill>
