<bill session="118" type="h" number="5409" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding American Farms from Foreign Influence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Safeguarding American Farms from Foreign Influence Act</title>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding American Farms from Foreign Influence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Defense Production Act of 1950 to require the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to determine whether a national security review is needed for reportable agricultural land transactions referred by the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001135" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2023-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 44 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-801, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-05">
      <text>House Committee on Foreign Affairs Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Dec. 19, 2024.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-05">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Dec. 19, 2024.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Affairs discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-19" calendar="Union" number="782">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 782.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Unknown, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Unknown, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-07T13:34:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding American Farms from Foreign Influence Act

This bill requires the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) to determine whether a national security review is necessary for reportable agricultural land transactions that are referred by the Department of Agriculture (USDA). (CFIUS oversees the national security risks of certain foreign investment in the United States. CFIUS has the authority to review covered transactions, which include&#160;mergers, acquisitions, and takeovers that could result in foreign control of a U.S. business; certain noncontrolling investments in businesses involved in critical technologies, critical infrastructure, or sensitive personal data; and certain real estate transactions. The President may, at the recommendation of CFIUS, suspend or prohibit transactions that threaten to impair U.S. national security.)

Specifically, the bill directs CFIUS to, within 30 days of receiving notification from USDA, determine (1) whether a reportable agricultural land transaction is a covered transaction, and (2) whether CFIUS should initiate a national security review or take another action with respect to the transaction.&#160;

Under this bill, reportable agricultural land transaction means a transaction (1) that USDA has reason to believe is a covered transaction; (2) that involves the acquisition of an interest in agricultural land by a foreign person, other than by a foreign person of an excepted foreign state or an excepted real estate foreign state, as such terms are defined in CFIUS regulations; and (3) with respect to which a foreign person is required to submit a report to USDA regarding their agricultural land transactions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-801</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
