<bill session="111" type="s" number="3775" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:25Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prostate Research, Outreach, Screening, Testing, Access, and Treatment Effectiveness Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve prostate cancer screening and treatment, particularly in medically underserved communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROSTATE Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prostate Research, Outreach, Screening, Testing, Access, and Treatment Effectiveness Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2010-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="6389" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-20T12:52:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prostate Research, Outreach, Screening, Testing, Access, and Treatment Effectiveness Act of 2010 or the PROSTATE Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish the Interagency Prostate Cancer Coordination and Education Task Force to coordinate federal activities relating to prostate cancer, including by: (1) developing a summary of advances in federal prostate cancer research and a list of best practices for treatment of prostate cancer that warrant broader adoption in health care programs; (2) coordinating information on federal research and health care program activities relating to prostate cancer; (3) developing a comprehensive interagency strategy on, and advising agencies in, the solicitation of proposals for collaborative, multidisciplinary research and health care programs relating to prostate cancer; and (4) developing a coordinated message related to screening and treatment for prostate cancer to be reflected in educational and beneficiary materials for federal health programs.

Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and carry out a program to coordinate and intensify prostate cancer research, including by: (1) carrying out research to develop advances in improved early detection, diagnostic, and prognostic methods and tests; (2) carrying out research to better understand the etiology of prostate cancer to improve prevention efforts; (3) expanding basic research into prostate cancer; and (4) establishing clinical registries for prostate cancer.

Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Defense (DOD), and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to incorporate prostate cancer prevention, diagnosis, and treatment for medically underserved populations into the telehealth programs of their departments, including by: (1) giving priority to populations in medically underserved areas and in rural and highly rural areas; (2) promoting the efficient use of specialist care; and (3) more effectively employing tumor boards to better counsel patients.

Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) carry out a national education campaign to encourage men to seek prostate cancer prevention, diagnosis, and treatment when appropriate; and (2) award grants to private nonprofit organizations to test alternative outreach and education strategies.</summary>
</bill>
