<bill session="117" type="h" number="6976" updated="2022-12-29T21:48:15Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Landings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Landings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve technology and address human factors in aviation safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-16T15:16:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Landings Act

This bill addresses technology needs and safety risks in the aviation industry.

Among other things, the bill

 requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to develop technology for a cockpit system that provides an alert to pilots when an airplane is not aligned to land on an intended runway surface, creates an FAA Task Force on Human Factors in Aviation Safety to review and provide recommendations related to aviation safety, directs the Department of Transportation to establish a program to investigate and develop new approaches to data analysis for understanding the factors in aviation safety incidents and identifying emerging risks of future safety incidents, requires the FAA to gather data and report on the use of instrument approach procedures as backup for visual approaches and issue guidance on the most effective techniques to use for such procedures, and directs the FAA to reform and update the notices to airmen (NOTAM) system.</summary>
</bill>
