<bill session="116" type="h" number="5039" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:32Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Life-Sustaining Prescription Drug Price Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To lower the prices of excessively costly life-sustaining prescription drugs under part D of the Medicare program by requiring the Secretary of Health and Human Services to negotiate their prices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Life-Sustaining Prescription Drug Price Relief Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8836"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-03T21:11:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Life-Sustaining Prescription Drug Price Relief Act of 2019

This bill establishes a series of oversight and disclosure requirements relating to the prices of life-sustaining prescription drugs. Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to review at least annually all life-sustaining drugs for excessive pricing; HHS must also review prices upon petition. HHS must create a public database with its determinations for each drug and report its overall findings and related activities.

Under the bill, a price is considered excessive if the domestic average manufacturing price exceeds 110% of the average price for the drug in Canada, the United Kingdom, Germany, France, and Japan. If a price does not meet this criteria, or if pricing information is unavailable in at least three of the aforementioned countries, the price is still considered excessive if it is higher than reasonable in light of specified factors, including cost, revenue, and the size of the affected patient population.

The bill also requires drug manufacturers, subject to civil penalties, to (1) report specified financial information for life-sustaining drugs, including research and advertising expenditures; and (2) negotiate the prices of excessively priced life-sustaining drugs under the Medicare prescription drug benefit with HHS.</summary>
</bill>
