<bill session="118" type="h" number="5046" updated="2025-11-19T04:21:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Election Subversion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Election Subversion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to provide increased protections for election workers and voters in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2023-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="11" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2344" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2575" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-02T19:57:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Election Subversion Act of 2023

This bill prohibits the removal or suspension of local election administrators except for specified reasons and sets forth additional requirements for federal elections.

Specifically, the bill restricts the ability of a statewide election administrator to remove a local election administrator. A statewide election administrator may suspend, remove, or relieve the duties of a local election administrator only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance while in office.

Further, the bill directs statewide election administrators to report any removals or suspensions of local election administrators to the Department of Justice.

 The bill also establishes certain requirements for challenging an individual's eligibility to register to vote or vote in federal elections. In particular, the bill prohibits any person (other than an election official) from challenging an individual's voting eligibility unless the challenge is supported by personal knowledge.</summary>
</bill>
