<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="657" updated="2022-02-03T06:10:40Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5136" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2010-05-27T17:11:29-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001146"/>
  <offered datetime="2010-05-27"/>
  <description>Page 122, after line 18, insert the following:    SEC. 359. SENSE OF CONGRESS REGARDING FIRE-RESISTANT UTILITY ENSEMBLES FOR NATIONAL GUARD PERSONNEL IN CIVIL AUTHORITY MISSIONS.    It is the sense of Congress that the Chief of the National Guard Bureau should issue fire-resistant utility ensembles to National Guard personnel who are engaged, or likely to become engaged, in defense support to civil authority missions that routinely involve serious fire hazards, such as wildfire recovery efforts.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in House Report 111-498 to express the sense of Congress that the Chief of the National Guard Bureau should issue fire-resistant utility ensembles to National Guard personnel who are engaged, or likely to become engaged, in defense support to civil authority missions that routinely involve serious fire hazards, such as wildfire recovery efforts.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2010-05-27T17:11:29-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="311">
      <text>On agreeing to the Marshall amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 423 - 0 (Roll no. 311).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T14:42:18-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Marshall.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3988-3990, H4013-4014" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3988" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T14:42:18-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Marshall.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3988-3990, H4013-4014" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3988" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T17:11:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T17:11:29-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27T17:11:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Marshall amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 423 - 0 (Roll no. 311).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
