<bill session="110" type="s" number="2359" updated="2023-01-11T14:50:57Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2007-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-539.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="982">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 982.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="4258" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-06T19:40:12Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission Act of 2008 - Establishes the St. Augustine 450th Commemoration Commission to plan and carry out programs and activities to commemorate the 450th anniversary of the founding of St. Augustine, Florida.

Sets forth provisions regarding the membership, duties, meetings, powers, and personnel matters of the Commission.

Requires the Commission to: (1) prepare a strategic plan for the activities of the Commission carried out under this Act; and (2) submit a final report that contains a summary of the Commission's activities, a final accounting of funds received and spent by the Commission, and the findings and recommendations of the Commission.

Authorizes appropriations to the Commission to carry out this Act for FY2009-FY2015 and makes such amounts available until December 31, 2015.

Terminates the Commission on December 31, 2015. Directs the Commission, before such termination date, to transfer all documents and materials of the Commission to the National Archives or another appropriate federal entity.</summary>
</bill>
