<bill session="115" type="s" number="2359" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:51Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DHS Joint Requirements Council Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Joint Requirements Council in the Department of Homeland Security.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Joint Requirements Council Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-10T18:25:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DHS Joint Requirements Council Act of 2018

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish leadership councils to ensure coordination and improve programs and activities of the department.

DHS must establish a Joint Requirements Council within the department to:

 identify, assess, and validate joint requirements to meet mission needs; ensure that appropriate efficiencies are made among life-cycle cost, schedule, performance, and procurement quantity objectives in the establishment and approval of joint requirements; and make prioritized capability recommendations for the joint requirements. A "joint requirement" is a condition or capability of multiple operating components of DHS that is required to be met or possessed by a system, product, service, result, or component to satisfy a contract, standard, specification, or other formally imposed document.</summary>
</bill>
