<bill session="118" type="hr" number="906" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-05T14:24:18-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-05T14:24:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4468) to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing a proposed rule with respect to emissions from vehicles, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5933) to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional information in disclosures of foreign gifts and contracts from foreign sources, restrict contracts with certain foreign entities and foreign countries of concern, require certain staff and faculty to report foreign gifts and contracts, and require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments; and providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H. J. Res. 88) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Department of Education relating to "Improving Income Driven Repayment for the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program and the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) Program".</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4468) to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing a proposed rule with respect to emissions from vehicles, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5933) to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional information in disclosures of foreign gifts and contracts from foreign sources, restrict contracts with certain foreign entities and foreign countries of concern, require certain staff and faculty to report foreign gifts and contracts, and require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments; and providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H. J. Res. 88) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Department of Education relating to "Improving Income Driven Repayment for the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program and the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) Program".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001093"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-298, by Mrs. Houchin.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04T17:52:31-05:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4468 and H.R. 5933 under a structured rule and H.J. Res. 88 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-04" calendar="House" number="52">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 52.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05T12:16:13-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6120-6127" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05T12:20:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 906.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05T13:09:06-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 906, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05T13:33:04-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6127-6129" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05T14:16:24-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 209 - 200 (Roll no. 692).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="693" datetime="2023-12-05T14:24:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 213 - 201 (Roll no. 693).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6120" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05T14:24:21-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4468" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5933" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hj" number="88" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-14T17:57:10Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4468) to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing a proposed rule with respect to emissions from vehicles, and for other purposes.

Further, it provides for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5933) to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional information in disclosures of foreign gifts and contracts from foreign sources, restrict contracts with certain foreign entities and foreign countries of concern, require certain staff and faculty to report foreign gifts and contracts, and require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments;.

Finally, it provides for consideration of the joint resolution (H. J. Res. 88) providing for congressional disapproval of the rule submitted by the Department of Education titled Improving Income Driven Repayment for the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program and the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-298</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
