<bill session="116" type="s" number="1309" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to identify and combat corruption in countries, to establish a tiered system of countries with respect to levels of corruption by their governments and their efforts to combat such corruption, and to assess United States assistance to designated countries in order to advance anti-corruption efforts in those countries and better serve United States taxpayers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2019-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Risch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="144">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7234-7236" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2019-12-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-23T11:03:05-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1275"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-03-02T15:26:21Z" status="Passed Senate">This bill requires the Department of State to develop a program to combat corruption in countries that receive U.S. aid.

The State Department shall annually report to Congress a tiered list of all countries that receive certain U.S. foreign assistance. The first tier shall contain countries that meet minimum standards for combatting public corruption, while the second tier shall contain countries that do not comply but are making significant efforts to do so. Third-tier countries do not meet the minimum anti-corruption standards and are not making significant efforts to do so.

For each second- and third-tier ranked country, the State Department shall (1) include a corruption risk assessment and mitigation strategy in each country's integrated country strategy, and (2) use appropriate anti-corruption mechanisms. Such mechanisms include requiring the disclosure of the beneficial ownership of contractors and partners involved in State Department programs and requiring claw-back provisions to recover misappropriated funds.

The State Department shall designate an anti-corruption point of contact in the U.S. diplomatic post in each second- or third-tier country and where the State Department determines that such a point of contact is necessary. The point of contact shall be responsible for coordinating a whole-of-government approach to enhancing the ability of foreign countries to combat public corruption.</summary>
</bill>
