<bill session="108" type="s" number="768" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:14Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Senior Executive Service Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for reform of the Senior Executive Service, adjustment in the rates of pay of certain positions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Executive Service Reform Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000888" joined="2003-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA03" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Senior Executive Service Reform Act of 2003 - Establishes level II of the Executive Schedule as the maximum annual rate of pay, including comparability pay adjustments, for Senior Executive Service (SES) positions, including positions in the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Drug Enforcement Administration.Requires establishment of a range of rates of basic pay for the SES, requiring each senior executive to be paid at one of such rates based on individual performance, contribution to the agency's performance, or both. Provides a minimum and maximum rates.Provides pay rate increases for administrative law judges, Contract Appeals Board members, and certain senior level positions by raising the Executive Schedule level on which their pay is based.Removes the authority for the appointment of limited emergency appointees. Sets duration limits for limited appointees, allowing the Office of Personnel Management to exceed such limits in rare circumstances. Outlines reemployment rights and reassignment and transfer authority for limited appointees.Provides one day of annual leave for each full biweekly pay period for positions classified above GS-15, senior executives, and any employee with a minimum rate of basic pay greater than the GS-15, step 10 rate.</summary>
</bill>
