<bill session="109" type="s" number="1257" updated="2019-11-15T21:56:08Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify that persons may bring private rights of actions against foreign states for certain terrorist acts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify that persons may bring private rights of actions against foreign states for certain terrorist acts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2005-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6746-6747"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6747" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="865" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Marines"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-07-11T19:23:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act of 1976 (FSIA) to require that a foreign state designated as a state sponsor of terrorism under specified laws, or an official, employee, or agent of such a foreign state, shall be liable to a U.S. national for the national's personal injury or death caused by acts of that state or official, employee, or agent acting within the scope of his or her duties.

Provides that the removal of a foreign state from designation as a state sponsor of terrorism shall not terminate such a cause of action arising during the period of designation.

 Authorizes U.S. courts to exercise jurisdiction over such actions for money damages under an FSIA provision concerning acts of torture, extrajudicial killing, aircraft sabotage, hostage taking, and material support for such acts. Mandates that property interests of foreign states, or agencies or instrumentalities of foreign states, against which judgment is entered pursuant to such provision are subject to attachment execution.

Requires foreign states to be held vicariously liable for the actions of their officials, employees, or agents.

Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (VCA) to modify the definition of "victim" for purposes of compensation under that Act. Requires the transfer of VCA funds to carry out an order appointing Special Masters in the matter of Peterson, et al. v. The Islamic Republic of Iran.

Revives previously dismissed causes of action that would be cognizable under this Act by retroactively tolling the applicable statute of limitations from the date of initial filing to 60 days after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
