<bill session="117" type="h" number="7959" updated="2023-08-09T19:15:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NO VOTE for Noncitizens Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NO VOTE for Noncitizens Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Noncitizens: Outlawed from Voting in Our Trusted Elections Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to clarify the authority of States to remove noncitizens from voting rolls and to require States to maintain separate voter registration lists for noncitizens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8528" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-09T19:04:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Noncitizens: Outlawed from Voting in Our Trusted Elections Act of 2022 or the NO VOTE for Noncitizens Act of 2022

This bill establishes additional requirements related to noncitizens and voting and addresses related issues.

Among other provisions, this bill (1) requires states to make reasonable efforts to remove noncitizens from the official eligible voter lists, (2) requires states to coordinate official registered voter lists with court records of individuals who have been recused from jury duty on the grounds that they are noncitizens, and (3) reduces election assistance to states and local jurisdictions that allow noncitizens to vote.</summary>
</bill>
