<bill session="117" type="s" number="2539" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:27Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue rules requiring the inclusion of new safety equipment in school buses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">School Bus Safety Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Bus Safety Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3381" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-20T14:20:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Bus Safety Act of 2021

This bill addresses safety features for school buses.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to implement rules requiring school buses to include

 a three-point safety belt at each designated seating position, a fire suppression system which addresses engine fires, a firewall that prohibits hazardous quantities of gas or flame to pass through the firewall from the engine compartment to the passenger compartment, an automatic emergency braking system, an event data recorder, and an electronic stability control system. DOT must also establish a grant program to assist local educational agencies to purchase school buses equipped with three-point safety belts or any of the other safety features under this bill and assist them in modifying existing school buses to be equipped with such features.</summary>
</bill>
