<bill session="116" type="h" number="8412" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Community Care Wait Time Transparency Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Community Care Wait Time Transparency Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish goals for the timely delivery of medical care and appointments, to make publicly available certain information regarding wait times under the community care program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2020-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-27T15:03:34Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Community Care Wait Time Transparency Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a goal for the maximum number of days between the date on which a veteran requests an appointment for medical care and the date on which the appointment occurs. Such a goal shall apply to medical care furnished by the VA via non-VA and VA providers for both new and returning patients.

The VA must publish on a public website the average wait times for new and returning patients seeking care under the Veterans Community Care Program (VCCP) and the percentage of appointments for care under the VCCP that occur within the number of days specified for the wait time access standard.</summary>
</bill>
