<bill session="111" type="h" number="3089" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accountability and Transparency in Medicare Marketing Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for standardized marketing requirements under the Medicare Advantage program and the Medicare Prescription Drug program and to provide for State certification prior to waiver of licensure requirements under the Medicare Prescription Drug program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability and Transparency in Medicare Marketing Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2009-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-09T18:41:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Accountability and Transparency in Medicare Marketing Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to request the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) to develop standardized marketing requirements for: (1) Medicare Advantage organizations with respect to Medicare Advantage plans; and (2) prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors with respect to Medicare PDPs. Requires such requirements to include prohibitions on certain activities and certain limitations.

Requires state certification before HHS waiver of licensing requirements under the Medicare PDP.

Directs the Secretary to request NAIC to establish a committee to study and make recommendations to the Secretary and Congress on the establishment of standardized benefit packages for Medicare Advantage plans and for Medicare PDPs and their regulation.</summary>
</bill>
