<bill session="116" type="h" number="1928" updated="2022-11-01T18:32:39Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Sanctuary for Criminals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to impose penalties for State noncompliance with enforcement of immigration law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Sanctuary for Criminals Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000827" joined="2019-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="574" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="9062" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-23T16:29:31Z" status="Introduced in House">No Sanctuary for Criminals Act of 2019

This bill bars any government entity or individual from prohibiting or restricting a government entity, official, or other personnel from (1) complying with immigration laws, (2) cooperating with immigration enforcement, (3) making inquiries to an individual to obtain immigration-related information, or (4) complying with immigration-related informational inquiries from federal law enforcement entities. States or local entities that fail to comply with such a bar shall be ineligible for certain federal funds and grants for at least one year. (Such provisions expand on current provisions barring a government entity or official from prohibiting or restricting a government entity or official from exchanging certain information with federal immigration officials.)

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may issue a detainer as to an individual in federal or state custody if DHS has probable cause to believe the individual is an inadmissible or deportable alien. (Currently, the statute allows immigration officials to issue a detainer for an individual who has been arrested for violating a controlled substance-related law if such officials have reason to believe the individual is violating immigration laws. Current DHS policy allows for the issuance of detainers in other situations as well, though this policy has been called into question by a federal district court, and this bill would provide statutory authority for the current policy.)

A victim of a felony (or certain close relatives) for which an alien has been convicted and sentenced for at least one year may sue each state or local government entity or official if the defendant (1) refused to honor an immigration-law related detainer and released the alien from custody prior to the crime, or (2) has a policy of not complying certain immigration enforcement-related laws.</summary>
</bill>
