<bill session="110" type="h" number="5292" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:05Z">
  <state datetime="2008-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To permit the Secretary of Health and Human Services to directly administer Ryan White part A and B grants for eligible areas, States, or territories that failed to make appropriate use of previous Ryan White part A and B grants.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit the Secretary of Health and Human Services to directly administer Ryan White part A and B grants for eligible areas, States, or territories that failed to make appropriate use of previous Ryan White part A and B grants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000452"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2008-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-08T15:47:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends provisions of title XXVI of the Public Health Service Act (popularly known as the Ryan White Care Act [RWCA]) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to administer certain RWCA grants in lieu of the chief elected official of an eligible area or state if the Secretary determines that the eligible area or state has substantially failed to make appropriate use of such grants during either of the two previous fiscal years.

Provides that the Secretary is not authorized to administer any such grant to an eligible area or state in consecutive fiscal years.

Requires the Secretary in making a determination under this Act to consider whether: (1) more than 5% of the grant funds awarded remained unobligated one year after the date on which the grant was made; (2) the eligible area or state has had additional requirements imposed on the grant under applicable federal regulations; or (3) the eligible area or state has had special conditions or restrictions imposed on the grant.

Allows the Secretary to delegate to a federal instrumentality or private entity the authority to administer such grant.</summary>
</bill>
