<bill session="118" type="s" number="2979" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">India Shrimp Tariff Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">India Shrimp Tariff Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the rate of duty on shrimp originating from India, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-02T19:32:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">India Shrimp Tariff Act

This bill addresses shrimp imports from India, including by phasing in an increased rate of duty for shrimp and prawns originating from India.

Specifically, the bill requires the general rate of duty for shrimp and prawns originating from India to be (1) 10% for 2024, (2) 20% for 2025, and (2) 40% for 2026 and after. The Office of the U.S. Trade Representative must take the necessary steps to modify the Schedule of Concessions to accommodate the increase in the rate of duty applicable under this bill. (Each World Trade Organization member country has its own Schedule of Concessions on goods. These schedules are legal instruments that describe the treatment a member country must provide to the trade of other members.)

Additionally, the bill eliminates the exemption of&#160;cooked shrimp and crawfish (both cooked whole and in sections) from country-of-origin labeling (COOL) requirements. (COOL is a labeling law that requires retailers, such as full-line grocery stores, supermarkets, and club warehouse stores, to notify their customers of information regarding the source of certain foods.) Further, the Department of Agriculture must modify its regulations to ensure that these cooked products are not considered processed food items.</summary>
</bill>
