<bill session="110" type="h" number="829" updated="2023-01-11T20:01:03Z">
  <state datetime="2007-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Power Act to make certain changes in provisions relating to National Interest Transmission Corridors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Interest Electric Transmission Corridor Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Interest Electric Transmission Corridor Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000672"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001065" joined="2007-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2007-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000136" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2007-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000472" joined="2007-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2007-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2007-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E256-257"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Underground construction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-03T20:40:46Z" status="Introduced in House">National Interest Electric Transmission Corridor Clarification Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to revise the factors the Secretary of Energy may consider in determining whether to designate a national interest electric transmission corridor.

Authorizes the Secretary to consider whether the designation would have potential impacts on natural values and special places considered to be in the national interest. Repeals authority to consider whether designation would serve U.S. energy independence.

Directs the Secretary, before a corridor designation, to analyze all alternatives measures that could address energy transmission constraints or congestion.

Prohibits a corridor designation from encompassing, within one mile of their respective boundaries, lands on which development is prohibited or limited to protect scenic, natural, cultural, or historic resources.

Revises conditions for issuance of permits by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) for construction or modification of electric transmission facilities in such a corridor. Requires that a state commission or other state entity with authority to approve facility siting has: (1) disapproved the siting in a decision that FERC considers an abuse of discretion; or (2) unreasonably withheld or delayed making a decision for at least a year.

Requires each permit application to include an engineering study of the feasibility of placing the line underground.

Requires treatment as a taking for which just compensation is due of a diminution of 10% or more in any property value resulting from acquisition of a right-of-way and the construction of a facility on it.

Requires each agency to issue its own record of decision in order to ensure that its environmental review complies with statutory mandates and regulatory requirements.

Repeals any right to appeal to the President an agency denial or failure to act regarding federal authorization for a transmission facility.</summary>
</bill>
