<bill session="118" type="h" number="6636" updated="2025-11-19T04:04:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Woman&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Right To Know Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Woman&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Right To Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that women seeking an abortion are notified, before giving informed consent to receive an abortion, of the medical risks associated with the abortion procedure and the major developmental characteristics of the unborn child.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2023-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2023-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H6825"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1126" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7044" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3609" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-24T23:45:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Woman's Right To Know Act

This bill requires health care providers to perform an ultrasound and obtain certain informed consent before performing an abortion procedure.

Specifically, before performing an abortion, providers must first perform an ultrasound and share the results with the woman, and also present the woman with an authorization form at least 24 hours before performing the abortion procedure. The form must (1) include specified information concerning gestational age, associated developmental characteristics,&#160;and medical risks; (2) include a statement that an ultrasound has been performed and the results were shared with the woman; (3) disclose penalties&#160;that&#160;providers may face for failing to comply with the bill's requirements; and (4) include an affirmation that the individual signing the form understands the information. The form must be signed and witnessed in person and retained in the medical file.

The bill's requirements do not apply if, in reasonable medical judgment, compliance would pose a greater risk of death or substantial physical impairment of a major bodily function, excluding psychological or emotional conditions, of the pregnant woman.

The bill also establishes civil penalties for providers who do not comply with these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
