<bill session="111" type="h" number="311" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:54Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Spending Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To cap discretionary spending, eliminate wasteful and duplicative agencies, reform entitlement programs, and reform the congressional earmark process.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spending Reform Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000755"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000358" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001239" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001062" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000550" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001036" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000289" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000220" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2009-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2010-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2009-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="393" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="534" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="General taxation matters"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-17T15:12:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Spending Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the concurrent budget resolution to include discretionary spending limit for five successive fiscal years.

Sets forth points of order against consideration of legislation in Congress (currently, only the Senate) that would exceed for any fiscal year discretionary spending limit established in the most recent concurrent budget resolution for that fiscal year (currently, the Balanced Budget and Deficit Control Act of 1985 [Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act]).

Makes such point of order inapplicable if a declaration of war by Congress is in effect.

Sets forth points of orders for consideration of certain concurrent budget resolutions. Establishes discretionary spending limit for FY2010 as the number set forth in the FY2010 budget resolution.

Permits waivers or suspension of such requirements, or successful appeals from rulings of the Chair, only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths (60) of the Senate.

Establishes the Federal Agency Sunset Commission to review and report to Congress on the efficiency and public need for each federal agency, recommending abolishment or reorganization.

Provides for relocation of federal employees if their agency is abolished.

Requires the Comptroller General and the Director of Congressional Budget Office (CBO), in cooperation with the Director of the Congressional Research Service (CRS), to inventory federal programs to advise and assist Congress and the Commission in carrying out such requirements.

Establishes a Joint Select Committee on Earmark Reform.

Sets forth a point of order against consideration of legislation containing a congressional earmark or limited tax or tariff benefit.

Establishes the Securing America's Future Economy Commission to examine the long-term fiscal challenges facing the United States and develop legislation designed to address specified issues. Authorizes the President and the House and Senate Budget Committees to propose alternative legislation.

Requires the long-term CBO cost estimate of such proposals to be published in the Congressional Record.</summary>
</bill>
