<bill session="117" type="h" number="9325" updated="2022-12-29T13:48:54Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EQUAL Defense Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Quality Access to Legal Defense Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EQUAL Defense Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To incentivize States and localities to improve access to justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2022-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2022-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1408" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-05T20:15:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Quality Access to Legal Defense Act of 2022 or the EQUAL Defense Act of 2022 

 This bill establishes and modifies certain programs that support the delivery of public defense services (i.e., legal services for criminal defendants who cannot afford counsel).

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to state and local governments, tribal organizations, and public defender offices for public defense. A grant recipient must use the grant to establish a data collection process, develop workload limits, and satisfy specified compensation requirements (e.g., pay parity between public defenders and prosecutors).

The bill also directs DOJ to award grants to nonprofits and government organizations to train public defenders, court-appointed attorneys, and contract attorneys.

Additionally, a state that receives Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program funds must annually submit to DOJ information related to the legal representation of defendants in criminal cases.

Finally, it reauthorizes through FY2026 the student loan repayment program for prosecutors and public defenders and otherwise revises the program, including by increasing the maximum benefit amount.</summary>
</bill>
