<bill session="118" type="s" number="2698" updated="2025-11-19T03:31:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agricultural Emergency Relief Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Emergency Relief Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a program to provide payments to producers experiencing certain crop losses as a result of a disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2023-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3764-3765" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5057" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-05T14:49:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agricultural Emergency Relief Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish an Emergency Relief Program to provide payments each crop year to producers that experience a qualified loss as a result of a disaster that occurred during the crop year. (Under current law, USDA provides payments under a temporary Emergency Relief Program for losses that occurred following disasters&#160;in 2020, 2021, or 2022.)

The bill defines a qualified loss as&#160;a loss incurred by a producer in a crop, trees, bushes, or vines as a consequence of a disaster (i.e., a drought, wildfire, hurricane, flood, derecho, excessive heat, excessive moisture, a winter storm, and a freeze event,&#160;including a polar vortex). Further, a qualified loss includes a loss incurred as a result of being prevented from planting a crop due to a disaster and a loss in the quality of a crop, trees, bushes, or vines due to a disaster or smoke exposure from a wildfire.

As a condition of receiving a payment under this program, a producer must purchase (for the next two years)&#160;Federal Crop Insurance or, if Federal Crop Insurance is&#160;not available, coverage under the Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program.

An eligible&#160;producer under the program is an individual or entity that is eligible to receive assistance under a Farm Service Agency administered disaster assistance program. The bill specifies that a producer does not include a joint venture or a general partnership.</summary>
</bill>
