<bill session="117" type="h" number="2016" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-15T13:50:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-06-15T13:50:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Disaster Recovery Reform Act of 2018 to develop a study regarding streamlining and consolidating information collection and preliminary damage assessments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2021-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 117-46.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-05-28" calendar="Union" number="29">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 29.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T13:36:09-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Norton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T13:36:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2769-2771" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T13:36:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-06-15T13:50:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2769" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T13:50:33-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-27T12:58:06Z" status="Passed House">Federal Disaster Assistance Coordination Act

This bill extends the deadline by which the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must (1) conduct a study and develop a plan under which the collection of information from disaster assistance applicants and grantees will be made less burdensome, duplicative, and time consuming for applicants and grantees; and (2) develop a plan for the regular collection and reporting of information on federal disaster assistance awarded.

Not later than two years after enactment of this bill, FEMA shall convene a working group on a regular basis to identify (1) potential areas of duplication or fragmentation in preliminary damage assessments after disaster declarations; and (2) potential emerging technologies, such as Unmanned Aircraft Systems (i.e., drones), to expedite the administration of preliminary damage assessments.

FEMA must submit a comprehensive report on the plans for streamlining and consolidating information collection and preliminary damage assessments and the findings and recommendations of the working group to Congress with a briefing. The report must be made available to the public and posted on FEMA's website.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-46</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
