<bill session="116" type="s" number="1898" updated="2022-11-01T13:51:01Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MERIT Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MERIT Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modern Employment Reform, Improvement, and Transformation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for an alternative removal for performance or misconduct for Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2019-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2019-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2019-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2019-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2019-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3348" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-28T18:15:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Modern Employment Reform, Improvement, and Transformation Act of 2019 or the MERIT Act of 2019

This bill revises provisions related to federal employment, including the furlough and removal of federal employees, the calculation of federal employee retirement benefits, and the length of the probationary employment period.

Specifically, the bill repeals the process for taking action against a federal employee for unacceptable performance, accelerates the process for removal or suspension based on performance or actions, and prohibits grievances based on adverse personnel actions and reductions in force. The bill also authorizes an agency to remove a senior executive from the civil service for performance-related reasons, and it revises provisions covering performance- or conduct-related actions against senior executives.

The bill authorizes agencies to furlough employees for such cause as will promote the efficiency of the service, and it prohibits appeals to the Merit Systems Protection Board based on short-term furloughs or furloughs due to a lapse in appropriations (i.e., government shutdown).

Additionally, the bill limits the retirement benefits of a federal employee who is removed due to a felony conviction related to their official duties by prohibiting felonious service from being taken into account when calculating the employee's annuity.

The bill also authorizes an agency to order the repayment of a bonus or award when performance or conduct issues are discovered and such bonus or award would not have been paid had such issues been known when they were made.

Lastly, the bill extends from one year to two years the probationary period for competitive service appointments and members of the Senior Executive Service.</summary>
</bill>
