<bill session="118" type="s" number="502" updated="2025-11-19T02:58:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy Dog Importation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Dog Importation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Animal Health Protection Act with respect to the importation of live dogs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2024-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2024-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2024-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2023-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1184" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T10:40:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Healthy Dog Importation Act 

This bill imposes requirements on the importation of live dogs.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the importation of a live dog into the United States unless the Department of Agriculture (USDA) determines the dog (1) is in good health; (2) has received all necessary vaccinations, internal and external parasite treatment, and demonstrated negative test results as evidenced by a certificate from a licensed veterinarian; and (3) is officially identified by a permanent method approved by USDA. Additionally, dogs entering the United States for transfer must be at least six months of age and accompanied by a USDA permit. Transfer is defined as a change of ownership or control of an imported dog to another person, including by sale, adoption, exchange, or donation.

USDA must provide an exception to any requirements under the bill for dogs that are transferred for (1) research purposes; (2) veterinary treatment under certain conditions, including appropriate quarantining; or (3) lawful importation into the state of Hawaii if the dog is not transported out of Hawaii for transfer at less than six months of age.

USDA also has enforcement authority under the bill.</summary>
</bill>
