<bill session="118" type="h" number="1219" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food and Agriculture Industry Cybersecurity Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food and Agriculture Industry Cybersecurity Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a food and agriculture cybersecurity clearinghouse in the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2023-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2393" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-28T15:16:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Food and Agriculture Industry Cybersecurity Support Act

This bill requires the establishment of a clearinghouse for food and agriculture cybersecurity resources and the development of related best practices recommendations.

Specifically, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) must establish a publicly available clearinghouse that contains current food and agriculture industry focused cybersecurity resources.

Further, the NTIA must develop voluntary cybersecurity recommendations relating to the development, maintenance, and operation of the food and agriculture industry. The recommendations must be based on a consolidation of public and private sector best practices and be included in the NTIA clearinghouse. The recommendations must also include, to the greatest extent practicable, materials that address (1) risk-based, cybersecurity-informed engineering; (2) planning for retention or recovery of positive control of systems in the event of a cybersecurity incident; (3) protection against unauthorized access to critical functions of the industry; and (4) plans for how industry businesses should respond to ransomware attacks.

The Government Accountability Office must coordinate a study on actions the federal government has taken or may take to improve cybersecurity in the food and agriculture industry.</summary>
</bill>
