<bill session="111" type="s" number="592" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:11Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Community Radio Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the recommendations of the Federal Communications Commission report to the Congress regarding low-power FM service.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Local Community Radio Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Community Radio Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2010-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-160.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="310">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 310.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1147" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="6533" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-07T16:30:08Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Local Community Radio Act of 2009 - Repeals provisions in the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001 that required the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to: (1) modify rules authorizing the operation of low-power FM radio stations to prescribe minimum distance separations for third-adjacent channels; (2) prohibit applicants who have engaged in the unlicensed operation of any station from obtaining a low-power FM license; and (3) conduct a program to test whether low-power FM radio stations will result in harmful interference to existing FM radio stations if minimum distance separations for third-adjacent channels are not required.

Requires the FCC to modify the rules authorizing the operation of low-power FM radio stations, as proposed, to prohibit any applicant from obtaining a low-power FM license if the applicant has engaged in any manner in the unlicensed operation of a station.

Requires the FCC to modify its rules to eliminate third-adjacent minimum distance separation requirements between specified FM stations.

Requires the FCC to retain rules that provide third-adjacent channel protection for full-power noncommercial FM stations that broadcast radio reading services via a subcarrier frequency from potential low-power FM station interference.

Requires the FCC, when licensing FM translator stations, to ensure that: (1) licenses are available to both FM translator stations and low-power FM stations; and (2) such decisions are made based on the needs of the local community.

Requires the FCC to conduct an economic study on the impact that low-power FM stations will have on full-power commercial FM stations.

Requires the FCC to retain its rules that provide third-adjacent channel protection for full-power FM stations that are licensed in significantly populated states with more than three million housing units and a population density greater than 1,000 per square mile land area.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-160</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
