<bill session="108" type="s" number="1055" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide physicians and other health care professionals with a tax credit for qualified expenditures for medical professional malpractice insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide physicians and other health care professionals with a tax credit for qualified expenditures for medical professional malpractice insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2003-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a business tax credit for medical professional malpractice insurance according to the following schedule: (1) 20 percent of expenditures for any physician who practices in any surgical specialty or subspecialty, emergency medicine, obstetrics, anesthesiology, or who does intervention work which is reflected in medical malpractice insurance expenditures; (2) ten percent of expenditures for any physician who practices in general medicine, allergy, dermatology, or pathology; and (3) 15 percent of expenditures for any hospital or clinic.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, to make grants to eligible nonprofit hospitals and clinics to pay 15 percent of qualified medical malpractice insurance costs.</summary>
</bill>
