<bill session="117" type="h" number="9393" updated="2023-08-31T21:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Court Authority Over Litigation Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Court Authority Over Litigation Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect State and Federal courts' primary and inherent authority to regulate and oversee the legal profession by prohibiting Federal agencies from regulating licensed attorneys and law firms engaged in litigation activities, prohibiting opposing parties in legal actions from bringing private rights of action against such attorneys and law firms for their litigation activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001195"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-31T21:36:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Court Authority Over Litigation Act of 2022 

This bill specifies that a federal agency does not have supervisory, enforcement, or regulatory authority over the litigation activities of attorneys or law firms. In addition, the bill prohibits a person from bringing a civil action in a court of the United States for harm due to alleged misconduct related to the litigation activities of an opposing attorney or law firm.</summary>
</bill>
