<bill session="118" type="h" number="3112" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Hungry Kids in Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Hungry Kids in Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish statewide community eligibility for certain special assistance payments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2024-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001220" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2024-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2024-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2023-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-26T18:29:25Z" status="Introduced in House">No Hungry Kids in Schools Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture&#160;(USDA) to establish an option for states to utilize a statewide Community Eligibility Provision (CEP) for USDA school meal programs. (The CEP allows eligible schools, groups of schools, and school districts the option to offer free breakfast and lunch to all enrolled students without collecting household applications.)

Specifically, USDA must establish a statewide CEP option that may be used by a state agency. The state agency must provide state (nonfederal) funding to local educational agencies to reimburse applicable schools at the free reimbursement rate for 100% of the meals served.

Eligibility for the statewide CEP must be based on a statewide calculation of the percentage of identified enrolled students, regardless of a school's local educational agency. Further, the bill lowers the CEP participation threshold for a statewide CEP to an identified student percentage (ISP) of zero, from 40%. The ISP is the percentage of students who are eligible for free school meals without a household application, primarily those who are directly certified through the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP).

In&#160;addition, the bill specifies that the reimbursement multiplier for school meals remains at the current level of 1.6. The reimbursement multiplier is used to calculate how many meals will be reimbursed at the free meal rate.</summary>
</bill>
