<bill session="108" type="s" number="749" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:14Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Votes for Women History Trail Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish the Votes for Women History Trail in the State of New York.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Votes for Women History Trail Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4631"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Women's voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Votes for Women History Trail Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish an automobile tour route, to be known as the Votes for Women History Trail, to link properties in New York State which are historically and thematically related to the struggle for women's suffrage. Requires the Secretary to administer the Trail through the Women's Rights National Historical Park.Requires the Secretary to: (1) produce and disseminate educational materials relating to the Trail; (2) coordinate, in partnership with properties designated as official stops, other Federal agencies, and State and local governments, the management, planning, and standards of the Trail; and (3) adopt an official symbol or device to mark the Trail and issue guidelines for its use.Authorizes the Secretary to designate as an official stop on the Trail: (1) a Park unit or program that relates to the struggle for women's suffrage; (2) a Federal, State, local, or privately owned property that has a verifiable connection to such struggle; and (3) an educational, commemorative, research, or interpretive facility or program that is directly related to such struggle. Allows the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with, and provide technical and financial assistance to, other Federal agencies, New York State, units of local government, regional governmental bodies, and private entities to coordinate such stops.</summary>
</bill>
