<bill session="119" type="h" number="1476" updated="2025-11-19T03:06:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PLASMA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLASMA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Life-saving Access to Specialty Medicines in America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide a phase-in for plasma-derived products under the manufacturer discount program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000405" joined="2025-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2025-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="694" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-05T21:30:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Preserving Life-saving Access to Specialty Medicines in America Act or the PLASMA Act

This bill phases-in certain price adjustments for plasma-derived products under the Medicare prescription drug benefit's Manufacturer Discount Program.

Current law requires manufacturers of covered drugs under the Medicare prescription drug benefit to provide a 10% discount for covered drugs during the initial coverage phase (i.e., before a beneficiary reaches the out-of-pocket spending threshold) and a 20% discount during the catastrophic coverage phase (i.e., after a beneficiary reaches the out-of-pocket spending threshold).&#160;

The bill phases-in discounts for plasma-derived products over several years, starting with a 1% discount in 2026 for both the initial and catastrophic coverage phases, and ending with a 10% discount beginning in 2030 for the initial coverage phase and a 20% discount beginning in 2032 for the catastrophic coverage phase.</summary>
</bill>
