<bill session="108" type="s" number="1727" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:20Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-03">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to authorize additional appropriations for the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize additional appropriations for the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12543"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-539.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-296.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="615">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 615.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9339-9340" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9339-9340" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:03:29-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T12:24:06-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T16:38:48-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gibbons moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T16:39:09-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9836-9837" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T16:39:12-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1727.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2004-11-17T16:41:20-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9836" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T16:41:23-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-22">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-03" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-439" type="public" datetime="2004-12-03">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-439.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4893" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2218"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-12-29T21:30:39Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 15, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to increase funding levels for projects to preserve the structural safety of Bureau of Reclamation dams and related facilities. Increases the ceiling (from $750,000 to $1.25 million) on the amount that may be obligated for dam modifications prior to 30 calendar days from the date that the Secretary of the Interior has reported on the safety of the existing dam to Congress.

Directs the Secretary: (1) during the construction of a modification of a structure under such Act, to consider cost containment measures recommended by a project beneficiary that has elected to consult with the Bureau; (2) to provide to project beneficiaries periodic notice regarding the costs and status of the modification; (3) upon identifying a Bureau facility for modification, to provide to the project beneficiaries written notice describing the need for and the process for identifying and implementing the modification and summarizing administrative and legal requirements; (4) to provide project beneficiaries an opportunity to consult with the Bureau on the planning, design, and construction of the proposed modification and to develop and provide time frames for such consultation; (5) prior to submitting required reports, to consider any alternative submitted by a project beneficiary that has elected to consult with the Bureau; and (6) to provide to the project beneficiary a timely written response of proposed actions to address the recommendation. (Requires that the Secretary's response be included in the required reports.)

Authorizes the Secretary to waive one or more of the requirements of this Act upon determining that implementation of the requirement could have an adverse impact on dam safety or security.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-296</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
