<bill session="117" type="h" number="7368" updated="2023-10-03T18:30:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to develop a program to provide assistance to creditworthy borrowers with Federal student debt in purchasing certain foreclosed homes owned by the Federal Government, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and local land banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2022-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4119"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-12T19:53:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Federal Housing Finance Agency&#160;to jointly establish and implement a pilot demonstration program to provide, to eligible applicants with federal student loan debt, assistance in purchasing eligible properties. Specifically, the program may provide for (1) discounts on the appraised value of eligible properties, (2) flexibility in certain underwriting standards, (3) the development of new mortgage products specifically targeted to eligible applicants, and (4) other appropriate assistance. The program must provide for the development of a program that uses actuarial information to determine how the repayment of federal student loans may be integrated into a mortgage repayment schedule to allow eligible applicants to accumulate home equity.

An eligible property is a property (1) that is designed as a dwelling&#160;for occupancy by one to four families; (2) that is safe and habitable; (3) the occupancy of which will promote community revitalization; and (4) that is owned by HUD, the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), a local land bank, the Department of Agriculture, or the Department of Veterans Affairs.</summary>
</bill>
