<bill session="118" type="h" number="166" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:11Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Lending for All Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Lending for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Office of Fair Lending Testing to test for compliance with the Equal Credit Opportunity Act, to strengthen the Equal Credit Opportunity Act, to ensure that persons injured by discriminatory practices, including organizations that have diverted resources to address discrimination and whose mission has been frustrated by illegal acts, can seek relief under such Act and to provide for criminal penalties for violating such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-23T20:35:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Lending for All Act 

This bill modifies provisions related to prohibited credit discrimination.

The bill adds sexual orientation, gender identity, and an applicant's location based on zip code or census tract as classes protected against discrimination with respect to credit transactions. (Currently, discrimination is prohibited on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, marital status, age, or because an applicant receives public assistance.)

The bill establishes criminal penalties for violations of prohibited credit discrimination.

 The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is required to review loan applications for compliance with specified consumer laws and to establish an Office of Fair Lending Testing.</summary>
</bill>
