<bill session="117" type="h" number="8300" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Empowering Resilient Local Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Resilient Local Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to issue guidance on extreme temperature events and resilience goals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2022-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5118" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-05T16:38:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering Resilient Local Communities Act

This bill addresses issues involving extreme temperature and resilience, as well as impacts on underserved communities.

Specifically, the bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to issue guidance related to extreme temperature events and resilience goals. It requires hazard mitigation plans to address resilience and disparate impacts on underserved communities.

The Government Accountability Office must evaluate and issue to Congress and FEMA a report regarding the impacts of wildfire smoke and poor indoor air quality, the challenges posed to FEMA in addressing wildfire smoke and indoor air quality, and recommendations for FEMA to better provide assistance to communities and individuals in dealing with wildfire smoke and indoor air quality.

FEMA must submit to Congress a report regarding the challenges posed by its requirements for declaring an incident or determining the cost effectiveness of mitigation activities and specifically how such requirements may disproportionately burden small impoverished communities, or specific vulnerable populations within communities.</summary>
</bill>
