<bill session="108" type="s" number="281" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:51Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian Tribal Surface Transportation Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to make certain amendments with respect to Indian tribes, to provide for training and technical assistance to Native Americans who are interested in commercial vehicle driving careers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="popular">TEA-21 bill</title>
    <title type="popular">TEA21 bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Tribal Surface Transportation Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Tribal Surface Transportation Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Indian Tribal Surface Transportation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Native American Commercial Driving Training and Technical Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2003-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1883"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1883-1884" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-122.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-150.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="284">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 284.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Truck drivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Tribal Surface Transportation Act of 2003 - Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (TEA-21) to prohibit the Secretary of Transportation from distributing the obligation authority for Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs for FY 2003 and 2004 with respect to amounts authorized for Indian reservation roads under the Federal Lands Highways Program.Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a demonstration project under which all funds made available for Indian reservation roads and highway bridges located on such roads shall be made available to an Indian tribal government, upon its request, for contracts and agreements for planning, research, engineering, and construction of any highway, road, bridge, parkway, or transit facility that provides access to or is located within the reservation or community of the Indian tribe.Deems an Indian tribe eligible to participate in the Indian reservation roads program to be a State eligible for: (1) safety incentive allocations to assist Indian communities in developing innovative programs to promote increased seat belt use rates; and (2) safety incentive grant funding to assist such communities in the prevention of the operation of motor vehicles by intoxicated persons.Native American Commercial Driving Training and Technical Assistance Act - Authorizes the Secretary to provide competitive grants to tribal colleges or universities to support programs providing training and certificates leading to the licensing of Native Americans with respect to commercial vehicle driving.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-150</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
