<bill session="117" type="h" number="9346" updated="2023-04-12T14:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coastal Communities Ocean Acidification Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal Communities Ocean Acidification Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2009 to require the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to collaborate with State and local governments and Indian Tribes on vulnerability assessments related to ocean acidification, research planning, and similar activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2022-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2022-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2022-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-17T16:01:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Coastal Communities Ocean Acidification Act of 2022

This bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to collaborate with state, local, and tribal entities that are conducting or have completed community vulnerability assessments, research planning, climate action plans, or other similar activities related to ocean acidification and coastal acidification and their impacts of ocean acidification on coastal communities.

 NOAA must (1) support collaborative interagency relationships and information at the state, local , and tribal level; and (2) assist state, local, and tribal entities in improving existing systems and programs to better address ocean acidification and coastal acidification and identify whether such activities can be used as a model for other communities.</summary>
</bill>
