<bill session="108" type="s" number="1608" updated="2023-01-15T07:02:59Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Anti-Terrorism Protection of Mass Transportation and Railroad Carriers Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the penalties for terrorism against mass transportation and railroads and provide law enforcement with the tools to combat and prevent attacks on mass transportation and railroads.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Terrorism Protection of Mass Transportation and Railroad Carriers Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="popular">Railroad Safety bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2003-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4008" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-12-19T20:55:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Anti-Terrorism Protection of Mass Transportation and Railroad Carriers Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit specified attacks and acts of violence against mass transportation systems and against railroad carriers, including derailing a train, placing a biological agent or toxin in or near a mass transportation vehicle, setting fire to a terminal, committing an act with intent to cause serious bodily injury to a railroad employee, and conveying false information concerning an attempt to commit such a crime. Lists circumstances resulting in aggravated offenses. Sets penalties for violations.

Authorizes: (1) the interception of wire, oral, or electronic communications in cases involving domestic or international terrorism and involving other specified offenses (such as violence at international airports, an attack on a Federal facility with a firearm, and conspiracy to harm persons or property overseas); and (2) the use of an emergency pen register or trap and trace device in cases involving domestic or international terrorism or conspiratorial activities threatening the national security interest.

Modifies the definition of: (1) "Federal crime of terrorism" to include an offense that appears by its nature or context to be intended to intimidate or coerce a civilian population, influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion, or affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, or kidnaping; and (2) "international terrorism" to include listed actions that appear "by their nature or context" to be intended to intimidate, influence, or affect governmental conduct.</summary>
</bill>
