<bill session="108" type="h" number="3914" updated="2023-01-15T10:18:05Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Children's Protection from Violent Programming Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require that violent video programming is limited to broadcast after the hours when children are reasonably likely to comprise a substantial portion of the audience, unless it is specifically rated on the basis of its violent content so that it is blockable by electronic means specifically on the basis of that content.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Protection from Violent Programming Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000165" joined="2004-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000422" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2004-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1030-1031"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="161" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Television and children"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="V-chips"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
    <term name="Violence in mass media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-14T16:39:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Children's Protection from Violent Programming Act - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to assess the effectiveness of measures to require television broadcasters and multichannel video programming distributors to rate and encode programming that could be blocked by parents by use of a V-chip. Authorizes the FCC, if it finds such measures ineffective, to prohibit the distribution of violent video programming during hours when children are reasonably likely to comprise a substantial portion of the audience.Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to make it unlawful for any person to distribute to the public any violent video programming not blockable by electronic means specifically on the basis of its violent content. Provides for exemptions for: (1) programming (including news programs and sporting events) the distribution of which does not conflict with the objective of protecting children from the negative influences of violent video programming; and (2) premium and pay-per-view direct-to-home satellite programming.Directs the FCC to impose a forfeiture penalty for violations and to revoke a broadcasting or distribution license of a repeat violator. Requires the FCC to continue to study and report annually to specified committees on the marketing to children of violent content by the motion picture, music recording, and computer and video game industries.</summary>
</bill>
