<bill session="119" type="h" number="52" updated="2025-06-03T18:31:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Woke Investing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Woke Investing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to amend a rule of the Commission relating to shareholder proposals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001132" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2025-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-11T22:32:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Woke Investing Act

This bill requires the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to amend regulations to limit the inclusion of shareholder proposals in proxy statements. A proxy statement is provided to shareholders prior to a public company holding a shareholder meeting and contains information relevant to a shareholder vote. Under current SEC rules, certain qualifying shareholder proposals must be included on a company's proxy statement, including proposals that raise significant social policy issues.

Under the bill, a shareholder proposal must have a material effect on the financial performance of the company to be included in a proxy statement. The bill also establishes a cap on the number of shareholder proposals required to be included in a shareholder meeting, depending on the size and type of the company. In addition, a proposal submitted by a member of the board of directors is prohibited from inclusion as a shareholder proposal.</summary>
</bill>
