<bill session="119" type="h" number="5240" updated="2025-09-18T13:33:29Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fully Funding our National Security Priorities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fully Funding our National Security Priorities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a report on the unfunded priorities of the Department of State.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-18T13:32:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Fully Funding our National Security Priorities Act

This bill requires the Department of State to submit an annual report to Congress regarding unfunded State Department priorities.

Under the bill, an unfunded priority generally refers to a program, activity, or mission requirement of the State Department that was not funded in the President's budget and is necessary to fulfill a foreign policy or national security objective or to satisfy an information requirement associated with a goal or objective outlined in the Joint Strategic Plan agreed upon by the State Department.

The report must be submitted no later than 10 days after the President's budget is submitted to Congress and must include specified details regarding each unfunded priority, including&#160;&#160;

a description of the priority, including the objectives to be achieved if the priority is funded;the amount of additional funding that is needed to achieve the objective; andcertain budget information (e.g., the appropriation account and the project).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
