<bill session="111" type="s" number="3711" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:39Z">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Viral Hepatitis and Liver Cancer Control and Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish, promote, and support a comprehensive prevention, education, research, and medical management referral program for viral hepatitis infection that will lead to a marked reduction in the disease burden associated with chronic viral hepatitis and liver cancer.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Viral Hepatitis and Liver Cancer Control and Prevention Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6886-6887"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3974" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-21T18:34:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Viral Hepatitis and Liver Cancer Control and Prevention Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop, implement, and update a plan for the prevention, control, and medical management of hepatitis B and hepatitis C.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA), to implement programs to increase awareness and enhance knowledge and understanding of hepatitis B and hepatitis C.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, to: (1) support the integration of voluntary hepatitis B and hepatitis C testing programs into existing clinical and public health programs; (2) provide increased support to Adult Viral Hepatitis Coordinators to integrate prevention and control activities into existing health programs; (3) support the establishment of a hepatitis B and hepatitis C surveillance program; and (4) report on seroprevalence studies and the impact of hepatitis B and hepatitis C.

Directs the Secretary to support state, local, territorial, and tribal efforts to: (1) provide counseling and education on hepatitis B and hepatitis C; (2) expand the current vaccination programs for hepatitis B; and (3) provide referrals for treatment to individuals with hepatitis B or hepatitis C.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, the Director of the National Cancer Institute, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to conduct research on hepatitis B and hepatitis C.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, governmental and nonprofit entities that have special expertise relating to hepatitis B and hepatitis C to support prevention activities.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of SAMHSA, to develop educational materials and intervention strategies to reduce the risks of hepatitis among substance abusers and individuals with mental illness.</summary>
</bill>
