<bill session="116" type="s" number="3648" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">E-BRIDGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">E-BRIDGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminating Barriers to Rural Internet Development Grant Eligibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to provide for a high-speed broadband deployment initiative.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2020-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6491" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-17T14:12:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Eliminating Barriers to Rural Internet Development Grant Eligibility Act or the E-BRIDGE Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Commerce to award economic development grants for public-private partnerships and certain consortiums to carry out specified broadband projects.

Such projects shall be to provide, extend, expand, or improve high-speed broadband service through (1) planning, technical assistance, or training; (2) land acquisition or development; or (3) acquisition, construction, or improvement of facilities.

Title to real or personal property acquired or improved with grant funds, or another acceptable possessory interest, must be vested in a public partner or eligible nonprofit organization or association for the useful life of the project. In addition, grant funds may be combined with amounts made available under any other federal program, and Commerce may provide credit toward the non-federal share of a broadband project's cost.</summary>
</bill>
