<bill session="118" type="s" number="418" updated="2025-11-19T04:07:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-26">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Justice for Jana Elementary Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Justice for Jana Elementary Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Jana Elementary Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide financial assistance to schools impacted by radioactive contaminants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2023-04-26" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1361-1362" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1361-1362" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27T12:31:51-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27T13:19:29-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2820" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T13:10:08Z" status="Passed Senate">Justice for Jana Elementary Act of 2023

This bill establishes a program and requirements regarding schools impacted by radioactive contaminants, including in the Hazelwood School District in Missouri.

Specifically, the bill requires the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) to establish and execute new remediation goals for Jana Elementary School in the Hazelwood School District so that no portion of the site is subjected to radiation above background levels. (The school is located near Coldwater Creek, which is contaminated with radioactive waste from nearby sites used for the World War II nuclear weapons program.)

The bill establishes a Radioactive School Assistance Program (and fund) to provide financial assistance to local educational agencies that have been financially impacted by the presence of radioactive contaminants stemming from U.S. atomic energy activities.

Under the bill, schools in the Hazelwood School District in Missouri must be designated as vicinity properties of the St. Louis Airport Site for purposes of the USACE Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program. Such schools must be investigated, including via on-site inspections and sampling, in accordance with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (CERCLA) and the National Contingency Plan (i.e., the national plan for responding to spills or releases of hazardous substances).

The Department of Energy must review and report on the methodology and results of all tests for radioactive contaminants conducted at Jana Elementary School.</summary>
</bill>
