<bill session="116" type="h" number="2120" updated="2022-11-01T19:17:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Saving for the Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a universal personal savings program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving for the Future Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2019-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1053" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-02T12:54:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Saving for the Future Act

This bill requires employers to make minimum contributions to savings plans for full-time employees and increases certain individual and corporate income tax rates. Specifically, it requires employers of 10 or more full-time employees to contribute 50 cents for each hour an employee works to a qualified pension plan. The minimum contribution increases to 60 cents per hour after two years and proportionally based on income beginning two years thereafter. The bill further establishes the Federal Universal Personal Savings Investment Board to oversee UP retirement and savings accounts. Employers may make contributions to such accounts directly as a qualified plan or through a state-run program. UP retirement accounts are portable, defined-contribution pension plans to which employees must contribute 4% of the employee's wages unless the employee opts out. Employers must make the minimum required contribution under this program as well as match employee contributions up to 10% of an employee's wages. The initial $2,500 of such employer contributions may be applied to an UP savings account and used for certain nonroutine expenses such as a large medical bill or home mortgage down payment. Employer contributions to UP accounts are generally exempt from income tax and employee contributions may be pretax or posttax. Employers also receive a tax credit for a specified portion of the minimum contribution amount for up to the employer's first 30 employees. Additionally, the bill also increases the highest individual income tax rate from 37% to 39.6% and the highest corporate income tax rate from 21% to 23%.</summary>
</bill>
