<bill session="117" type="s" number="3284" updated="2022-12-30T02:48:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Assistance Helpline Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Assistance Helpline Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a toll-free telephone helpline for veterans and other eligible individuals to use to obtain information about the benefits and services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2021-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-04T19:30:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Assistance Helpline Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a toll-free telephone help line for the purpose of providing information to specified individuals about VA services and benefits available in their area. Specifically, the help line is for veterans, persons acting on behalf of veterans, or individuals who are eligible to receive benefits or services from the VA.

The VA, in coordination with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), may contract with a third party to direct calls to the appropriate person regarding a VA service or benefit.

Additionally, the VA must coordinate with the FCC to study and report on the feasibility and advisability of designating a covered dialing code for the purpose of reaching the help line.</summary>
</bill>
