<bill session="108" type="s" number="1732" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a rural water supply program in the Reclamation States to provide a clean, safe, affordable, and reliable water supply to rural residents.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12609"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12609-12610" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-539.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-19T19:30:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">The Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act of 2003 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a rural water supply program in Reclamation States.

Directs the Secretary to develop and publish in the Federal Register criteria for determining the eligibility of a water supply project for assistance under this Act, including: (1) whether a project serves rural areas or Indian tribes; (2) whether there is an urgent need for a project that would result in continuous, measurable, and significant water quality benefits, address current or future water supply shortages, or improve the health or aesthetic quality of water; (3) whether a project helps meet any applicable legal requirements; (4) whether a project promotes a regional perspective to water resource management issues, implements an integrated resources management approach, increases water management flexibility, or forms a partnership with other entities; and (5) whether a project provides benefits outside the region in which the project is carried on.

Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) conduct appraisal investigations of proposed rural water supply projects; and (2) carry out feasibility studies of proposed rural water supply systems.

Requires State and local authorities, Indian Tribes, or other entities carrying out rural water supply projects under this Act to demonstrate the ability to pay all operation, maintenance, and replacement costs of such projects.</summary>
</bill>
