<bill session="116" type="s" number="3145" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Desert National Wildlife Refuge and Nevada Test and Training Range Withdrawal and Management Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Desert National Wildlife Refuge and Nevada Test and Training Range Withdrawal and Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the withdrawal and reservation of certain public land in the State of Nevada for the continued use of the Nevada test and training range, to designate certain land in the Desert National Wildlife Refuge as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2019-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5606" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-21T23:10:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Desert National Wildlife Refuge and Nevada Test and Training Range Withdrawal and Management Act

This bill provides for the termination or expansion of certain withdrawn and reserved military lands in Nevada and designates certain lands within the Desert National Wildlife Refuge in Nevada as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill terminates the withdrawal and reservation of lands for the Naval Air Station Fallon Ranges and the Nevada Test and Training Range in 2021 and 2041, respectively.

The bill expands the boundaries of Nellis Air Force Range to comprise 3,006,386 acres of land. The Department of the Air Force and the Department of the Interior shall not withdraw the new lands until they implement a cultural resources plan.

The bill provides for fish and wildlife habitat support in the Desert National Wildlife Refuge. Mitigation payments shall be provided by the Air Force to Interior for such support on lands withdrawn and reserved for use by the Air Force within the refuge.

Interior and the Air Force must jointly establish (1) an interagency committee to facilitate coordination and minimize potential conflict regarding joint operating areas within the refuge, and (2) an intergovernmental executive committee for the management of the natural and cultural resources of the withdrawn and reserved lands of the ranges and certain other ranges.

Interior shall facilitate public access to portions of the joint use area of the refuge for tribal, recreational, educational, and research purposes.

The bill sets the western boundary of refuge between the refuge and the land jointly managed by the Air Force and Interior concerning Nellis Air Force Range.</summary>
</bill>
