<bill session="112" type="h" number="2212" updated="2019-11-15T21:34:23Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Democracy Restoration Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To secure the Federal voting rights of persons who have been released from incarceration.</title>
    <title type="display">Democracy Restoration Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2012-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2012-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1121-1122"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="108" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="5799" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2017" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3608" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-30T18:22:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Democracy Restoration Act of 2011 - Declares that the right of a U.S. citizen to vote in any election for federal office shall not be denied or abridged because that individual has been convicted of a criminal offense unless, at the time of the election, such individual is serving a felony sentence in a correctional institution or facility. Provides for enforcement and remedies for violations of this Act.

Specifies that: (1) nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit a state from enacting any state law that affords the right to vote in any election for federal office on terms less restrictive than those terms established by this Act; and (2) the rights and remedies established by this Act shall be in addition to all other rights and remedies provided by law, and shall not supersede, restrict, or limit the application of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 or the National Voter Registration Act of 1993. Prohibits any state, unit of local government, or other person from receiving or using any federal grant amounts to construct or improve a place of incarceration unless that person has a program to notify each U.S. citizen incarcerated in that person's jurisdiction, on release from such incarceration, of that individual's rights under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
