<bill session="110" type="s" number="2396" updated="2023-01-11T20:08:09Z">
  <state datetime="2007-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to modernize the quality improvement organization (QIO) program.</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Quality Improvement Organization Modernization Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Quality Improvement Organization Modernization Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000382" joined="2007-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2008-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2008-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2007-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2007-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2007-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14642-14643"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-02-07T22:55:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Quality Improvement Organization Modernization Act of 2007 - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require utilization and quality control peer review organizations to offer quality improvement assistance to providers, practitioners who provide health care items and services to individuals dually eligible for benefits under SSA titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid), and programs that provide items and services to such individuals.

Requires the organization to establish a Medicare quality accountability program.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, to contract with an entity to conduct a medical review audit to evaluate whether quality improvement organizations are making appropriate noncompliance determinations and sanction recommendations to the Secretary regarding health care practitioners and providers with respect to a corrective action plan.

Revises requirements for the quality improvement program (QIO), including program administration, data disclosure, use of evaluation and competition, quality improvement organization program funding, and qualifications for QIOs under part B (Peer Review) of SSA title XI.</summary>
</bill>
