<bill session="119" type="h" number="3838" updated="2025-11-21T15:57:25Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-10T17:56:37-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-10T17:56:37-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPEED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Procurement for Effective Execution and Delivery Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Streamlining Procurement for Effective Execution and Delivery and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Streamlining Procurement for Effective Execution and Delivery and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Anti-CBDC Surveillance State Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">SAFE Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Securing American Funding and Expertise from Adversarial Research Exploitation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2026 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2026 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Streamlining Procurement for Effective Execution and Delivery and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2025-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 55 - 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 119-231.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-08-19" calendar="Union" number="189">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 189.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T10:12:05-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 682 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3838 and H.R. 3486. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3838 under a structured rule and H.R. 3486 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T14:16:17-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 682.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3915-4158: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T14:16:22-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3838 and H.R. 3486. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3838 under a structured rule and H.R. 3486 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T14:16:34-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 682 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T14:16:37-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Michelle Fischbach to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T14:17:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3838.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:12:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:21:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Smith (NJ) amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:33:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Smith amendment No. 7, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Courtney demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:34:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Patronis amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:44:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Patronis amendment No. 9, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Beyer demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:45:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T15:54:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:06:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment No. 11, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:07:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment en bloc No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:15:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment en bloc No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:18:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment en bloc No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:21:49-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (AL) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:22:02-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09T16:22:49-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3838 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:19:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4176-4213: 6" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:19:46-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:21:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:33:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 13, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:34:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:45:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mace amendment No. 14, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:45:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:56:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mace amendment No. 15, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Stansbury demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T12:57:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:09:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mace amendment No. 16, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Takano demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:10:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:20:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mace amendment No. 17, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jacobs demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:22:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mills amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:33:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mills amendment No. 18, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Takano demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:34:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:45:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Brownley demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:46:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Austin Scott amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T13:55:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:08:19-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 22, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:08:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:20:05-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:21:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:32:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 24, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Greene (GA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:33:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:45:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 25, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:46:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs (AZ) amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:57:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs (AZ) amendment No. 29, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Elfreth demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T14:58:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rouzer amendment No. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:05:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Meeks amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:15:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Meeks amendment No. 34, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Mast demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:16:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rose amendment No. 253.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:20:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rose amendment No. 253, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Rose demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:21:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 682, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Rogers (AL) amendment en bloc No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:44:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (AL) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:45:05-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T15:45:17-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3838 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:04:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4213-4214" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:04:28-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:35:37-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (AL) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:35:56-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:36:28-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 3838 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:45:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4125-4128" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T16:45:37-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:41:13-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3838.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:42:02-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:42:11-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gros as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:43:03-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Houlahan moved to recommit to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4211"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:43:19-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:50:24-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 208 - 219 (Roll no. 261).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="262" datetime="2025-09-10T17:56:37-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 231 - 196 (Roll no. 262).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:56:42-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10T17:56:43-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3838.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Bills Of Interest - Exchange Of Letters"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5400" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="6009" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="682" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4704" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4812" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5188" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5090" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5189" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5176" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5193" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5191" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5187" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces Retirement Home"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Belarus"/>
    <term name="Belgium"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Diego Garcia"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Greenland"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="New Zealand"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Norway"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Spain"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h99"/>
    <amendment number="h98"/>
    <amendment number="h97"/>
    <amendment number="h96"/>
    <amendment number="h95"/>
    <amendment number="h94"/>
    <amendment number="h93"/>
    <amendment number="h92"/>
    <amendment number="h91"/>
    <amendment number="h90"/>
    <amendment number="h89"/>
    <amendment number="h88"/>
    <amendment number="h87"/>
    <amendment number="h86"/>
    <amendment number="h85"/>
    <amendment number="h84"/>
    <amendment number="h83"/>
    <amendment number="h82"/>
    <amendment number="h81"/>
    <amendment number="h80"/>
    <amendment number="h79"/>
    <amendment number="h78"/>
    <amendment number="h77"/>
    <amendment number="h101"/>
    <amendment number="h100"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-09-11T13:20:33Z" status="Reported to House">Streamlining Procurement for Effective Execution and Delivery and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026

This bill sets forth policies&#160;and authorities for FY2026 for Department of Defense (DOD) programs and activities, military construction, and the national security programs of the Department of Energy and the Maritime Administration. It also authorizes appropriations for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board and the Naval Petroleum Reserves, and modifies the defense acquisition system to expedite delivery of capabilities to the Armed Forces.

Among other elements, the bill

authorizes the acquisition or modification of various military items (e.g., aircraft) and sets policy for certain procurement programs;authorizes research, development, test, and evaluation and sets policy for such&#160;activities;sets active component and reserve component end-strength levels;sets policy regarding various aspects of military health care and military compensation;sets policy regarding acquisitions and acquisition management, including contracting authorities and small businesses;sets policy for various matters related to DOD interactions with foreign nations, including matters concerning Israel;sets policy for various matters related to DOD cyber activities, cyber workforce and training, cybersecurity, and artificial intelligence matters; andauthorizes the activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration, defense environmental cleanup, nuclear energy, and other defense activities.For additional information on the National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA) see

CRS In Focus IF10516, Defense Primer: Navigating the&#160;NDAA, andCRS In Focus IF10515, Defense Primer: The&#160;NDAA Process.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-231</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
