<bill session="117" type="h" number="5545" updated="2023-08-28T16:45:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Education Mitigating Options and Technical Extensions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Responsible Education Mitigating Options and Technical Extensions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Responsible Education Mitigating Options and Technical Extensions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Responsible Education Mitigating Options and Technical Extensions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Responsible Education Mitigating Options and Technical Extensions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To extend certain expiring provisions of law relating to benefits provided under Department of Veterans Affairs educational assistance programs during COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend certain expiring provisions of law relating to benefits provided under Department of Veterans Affairs educational assistance programs during COVID-19 pandemic.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend certain expiring provisions of law relating to benefits provided under Department of Veterans Affairs educational assistance programs during COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2021-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000588" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000590" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2021-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2021-11-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2021-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2021-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T10:20:46-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T10:21:04-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7468-7470" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T10:21:17-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5545.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-12-08T10:35:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7468-7469" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T10:35:49-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T10:35:53-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2021-12-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9216-9217" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2021-12-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2021-12-21" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-76" type="public" datetime="2021-12-21">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-76.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-28T16:40:11Z" status="Public Law">Responsible Education Mitigating Options and Technical Extensions Act or the REMOTE Act

This act addresses the administration of certain Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) educational assistance benefits.

First, the act extends through June 1, 2022, certain adjustments for veterans' education benefits that were put in place due to COVID-19.

The act allows the VA to waive the requirement that an educational institution verify the enrollment of a student utilizing VA educational assistance if the VA determines the institution uses a flat rate tuition and fee structure that would make the use of a second verification unnecessary. The act provides an exception from the imposition of specified disciplinary actions (e.g., suspending course and program approval) in situations where an educational institution provides a commission, bonus, or other incentive payment to entities engaged in student recruiting or admission activities related to recruiting foreign students who reside in foreign countries and are ineligible for federal student assistance.

Additionally, the act generally exempts from certain requirements and restrictions imposed by the VA or a state approving agency educational institutions (1) located in foreign countries, or (2) that provide information regarding the costs of a program of education using a form or template developed by the Department of Education.

The act also exempts educational institutions located in foreign countries from (1) having records and accounts that pertain to an individual who is not receiving VA educational assistance examined by government representatives, and (2) furnishing certain information related to tests that require payment.

The act authorizes the VA, in certain circumstances, to provide educational assistance (including a housing stipend) to veterans or eligible persons who are in their last academic period (e.g., semester) of a program of education and are pursuing the program on less than a half-time basis. Specifically, such assistance may be provided if the number of credits the person needs to complete the program of education is less than the number of credits that would constitute enrollment on more than a half-time basis for that last academic period and the person (1) is enrolled in or has completed every course offered by the program of education during that academic period, and (2) enrolls in an additional course that is not required for the program of education to reach enrollment on a more than a half-time basis.

The act extends certain loan fee rates through January 14, 2031, under the VA's home loan program.

Finally, the act removes the cap on the number of full-time VA employees who provide equal employment opportunity counseling.</summary>
</bill>
