<bill session="109" type="h" number="54" updated="2022-02-03T05:36:29Z">
  <state datetime="2005-01-26T13:08:39-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-01-26T13:08:39-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Congressional Gold Medal Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Gold Medal Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="popular">Congressional Gold Medals bill</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Gold Medal Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide reasonable standards for congressional gold medals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-25T19:46:56-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 42 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 54 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T10:43:20-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 42 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T10:43:28-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 42.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H206-216, H216-219" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H211" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T10:43:33-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 54 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T10:43:41-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 42 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T10:43:42-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ray LaHood to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T10:43:50-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T11:27:25-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 42, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Oxley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T11:28:58-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 42, the Commitee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Crowley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T11:38:54-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crowley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Crowley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T11:39:54-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 42, the Commitee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Crowley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T11:56:10-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crowley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Crowley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T11:56:37-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:26:21-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:27:11-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:27:21-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:27:48-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Crowley moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:28:20-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crowley motion to recomit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House forthwith with an amendment which inserts a new paragraph preventing the Secretary from striking a congressional gold medal for presentation posthumously on behalf of any individual except during the 20-year period beginning 5 years after the death of the individual (unless the Act of Congress authorizing the striking of such medal was enacted before the death of such individual).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:40:18-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T12:59:36-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 187 - 217 (Roll no. 12).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H216-218" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="13" datetime="2005-01-26T13:08:39-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 231 - 173 (Roll no. 13).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26T13:08:40-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="42" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional gold medals"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h4"/>
    <amendment number="h3"/>
    <amendment number="h2"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2005-01-28T14:41:38Z" status="Passed House amended">Congressional Gold Medal Enhancement Act of 2005 - Sets forth standards under which the Secretary of the Treasury, beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, is authorized to strike not more than two congressional gold medals for presentation during any calendar year.

Provides that: (1) only an individual may be a recipient of a congressional gold medal; and (2) no gold medal may be presented posthumously on behalf of any individual except during the 20-year period beginning five years after the individual's death (unless the Act of Congress authorizing the striking of such medal was enacted before the death).</summary>
</bill>
