<bill session="114" type="h" number="6480" updated="2023-01-11T13:33:55Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-08T14:26:18-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-12-08T14:26:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2017 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Intelligence Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2016-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08T14:26:03-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Nunes asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Committee on Intelligence (Permanent) discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08T14:26:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7540-7550" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote" datetime="2016-12-08T14:26:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7540-7550" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08T14:26:19-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="5077" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="6393" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="3017" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="4239" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Belarus"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Director of National Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-10T16:41:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017

This bill authorizes FY2017 appropriations for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities of:

 the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI); the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); the Department of Defense; the Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA); the National Security Agency (NSA); the Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force; the U.S. Coast Guard; the Departments of State, the Treasury, Energy, and Justice; the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); the Drug Enforcement Administration; the National Reconnaissance Office (NRO); the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). The bill authorizes FY2017 appropriations for: (1) the Intelligence Community Management Account, and (2) the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund.

The ODNI must: (1) submit a five-year investment strategy for outreach and recruiting efforts in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) that includes cybersecurity and computer literacy; (2) implement a multisector workforce initiative to enable the intelligence community to build and maintain an appropriate ratio of employees and core contractors; (3) issue guidance regarding the intelligence community's engagements with the entertainment industry; and (4) implement a uniform policy to ensure the independence of inspectors general of the intelligence community, the ODNI, the CIA, the NSA, the DIA, the NGA, and the NRO.

For FY2017 and FY2018, personnel of the intelligence community must be managed solely on the basis of: (1) the workload required to carry out intelligence community functions, and (2) the funds made available for each such fiscal year. Management of intelligence personnel during this period shall not be subject to any constraint or limitation in terms of man years, end strength, positions, or maximum number of employees.

DHS's national cybersecurity and communications integration center must carry out a program to provide assistance to certain critical infrastructure entities to reduce the risk of regional or national catastrophic harm caused by a cyber attack.

The Office of the National Counterintelligence Executive is redesignated as the National Counterintelligence and Security Center with a director to be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate.

The bill revises or sets forth requirements for:

 the ODNI to participate in fund-raising events for nonprofit organizations that support intelligence community employees and their families, CIA employee death and retirement benefits, publication of the logos of terrorist organizations, space-based environmental monitoring missions and acquisition programs to meet national security requirements for cloud characterization and theater weather imagery, an evaluation of aerial imagery technologies that can be used to share intelligence with other countries as a replacement for the current regime of observation flights, a declassification review of intelligence reports regarding past terrorist activities of detainees transferred or released from Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and a concept for a combined interagency space operations center and an updated strategy for national security satellite systems. The bill establishes an executive branch interagency committee to counter active measures by the Russian Federation to exert covert influence over peoples and governments. The State Department must coordinate with the FBI and the ODNI to establish a mandatory advance notification regime governing all travel by accredited diplomatic and consular personnel of the Russian Federation in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
