<bill session="118" type="s" number="1429" updated="2025-01-14T17:12:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Resource Management PFAS Liability Protection Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resource Management PFAS Liability Protection Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to exempt certain entities from liability under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 with respect to releases of perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2024-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-22T23:55:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Resource Management PFAS Liability Protection Act of 2023

This bill exempts the owner or operator of a solid waste management facility or a facility that processes compost for sale or distribution to the public from liability under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) for releases of certain perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS.

Specifically, such exemption only applies if the release of a PFAS resulted from (1) the disposal or management of any residuals or byproduct of municipal solid waste in accordance with a permit, (2) the disposal or management of biosolids consistent with the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, or (3) the application or processing of compost in accordance with state law.

Liability for damages or costs associated with the release of certain PFAS must not be precluded if an entity acted with gross negligence or willful misconduct.</summary>
</bill>
