<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1270</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:18:37Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:18:37Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-06-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg04</systemCode>
            <name>National Parks Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2009-07-22T19:37:19Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-08-05T18:38:38Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-06-21T23:57:12Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-06-16T18:59:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-256</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>2889</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-05-28</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 285.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 526.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-256.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-256.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-07-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg04</systemCode>
            <name>National Parks Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-16</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6652-6653)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <lastName>Wyden</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Merkley, Jeff [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <lastName>Merkley</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-06-16</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-06-30T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1270, Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21591</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Eenrgy and Natural Resources on June 21, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-06-30T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1270, Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21591</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Eenrgy and Natural Resources on June 21, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oregon</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-06-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-08-04T20:13:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2009 - Adjusts the boundary of Oregon Caves National Monument (Monument). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) transfer certain land identified as proposed addition lands to the Secretary of the Interior; and (2) adjust the boundary of the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest to exclude such lands transferred by the Secretary. </p> <p>Designates the transferred land as a National Preserve (the Preserve). Redesignates the Monument as the Oregon Caves National Monument and Preserve. </p> <p>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain additional segments of the Monument as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Interior to carry out forest restoration activities within the boundaries of the Monument and the Preserve. Permits the grazing of domestic livestock on land within the Preserve at a level not greater than that at which the grazing exists as of enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture or the Interior to accept any grazing lease or permit that is donated by a livestock operator that holds a valid existing grazing lease or permit for a grazing allotment. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary of the Interior to permit hunting, fishing, and trapping on land and water within the Preserve. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-10-20T16:36:31Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010 - (Sec. 3) Redesignates the Oregon Caves National Monument and lands identified as proposed addition lands as the Oregon Caves National Monument and Preserve, to be administered as a single unit of the National Park System. </p> <p>Designates the proposed addition lands as a National Preserve. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to: (1) transfer the proposed addition lands to the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), to be administered as part of the Monument and Preserve; and (2) adjust the boundary of the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest to exclude such lands transferred to the Secretary. Adjusts the boundary of the Monument and Preserve to exclude certain land in the city of Cave Junction. </p> <p> (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to revise the fire management plan for the Monument to include the Preserve and carry out hazardous fuel management activities within the Monument and Preserve. Allows for the completion of existing Forest Service stewardship and service contracts executed as of the enactment of this Act. Recognizes the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to administer such existing contracts through their completion. Permits the grazing of livestock on land within the Preserve to continue as authorized under permits or leases in existence as of enactment at not more than the level at which the grazing exists. </p> <p> Allows the Secretary, with specified administrative exceptions, to permit hunting and fishing on land and waters within the Preserve. </p> <p> (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary to accept the donation of a grazing lease or permit from a lessee or permittee for: (1) the Big Grayback Grazing Allotment located in the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest; and (2) the Billy Mountain Grazing Allotment located on a parcel of BLM-managed land. Instructs the Secretary to terminate each donated permit or lease and ensure a permanent end to grazing on the land covered by such permit or lease. Considers a lessee or permittee donating a grazing lease or permit to have waived any claim to any range improvement on the associated grazing allotment or portion. </p> <p> (Sec. 6) Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate: (1) the subterranean segment of the Cave Creek in Oregon known as the River Styx as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system; and (2) certain additional segments of the Monument and Preserve for study for potential addition to the system. Directs the Secretary to report the results of such study to Congress. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to modify the boundary of the Oregon Caves National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2010</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-08-05T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s1270rs/xml/BILLS-111s1270rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-06-16T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s1270is/xml/BILLS-111s1270is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 526.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
