<bill session="117" type="s" number="940" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Transit Frontline Workforce Training Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to establish a National Transit Frontline Workforce Training Center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Transit Frontline Workforce Training Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2021-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2129" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-06T12:56:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Transit Frontline Workforce Training Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of Transportation to establish a national transit frontline workforce training center to meet the needs of the rural and urban transit system frontline workforce through standards-based training relating to relevant maintenance and operations occupations. It must also evaluate, and provide a grant to, a nonprofit organization with demonstrated capacity to develop and provide transit career ladder programs through labor-management partnerships and apprenticeships on a nationwide basis to carry out the duties of the center.

The center must develop and carry out training and educational programs for public transportation employees serving in the frontline workforce, including programs relating to (1) developing consensus national training standards for key frontline occupations with demonstrated skill gaps; (2) developing national systems of qualification and apprenticeship for transit maintenance and operations occupations; and (3) establishing local, regional, and statewide transit training partnerships.</summary>
</bill>
