<bill session="112" type="h" number="2215" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:53Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hezbollah Anti-Terrorism Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Hezbollah Anti-Terrorism Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that United States taxpayer dollars are not used to fund terrorist entities in Lebanon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000410"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001050" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000021" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000569" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2012-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000011" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2011-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2011-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2011-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA20" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-07-20T13:13:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Hezbollah Anti-Terrorism Act of 2011 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit assistance from being provided to or for the benefit of a Hezbollah-dependent government of Lebanon unless the President certifies to Congress that: (1) Hezbollah has ceased its support for terrorism, renounced violence, and disarmed; or (2) the government of Lebanon has made progress toward dismantling Hezbollah terrorist and military infrastructure within Lebanon, arresting and bringing wanted Hezbollah terrorists to justice, ending Hezbollah imports of military and terrorism-related equipment, destroying unauthorized Hezbollah arms factories, stopping terrorist attacks, and fully cooperating with United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL) peacekeepers.

Requires recertifications to be made every six months.

Exempts from such prohibition assistance for: (1) basic human needs, (2) promotion of democracy, (3) disarmament, (4) the U.S. government's International Military Education and Training (IMET) program, and (5) educational institutions.

Prohibits, in the case of a government of Lebanon in which Hezbollah is a minority element in a governing coalition, assistance from being provided to, or for the benefit of, any ministry, agency, or instrumentality in which the chief official or other senior-level officials are members of Hezbollah or which is otherwise controlled by Hezbollah unless a certification or a recertification is in effect.

Provides that assistance may be provided to nongovernmental organizations working in Lebanon only during a period for which a certification or a recertification is in effect. Exempts from such limitation assistance for: (1) basic human needs, (2) promotion of democracy, (3) disarmament, (4) non-salary assistance to Lebanese government members who are not members of Hezbollah or any other foreign terrorist organization, and (5) other assistance that is in U.S. national security interests.

Provides, with respect to assistance for such nongovernmental organizations, that: (1) the Secretary of State shall ensure that such assistance is not provided to or through any individual or entity that has engaged in terrorist activity, and (2) no funds shall be used to honor individuals who have committed acts of terrorism.

Urges the President to direct the U.S. Executive Directors at international financial institutions to use U.S. influence to prohibit assistance to a Hezbollah-dependent government of Lebanon during any period for which a certification or a recertification is not in effect. Exempts from such prohibition assistance for basic human needs or to promote democracy.</summary>
</bill>
