<bill session="117" type="h" number="4544" updated="2022-12-31T05:06:04Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">WORK Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WORK Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Opportunity Realignment Kickstart Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000815"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2021-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Worker and Family Support.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-08T19:47:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Workforce Opportunity Realignment Kickstart Act or the WORK Act

This bill modifies requirements for states with respect to the administration of Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) funds.

Specifically, the bill (1) establishes new performance indicators related to employment and educational outcomes for states receiving TANF funds; (2) increases the percentage of TANF funds, from 30% to 50%, that may be used to support other state programs; and (3) allows states to use TANF funds to carry out certain workforce development programs. Under current law, states may use TANF funds to support other state programs only if they are related to Child Care and Development Block Grants or Social Services Block Grants.

States must negotiate with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a level of performance for each indicator, taking into account certain economic, demographic, and other factors. HHS must periodically revise levels of performance for states to reflect economic and other conditions.</summary>
</bill>
