<bill session="112" type="s" number="1107" updated="2020-02-10T17:06:56Z">
  <state datetime="2011-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Psoriasis and Psoriatic Arthritis Research, Cure, and Care Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Psoriasis and Psoriatic Arthritis Research, Cure, and Care Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize and support psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis data collection, to express the sense of the Congress to encourage and leverage public and private investment in psoriasis research with a particular focus on interdisciplinary collaborative research on the relationship between psoriasis and its comorbid conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2011-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2011-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2011-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2011-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2033" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-08-02T20:50:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Psoriasis and Psoriatic Arthritis Research, Cure, and Care Act of 2011 - Authorizes the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to undertake psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis data collection efforts to collect information regarding: (1) the prevalence of psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis in the United States; (2) the age of onset; (3) health-related quality of life; (4) health care utilization; (5) the burden of such disease; (6) direct and indirect costs; (7) health disparities, including with respect to age, gender, race, and ethnicity; and (8) comorbidities and the natural history of such disease. Allows such data collection efforts to include: (1) incorporating questions into public health surveys, questionnaires, and other databases in existence as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and (2) the consideration and development of a patient registry.

Encourages the Director of the National Institutes of Health to explore the development of a virtual Center of Excellence for Collaborative Discovery in Psoriasis and Comorbid Research or some other mechanism through which public and private sector findings regarding psoriasis and its comorbid conditions can be regularly shared and leveraged.</summary>
</bill>
