<bill session="111" type="h" number="3453" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:22Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Recovery Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to make improvements in the provision of Federal disaster assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Recovery Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000361" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001079" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-10T19:49:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Recovery Improvement Act - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to increase the maximum total contributions for a major disaster by 5% under such Act if, at the time of a declaration of a major disaster, the affected state has in effect and is actively enforcing an approved building code.

Sets forth state building code submission and approval requirements, including use of the nationally recognized model building code as a minimum standard.

Directs the President, in making a contribution to a state or local government or a person that owns a nonprofit facility for repair, restoration, and replacement of a damaged facility, to provide not less than 50% of the President's initial estimate of the federal share as an initial payment. Provides for expedited payments.

Requires the federal share for debris removal to be increased by 5% for states and local governments that have: (1) a debris management plan approved by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA); (2) prequalified two or more debris and wreckage removal contractors before the date of declaration of the major disaster; and (3) resubmitted such plan to the Administrator for approval every four years. Allows a recipient of a debris removal grant to: (1) use funds for the costs of recycling debris and wreckage resulting from a major disaster; and (2) retain any financial benefit received from the salvage.

Increases the period for appeals of disaster assistance decisions. Directs the Administrator to review, update, and revise the factors considered to measure the severity, magnitude, and impact of a disaster.

Authorizes the President to provide emergency assistance to pets and animals and their owners.</summary>
</bill>
