<bill session="108" type="s" number="1963" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wireless 411 Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to protect the privacy right of subscribers to wireless communication services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wireless 411 Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless 411 Privacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-11-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2004-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2004-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2004-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2004-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16004-16005"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16005-16006" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-956.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="810">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 810.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>By Senator McCain from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 108-423. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1973" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3558" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-04T20:28:55Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Wireless 411 Privacy Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit a provider of commercial mobile services, or any affiliate or agent of such provider (provider), from including the wireless telephone number (wireless number) of any subscriber in any wireless directory assistance service (WDAS) database unless the provider: (1) provides a conspicuous, separate notice to the subscriber of the right not be listed in any WDAS; and (2) obtains express prior listing authorization from such subscriber, and that authorization has not been withdrawn.

Requires a provider to remove the wireless number of any subscriber from a WDAS upon request of that subscriber and without subscriber cost.

Prohibits a telecommunications carrier from disclosing in billing information provided to customers wireless numbers of subscribers who have indicated a preference to their provider for not having their wireless number disclosed.

Prohibits a provider from publishing (listing) in any form, selling, or otherwise distributing the contents of any WDAS database unless the provider: (1) notifies the subscriber of the right not to be listed; and (2) obtains express prior authorization for listing from such subscriber, and that authorization has not been withdrawn.

Prohibits a provider from charging a subscriber for the exercise of any rights under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-423</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
