<bill session="108" type="s" number="1347" updated="2023-01-15T17:04:08Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to provide for training service and delivery innovation projects.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to provide for training service and delivery innovation projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8735-8736"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8737" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-01T15:08:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to include, among authorized demonstration and pilot projects, targeted innovation projects that improve access to and delivery of employment and training services.

Emphasizes projects that incorporate advanced technologies to help connect individuals to information and tools to upgrade their skills. Includes projects that link individuals to opportunities for self-guided learning. Gives priority to projects that provide: (1) technology directly to eligible training recipients to reach information about training opportunities and content; (2) for conducting of online eligibility determinations for Federal and State training programs, and directing individuals to appropriate area programs; and (3) high-quality employment and training services information integrated with delivery of information regarding other social services and health care programs.</summary>
</bill>
