<bill session="108" type="h" number="959" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Oceanography Amendments Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the conservation and management of coastal and ocean resources by authorizing National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration oceanographic programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Oceanography Amendments Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000097"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Technology, and Standards.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY19" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oceanography"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Tsunamis"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Oceanography Amendments Act of 2003 - Amends Federal law to establish as a permanent program (previously conducted in FY 1992 and 1993) a Coastal Ocean Program to augment and integrate existing research capabilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (Administration) with other research capabilities.Establishes in the Administration a Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory (Great Lakes Lab), a Pacific Marine Environmental Laboratory, and an Atlantic Oceanographic and Meteorological Laboratory. Authorizes the Great Lakes Lab to support, in partnership with the University of Michigan, a Cooperative Institute for Limnology and Ecosystem Research.Establishes a National Undersea Research Program in the Administration and requires the Secretary of Commerce to appoint its director.Establishes an Ocean Exploration Program in the Administration. Authorizes the Secretary (in conjunction with specified entities) to: (1) conduct interdisciplinary exploration voyages or other activities to survey, inventory, monitor and assess little known areas of the marine environment; (2) promote the development of oceanographic research; (3) conduct public education and outreach activities that improve the public understanding of ocean science, resources, and processes; and (4) accept donations for such purposes.Specifies requirements the Secretary must meet before designating a Regional Coastal Observation Technology System.Authorizes the Secretary to coordinate and designate units of a Coastal Observation Technology System to collect data necessary to carry out the missions of the Administration. Requires the Secretary to use such data to develop forecast models to support coastal and fishery management, safe and efficient marine navigation, weather and climate prediction, and other appropriate activities.</summary>
</bill>
