<bill session="108" type="s" number="787" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:13Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair and Independent Federal Judiciary Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the fair treatment of the Federal judiciary relating to compensation and benefits, and to instill greater public confidence in the Federal courts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Independent Federal Judiciary Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2003-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4839-4840"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4840-4841" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial ethics"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair and Independent Federal Judiciary Act of 2003 - Increases salaries for justices of the Supreme Court and for district court and other specified judges. Repeals Federal law that requires specific congressional authorization for salary increases for Federal judges and Supreme Court justices.Modifies provisions regarding survivor annuity benefits, including to increase the notification period for survivor annuity coverage for a judge of the U.S. Court of Federal Claims.Directs the President to appoint members to the Citizens' Commission on Public Service and Compensation pursuant to the Federal Salary Act of 1967.Amends the Federal judicial code to: (1) establish within the Treasury a Judicial Education Fund for the payment of necessary expenses incurred by a judge or justice in attending a private judicial seminar approved by the Board of the Federal Judicial Center; and (2) require each justice, judge, and magistrate of the United States to maintain a list (to be made available to the public) of all financial interests that would require disqualification.Directs the Judicial Conference of the United States to promulgate regulations to prohibit the solicitation or acceptance of anything of value in connection with a private judicial seminar, with exceptions.Requires a judge to avoid all impropriety and appearance of impropriety. Makes the prohibition against behaving with impropriety applicable to both the professional and personal conduct of a judge. Prohibits a judge from holding membership in any organization, except for religious or fraternal organizations, that practices discrimination on the basis of race, gender, religion, or national origin.</summary>
</bill>
