<bill session="108" type="sr" number="375" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:23Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding initiatives for Greater Middle East reform and modernization including a Twenty-First Century Trust.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding initiatives for Greater Middle East reform and modernization including a Twenty-First Century Trust.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6677-6678" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="France"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Islam"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-15T18:40:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the President encouraged the Group of Eight to outline a plan to engage with the countries of the ``Broader Middle East and North Africa'' in a way that allows such countries' reform and modernization; (2) reforms in the countries of the Greater Middle East, including nations of the Middle East, North Africa, and Central and South Asia, must be generated by the people and governments of such countries; (3) the President should seek to build on the initiatives of the Group of Eight and establish specific mechanisms for accomplishing the goals of reform and modernization of the Greater Middle East such as establishment of a Greater Middle East Twenty-First Century Trust; (4) the members of the Group of Eight can help effect long-term political and economic change in the Greater Middle East by leveraging financial contributions from Europe, Asia, and the wealthy countries of the region, and by providing the imprimatur of the broad international community; (5) the President should use his leverage with allies inside and outside the region to promote democratic reforms and political freedom; and (6) recognizing that social and political change would be more difficult in an atmosphere of violence, the President should work with other industrialized democracies and with the countries of the Greater Middle East to promote peace and maintain a stable environment.

States that the Senate urges the President to consider generating support for a Greater Middle East Twenty-First Century Trust in coordination and partnership with the members of the Group of Eight and the countries of the Greater Middle East in a quest for political, economic, and educational reform and modernization. (Sets forth Trust guidelines.)</summary>
</bill>
