<bill session="116" type="h" number="6077" updated="2022-03-02T16:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Woman&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Right To Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that women seeking an abortion are notified, before giving informed consent to receive an abortion, of the medical risks associated with the abortion procedure and the major developmental characteristics of the unborn child.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Woman&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Right To Know Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2020-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2020-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3388" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-13T18:05:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Woman's Right To Know Act

This bill specifies requirements for&#160;informed consent that health care providers must obtain before performing an abortion procedure.

Providers must present a woman seeking an abortion with an authorization form at least 24 hours before performing the procedure. The form must (1) include specified information concerning gestational age, associated developmental characteristics,&#160;and medical risks; (2) disclose penalties&#160;that&#160;providers may face for failing to obtain the requisite informed consent; and (3) include an affirmation that the individual signing the form understands the information. The form must be signed and witnessed in person and retained in the medical file.

Providers do not&#160;have to obtain such consent if, in reasonable medical judgment, obtaining it would pose a greater risk of death or substantial physical impairment of a major bodily function, excluding psychological or emotional conditions, of the pregnant woman.

The bill also establishes civil penalties for providers who do not comply with these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
