<bill session="119" type="h" number="851" updated="2025-11-19T03:49:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DOT Victim and Survivor Advocate Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DOT Victim and Survivor Advocate Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the position of National Roadway Safety Advocate within the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="415" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-27T17:48:11Z" status="Introduced in House">DOT Victim and Survivor Advocate Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish the position of National Roadway Safety Advocate to work directly with victims and survivors of road crashes and their families (i.e., stakeholders).

Specifically, the purposes of the advocate are to (1) document and communicate recommendations from stakeholders to DOT on the needs, objectives, plans, approaches, content, and accomplishments of DOT's roadway safety programs and activities; and (2) serve as a resource and point of contact for stakeholders on relevant roadway safety issues.

The bill specifies that the advocate position must be filled by a career appointment.

The bill prohibits the advocate from taking certain actions, such as

creating or authorizing DOT policies, priorities, or activities; ordisclosing or discussing any enforcement matters that are under investigation or in litigation.The advocate must submit an annual report to DOT highlighting systemic issues relating to roadway safety based on information provided by stakeholders. The report must include recommendations on how to remedy the issues.</summary>
</bill>
