<bill session="116" type="s" number="4562" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Health Data Improvement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Health Data Improvement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the collection and availability of health data with respect to Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2020-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2020-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7948" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-26T17:17:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Health Data Improvement Act of 2020

This bill expands tribal access to public health care data and public health surveillance programs. It also reauthorizes through FY2025 the National Center for Health Statistics, which is part of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), and requires the CDC to take certain actions to address the collection and availability of health data for American Indians and Alaska Natives.

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services must (1) establish a strategy for providing data access to Indian tribes and tribal epidemiology centers; and (2) make available all requested data related to health care and public health surveillance programs and activities to the Indian Health Service, tribes, tribal organizations, and tribal epidemiology centers.

Next, the CDC must make grants to and enter into contracts with tribes, tribal organizations, and tribal epidemiology centers for data collection and related activities.

Among other things, the CDC must (1) develop guidance for state and local health agencies to improve birth and death record data for American Indians and Alaska Natives; (2) enter into cooperative agreements with tribes, tribal organizations, urban Indian organizations, and tribal epidemiology centers to analyze and address certain inaccuracies related to records for American Indians and Alaska Natives; (3) adopt uniform standards for the collection of health data on race and ethnicity; and (4) encourage states to enter into data sharing agreements with tribes and tribal epidemiology centers to improve the quality and accuracy of health data.</summary>
</bill>
