<bill session="117" type="h" number="4733" updated="2022-12-31T05:04:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To deem certain voyages transporting passengers between ports or places within the United States in compliance with certain requirements upon calling on a port owned by an Indian Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Tribal Tourism Sovereignty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Tourism Sovereignty Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-05T15:07:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Tribal Tourism Sovereignty Act

 This bill allows covered passenger vessels (e.g., foreign-flagged cruise ships) to comply with the foreign-stop requirement by calling on ports or places owned by an Indian tribe. Under current law, these vessels may not transport passengers from one U.S. port to another without stopping in a foreign country.

The bill allows a voyage transporting passengers to call on a port owned by an Indian tribe if the voyage (1) is made by a covered passenger vessel that complies with security and safety requirements and certain training for crew members, and (2) employs alien crew members with valid nonimmigrant work visas. A vessel performing such a voyage must receive permission from the tribe to dock at a port or place owned by the tribe and disembark passengers on tribal lands.

In addition, the bill outlines tribal powers and privileges, including that the tribe shall have the authority to levy and collect fees from port calls.</summary>
</bill>
