<bill session="108" type="s" number="2634" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:24Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to support the planning, implementation, and evaluation of organized activities involving statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies, to authorize grants to institutions of higher education to reduce student mental and behavioral health problems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An act to amend the Public Health Service Act to support the planning, implementation, and evaluation of organized activities involving statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies, to provide funds for campus mental and behavioral health service centers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Public Health Service Act to support the planning, implementation, and evaluation of organized activities involving statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies, to authorize grants to institutions of higher education to reduce student mental and behavioral health problems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2004-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000439" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000102" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000154" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2004-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-07-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7864-7867" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7864-7867" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09T09:06:15-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T19:29:06-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barton (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T19:29:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6865-6874" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T19:29:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2634.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T20:15:26-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09T12:18:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6921-6922" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="433" datetime="2004-09-09T12:30:09-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 352 - 64 (Roll no. 433).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/8/2004 H6865-6868" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09T12:30:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09T12:30:17-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="pingpong" datetime="2004-09-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to House amendments to Senate bill by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9020-9023" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 9/10/2004 S9083-9086" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendments"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-10-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-10-21" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-355" type="public" datetime="2004-10-21">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-355.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4557" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2175" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4799" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mental depression"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-13T16:51:20Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 9, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award a grant to an additional research, training, and technical assistance center to provide information, training, and technical assistance to various entities, including for: (1) developing or continuing statewide or tribal suicide early intervention and prevention strategies; (2) ensuring the surveillance of such strategies; (3) studying the costs and effectiveness of such strategies; (4) promoting the sharing of data regarding youth suicide; and (5) evaluating and disseminating outcomes and best practices of mental and behavioral health services at institutions of higher education.

Requires the Secretary to award grants or cooperative agreements to various entities to design early intervention and prevention strategies that will complement the State-sponsored statewide or tribal youth suicide prevention strategies developed under this Act, including by: (1) providing for the timely assessment, treatment, or referral for mental health or substance abuse services of youth at risk for suicide; (2) offering access to services and care to youth with diverse linguistic and cultural backgrounds; and (3) conducting annual self-evaluations of outcomes and activities. Provides grants for three years.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award grants or cooperative agreements to States or Indian tribes to: (1) develop and implement the suicide prevention strategies in schools, juvenile justice systems, and other child and youth support entities; (2) support organizations actively involved in such strategies and in developing and continuing such strategies; (3) provide grants to institutions of higher education to coordinate the implementation of such strategies; (4) collect and analyze data to monitor the effectiveness of suicide prevention services and for research, technical assistance, and policy developments; and (5) assist eligible entities in achieving their targets for youth suicide reductions. Limits grant or cooperative agreement awards to one per State.

Requires States to give preference to certain entities in providing assistance, including those that: (1) provide suicide prevention services to at-risk youth and that are integrated with child and youth support organizations; (2) provide immediate support and information resources to families of at-risk youth; (3) offer appropriate post-suicide intervention services, care, and information; (4) train professionals in suicide prevention services and in effectively identifying youth who are at risk; and (5) obtain informed written consent from a parent or legal guardian of an at-risk child before involving the child in an intervention and prevention program. Requires 85 percent of grant funds to be used to provide direct services and at least 5% to be awarded to institutions of higher education.

Requires the Secretary to coordinate and collaborate on policy development with relevant Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) agencies and suicide working groups and to consult with the private sector on policy development with respect to suicide prevention strategies.

States that this Act does not: (1) require suicide assessment, early intervention, or treatment services for youth whose parents or legal guardians object based on the parents' or legal guardians' religious beliefs or moral objections; or (2) allow school personnel to require that a student obtain any medication as a condition of attending school or receiving services.

Prohibits funds appropriated under this Act from being used to pay for or refer for abortion.

Requires that States and entities receiving funding under this Act obtain prior written, informed consent from the child's parent or legal guardian for assessment services, school-sponsored programs, and treatment involving medication related to youth suicide conducted in elementary and secondary schools, except in: (1) an emergency where it is necessary to protect the immediate health and safety of a student; or (2) other instances defined by the State where parental consent cannot be reasonably obtained.

Provides that States that have rates of suicide that significantly exceed the national average be given preference in the event of limited appropriations.

Allows the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services, to award competitive matching grants to institutions of higher education to enhance services for students with mental and behavioral health problems that can lead to school failure, such as depression, substance abuse, and suicide attempts, so that students can successfully complete their studies. Provides that institutions receiving such grants must agree to use such funds only for: (1) educational seminars; (2) the operation of hot lines; (3) the preparation of informational material, including materials for families to increase awareness of potential mental and behavioral health issues of students; (4) training programs for students and campus personnel to respond effectively to students with mental and behavioral health problems that can lead to school failure; or (5) the creation of a networking infrastructure to link colleges and universities that do not have mental health services with health care providers who can treat mental and behavioral health problems. Sets forth application requirements.

Sets forth reporting requirements.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
