<bill session="117" type="s" number="5140" updated="2023-08-22T15:45:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for rental assistance for homeless or at-risk Indian veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for rental assistance for homeless or at-risk Indian veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2022-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2022-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2022-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5195" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2264" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4670" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5186" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9439" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-22T15:44:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides statutory authority for the Tribal HUD-VASH program, which provides rental assistance and supportive services to Indian veterans who are homeless or at risk of homelessness and living in or near an area where a tribe or tribally designated housing entity provides assistance for affordable housing.

The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) must use at least 5% of rental assistance amounts under the HUD-VASH program, which provides housing assistance to homeless veterans, for the Tribal HUD-VASH program. The Tribal HUD-VASH program must be carried out by HUD in conjunction with the Department of Veterans Affairs.

Under the program, grants must be made to entities eligible for housing assistance block grants. HUD may make renewal grants to entities that have received prior program grants.</summary>
</bill>
