<bill session="116" type="h" number="8163" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Countering China Through American Export Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering China Through American Export Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit support for deals with Chinese state-owned enterprises, to increase the set-aside goal for the Program on China and Transformational Exports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-11T20:43:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Countering China Through American Export Competitiveness Act

This bill modifies certain responsibilities of the Export-Import Bank of the United States related to its Program on China and Transformational Exports. The program supports financing at rates and on terms that are fully competitive with rates and terms established by China in order to (1) directly neutralize export subsidies for competing goods and services, or (2) advance the comparative leadership of the United States through specified exports.

The bill prohibits the bank generally from guaranteeing, insuring, or extending credit for which the end user, lender, or obligor is China. The bill also raises from 20% to 33% the dedicated amount that the bank should reserve for the program, and it sets the default rate limit for program loans at 5%.

The bill authorizes the bank to waive some, or all, of the domestic content requirements that would otherwise apply to a transaction if it determines that doing so would be in the national security interest of the United States. The bill also establishes an advisory committee to advise the bank on the development of policies and programs that support the expansion of the bank's financial commitments in accordance with the program to counter China.</summary>
</bill>
