<bill session="109" type="s" number="2291" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:04Z">
  <state datetime="2006-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Responsible Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of a biodefense injury compensation program and to provide indemnification for producers of countermeasures.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2006-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2006-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2006-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2006-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1361-1363" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="3982" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="3983" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Epidemics"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Smallpox"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-04-20T15:29:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Responsible Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness Act - Repeals the Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness Act (Division C of the Department of Defense, Emergency Supplemental Appropriations to Address Hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico, and Pandemic Influenza Act, 2006).

Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Biodefense Injury Compensation Program to provide compensation for death or any injury, illness, disability, or condition that is likely to have been caused by the administration of a covered countermeasure pursuant to a declaration by the Secretary of Health and Human Services that an actual or potential bioterrorist incident or public health emergency makes such administration to a category of individuals advisable.

Requires the Secretary: (1) after making such a declaration, to enter into a contract for the Institute of Medicine to provide its recommendations on the injuries, disabilities, illnesses, and conditions likely to have been caused by the countermeasure; and (2) after receiving such recommendations, to specify those injuries, disabilities, illnesses, and conditions deemed to be included in the Vaccine Injury Table.

Sets the effective date for such Program as November 25, 2002.

Extends liability protection for health professionals administering small pox countermeasures to include covered countermeasures under this Act. Excludes from such protection the administration by a qualified person of a covered countermeasure to an individual who was not within a category of individuals covered by the declaration where such qualified person did not have reasonable grounds to believe such individual was within a category.

Makes the United States liable for any claims arising out of the manufacture, distribution, or administration of a covered countermeasure, including claims brought by U.S. military personnel.</summary>
</bill>
