<bill session="117" type="h" number="3274" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Fab Lab Network, a nonprofit organization consisting of a national network of local digital fabrication facilities providing universal access to advanced manufacturing tools for workforce development, STEM education, developing inventions, creating businesses, producing personalized products, mitigating risks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1661" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-08T19:01:03Z" status="Introduced in House">National Fab Lab Network Act of 2021

This bill establishes the National Fab Lab Network as a nonprofit corporation.

A fab lab is a digital fabrication facility with the capabilities necessary to create form and function from digital designs. The bill requires the National Fab Lab Network to (1) endeavor to establish at least one fab lab in each congressional district and additional labs according to local demand, (2) link fab labs into a national network and promote their further expansion across the country, (3) serve as a training and operating resource for fab labs and their leaders and mentors, (4) maintain a national registry of fab labs, (5) provide standards and protocols for connecting fab labs, and (6) assist fab labs in producing fab labs.</summary>
</bill>
