<bill session="108" type="s" number="1217" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:44Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keeping Seniors Safe From Falls Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to intensify programs with respect to research and related activities concerning falls among older adults.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to expand and intensify programs with respect to research and related activities concerning elder falls.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Keeping Seniors Safe From Falls Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Keeping Seniors Safe From Falls Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elder Fall Prevention Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2004-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2004-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2003-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7554-7555"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Gregg with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-395.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-10-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="785">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 785.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11508-11510" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11509-11510" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11508-11509" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T09:45:12-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3513" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Continuum of care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the aged"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Life care communities"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Elder Fall Prevention Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Administration on Aging within the Department of Health and Human Services to: (1) oversee and support a three-year national education campaign by the National Safety Council focusing on ways to reduce the risk of elder falls and prevent repeat falls; and (2) provide grants for State coalitions for local education campaigns addressing reduction and prevention of elder falls.Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) conduct and support research concerning various topics, including: high-risk elders, risk and protective factors, fall reduction strategies, fall prevention interventions, diagnosis and treatment of victims, barriers to adopting proven interventions, and the effectiveness of community programs in preventing assisted living and nursing home falls; (2) support the development of ways to reduce falls among very high risk elders; and (3) award grants to enable organizations to provide professional education for physicians and health professionals in elder fall prevention.Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to oversee and support demonstration and research projects to be carried out by the Council and other qualified organizations in the following areas: (1) a multi-State demonstration project assessing the utility of targeted fall risk screening and referral programs; (2) programs designed for community-dwelling elderly; (3) programs targeting newly-discharged fall victims at high risk for second falls; and (4) private-public partnerships to develop technologies to prevent falls and prevent or reduce injuries from falls. Requires the Secretary to provide grants to design and implement fall prevention programs in residential and institutional settings and to provide one or more grants for a multi-State demonstration project to implement and evaluate fall prevention programs.Directs the Secretary to review the effects of falls on the costs of the Medicare and Medicaid Programs and the potential for reducing costs by expanding covered services. States that such review shall include a review of reimbursement policies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-395</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
