<bill session="110" type="h" number="5541" updated="2022-02-27T13:49:45Z">
  <state datetime="2008-07-09T15:10:20-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-09T15:10:20-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Land Assistance, Management and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FLAME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Assistance, Management and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLAME Act</title>
    <title type="display">FLAME Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a supplemental funding source for catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities on Department of the Interior and National Forest System lands, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a cohesive wildland fire management strategy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000357" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001229" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001228" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001058" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000962" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000180" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001037" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000283" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000113" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000552" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000085" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2008-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000573" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000097" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2008-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001171" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001153" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000749" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2008-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2008-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2008-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E331-332"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-704, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 27, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>House Committee on The Budget Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 27, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-27">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 11, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-27">
      <text>House Committee on The Budget Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 11, 2008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T14:32:42-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T14:33:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6285-6291" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T14:33:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5541.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2008-07-09T15:10:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6285-6286" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09T15:10:23-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3256" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-11-10T20:01:35Z" status="Passed House amended">Federal Land Assistance, Management and Enhancement Act or FLAME Act - (Sec. 2) Establishes in the Treasury the Federal Land Assistance, Management, and Enhancement Fund (the Flame Fund).

Requires amounts in the Flame Fund to be made available to the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretaries) to pay the costs of catastrophic emergency wildland fire suppression activities that are separate from amounts annually appropriated for the predicted annual workload for such activities.

Authorizes appropriations for the Flame Fund. States the intent of Congress with respect to the expenditure of amounts appropriated to the Fund. Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the designation of certain appropriations as amounts necessary to meet emergency needs.

Instructs the Secretaries to notify specified congressional committees whenever only an estimated two months worth of funding remains in the Fund.

Provides for the transfer of unobligated wildland fire suppression funds into the Flame Fund.

Provides for amounts in the Flame Fund to be made available to the Secretaries only after such Secretaries issue a declaration that a wildland fire suppression activity is eligible for funding through the Fund. Sets forth the criteria upon which such a declaration shall be based.

Provides for the continuation of funding for anticipated and predicted wildland fire suppression activities within appropriate agency budgets. States that use of the additional funding made available through the Flame Fund is intended to supplement the budgeted and appropriated agency funding and is to be used only for purposes and in instances consistent with this section.

Provides that, all amounts in the Flame Fund and all funds appropriated for wildland fire suppression on federal land, must be obligated before the transfer of funds from non-fire accounts for wildland fire suppression.

Directs the Secretaries to establish an accounting and reporting system for the Flame Fund compatible with existing National Fire Plan reporting procedures.

Requires the Secretaries to annually report on the use of the funds from the Flame Fund, together with recommendations that the Secretaries may have to improve administrative control and oversight of the Fund. Requires such report to be made available to the public.

(Sec. 3) Requires the Secretaries to submit a report that contains a cohesive wildland fire management strategy, consistent with the recommendations of the Comptroller General.

Sets forth the elements of the strategy. Includes a system for ensuring that the highest priority fuels reduction projects are being funded first.

Ensures that owners of adjacent private land are notified before any prescribed fire is used on National Forest System land.

(Sec. 4) Directs the Secretaries to conduct a review, using independent panels, of each wild fire incident that incurs expenses exceeding $10 million, and to submit a report containing the results of each review conducted.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretaries to develop regional maps of communities most at risk of wildfire and in need of hazardous fuel treatment and maintenance.

Requires such maps to identify priority areas for hazardous fuels reduction projects, including: (1) at-risk communities in fire-prone areas of the wildland-urban interface; (2) watersheds and municipal drinking water sources; (3) emergency evacuation corridors; (4) electricity transmission corridors; and (5) low-capacity or low-income communities.

Authorizes the Secretaries to provide cost-share grants to fire-ready communities which may be used for: (1) education programs to raise awareness of homeowners and citizens about wildland fire protection practices, including FireWise or other similar programs; (2) training programs for local firefighters on wildland firefighting techniques and approaches; (3) equipment acquisition to facilitate wildland fire preparedness; and (4) implementation of a community wildfire protection plan.

Instructs the Secretaries, in developing any wildland fire cost-share agreement with a state forester or equivalent official, to encourage the state and local communities involved to become fire-ready communities.

Authorizes appropriations to carry out this section.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-704</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
