<bill session="117" type="s" number="3359" updated="2022-12-30T03:34:02Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CREATE Graduates Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Correctly Recognizing Educational Achievements To Empower Graduates Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CREATE Graduates Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to award grants to States to support efforts at institutions of higher education to increase degree attainment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2021-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4533" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2379" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-12T18:47:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Correctly Recognizing Educational Achievements To Empower Graduates Act or the CREATE Graduates Act

This bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to take specified actions to increase postsecondary degree attainment.

Specifically, the bill requires ED to provide grants to states to support institutions of higher education in awarding associate degrees to students who have accumulated enough credits.

Additionally, the bill allows the release of a transfer student's educational records from an institution of postsecondary education where a student earned credit for coursework to an institution of postsecondary education where the student was previously enrolled in order to apply the student's coursework and credits toward completion of a recognized postsecondary credential, such as an associate's degree. In particular, the bill allows ED to provide funding to an institution of postsecondary education that releases a student's records of postsecondary coursework and credits without the consent of the student or the student's parents if the student provides written consent prior to receiving the credential.</summary>
</bill>
