<bill session="108" type="s" number="1205" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide discounted housing for teachers and other staff in rural areas of States with a population less than 1,000,000 and with a high population of Native Americans or Alaska Natives.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000888"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2003-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7495-7496"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7496" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-03T17:26:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Teacher Housing Act of 2003 - Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide funds to an eligible State (with a population of fewer than one million people) to make grants to eligible school districts located within a qualified municipality (with a population of 6,500 or fewer and no direct access to either a State or interstate highway system) within the boundaries of Indian lands, one or more Native villages, or land owned by one or more Village Corporations).



Requires such grants to be used for: (1) construction of new housing units within a qualified municipality; (2) the purchase and rehabilitation of existing housing units within a qualified municipality; or (3) the rehabilitation of housing units within a qualified municipality that are owned by an eligible school district.

Requires the occupants of such housing units to be teachers or other staff employed by the public school district in which the housing units are located.</summary>
</bill>
