<bill session="117" type="s" number="576" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:16Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Winter Commerce Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 14, United States Code, to require the Coast Guard to conduct icebreaking operations in the Great Lakes to minimize commercial disruption in the winter months, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Great Lakes Winter Commerce Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Winter Commerce Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2021-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-12-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="197">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 197.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1561" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-02T13:31:50Z" status="Reported to Senate">Great Lakes Winter Commerce Act of 2021

This bill directs the U.S. Coast Guard to conduct icebreaking operations in the Great Lakes in accordance with specific performance standards.

Specifically, the Coast Guard must

 keep channels and harbors in the Great Lakes open to navigation not less than 90% of the hours that commercial vessels and ferries attempt to transit ice-covered waterways; and in a year in which the Great Lakes are not open to navigation because of ice of a thickness that occurs on average only once every 10 years, keep channels and harbors open to navigation at least 70% of the hours that commercial vessels and ferries attempt to transit ice-covered waterways. Additionally, the Coast Guard must establish and maintain a database for collecting, archiving, and disseminating data on icebreaking operations and commercial vessel transit in the Great Lakes during ice season.

The bill also directs the Coast Guard to acquire a Great Lakes icebreaker that is at least as capable as Coast Guard Cutter Mackinaw.

The Government Accountability Office must submit to Congress a report on the Coast Guard Great Lakes icebreaking program.</summary>
</bill>
