<bill session="111" type="h" number="546" updated="2019-11-15T21:51:29Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solar Stimulus for Job Creation and Energy Independence Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Solar Stimulus for Job Creation and Energy Independence Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat certain solar energy credits as refundable credits, to allow a new refundable credit for equipment used to manufacture solar energy property, to waive the application of the subsidized financing rules to such property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001228" joined="2009-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2009-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="284" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-06T20:34:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Solar Stimulus for Job Creation and Energy Independence Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide for the refundability of the residential energy efficiency tax credit for solar electric and water heating property, and for business-related solar energy tax credits, through 2010; (2) allow an election to take an increased depreciation allowance for solar energy property until 2011; (3) exempt solar energy property from private activity bond usage and loan financing rules; and (4) allow a refundable energy tax credit for investment in property used to manufacture solar energy property.

Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to limit to 25 years the contract period for federal purchases of renewable energy.</summary>
</bill>
