<bill session="111" type="h" number="2255" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:18Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 to ensure that actions taken by regulatory agencies are subject to that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000450"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2009-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2010-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, the Budget, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU09" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-19T13:57:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2009 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require reports on federal mandates to include: (1) an assessment of the prospective costs of carrying out changes to a condition of federal assistance being imposed on participating state, local, or tribal governments and how these costs compare with the funds being authorized; (2) for reauthorizations, an assessment of the additional costs of changes in those conditions compared with the changes in funding being authorized; (3) in cases where a bill or joint resolution provides necessary sums, an estimate of that amount; and (4) an identification and description of any reasonably foreseeable indirect costs to such governments or the private sector from implementing the federal mandate.

Repeals a provision excluding independent regulatory agencies from reporting requirements.

 Makes requirements under this Act applicable to general notice of any final rule that includes such a mandate.</summary>
</bill>
