<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3303</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:20:01Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:20:01Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-05-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg04</systemCode>
            <name>National Parks Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2010-05-19T21:09:27Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-09-27T20:37:16Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-07-21T21:04:33Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-05-04T19:39:12Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-317</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Chimney Rock National Monument Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>5223</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-05-07</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 603.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-317.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-317.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg04</systemCode>
            <name>National Parks Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-645.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001267</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bennet, Michael F. [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Bennet</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000038</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Mark [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARK</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-08-26T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3303, Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21790</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on July 21, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-08-26T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3303, Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21790</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on July 21, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Colorado</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Monuments and memorials</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-05-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-06-22T18:12:30Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Chimney Rock National Monument Act of 2010 - Designates the Chimney Rock National Monument in Colorado to preserve, protect, and restore the archeological, anthropological, geological, hydrologic, biological, visual, and scenic resources of Chimney Rock. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make minor adjustments to the boundaries of the Monument for the inclusion of significant archaeological resources discovered on adjacent public land. </p> <p>Requires management of, and authorizes use of, the Monument as a unit of San Juan National Forest. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to carry out vegetative management treatments within the Monument, with the exception of timber harvesting and the use of prescribed fire, which may only be used when necessary to address the risk of wildfire, insects, or diseases.</p> <p>Prohibits uses of the Monument other than those authorized by the Secretary. Includes as authorized uses: (1) construction of a visitor's center and related exhibit and curatorial facilities to interpret the Monument's scientific and cultural resources; (2) scientific research (including archaeological research) and educational and interpretive uses; (3) acquisition and display of artifacts; (4) recreational use of mountain bikes and motorized vehicles; (5) installation and maintenance of a certain public utility right of way; and (6) grazing uses. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Monument, which shall include: (1) providing for the continued use of the Monument by Indian tribes for traditional ceremonies and as a source for traditional plants and other materials; and (2) specifying permitted uses of artifacts. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-03-16T16:29:33Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act - (Sec. 3) Designates the Chimney Rock National Monument in Colorado to preserve, protect, and restore the cultural, historic, natural, educational, and scenic resources of Chimney Rock and adjacent land and to provide for public interpretation and recreation consistent with the protection of such resources. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make minor adjustments to the boundaries of the Monument to reflect the inclusion of significant archaeological resources discovered on adjacent National Forest System land. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Sets forth provisions for the administration of the Monument. Permits only such uses of the Monument that would further the purposes specified above. </p> <p>Requires the Monument to be administered according to the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act and the policy specified in the American Indian Religious Freedom Act. </p> <p>Allows for continued use of the Monument by Indian tribes for traditional ceremonies and as a source of traditional plants and other materials. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to carry out vegetative management treatments within the Monument, with the exception of timber harvesting which shall only be used when necessary for ecosystem restoration or the control of fire, insects, or diseases. </p> <p>Limits the use of motor vehicles and mountain bikes in the Monument to roads and trails identified as appropriate for such use. </p> <p>Permits grazing in the Monument where established prior to this Act's enactment. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in this Act precluding upgrading an existing utility right-of-way through the Monument. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to construct an education and interpretive center to interpret the Monument's scientific and cultural resources for the public. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Monument in consultation with Indian tribes having a cultural or historic tie to Chimney Rock. Requires an opportunity for public comment on the plan. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to acquire, by purchase from willing sellers, donation, or exchange, land and interests within or adjacent to the Monument. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) Withdraws federal land in the Monument and any acquired land from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws, except for the issuance of gas pipeline rights-of-way within existing easements. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) Specifies this Act's effect on: (1) valid water rights, (2) federal reserved water rights, (3) specified tribal rights, (4) fish and wildlife on public lands in Colorado, and (5) buffer zones or private property adjacent to the Monument. </p> <p>(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish the Chimney Rock National Monument in the State of Colorado.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Chimney Rock National Monument Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Chimney Rock National Monument Establishment Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-27T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3303rs/xml/BILLS-111s3303rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-05-04T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3303is/xml/BILLS-111s3303is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 603.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
