<bill session="117" type="s" number="4784" updated="2023-09-06T19:30:04Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of the Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument in the State of Maine, to improve public access to the National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2022-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-10T01:52:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument Access Act

This bill modifies the boundaries of the Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument in Maine.

The boundaries of the monument shall be the boundaries depicted on the map titled Katahdin Woods and Waters National Monument Proposed Boundary Revision and dated July 2022.

The Department of the Interior may acquire, by purchase from a willing seller, donation, or exchange (1) land and interests in land within the boundary of the monument, and (2) land and interests in land for access into the monument from roads and communities adjacent to or in the vicinity of the monument. Nothing in this bill authorizes the use of eminent domain to acquire land or an interest in land.

Any land added to the monument shall be managed to preserve existing hunting, fishing, and snowmobile uses.

The bill allows for the gathering by hand of fiddlehead ferns in the monument for personal use and consumption by the general public.</summary>
</bill>
