<bill session="116" type="h" number="7348" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal PFAS Research Evaluation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the National Academies to study and report on a Federal research agenda to advance the understanding of PFAS, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal PFAS Research Evaluation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2020-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-01T18:11:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal PFAS Research Evaluation Act

This bill requires various studies and reports on the exposure, hazards, and management of perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS. These substances are man-made and may have adverse human health effects. A variety of products contain the compounds, such as nonstick cookware or weatherproof clothing.

Specifically, the bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM) to conduct a two-phase study and report on the research and development needed to advance human exposure estimation and toxicity hazard estimation of individual or total PFAS.

The bill also requires the EPA to jointly enter into an agreement with NASEM to conduct a study and submit a report on the research and development needed to advance the understanding of the extent and implications of environmental contamination by PFAS, how to manage and treat such contamination, and the development of safe alternatives.

Finally, the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy must submit an implementation plan for federal PFAS research, development, and demonstration activities, taking into account the recommendations of the NASEM reports.</summary>
</bill>
