<bill session="118" type="h" number="905" updated="2025-11-19T04:07:34Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Protections for Domestic Violence and Stalking Survivors Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Protections for Domestic Violence and Stalking Survivors Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to define intimate partner to include someone with whom there is or was a dating relationship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2023-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001091" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2024-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2024-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="321" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T20:04:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Protections for Domestic Violence and Stalking Survivors Act of 2023

This bill extends federal firearms-related restrictions to individuals who are convicted of a misdemeanor crime of stalking.

The term&#160;misdemeanor crime of stalking&#160;means an offense that is a misdemeanor under federal, state, tribal, or local law and has a course of harassment, intimidation, or surveillance that (1) causes emotional distress, or (2) places a person in reasonable fear of harm to themselves, an immediate family member, an individual who shares or has shared a residence, an intimate partner, or a pet. The term intimate partner includes an individual who is or was in a dating relationship with the person or any other individual similarly situated to a spouse.

Additionally, the bill extends federal firearms-related restrictions to individuals who are subject to a court order restraining them from harassing, stalking, or threatening an individual who is in a current or former dating relationship with them or who is similarly situated to a spouse. Currently, federal firearms-related restrictions generally only apply to individuals who are subject to a court order restraining them from harassing, stalking, or threatening a co-parent of a child, a current or former spouse, or a current or former cohabitant.</summary>
</bill>
