<bill session="116" type="s" number="2728" updated="2022-11-01T04:32:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Counterintelligence Threat Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Counterintelligence Threat Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Department of Homeland Security counterintelligence vetting task force, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4892" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6916" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-19T19:35:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeland Security Counterintelligence Threat Reduction Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to take various actions related to counterintelligence activities.

DHS shall establish a counterintelligence vetting task force to report to Congress recommendations to improve counterintelligence vetting for DHS programs.

DHS shall also develop counterintelligence awareness training as part of an established program for collecting information about nonimmigrant foreign students and other exchange program participants. DHS shall require appropriate faculty from approved educational institutions and exchange visitor programs to participate in the training.

DHS shall take various actions related to the program for collecting information about exchange program participants, such as identifying degrees and fields of study that are sensitive for homeland security and counterintelligence purposes.

DHS shall notify Congress if it decides to not extend the existence of the Homeland Security Academic Advisory Council.</summary>
</bill>
