<bill session="117" type="h" number="6747" updated="2022-12-30T04:18:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Courts Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Courts Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 11, District of Columbia Official Code, to modernize the rules and procedures for the service of jurors in District of Columbia courts, to adjust compensation rates for criminal justice investigators and attorneys representing indigent defenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E150"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-13T13:53:53Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia Courts Improvement Act of 2022

This bill amends certain laws relating to the District of Columbia (DC) courts.

The bill revises and modifies the rules and procedures for the service of jurors in the DC courts, including to allow the exclusion from jury service of an individual who is 70 years of age or older upon the person's request. Grand and petit jurors serving in the Superior Court shall receive fees and allowances at the same rates provided for fees and allowances paid to grand and petit jurors appearing in the district courts of the United States.

The bill adjusts the amount of compensation paid to attorneys representing indigent defendants in criminal cases and criminal investigators in DC courts to equal the amount that is paid to such persons with regard to a U.S. district court.

The bill also

 modifies the process for appointment of the Register of Wills; authorizes retroactive pay adjustments for employees of the DC courts; revises certain administrative functions, including those concerning use of fees, acceptance of gifts, procurement of motor vehicles, and use of space in courts buildings; and revises the administration of the Small Claims and Conciliation Branch, including regarding the use of arbitration, mediation, and conciliation to settle cases.</summary>
</bill>
