<bill session="118" type="h" number="6312" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Inaugural Fund Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inaugural Fund Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit certain donations to Inaugural Committees, to establish limitations on donations to Inaugural Committees, to require certain reporting by Inaugural Committees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2024-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2024-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2023-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2023-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5048" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-18T01:21:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Inaugural Fund Integrity Act

This bill limits donations to inaugural committees and requires these committees to disclose donations and disbursements.

Specifically, inaugural committees may not solicit, accept, or receive donations from corporations or foreign nationals. An individual may not make a donation in the name of another individual or authorize his or her name to be used to make such a donation. In addition, foreign nationals may not make donations or make promises to make donations to inaugural committees.

Further, the bill caps the amount an individual may donate to an inaugural committee.

Donations to inaugural committees may not be converted to personal use.

Finally, inaugural committees must report certain information on donations and disbursements to the Federal Election Commission.</summary>
</bill>
