<bill session="118" type="h" number="4557" updated="2025-11-19T04:26:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Manufactured Housing Tenant&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Bill of Rights Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufactured Housing Tenant&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Bill of Rights Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that federally backed financing for the construction, rehabilitation, or purchase of manufactured home communities is available only for communities whose owner has implemented minimum consumer protections in the lease agreements with residents of all manufactured home communities owned by such owner, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000620"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000477" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2024-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2024-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2204" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-01T19:28:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Manufactured Housing Tenant's Bill of Rights Act of 2023 

This bill requires manufactured housing communities and home parks to meet minimum consumer protections to be eligible for certain federally-backed loans for the construction, substantial rehabilitation, or purchase of these communities. Specifically, the Department of Housing and Urban Development is prohibited from insuring such a loan, and Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac are prohibited from purchasing such a loan, unless a borrower provides specified tenant protections, including

 one-year renewable lease terms, unless there is good cause for nonrenewal; at least a 60-day advance notice of any increase in rent, or of a sale or closure of the community; a five-day grace period for rent payments; and a right for a tenant to sell a manufactured home within a reasonable time period after eviction. The bill sets forth penalties for violations of these protections.

The bill also establishes the Manufactured Home Company Lending Standards Commission to propose additional consumer protection standards.</summary>
</bill>
