<bill session="108" type="s" number="337" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:50Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Arsenic-Treated Residential-Use Wood Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act and the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit the use of arsenic-treated lumber as mulch, compost, or a soil amendment, and to prohibit the manufacture of arsenic-treated wood for use as playground equipment for children, fences, walkways, or decks or for other residential or occupational purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arsenic-Treated Residential-Use Wood Prohibition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-11-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2122"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3629" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Arsenic"/>
    <term name="Building materials"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compost"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Furniture industry"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Playgrounds"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Warning labels"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-12-30T16:20:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Arsenic-Treated Residential-Use Wood Prohibition Act - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to: (1) list CCA-treated wood (wood treated with a pesticide that is an inorganic arsenical or chromated copper arsenical) as a hazardous waste; (2) require disposal of discarded CCA wood, notwithstanding regulations exempting certain solid wastes from the definition of hazardous waste, in a lined landfill with a leachate system and groundwater monitoring system; (3) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct an assessment of the risks of CCA-treated wood production, processing, and use; and (4) direct the Administrator to promulgate regulations for the cessation and prohibition of production of such wood, with exceptions.

 Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) to require the Administrator to promulgate regulations prohibiting the use of CCA-treated wood (for FIFRA purposes, wood treated with a pesticide that is a chromated copper arsenical) in the manufacture, production, or use of any product that may be used for or by children or for mulch, compost, a soil amendment, or any other residential or occupational purpose.

 Requires the Administrator to: (1) develop and conduct an educational program to assist consumers, State and local governments, school systems, and other institutions in testing arsenic levels and making decisions concerning CCA-treated wood containment, removal, and decontamination; and (2) establish a pilot program of grants and technical assistance to assist school systems in removal of playground and other equipment containing CCA-treated wood and remediation activities.</summary>
</bill>
