<bill session="116" type="s" number="4219" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Long Island All-Water Helicopter Route Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long Island All-Water Helicopter Route Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the special air traffic rule for civil helicopters operating VFR along the North Shore, Long Island, New York, to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to promulgate a new special air traffic rule, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4267" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7730" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-12T17:11:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Long Island All-Water Helicopter Route Act of 2020

This bill extends the special air traffic rule for civil helicopters operating under visual flight rules (VFR) along the North Shore in Long Island, New York to use the New York North Shore Helicopter Route. (VFR are a set of regulations under which a pilot operates an aircraft in weather conditions generally clear enough to allow the pilot to see where the aircraft is going.)

The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must conduct a rulemaking proceeding to promulgate a new special air traffic rule for civil helicopters operating VFR along the North Shore and South Shore of Long Island, New York in accordance with specified requirements of the bill.

A person who pilots a civil helicopter operating VFR along Long Island, New York's northern shoreline or southern shoreline may deviate from the North Shore Helicopter Route or South Shore Helicopter Route requirements: (1) for safety or weather conditions; or (2) when transitioning to or from a destination or point of landing, except for on the North Shore Helicopter Route when departing from or arriving to certain locations.

 If safety or weather conditions cause a person piloting a civil helicopter operating VFR to deviate from either route, the person must submit a one page report to the FAA identifying the condition not later than 14 days after landing.</summary>
</bill>
