<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3073</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:14Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-03-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
        <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-09-02T17:23:14Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-06-30T20:14:57Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-03-04T16:37:54Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-283</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>4755</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-03-05</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-02</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 554.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2010 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-283.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-02</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2010 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-283.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-30</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-04</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1171)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000261</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Levin, Carl [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>CARL</firstName>
        <lastName>LEVIN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <middleName>MILTON</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>V000126</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Voinovich, George V. [R-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>GEORGE</firstName>
        <lastName>VOINOVICH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <middleName>V.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-03-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000367</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Klobuchar, Amy [D-MN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Amy</firstName>
        <lastName>Klobuchar</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-03-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sherrod</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-03-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000457</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Franken, Al [D-MN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Al</firstName>
        <lastName>Franken</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-03-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000770</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Stabenow, Debbie [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Debbie</firstName>
        <lastName>Stabenow</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-03-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000563</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Durbin, Richard J. [D-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Durbin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-03-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001266</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Burris, Roland [D-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Roland</firstName>
        <lastName>Burris</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-05</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001070</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Casey, Robert P., Jr. [D-PA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bob</firstName>
        <lastName>Casey</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000555</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Gillibrand, Kirsten E. [D-NY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kirsten</firstName>
        <lastName>Gillibrand</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-06-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000360</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kirk, Mark Steven [R-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARK</firstName>
        <lastName>KIRK</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>STEVEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-12-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-07-19T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3073, Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21643</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on June 30, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-07-19T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3073, Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21643</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on June 30, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Great Lakes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water quality</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Environmental Protection</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-03-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-09-03T20:13:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to expand the duties of the Great Lakes Program Office by requiring the Office to: (1) provide support for Great Lakes governance and management; and (2) coordinate with the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force.</p> <p>Establishes: (1) the Great Lakes Leadership Council to establish policy, goals, and priorities with respect to Great Lakes protection and restoration, determine a process for participating in international forums, and provide annual input regarding federal budget priorities and levels for Great Lakes protection and restoration; (2) the Great Lakes Management Committee within the Council to report to and provide direction for the Council, monitor and assist implementation activities relating to Great Lakes management, and engage in problem solving regarding Great Lakes management; and (3) the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to report annually to Congress on budgets and restoration activities relating to EPA's organizational elements involved in Great Lakes activities and EPA's reasons for approving or disapproving the Council's recommendations.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for: (1) remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern in the Great Lakes; and (2) the Great Lakes Program.</p> <p>Requires EPA, in coordination with federal partners, to implement a Great Lakes Restoration Initiative which will: (1) identify and support programs to target the most significant environmental problems in the Great Lakes ecosystem; (2) be based on the work of the Task Force and the Council's stakeholders and nongovernmental partners; and (3) represent the government's commitment to significantly advance Great Lakes protection and restoration. Prohibits funding made available to implement the Initiative from being used for water infrastructure activity that is implemented using funds made available under the clean water or drinking water state revolving fund program.</p> <p>Requires federal agencies to: (1) maintain the base level of funding for their Great Lakes activities; and (2) identify new activities to support the environmental goals of the Initiative.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-01-05T19:18:23Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to include as a purpose of such Act to achieve the goals established in the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative Action Plan (Action Plan), the Great Lakes Regional Collaboration Strategy (Strategy), and the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement (Agreement) through: (1) improved organization and definition of mission on the part of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA); (2) the funding of grants, contracts, and interagency agreements for protection, restoration, and pollution control in the Great Lakes area; and (3) improved accountability.</p> <p>Expands the duties of the Great Lakes Program Office to include: (1) providing support for Great Lakes governance and management; and (2) coordinating with the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force (Task Force).</p> <p>Establishes the Great Lakes Leadership Council (Council) to: (1) review, every five years, such Strategy and revise it if necessary; (2) establish annual priorities with respect to Great Lakes protection and restoration; (3) report to Congress, the President, and the public on the progress made in Great Lakes protection and restoration; (4) make recommendations to the Administrator of EPA and the Secretary of State regarding a process for participation in international forums, such as the Agreement, and regarding whether any existing advisory committees are duplicative and should be replaced; and (5) make recommendations to Congress and the President for streamlining the work of existing advisory and coordinating committees. Requires the Council's nonfederal members to provide input annually to the Council and the Task Force on federal budget priorities and funding levels for Great Lakes protection and restoration.<br> </p> <p>Requires the Council to establish the Great Lakes Advisory Committee to report to and provide advice to the Council on monitoring implementation activities relating to Great Lakes management and other relevant Great Lakes issues.</p> <p>Requires the EPA to commence implementation of a new Great Lakes Restoration Initiative (Initiative), which shall: (1) identify programs and projects that are strategically selected to target the most significant environmental problems in the Great Lakes ecosystem; (2) be based on the work of the Task Force, the Council, stakeholders, and nongovernmental partners; and (3) represent the government's commitment to significantly advancing Great Lakes protection and restoration. Requires that the Initiative give priority to work done by nonfederal partners using funding made available for the Great Lakes for priority areas for each fiscal year. Authorizes the Administrator: (1) to transfer funding to agencies to support such Initiative and the Agreement; and (2) make grants for carrying out planning, research, monitoring, outreach, training, studies, surveys, investigations, experiments, demonstration projects, and implementation relating to the Initiative's activities. Requires the Initiative's projects to be carried out on multiple levels, including local, Great Lake-wide, and Great Lakes basin-wide levels. Prohibits funding made available to implement the Initiative from being used for any water infrastructure activity (other than a green infrastructure project that improves habitat and other ecosystem functions in the Great Lakes) that is implemented using funds made available under the clean water or drinking water state revolving fund program. Requires federal agencies to: (1) maintain the base level of funding for their Great Lakes activities; and (2) identify new activities to support the environmental goals of the Initiative. Authorizes funding for the Initiative. </p> <p>Establishes the Task Force to: (1) collaborate with Canada, provinces of Canada, and binational bodies involved in the Great Lakes region regarding policies, strategies, projects, and priorities for the Great Lakes System; (2) coordinate the development of federal policies, strategies, projects, and priorities for addressing the restoration and protection of the System consistent with the Strategy, the Action Plan, the Agreement, and federal implementation of the Council's recommendations; (3) assist in the appropriate management of the System; (4) develop goals for the System that focus on outcomes such as cleaner water, sustainable fisheries, and biodiversity; (5) ensure that federal policies, strategies, projects, and priorities support measurable results and are consistent with the Strategy and Action Plan; (6) exchange information regarding policies, strategies, projects, and activities of the agencies represented on the Task Force relating to the System, the Strategy, and the Action Plan; (7) coordinate government action and research associated with the System; (8) ensure coordinated federal scientific and other research associated with the System; and (9) provide assistance and support to agencies represented on the Task Force in activities relating to the System.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator to report annually to Congress on the overall health of the Great Lakes, the Initiative's accomplishments, recommendations for streamlining work of existing advisory and coordinating committees, budgets and restoration activities relating to EPA's organizational elements involved in Great Lakes activities, and EPA's reasons for approving or disapproving the Council's recommendations.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for: (1) remediation of sediment contamination in areas of concern in the Great Lakes; and (2) the Great Lakes Program.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to protect and restore the Great Lakes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Great Lakes Ecosystem Protection Act of 2010</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-02T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3073rs/xml/BILLS-111s3073rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-03-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3073is/xml/BILLS-111s3073is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-02</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 554.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
