<bill session="108" type="s" number="2556" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend chapter 7 of title 31, United States Code, to provide for a technology assessment capability within the General Accounting Office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 7 of title 31, United States Code, to provide for a technology assessment capability within the General Accounting Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2004-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7180-7182"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7182" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="General Accounting Office"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-01T18:49:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the General Accounting Office (GAO) to establish a technology assessment capability to coordinate and prepare information for Congress relating to the policy implications of applications of technology.

 Provides for technology assessments performed under this Act to: (1) provide Congress with timely and objective information to contribute to legislative consideration of technology applications and their policy implications; (2) be undertaken by the Comptroller General with special attention to the technical expertise and policy analysis skills needed to perform a prospective assessment of technology applications and policy implications; (3) be designed to review an application of technology to an issue of public interest; and (4) include peer review by persons and organizations of appropriate expertise.

Instructs the Comptroller General, in performing technology assessments, to be properly apprised of Federal and non-Federal entities providing information to Congress to: (1) enable effective coverage of critical issues; and (2) avoid duplication of effort.

Directs the Comptroller General, in consultation with the National Academy of Sciences, to establish a technology assessment advisory panel to provide advice on such technology assessments, methodologies, possible subjects of study, and the means of improving the quality and timeliness of technology assessment services provided to Congress.

Allows the Comptroller General to utilize individuals and enter into contracts or other arrangements to acquire needed expertise.

Requires the Comptroller General to submit annual reports to Congress on GAO's technology assessment activities.</summary>
</bill>
