<bill session="111" type="s" number="3052" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:15Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ending Taxpayer Bailouts by Making Wall Street Pay Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address the establishment and maintenance of the Systemic Resolution Fund of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Taxpayer Bailouts by Making Wall Street Pay Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-05T18:58:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ending Taxpayer Bailouts by Making Wall Street Pay Act of 2010 - Establishes the Systemic Resolution Fund, to be administered by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), to: (1) cover the costs of the FDIC, including as receiver, in exercising its rights, authorities, and powers, and in fulfilling its obligations and responsibilities; (2) repay initial capitalization appropriations; and (3) cover the costs of systemic stabilization purposes.

Prohibits the use of amounts in the Fund to convert or maintain a financial company that is insolvent or in receivership, except to the extent necessary to insure systemic stabilization in the company's resolution.

Requires all amounts assessed against a financial company under this Act to be deposited into the Fund.

Directs the FDIC to: (1) impose assessments on financial companies for Fund maintenance and, if need be, replenishment; and (2) establish a mechanism whereby the systemic risk regulator reallocates annually the assessments for the Fund among all the systemically risky financial companies.

Prohibits the FDIC from imposing an assessment on any financial company which it determines does not pose a systemic risk to the U.S. financial system.</summary>
</bill>
