<bill session="109" type="h" number="1939" updated="2019-11-15T20:54:19Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To prohibit funds appropriated for the Export-Import Bank of the United States, any international financial institution, or the North American Development Bank from being used for loans to any country until the country has honored all United States requests to extradite criminals who have committed a crime punishable by life imprisonment or death.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit funds appropriated for the Export-Import Bank of the United States, any international financial institution, or the North American Development Bank from being used for loans to any country until the country has honored all United States requests to extradite criminals who have committed a crime punishable by life imprisonment or death.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA19" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-05-26T15:01:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Bank from guaranteeing, insuring, or extending credit to any government until that government has honored all U.S. requests to extradite criminals who have committed a crime punishable by life imprisonment or death.

Amends the International Financial Institutions Act to prohibit appropriated funds from being made available to an international financial institution unless that institution has made a binding commitment to the Secretary of the Treasury to provide no loans or extend any credit to any government until that government has honored all such U.S. extradition requests.

Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Implementation Act to prohibit appropriated funds from being made available to the North American Development Bank until the Bank has made such a binding commitment.</summary>
</bill>
