<bill session="118" type="h" number="1667" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:43Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ouachita National Forest Overnight Camping Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ouachita National Forest Overnight Camping Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to identify and develop campsites and related facilities for public use in the Ouachita National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000821"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-25T21:45:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Ouachita National Forest Overnight Camping Act

This bill requires the Forest Service to identify and develop campsites and related facilities within the Albert Pike Recreation Area in the Ouachita National Forest in Arkansas to be reopened for overnight camping.

Overnight camping within that area has been prohibited since several people died in a major flood on June 11, 2010.

Specifically, the Forest Service must identify areas within the Albert Pike Recreation Area that may be suitable for overnight camping and select and establish campsites and related facilities for public use within the identified areas.

The Forest Service must ensure that (1) at least 54 campsites are available, of which at least 8 have electric and water hookups; and (2) each campsite and related facility identified or established is located outside of the recreation area's 100-year floodplain, which is an area that has a 1% chance of flooding in any given year.

Not later than 30 days after the enactment of this bill, the Forest Service shall open each existing campsite within the recreation area that is located outside of the 100-year floodplain.</summary>
</bill>
