<bill session="111" type="h" number="2044" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:32Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Obesity in Schools Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce childhood obesity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Obesity in Schools Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-03T15:49:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Obesity in Schools Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a national strategy to reduce childhood obesity that: (1) provides for the reduction of childhood obesity rates by 10% by the year 2013; (2) addresses short-term and long-term solutions; (3) identifies how the federal government can work effectively with entities to implement the strategy; and (4) includes measures to identify and overcome obstacles.

Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) make matching grants to local educational agencies to reduce childhood obesity by adopting wellness policies and anti-obesity initiatives; (2) arrange for the evaluation of a wide variety of existing programs designed to prevent obesity in children and adolescents to determine their effectiveness, factors contributing to their effectiveness, and the feasibility of replicating the programs in other locations; and (3) make matching grants to state governments, local governments, and consortia of local governments to reduce childhood obesity through establishing or expanding healthy living and wellness coordinating councils (that are charged to increase healthy living and reduce obesity in elementary and secondary schools) and supporting regional workshops.</summary>
</bill>
