<bill session="118" type="h" number="5315" updated="2025-01-24T18:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Forest Markets Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Forest Markets Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to guarantee investments that will open new markets for forest owners in rural areas of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2024-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000480" joined="2023-08-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3399" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-28T15:00:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Forest Markets Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a Rural Forest Market Investment Program to guarantee environmental impact bonds, loans, or other investment vehicles to enable rural private forest landowners to participate in voluntary environmental credit markets (i.e., voluntary markets through which environmental credits may be bought or sold).

Projects eligible for the program are those developed by a private entity, state forestry agency, or publicly supported, charitable nonprofit organization engaged in the aggregation of sustainable forestry practices implemented by rural private forest landowners to facilitate the sale of credits in the voluntary environmental credit markets. These projects must use methodologies that (1) are approved by a credible, third-party entity; and (2) meet global benchmarks for high integrity.

The bill&#160;has specific requirements for projects that include the practice of tree planting (e.g., be on land that was historically&#160;forested).

In addition, the bill prohibits a bond, loan, or other investment vehicle guaranteed under the program from being used to create a floor price or artificial demand for the environmental credits generated.

Further, under the program, USDA must

guarantee not more than $150 million in the aggregate for bonds, loans, and other investment vehicles;assess certain fees to offset the subsidy cost of the issued guarantees; andissue implementing regulations.</summary>
</bill>
