<bill session="116" type="h" number="4854" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:44Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Making DI Work For All Americans Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to update and improve eligibility criteria for the Social Security Disability Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making DI Work For All Americans Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-18T15:57:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Making DI Work For All Americans Act of 2019

This bill revises the Social Security Disability Insurance and Supplemental Security Income (SSI) programs, including with respect to benefits, disability reviews, and claimant representative fees. It also modifies administrative and other activities of the Social Security Administration (SSA) concerning these programs.

Specifically, the bill sets the SSI benefit amount at 1/12 of the federal poverty level and prohibits the receipt of disability benefits and unemployment compensation in the same month. It also increases the frequency of continuing disability reviews, eliminates certain stages of disability review reconsiderations, and requires the SSA to use social media evidence in these reviews. Additionally, the bill eliminates the authority of the SSA to set fees for, and certify payments to, representatives of Social Security claimants.

Other changes include applying the Code of Conduct for U.S. Judges to Administrative Law Judges (ALJs) and requiring the SSA to review disability determinations of ALJs who are considered outliers based on the relative number of awards they have made. Furthermore, the SSA must estimate the number of ALJs and support staff that are necessary to complete disability determinations within specified time frames.

Additionally, the SSA must update certain guidelines used in disability determinations to account for factors including employment made possible due to advances in treatment, rehabilitation, and technology; update the jobs that exist in the national economy for purposes of disability determinations; study the impact of using different disability standards to determine disability status; and provide specified training to state partners.</summary>
</bill>
