<bill session="118" type="s" number="885" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Civilian Cybersecurity Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Homeland Security Civilian Cybersecurity Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Civilian Cybersecurity Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Civilian Cybersecurity Reserve in the Department of Homeland Security as a pilot project to address the cybersecurity needs of the United States with respect to national security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-96.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="204">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 204.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-07T14:31:47Z" status="Reported to Senate">Department of Homeland Security Civilian Cybersecurity Reserve Act

This bill authorizes the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to create a temporary Civilian Cybersecurity Reserve to address U.S. cybersecurity needs with respect to national security.

Reserve members must (1) be former employees or contractors of the executive branch, former military personnel, or former state or local government employees; (2) have cybersecurity expertise; and (3) obtain any necessary security clearances. Membership in the reserve is contingent on a mutual agreement between the agency and the individual. CISA must submit an implementation plan for congressional review before taking any further action with respect to the reserve. In addition, CISA and the Government Accountability Office must evaluate and report on the reserve. The report must include recommendations that address whether the program should be made permanent, extended, or modified.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-96</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
