<bill session="117" type="h" number="6791" updated="2022-12-30T04:33:56Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">John White Ensuring Timely Black Lung Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John White Ensuring Timely Black Lung Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to provide for the timely payment of black lung benefits pending liability determinations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000395"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2022-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-02T16:45:32Z" status="Introduced in House">John White Ensuring Timely Black Lung Benefits Act

This bill requires payment of black lung benefits to eligible individuals within 60 days of their eligibility determination.

Black lung disease (or pneumoconiosis) is a lung disease caused by the inhalation of coal dust. Coal miners and certain other workers (and their survivors) are eligible for benefits for disability or death caused by black lung disease arising out of coal mine employment. Generally, operators of underground coal mines are responsible for the payment of black lung benefits for their workers.

Under this bill, if operator liability has not been determined within 60 days of a worker's eligibility determination, the Department of Labor must pay the worker's benefits from the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund. (Typically, that fund pays benefits in cases where the responsible operator either no longer exists and has no successor operator or is unable to pay benefits.)

Operators that are subsequently found liable for the benefits must reimburse the fund.</summary>
</bill>
