<bill session="118" type="h" number="7556" updated="2025-01-15T18:51:50Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LNG Coordination Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LNG Coordination Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a working group to coordinate regulatory oversight of liquefied natural gas facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000814"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2024-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy, Climate and Grid Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7655" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-13T10:38:48Z" status="Introduced in House">LNG Coordination Act of 2024

This bill establishes a process to coordinate the authorities of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Department of Energy, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, and the Coast Guard with respect to liquefied natural gas (LNG) facilities, other than peak shaving facilities (e.g., facilities that reduce&#160;LNG demand spikes).

First, the bill directs the Department of Transportation to establish and convene a Liquefied Natural Gas Regulatory Safety Working Group through the National Center of Excellence for Liquefied Natural Gas Safety. The working group must evaluate the authorities of each entity pertaining to the&#160;siting and design, construction, operation and maintenance, and operational and process safety regulations of LNG facilities.&#160;

Next, the working group must negotiate an agreement between the entities to establish procedures for (1) applying their respective authorities in a manner that ensures that LNG facilities are safe and in the public interest; (2) resolving conflicts concerning overlapping jurisdiction; and (3) avoiding conflicting or duplicative regulation, inspection protocols, and reporting obligations.

Within two years, the entities must enter into agreements with respect to best practices and individual agency safety oversight and enforcement responsibilities regarding LNG facilities, other than peak shaving facilities.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
