<bill session="117" type="h" number="7800" updated="2022-12-30T00:04:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation Fuel Market Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Fuel Market Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure transparent and competitive transportation fuel markets in order to protect consumers from unwarranted price increases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2022-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4217" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-02T14:19:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Transportation Fuel Market Transparency Act

This bill expands prohibitions against manipulating fuel markets, establishes a body within the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to monitor fuel markets to ensure competitiveness, and addresses related issues.

Prohibitions against the manipulation of wholesale fuel markets or reporting false (or misleading) information shall apply to actions related to crude oil and transportation fuel, defined in this bill to include gasoline, distillate fuels, jet fuel, aviation gasoline, and biofuel. Currently, such prohibitions only apply to crude oil, gasoline, and petroleum distillates.

The bill further expands the prohibition on reporting false information to include such information that (1) concerns the supply of, operational actions related to, or output related to wholesale fuel markets; (2) is not required to be reported by law; or (3) affects the analyses or data compiled by a private sector price-reporting agency.

The bill also increases the maximum civil penalty for violating these prohibitions from $1 million to $2 million for each day of the violation.

Furthermore, the bill establishes within the FTC the Transportation Fuel Monitoring and Enforcement Unit. The unit must continuously and comprehensively collect and analyze fuel market data to support competitive market practices, identify market manipulation and other unfair methods of competition, and facilitate enforcement of competition-related statutes.

The Energy Information Administration within the Department of Energy must collect data to facilitate transparent and competitive transportation fuel markets, determine adherence to sanctions, and protect consumers.</summary>
</bill>
