<bill session="112" type="h" number="26" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:00Z">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Mental Health Screening and Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to adopt a program of professional and confidential screenings to detect mental health injuries acquired during deployment in support of a contingency operation and ultimately to reduce the incidence of suicide among veterans.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Mental Health Screening and Assessment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001252" joined="2011-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2012-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-01-13T17:14:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Mental Health Screening and Assessment Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the increasing rate of suicide among veterans returning from Operations Enduring Freedom and Iraqi Freedom is a serious problem; and (2) the Secretary of Defense should conduct mandatory, face-to-face, and confidential mental health and traumatic brain injury screenings for each member of the Armed Forces (member) during the period beginning 90 days after the member completes a deployment in support of a contingency operation and ending 180 days thereafter.

Directs the Secretary to carry out such screenings. Prohibits the Secretary from prohibiting a member from returning to the United States due to any screening result or determination.

Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a joint protocol to share existing and future reports from confidential screenings conducted to help aid members in their transition from health care and treatment provided by the Department of Defense (DOD) to health care and treatment provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).</summary>
</bill>
