<bill session="116" type="s" number="4687" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Made in America Shipbuilding Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made in America Shipbuilding Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand domestic content requirements for certain shipboard components, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-15T13:40:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Made in America Shipbuilding Act of 2020

This bill expands domestic content requirements for certain shipboard components.

Specifically, the bill (1) prohibits an executive agency from entering into a contract for the acquisition, construction, or conversion of a vessel unless the vessel is to be constructed or converted in the United States; and (2) lists components that may be procured for vessels only if manufactured in the United States.

An agency may waive such limitation under specified circumstances, such as when the limitation would increase the cost of the overall acquisition by more than 25% or cause unreasonable delays.

An agency may not (with exceptions) enter into a contract (1) for the procurement of end items or components for ships that contain a specialty metal not melted or produced in the United States; and (2) for the construction of a vessel unless the steel, iron, aluminum, and manufactured products to be used in the construction are produced in the United States.

If a court or federal agency determines that a person intentionally affixed a label bearing a Made in America inscription to specified products sold in or shipped to the United States that were not made domestically, that person shall be debarred from contracting with the government for at least five years.</summary>
</bill>
