<bill session="117" type="s" number="1254" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rebuild America Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the processes by which environmental documents are prepared and permits and applications are processed and regulated by Federal departments and agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rebuild America Now Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-06T21:35:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rebuild America Now Act 

This bill generally expedites the environmental review and permitting process of certain infrastructure projects and projects undertaken or funded by the federal government that could have significant environmental consequences.

Specifically, the bill establishes deadlines for federal agencies to complete environmental assessments and environmental impact statements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA). The bill makes additional revisions to NEPA, including revisions to

 categorically exclude from environmental review certain projects to repair infrastructure for communities that are imminently threatened from flooding or erosion, limit the number of assessment documents for proposed federal actions, allow agencies to reuse certain documents and to adopt environmental documents prepared by states or other entities as specified by the bill, and limit the judicial review of NEPA cases. The bill also establishes a permittee bill of rights, which creates a presumption of approval for permits under specified environmental and energy laws.

In addition, the bill establishes requirements to expedite certain permits for natural gas or oil pipelines as well as agreements relating to transportation projects.</summary>
</bill>
