<bill session="118" type="h" number="4365" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-28T22:59:11-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-09-28T22:59:11-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-27">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-121, by Mr. Calvert.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-27" calendar="Union" number="93">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-09-13T10:07:46-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 680 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1435 and H.R. 4365. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1435 under a closed rule and H.R. 4365 under a structured rule. The rule provides for one hour of general debate on each measure with one motion to recommit allowed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19T15:31:45-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 680 failed passage of House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21T08:05:46-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 712 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 1130 and H. Res. 684. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, under a structured rule; H.R. 1130, under a structured rule; and H.Res. 684, under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on all three bills.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26T10:29:47-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 723 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4665. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368, and H.R. 4665, under a structured rule for each bill. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:06:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 723.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4567-4633" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4573-4590" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:06:14-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4665. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368, and H.R. 4665, under a structured rule for each bill. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:06:50-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 723 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:06:54-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Mike Carey to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:07:34-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4365.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:45:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Calvert amendment en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T09:49:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Calvert amendment en bloc No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:05:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Houlahan amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:09:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Houlahan amendment No. 34, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Houlahan demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:10:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Luttrell amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:18:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norton amendment No. 125.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:20:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norton amendment No. 125, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Norton demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:25:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 149.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:36:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 149, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:38:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Griffith amendment No. 150.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:45:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Plaskett amendment No. 151.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:51:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Plaskett amendment No. 151, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Plaskett demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:52:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 152.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T10:59:40-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 152, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:00:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 153.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:11:19-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 153, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:12:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 154.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:19:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 154, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Molinaro demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:19:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 155.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:28:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 155, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:28:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 156.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:36:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment No. 156, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:53:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment No. 157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>VACATING DEMAND FOR A RECORDED VOTE - Ms. McCollum asked unanimous consent that the request for a recorded vote on the Norton amendment No. 125 be withdrawn to the end that the amendment stands disposed by the earlier voice vote that was recorded thereon. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:56:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fallon amendment No. 158.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T11:57:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 160.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:04:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 160, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gaetz demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:05:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 161.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:12:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 161, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Calvert demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:13:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 164.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:24:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 165.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:34:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jayapal amendment No. 166.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:41:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jayapal amendment No. 166, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jayapal demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:42:31-04:00">
      <text>VACATING DEMAND FOR A RECORDED VOTE - Mr. Molinaro asked unanimous consent that the request for a recorded vote on the Clyde amendment No. 154 be withdrawn to the end that the amendment stands disposed by the earlier voice vote that was recorded thereon. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:44:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the D'Esposito amendment No. 167.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T12:53:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:04:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 169.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:13:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 170.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:18:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 171.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 172.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:40:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 173.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:48:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 174.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T13:59:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 175.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:08:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 175, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:09:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 176.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:21:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 177.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:32:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 178.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:40:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 179.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:48:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 180.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:56:29-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Calvert moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:56:43-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:56:53-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4365 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T17:50:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4659-4666" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T17:50:46-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T17:51:49-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on agreeing to the amendments to H.R. 4365, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:29:20-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4365.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:30:16-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:30:34-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:30:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX further proceedings were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:42:33-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 730 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5692, H.R. 4365 and H.R. 4367. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5692, under a closed rule. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of general debate on the bill H.R. 5692 and one motion to recommit. The resolution provides that further consideration of H.R. 4365, the further amendments specified in section 3 shall be considered as adopted and the resolution provides for further consideration of H.R. 4367, the further amendment specified in section 5 shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:46:38-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the House resumed consideration of H.R 4365.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:46:41-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:47:42-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Jacobs moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:48:08-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:53:46-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 210 - 218 (Roll no. 501).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="502" datetime="2023-09-28T22:59:11-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 210 (Roll no. 502).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:59:13-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:30:17-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4365.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-10-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="226">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 226.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="143" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2587" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="680" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="712" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="723" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="730" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2927" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2882" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1102" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h387"/>
    <amendment number="h386"/>
    <amendment number="h385"/>
    <amendment number="h384"/>
    <amendment number="h383"/>
    <amendment number="h382"/>
    <amendment number="h381"/>
    <amendment number="h380"/>
    <amendment number="h379"/>
    <amendment number="h378"/>
    <amendment number="h377"/>
    <amendment number="h376"/>
    <amendment number="h375"/>
    <amendment number="h374"/>
    <amendment number="h373"/>
    <amendment number="h372"/>
    <amendment number="h371"/>
    <amendment number="h370"/>
    <amendment number="h369"/>
    <amendment number="h368"/>
    <amendment number="h367"/>
    <amendment number="h366"/>
    <amendment number="h365"/>
    <amendment number="h364"/>
    <amendment number="h363"/>
    <amendment number="h362"/>
    <amendment number="h361"/>
    <amendment number="h360"/>
    <amendment number="h359"/>
    <amendment number="h358"/>
    <amendment number="h357"/>
    <amendment number="h356"/>
    <amendment number="h355"/>
    <amendment number="h354"/>
    <amendment number="h353"/>
    <amendment number="h352"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-10-12T17:04:18Z" status="Passed House">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2024

This bill provides FY2024 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military activities.

(The bill excludes military construction, military family housing, civil works projects of the Army Corps of Engineers, and nuclear warheads, which are all included in other appropriations bills.)

Within the DOD budget, the bill provides appropriations for

 Military Personnel; Operation and Maintenance; Procurement; Research, Development, Test and Evaluation; and Revolving and Management Funds. The bill provides appropriations for Other Department of Defense Programs, including

 the Defense Health Program, Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, and the Office of the Inspector General. In addition, the bill provides appropriations for Related Agencies, including (1) the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund, and (2) the Intelligence Community Management Account.

The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-121</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
