<bill session="108" type="s" number="2278" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:33Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ninth Circuit Judgeship and Reorganization Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for the appointment of additional Federal circuit judges, to divide the Ninth Judicial Circuit of the United States into 3 circuits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ninth Circuit Judgeship and Reorganization Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2004-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2004-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2004-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000888" joined="2004-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-07">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Administrative Oversight and the Courts. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU02" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative Oversight and the Courts" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4247" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Judicial reform"/>
    <term name="Judicial tenure"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-07-01T18:49:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ninth Circuit Judgeship and Reorganization Act of 2004 - Amends the Federal judicial code to divide the Ninth Judicial Circuit into the Ninth Circuit (to be composed of California, Guam, Hawaii, and the Northern Marianas Islands), the Twelfth Circuit (to be composed of Arizona, Nevada, Idaho, and Montana), and Thirteenth Circuit (to be composed of Alaska, Oregon, and Washington State).

Requires the President to appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, five additional circuit judges for the new Ninth Circuit (not before January 21, 2005) and two temporary judges for the former Ninth Circuit.

Specifies the locations where the new circuits are to hold regular sessions.

Assigns active circuit judges of the former Ninth Circuit to the new circuits based on their current duty station. Allows senior circuit judges of the former Ninth Circuit to elect assignment to any of the three new circuits.

Specifies the disposition of cases pending in the former Ninth Circuit before the effective date of this Act as follows: (1) proceedings in matters that have been submitted for decision shall continue without regard to this Act; (2) matters not yet submitted for decision must be transferred to the court to which they would have been submitted under this Act; and (3) proceedings on petitions for rehearing or rehearing en banc that have been submitted or decided shall continue without regard to this Act.

Authorizes the temporary assignment of the circuit and district judges of the former Ninth Circuit among the new circuits. Authorizes administrative coordination among any two contiguous circuits among the new circuits.

Directs that the former Ninth Circuit shall cease to exist for administrative purposes two years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
