<bill session="116" type="s" number="1467" updated="2022-02-08T23:14:39Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sergeant Daniel Somers Network of Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sergeant Daniel Somers Network of Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a pilot program on information sharing between the Department of Defense and designated relatives and friends of members of the Armed Forces regarding the experiences and challenges of military service, particularly during and after overseas deployments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2019-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2727" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-13T15:53:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sergeant Daniel Somers Network of Support Act

This bill provides a means of disseminating information to personal contacts of Armed Forces members about the experiences and challenges of military service. Specifically, it requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to seek an agreement with the American Red Cross for the conduct of a pilot program to encourage new Armed Forces members to designate up to 15 persons with whom certain information regarding their military service would be shared. This includes information concerning aspects of daily life in the military and its challenges, particularly during and after deployment in a contingency operation; availability of services to help members and dependents to cope with experiences; and benefits provided by DOD.

The bill provides privacy protections and mechanisms to modify the contact information or opt out of the program.</summary>
</bill>
