<bill session="117" type="s" number="4936" updated="2023-08-31T21:30:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Council on African American History and Culture Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Council on African American History and Culture Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Council on African American History and Culture within the National Endowment for the Humanities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8971" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-31T21:25:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Council on African American History and Culture Act of 2022

This bill establishes within the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) a National Council on African American History and Culture.

The council shall

 prepare an annual report to be submitted to NEH on the work of NEH to preserve and celebrate African-American history and culture; gather timely and authoritative information concerning historical developments and cultural trends in African-American history and culture and take other specified steps; evaluate the various programs and activities of NEH to determine the extent to which such programs and activities are contributing to the successful preservation and celebration of African-American history and culture and make recommendations to the President; develop and recommend national policies to foster and promote the understanding and preservation of African-American culture and the celebration of African Americans as contributors to the country's success; and make and furnish such studies, reports thereon, and recommendations with respect to matters of cultural preservation and African-American history. The bill terminates the council 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
