<bill session="119" type="h" number="1525" updated="2025-09-10T08:06:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Life from Chemical Abortions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Life from Chemical Abortions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use or declaration of a public health emergency with respect to abortion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2025-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000634" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001101" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001091" joined="2025-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000612" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2025-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-14T15:17:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Life from Chemical Abortions Act

This bill nullifies certain changes made by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to dispensing requirements for mifepristone. (Mifepristone is a drug that is approved to end pregnancies through 10 weeks gestation when used in conjunction with the drug misoprostol. The procedure is often referred to as medication abortion or the abortion pill.)

The FDA regulates mifepristone through the Mifepristone Risk Evaluation and Mitigation Strategy (REMS) program. The program requires health care providers to comply with certain requirements in order to prescribe or dispense mifepristone to end a pregnancy; the program previously included an in-person dispensing requirement that required mifepristone to be directly dispensed to patients in clinics, medical offices, or hospitals. During the COVID-19 public health emergency, the FDA stopped enforcing the in-person dispensing requirement, which allowed mail-order pharmacies to fill and dispense mifepristone prescriptions.

In January 2023, the FDA modified program requirements so as to (1) remove the in-person dispensing requirement, and (2) require pharmacies to be program-certified in order to dispense mifepristone. The modifications allow certified retail pharmacies to dispense mifepristone pursuant to prescriptions that are written by certified prescribers.

The bill nullifies the January 2023 changes and prohibits the FDA from (1) exercising any enforcement discretion with respect to program requirements, or (2) reducing program protections until every state submits certain data regarding abortions to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.

The bill also generally prohibits the declaration of a public health emergency with respect to abortions.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
