<bill session="108" type="h" number="4869" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:17Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prescott Marine Mammal Stranding Program Amendments of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to authorize appropriations for the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prescott Marine Mammal Stranding Program Amendments of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000180"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine mammals"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-07-26T20:54:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Prescott Marine Mammal Stranding Program Amendments of 2004 - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to authorize appropriations for FY 2005 through 2010 for: (1) the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program to provide grants to eligible stranding network participants for the recovery or treatment of marine mammals, the collection of data from living or dead stranded marine mammals for scientific research regarding marine mammal health, and related facility operation costs; and (2) the Marine Mammal Unusual Mortality Event Fund to compensate persons for certain special costs associated with the contingency plan for responding to any unusual mortality event, for reimbursing any stranding network participant for costs incurred in preparing and transporting tissues collected with respect to such event for the Tissue Bank, and for care and maintenance of a marine mammal seized for lack of a permit.</summary>
</bill>
