<bill session="117" type="h" number="296" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Technology Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Independent Financial Technology Task Force to Combat Terrorism and Illicit Financing, to provide rewards for information leading to convictions related to terrorist use of digital currencies, to establish a Fintech Leadership in Innovation and Financial Intelligence Program to encourage the development of tools and programs to combat terrorist and illicit use of digital currencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Technology Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2021-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2021-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2021-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2021-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2021-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-11T14:31:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Technology Protection Act 

This bill provides for the investigation of new financial technologies (e.g., digital currencies) and their use in terrorism and other illicit activities.

Specifically, the bill establishes the Independent Financial Technology Task Force to Combat Terrorism and Illicit Financing, which must research terrorist and illicit use of new financial technologies and issue an annual report.

The Department of the Treasury must establish a fund to provide a reward for a person who provides information leading to the conviction of an individual involved with terrorist use of digital currencies.

Additionally, the bill establishes the FinTech Leadership in Innovation and Financial Intelligence Program to support the development of tools and programs to detect terrorist and illicit use of digital currencies.</summary>
</bill>
