<bill session="108" type="s" number="2360" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:54Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nontraditional Student Success Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide higher education assistance for nontraditional students, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nontraditional Student Success Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2004-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000352" joined="2004-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4694-4695"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="College administration"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student employment"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-24T21:38:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nontraditional Student Success Act - Authorizes and appropriates specified funds for Federal Pell grants under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA), including increasing maximum grant amounts for academic years 2005-2006 through 2009-2010, after a specified reduction from the academic year 2003-2004 level for academic year 2004-2005.

Amends the HEA to revise the requirements for the allowance of two Pell grants during a single award year to allow the student to be enrolled full-time in a certificate (or, as currently, a degree) program.

Requires the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register each academic year a revised table of income protection allowances.

Excludes the earned income tax credit (EITC) from financial aid determinations.

Authorizes the Secretary to select institutionsof higher education, or systems or consortia of such institutions, for voluntary participation in a Nontraditional Students Demonstration Program, strictly monitored by the Department of Education, to test the effectiveness of providing expanded financial assistance to: (1) less than half-time students for not more than three terms over the duration of the students' course of study; and (2) students in compressed, modular, or other alternative schedules.

Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to eligible institutions for the purposes of improving remedial education.

Increases minimum grant amounts for the Federal TRIO programs.

Permits student support services and educational opportunity centers to include career and academic (as well as personal) counseling provided by assigned counselors.

Makes awards under the Early Intervention and College Awareness Program for six years. Requires services under the Program provided in a cohort approach to be provided through the first year of attendance at a postsecondary education institution to students in the participating grade level. Requires the continuing system of mentoring and advising under an early intervention program to be provided to eligible students through the first year of attendance at a postsecondary education institution. Authorizes appropriations for the Program through FY 2010.

Authorizes FY 2005 appropriations for the Child Care Access Means Parents in School Program of campus-based child care services for low-income parents in postsecondary education.

Directs the Secretary to establish a website and brochures for providing outreach about financial aid and education tax credits that targets employers, one-stop centers, Head Start centers, and other appropriate locations.

Includes among the activities for which grants to Hispanic-serving institutions, as well as grants from the Fund for the Improvement of Postsecondary Education, may be used the introduction of reforms to customize remedial education, including English language instruction, to help students move rapidly from remedial courses into core courses and through program completion.

Revises requirements for Special Programs for Students Whose Families Are Engaged in Migrant and Seasonal Farmwork to: (1) specify childcare and transportation among the essential supportive services which may be provided by the high school equivalency program; and (2) authorize appropriations through FY 2010 for both the high school equivalency program and the college assistance migrant program.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase from 20 to 50 percent the Lifetime Learning income tax credit, specify that it is for qualified higher education expenses, but reduce the credit limit from $10,000 to $4,000 per year. Makes a portion of the credit refundable. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for making advance payments to eligible educational institutions of such credits on behalf of certified individuals in an amount equal to such a credit for the year.</summary>
</bill>
