<bill session="108" type="s" number="2543" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Heritage Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program and criteria for National Heritage Areas in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">National Heritage Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Heritage Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Heritage Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2004-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/18/2004 S7012"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/18/2004 S7012-7014" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-692.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/22/04 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-329.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-08-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="685">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 685.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9356-9360" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9356-9360" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:04:25-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-01T17:20:36Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">National Heritage Partnership Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a National Heritage Areas program under which the Secretary shall provide technical and financial assistance to local coordinating entities to support the establishment of National Heritage Areas. Describes the Secretary's duties, including conducting studies, providing technical assistance, and submitting annual reports.

(Sec. 4) Specifies the criteria that the Secretary shall apply to determine the suitability and feasibility of designating proposed Areas. States that designation of an Area shall be: (1) by Act of Congress; and (2) contingent on the prior completion of a study and an affirmative determination by the Secretary that the area meets such criteria.

(Sec. 5) Sets forth requirements for Area management plans. Instructs local coordinating entities to submit plans to the Secretary for approval. Prohibits a local coordinating entity from using Federal funds authorized by this Act to implement an amendment until the Secretary approves the amendment.

(Sec. 6) Requires such an entity to submit annual reports to the Secretary for each fiscal year for which the local coordinating committee receives Federal funds under this Act.

Bars local coordinating entities from using Federal funds authorized under this Act to acquire any interest in real property.

(Sec. 7) Specifies this Act's effect with regard to: (1) the provision of technical or financial assistance by other Federal agencies; (2) the management or use of Federal land by other Federal agencies; and (3) specified private property and regulatory protections.

(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations.

Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance to an individual local coordinating entity (excluding technical assistance and administrative oversight) 15 years after the initial receipt of the assistance by the local coordinating committee.

Limits to five percent the amount of funds that may be used by the Secretary for technical assistance, oversight, and administration.

Requires grant recipients to provide, as a condition of receiving a grant under this Act, matching funds from non-Federal sources equal to the grant amount.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-329</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
