<bill session="118" type="h" number="6107" updated="2025-11-19T04:28:43Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Canal Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Urban Canal Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="display">Urban Canal Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to authorize certain extraordinary operation and maintenance work for urban canals of concern.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2023-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 118-734.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-14" calendar="Union" number="619">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 619.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife and Fisheries" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2160" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-02T21:58:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Urban Canal Modernization Act

This bill expands the Bureau of Reclamation's responsibility under the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to address aging irrigation and water resources infrastructure in western states to include additional work for urban canals of concern.

Specifically, the bill directs Reclamation or the operating entity of a transferred work (i.e., infrastructure owned by Reclamation, but maintained by a nonfederal entity) to carry out any necessary extraordinary operation and maintenance work for urban canals of concern, which are certain transferred works the failure of which would result in loss of life&#160;and&#160;property in the vicinity of the canal.

Reclamation must also provide federal funds to transferred works on a nonreimbursable basis sufficient to cover 35% of the cost of extraordinary operation and maintenance work for (1) urban canals of concern, and (2) certain project facilities which are in proximity to urbanized areas and which could pose a risk to public safety or&#160;property if the facilities failed.

The bill further specifies that any reimbursable funds provided under the bill must be considered a nonfederal source of funds for purposes of federal grant cost-sharing requirements.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-734</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
