<bill session="110" type="hr" number="202" updated="2023-01-11T19:59:25Z">
  <state datetime="2007-03-08T14:56:25-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-03-08T14:56:25-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the expenses of certain committees of the House of Representatives in the One Hundred Tenth Congress.</title>
    <title type="display">Providing for the expenses of certain committees of the House of Representatives in the One Hundred Tenth Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2007-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 110-29.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-03-05" calendar="House" number="19">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-03-07T17:35:21-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 219 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 202 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on House Administration now printed in the resolution, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T11:56:44-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 219 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T12:00:33-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 219.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2316-2321" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2316" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T12:00:38-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 202 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on House Administration now printed in the resolution, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T12:05:42-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 202.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T12:42:26-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2321" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T12:42:46-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of the debate on H.Res. 202, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ehlers demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T14:44:53-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2330-2331" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="131" datetime="2007-03-08T14:56:25-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 269 - 150 (Roll no. 131).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2316-2317" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-08T14:56:26-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="hr" number="219" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="House Administration"/>
    <term name="House Agriculture"/>
    <term name="House Armed Services"/>
    <term name="House Budget"/>
    <term name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <term name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <term name="House Financial Services"/>
    <term name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <term name="House Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="House Intelligence"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="House Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <term name="House Rules"/>
    <term name="House Science and Technology"/>
    <term name="House Small Business"/>
    <term name="House Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <term name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h28"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2007-03-12T19:35:57Z" status="Passed House amended">Sets forth the levels of payment for 110th Congress expenses (including staff salaries) for the Committees on Agriculture, Armed Services, the Budget, Education and Labor, Energy and Commerce, Financial Services, Foreign Affairs, Homeland Security, House Administration, the Judiciary, Natural Resources, Oversight and Government Reform, Rules, Science and Technology, Small Business, Standards of Official Conduct, Transportation and Infrastructure, Veterans' Affairs, Ways and Means, as well as the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence.

Prescribes limitations to such expenses for the 1st and 2nd sessions of the 110th Congress.

Establishes a Select Committee on Energy Independence and Global Warming, and provides funding for it.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-29</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
