<bill session="111" type="h" number="4340" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Main Street Survival Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a revolving loan fund program for certain businesses to facilitate increased lending in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Main Street Survival Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000602"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-25T21:30:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Main Street Survival Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should encourage financial institutions that have received federal financial support to maintain historic levels of lending to small and medium-sized businesses.

Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a three-year Main Street Revolving Loan Fund Program to provide temporary loans to businesses with less than 1,000 full-time equivalent employees.

Establishes in the Treasury a revolving loan fund to implement the Program.

Permits a business to use a Main Street revolving loan to finance the cost of certain operations, but prohibits the use of it to expand its operations significantly. Limits the term of such a loan to nine months, and the maximum total amount of loans to a particular business in any fiscal year to $1 million.</summary>
</bill>
