<bill session="108" type="s" number="1322" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sexual Offender Parental Notification Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require States to make certain information regarding sexually violent predators accessible on the Internet.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sexual Offender Parental Notification Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-02T14:05:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sexual Offender Parental Notification Act of 2003 - Amends the Jacob Wetterling Crimes Against Children and Sexually Violent Offender Registration Act to direct the State or any agency authorized by the State to: (1) notify members or organizations of the community vulnerable to persons required to register of relevant information concerning such persons that is necessary to protect the public, provided that the State or any such agency retain discretion to determine the community members or organizations to be notified and the manner of notification; (2) make relevant information that is necessary to protect the public (including the offender's name, address, photograph, and crime of conviction, the sentence imposed, the age and gender of the victim, a description of the offense and modus operandi, and any special conditions imposed on the offender) accessible on an Internet registry website that is free of charge and designed to ensure the privacy, confidentiality, and anonymity of users, as long as such accessibility is consistent with State law; and (3) not release the identity of a victim of an offense that requires registration (or the victim's age if the age would identify that victim).

Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit intentionally accessing a sex offender Internet registry to obtain information to facilitate, commit, or aid in the commission of an act of violence or other crime against a listed offender.

Requires the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to award a grant to each State to offset costs directly associated with complying with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
