<bill session="117" type="h" number="6350" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:58Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rescuing Every Contributor from Unwanted Recurrences (RECUR) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rescuing Every Contributor from Unwanted Recurrences (RECUR) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require disclosures to contributors regarding recurring contributions or donations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1786" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-03T17:26:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Rescuing Every Contributor from Unwanted Recurrences (RECUR) Act

This bill requires certain disclosures for recurring political contributions or donations.

Specifically, the bill requires any person who is soliciting a recurring contribution or donation for a political committee, an independent expenditure, or an electioneering communication to receive the affirmative consent of the contributor or donor. This affirmative consent cannot be a passive action by the contributor or donor, such as failing to uncheck a prechecked box.

In addition, any person who accepts a recurring contribution or donation must (1) provide a receipt for the initial contribution or donation and for each recurrence that clearly and conspicuously discloses all material terms, (2) provide all information needed to cancel the recurring contribution or donation in each communication with the contributor or donor, and (3) immediately cancel recurring contributions or donations upon request of the contributor or donor.</summary>
</bill>
