<bill session="119" type="h" number="264" updated="2025-02-26T09:05:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Train EATS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Train EATS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Train Establishment of Appetizing Table Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require Amtrak to make traditional dining and an alternative, more affordable food and beverage service available to passengers on overnight routes of Amtrak, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001229" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2025-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2025-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-18T14:58:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Train Establishment of Appetizing Table Service Act or the Train EATS Act&#160;

This bill requires Amtrak to provide a range of dining services to passengers on overnight routes.

Specifically, Amtrak must make available (1) traditional dining (i.e., table service), to the extent practicable; and (2) an alternative food and beverage service that is more affordable than traditional dining.

On each overnight route, Amtrak must offer any traditional dining capacity not otherwise used by first-class or business-class passengers&#160;to passengers in coach class for a fee.

In addition, Amtrak must ensure that traditional dining on overnight routes includes (1) a healthy meal option, and (2) the option for passengers to preorder meals that satisfy their dietary restrictions.

The Department of Transportation must issue any necessary regulations.</summary>
</bill>
