<bill session="117" type="s" number="316" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fly Safe and Healthy Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a temperature checks pilot program for air transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fly Safe and Healthy Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fly Safe and Healthy Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="207">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 207.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2387" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-23T18:25:07Z" status="Reported to Senate">Fly Safe and Healthy Act of 2021

This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to establish a 180-day pilot program to conduct temperature checks for domestic and international passengers, individuals accompanying those passengers, crew members, and other individuals who pass through airport security screening locations at which screening is conducted by the TSA.

In developing the pilot program, the TSA must address certain policies and procedures, including (1) types and costs of technology that may be used to conduct temperature checks, (2) mechanisms to protect the privacy and medical information of individuals subjected to temperature checks, and (3) exempting individuals who may have a fever unrelated to COVID-19.

The pilot program must ensure airlines allow passengers who are prohibited from flying due to a fever or a secondary medical screening to reschedule, request a voucher, or cancel a flight at no cost.

The TSA must design, test, and implement a passenger notification system for alerting passengers of temperature checks under the pilot program that includes (1) a message discouraging any individual who has a fever from traveling in air transportation; and (2) a notification that each passenger and any individual accompanying a passenger into the sterile area of the airport will undergo a temperature check, subject to a secondary medical screening, if the pilot program established under this bill is in effect in that airport.</summary>
</bill>
