<bill session="118" type="h" number="6501" updated="2025-11-11T22:50:11Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Snap Back Inaccurate SNAP Payments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Snap Back Inaccurate SNAP Payments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to improve the calculation and reduce the taxpayer cost of payment errors under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2023-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2923" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-12T15:57:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Snap Back Inaccurate SNAP Payments Act

This bill requires states to recoup any overpayments of benefits made to Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) recipients and adjusts the formula for determining a state's liability rate for overpayments.

As background, the SNAP quality control system measures how accurately SNAP state agencies determine a household&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s eligibility and benefit amount and determines overpayments of benefits and underpayments. States that have comparatively high payment error rates for two consecutive years are assessed a penalty (i.e., liability amount). The Food and Nutrition Service (FNS) must use a statutory formula to determine the liability amount.

Under current law, FNS must set a tolerance level for excluding small payment errors (e.g., $54 or less in FY2023). This bill reduces the tolerance level for excluding small errors to $0 for FY2024 and each succeeding fiscal year.

The bill also requires state agencies to recoup any overpayments of benefits made to SNAP beneficiaries.

The bill adjusts the liability rate formula to reduce the state payment error rate based on the percentage of overpayments recouped by the state. Further, the bill increases the multiplier used in the formula to 25% (from 10%).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
