<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="181" updated="2024-03-18T20:44:02Z">
  <amends type="hc" number="40" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-05-18T10:47:33-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000632"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part C of House Report 118-59 to recognize the important work that local law enforcement personnel do every day and states that officers should have certain rights during investigations into alleged misconduct such as legal resources and counsel. Encourages states across the nation to adopt their own Bill of Rights to protect our local law enforcement and denounces calls to defund the police.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment recognizes the important work that local law enforcement personnel do every day and states that officers should have certain rights during investigations into alleged misconduct such as legal resources and counsel. Amendment encourages states across the Nation to adopt their own Bill of Rights to protect local law enforcement and denounces calls to defund the police.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-05-18T10:47:33-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="226">
      <text>On agreeing to the D'Esposito amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 268 - 156 (Roll no. 226).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18T10:06:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. D'Esposito.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2438-2440" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2438-2439" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18T10:06:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. D'Esposito.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2438-2440" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2438-2439" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18T10:47:33-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18T10:47:33-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the D'Esposito amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 268 - 156 (Roll no. 226).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18T10:47:33-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the D'Esposito amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 268 - 156 (Roll no. 226).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
