<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4880</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-03-18</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2010-03-22T20:26:23Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-03-18T14:02:33Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>2509</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-06-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>409</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-03-02</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 279.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-18</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000368</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Kirkpatrick, Ann [D-AZ-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ann</firstName>
        <lastName>Kirkpatrick</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <district>1</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Archaeology and anthropology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arizona</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Historical and cultural resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mining</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-03-18</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-04-30T15:41:50Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Copper Basin Jobs Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary), if Resolution Copper Mining, LLC offers to convey specified parcels of non-federal land in Gila, Yavapi, Maricopa, Coconino, Pinal, or Santa Cruz Counties, Arizona to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior, and if the public interest would be well served, to convey certain federal land in Pinal County, Arizona to Resolution Copper. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary to authorize Resolution Copper to carry out mineral exploration activities: (1) under the Oak Flat Withdrawal Area; and (2) on the Withdrawal Area (with the exception of within the Oak Flat Campground) so long as they are conducted from a single exploratory drill pad. </p> <p>Makes lands acquired by the Secretary under this Act part of the National Forest within which the land is located. </p> <p>Adds certain of the non-federal land acquired by the Secretary of the Interior in Pinal and Santa Cruz counties to the San Pedro Riparian National Conservation Area and the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area, respectively. </p> <p>Instructs Resolution Copper to surrender its rights under mining and other U.S. laws to commercially extract minerals under Apache Leap and certain of the non-federal land in Pinal County (the Pond). </p> <p> Requires Resolution Copper to make value adjustment payments to the United States based upon locatable minerals produced from such land.</p> <p>Withdraws Apache Leap, and any land acquired by the United States under this Act, from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.<br> </p> <p> Directs the Secretary to manage Apache Leap so as to preserve its natural character and to protect the archaeological and cultural resources located on it. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to issue to Resolution Copper special use permits that allow it to carry out underground activities (other than the commercial extraction of minerals) under the surface of Apache Leap that would not disturb the surface.</p> <p>Requires preparation of a management plan for Apache Leap.</p> <p> Directs the Secretary to convey specified lands in Pinal County to the town of Superior, Arizona. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Copper Basin Jobs Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Copper Basin Jobs Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To secure Federal ownership and management of significant natural, scenic, and recreational resources, to provide for the protection of cultural resources, to facilitate the efficient extraction of mineral resources by authorizing and directing an exchange of Federal and non-Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Copper Basin Jobs Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-03-18T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr4880ih/xml/BILLS-111hr4880ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-03-22</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
