<bill session="118" type="h" number="6894" updated="2024-10-21T14:22:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Scam PACs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Scam PACs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit the misrepresentation of actions on behalf of candidates, political parties, and political committees and organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2023-12-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-21T14:21:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Scam PACs Act

This bill expands prohibitions with respect to fraudulent misrepresentation of campaign authority.

Current law sets forth two prohibitions with respect to fraudulent misrepresentation of campaign authority. The first prohibits a candidate for federal office or the candidate's employees or agents from fraudulently misrepresenting themselves as speaking&#160;or otherwise acting for or on behalf of another candidate or political party on a matter that is damaging to such other candidate or political party. The bill instead applies this prohibition to any person, to any misrepresentation, and for any purpose.

The second prohibits any person from fraudulently misrepresenting themselves as speaking or otherwise acting for or on behalf of any candidate or political party to solicit contributions or donations. The bill instead applies this prohibition to any misrepresentation and for purposes of soliciting money or any other thing of value.

The two prohibitions under current law refer to misrepresentations on behalf of candidates or political parties. This bill also extends applicability to political committees and organizations.</summary>
</bill>
