<bill session="108" type="s" number="744" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to notify plan participants and beneficiaries of the commencement of proceedings to terminate such plan.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to notify plan participants and beneficiaries of the commencement of proceedings to terminate such plan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001233"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to direct the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) to notify affected parties of the commencement of PBGC proceedings to terminate a defined benefit plan, within 30 days after the PBGC notifies a plan administrator regarding such proceedings.Requires the plan administrator to provide the PBGC with a list of the names and addresses of all participants and beneficiaries of such a plan. Requires the PBGC to provide: (1) written notice to each affected party of the plan; (2) notice in the two newspapers with the largest circulation in the area of the majority of the affected parties; and (3) the proposed date and the procedure for such intended termination.</summary>
</bill>
