<bill session="117" type="h" number="8692" updated="2023-05-30T18:30:27Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Physicians for Underserved Areas Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Physicians for Underserved Areas Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make improvements to the redistribution of residency slots under the Medicare program after a hospital closes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2022-08-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4234" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-21T20:44:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Physicians for Underserved Areas Act

This bill modifies how a hospital's residency positions are redistributed after it closes for purposes of graduate medical education payments under Medicare.

Under current law, if a hospital with an approved medical residency program closes, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must redistribute the hospital's residency positions to other hospitals in the following order: (1) hospitals in the same core-based statistical area as the closed hospital, (2) hospitals in the same state as the closed hospital, (3) hospitals in the same region of the country as the closed hospital, and (4) other remaining hospitals. In order to receive the additional positions, hospitals must demonstrate a likelihood of filling the positions within three years.

The bill removes the requirement that the CMS prioritize hospitals in the same region of the country as the closed hospital. It also requires hospitals to demonstrate a likelihood of (1) starting to use the positions within two years, and (2) filling the positions within five years.</summary>
</bill>
