<bill session="118" type="s" number="1162" updated="2025-11-19T04:12:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accurate Map for Broadband Investment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Map for Broadband Investment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that broadband maps are accurate before funds are allocated under the Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment Program based on those maps.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2023-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3609" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-02T03:00:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accurate Map for Broadband Investment Act of 2023

This bill modifies the Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment (BEAD) Program by requiring a portion of program funds to be reallocated using an updated version of the National Broadband Map. (The map identifies areas that lack access to broadband internet; the Federal Communications Commission is responsible for creating and periodically updating the map.)

The BEAD Program is managed by the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) and provides funds to states and territories for broadband deployment, connectivity, mapping, and adoption projects. Current law allocates the majority of BEAD funds based on the share of locations in a given state or territory that the National Broadband Map designates as unserved by broadband internet. Current law also provides for the release of BEAD funds in stages; generally, a state or territory receives 20% of its funds after the NTIA approves its initial proposal for using the funds and the remaining funds after the NTIA approves its final proposal.

Under this bill, after distributing BEAD funds for initial proposals, the NTIA must reallocate the remaining funds using the most current version of the National Broadband Map and distribute those funds based on the reallocation.</summary>
</bill>
