<bill session="115" type="h" number="6583" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:55Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Big Sand Wash Project Title Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain lands and facilities of the Big Sand Wash Project, Utah.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Big Sand Wash Project Title Transfer Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="3472" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-03T18:08:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Big Sand Wash Project Title Transfer Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey to the Central Utah Water Conservancy District in Utah certain acquired lands, certain federal lands, and certain existing Big Sand Wash facilities.

The bill requires that specified actions must be taken by the District, the Moon Lake Water Users Association, Duchesne County, Utah, and the federal government before such conveyance is completed.

The bill grants the District the authority to prepay, at net present value, all irrigation block notices associated with the Bonneville Unit of the Central Utah Project.

The bill shields the United States, after conveyance, from liability for damages arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to the facilities, the acquired lands, and the federal lands, except for damages caused by acts of negligence committed by any U.S. employee or agent before the conveyance, consistent with the Federal Tort Claims Act.</summary>
</bill>
