<bill session="117" type="h" number="2462" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Fee Reauthorization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to make modifications to the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Fee Reauthorization Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001109"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000563" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2021-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1447" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1600" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-14T16:40:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Fee Reauthorization Act of 2021

This bill reduces the fee certain coal mining operations must pay to the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund, reauthorizes such fee through FY2028, and otherwise revises provisions regarding the fund and mine reclamation.

Under the existing Abandoned Mine Land Reclamation Program, the Office of Surface Mining, Reclamation and Enforcement (OSMRE) collects a fee from coal mining companies for each ton of coal produced. The fees are deposited into the fund, which may be used to address hazards to public health, safety, and the environment from coal mining sites that were abandoned or unreclaimed as of August 3, 1977. For example, the fund may be used to provide grants to states and Indian tribes to reclaim and clean up land and water affected by such sites.

OSMRE's authority to collect the fee expires on September 30, 2021. This bill extends the authority to collect the fee for seven years and reduces the fee for all categories of coal. It also provides additional grants for certain priority sites and revises requirements governing the distribution of grants to states and Indian tribes from the program.

In addition, the bill allows states to (1) enter into a memorandum of understanding with relevant states or federal agencies to clean up lands and waters affected by such sites, and (2) partner with a community reclaimer who volunteers to carry out a reclamation project approved by the Department of the Interior.</summary>
</bill>
