<bill session="117" type="s" number="4890" updated="2022-12-29T13:03:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protections for Student Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protections for Student Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish protections for a member of the Armed Forces who leaves a course of education, paid for with certain educational assistance, to perform certain service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-02T18:36:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protections for Student Veterans Act of 2022

This bill authorizes covered individuals who are utilizing Department of Veterans Affairs educational assistance benefits to withdraw or take a leave of absence after they receive orders for active service, inactive-duty training, or state active duty. A covered individual means a member of the Armed Forces (including reserve components) or the spouse of such a member.

Institutions of higher education are prohibited from taking adverse actions against such individuals for withdrawing or taking a leave of absence, including

 assigning a failing grade, reducing the individual's grade point average, characterizing any absence as unexcused, or assessing financial penalties. The bill requires institutions of higher education to refund all tuition and fees (including for housing) for the academic term for which the individual withdraws.

In situations where the individual takes a leave of absence, the institution of higher education must assign a grade of incomplete for the applicable term and permit the individual to complete the academic term after the period of service.</summary>
</bill>
