<bill session="115" type="s" number="2852" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:12Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness and Advancing Innovation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize certain programs under the Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness Reauthorization Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness and Advancing Innovation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness and Advancing Innovation Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2018-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2018-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2018-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2018-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2018-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2018-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2018-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2018-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="467">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 467.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="7328" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2851" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6378" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-08T16:55:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness and Advancing Innovation Act of 2018

This bill reauthorizes through FY2023 various programs relating to pandemic and all-hazards preparedness, including:

 the Hospital Preparedness Program, biosurveillance programs, the emergency system for advanced registration of volunteer health professionals, the National Advisory Committee on Children and Disasters, the Strategic National Stockpile, the National Disaster Medical System, the Medical Reserve Corps, and the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority&#160;and the BioShield Special Reserve Fund. The bill requires the National Health Security Strategy developed by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to describe potential emergency health security threats and identify the process for achieving the preparedness goals.

The bill also requires HHS to develop guidelines to inform regional systems of hospitals and health care facilities of capabilities to treat patients affected by chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear threats.

The bill reauthorizes through FY2023 funding for medical facilities of the Veterans Administration and for influenza vaccine tracking and distribution.</summary>
</bill>
