<bill session="109" type="s" number="32" updated="2022-02-03T05:25:24Z">
  <state datetime="2005-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard and Reserve Bill of Rights Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">National Guard and Reserve Bill of Rights Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the benefits and protections for members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who are called or ordered to extend active duty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2005-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2005-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2005-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="1169" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-08T20:19:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Guard and Reserve Bill of Rights Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Defense to limit the length of assignment of reservists during U.S. Central Command deployments of not less than one year.

Requires the Secretary to submit to specified congressional committees a report on Department of Defense policies and communications regarding the length of deployments for reservists in connection with Operation Iraqi Freedom.

Directs the Secretary of the Army to designate a senior level official of the Department of the Army to implement recommendations for executive action to address military pay problems.

Expands reenlistment bonus eligibility and the amount of such bonuses for members of the Selected Reserve.

Removes conditions on Ready Reserve members' eligibility for TRICARE enrollment. Makes such eligibility permanent.

Requires the Secretary concerned to pay applicable premiums to continue qualified health benefit plan coverage for family members of eligible reservists serving on active duty for the benefits coverage continuation period.

Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to fund child care for members of the Armed Forces on active duty for Operation Enduring Freedom or Operation Iraqi Freedom.

Requires employers to provide notice of rights and benefits under the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act (USERRA).

Increases monthly educational assistance benefits for members of the Selected Reserve. Expands eligibility for such benefits to include reservists who have served on active duty for a cumulative period of 24 months during any five-year period.

Reduces from 60 to 55 the age at which members of Reserve components may receive military retirement pay.

Establishes the position of Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness (Reserve Affairs). Eliminates the position of Assistant Secretary of Defense for Reserve Affairs. Reduces the number of Assistant Secretaries of Defense.</summary>
</bill>
