<bill session="118" type="h" number="1106" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COST of Relocations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Oversight to Secure Transparency of Relocations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COST of Relocations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Federal agencies to conduct a benefit-cost analysis on relocations involving the movement of employment positions to different areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000825"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="487" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-28T19:15:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Oversight to Secure Transparency of Relocations Act or the COST of Relocations Act

This bill requires a federal agency seeking to relocate more than 5% of its employees or more than 100 employees to conduct and make public a comprehensive cost-benefit analysis of the proposed change.

Specifically, the agency must conduct such analysis and submit it to the agency's office of inspector general for review and submission to Congress.

The report must include

 the anticipated outcomes and improvements that will result from the proposed relocation, the metrics for measuring whether the proposed relocation results in the anticipated outcomes and improvements, a timeline of past and future engagements with stakeholders regarding the proposed relocation, a comprehensive strategy for accomplishing the proposed relocation, and an assessment of the short- and long-term effects of the proposed relocation on the agency's mission.</summary>
</bill>
