<bill session="116" type="h" number="3651" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To facilitate the use of certain land in Nebraska for public outdoor recreational opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the use of certain land in Nebraska for public outdoor recreational opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000449"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-630.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-08" calendar="Union" number="515">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 515.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-15T20:43:36Z" status="Reported to House">This bill authorizes the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation to use, or enter into a lease or agreement with another party to use for public outdoor recreation, up to 40 acres of the land in Nebraska City, Nebraska, that was conveyed for use as an historic site and an interpretive center for the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail under conditions that

 the land shall continue to be maintained in a manner compatible with the use of the conveyed land as an historic site and interpretive center, the nature trail around the perimeter of the land shall remain in place and may be enhanced with educational signage about the flora and fauna that are native to the land and the planting of native flora, and revenue from any use of the land for public outdoor recreation shall be used to offset maintenance and operating costs of the interpretive center.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-630</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
