<bill session="117" type="h" number="557" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Make Education Local Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To allow a State to submit a State management decision to the Secretary of Education to combine certain funds to improve the academic achievement of students.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Make Education Local Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2021-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="513" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="106" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-08T19:53:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Make Education Local Act of 2021

This bill creates a framework under which states may receive federal elementary and secondary education funds on a consolidated basis and use such funds for any educational purpose permitted by state law.

Specifically, the bill permits each state to submit to the Department of Education a state management decision that, among other requirements, describes how the state will address persistently failing public schools. The bill defines state management decision as a state decision to assume full management responsibility for the expenditure of federal funds to advance the educational policy of the state. The duration of a state management decision shall be between 5 and 10 years.

Additionally, each state that operates under a state management decision must establish an accountability system that focuses on the academic achievement of students and includes a system for evaluating the academic achievement and progress of students.</summary>
</bill>
