<bill session="111" type="h" number="5921" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:51Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Support for Families of the Fallen Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the payment of an additional death gratuity on behalf of a member of the Armed Forces killed in action in an amount equal to all social security taxes paid by the member before and during the military service of the member and taxes paid on self-employment income, to be derived from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support for Families of the Fallen Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-15T19:35:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Support for Families of the Fallen Act - Increases the death gratuity paid with respect to a member of the Armed Forces killed in action by: (1) the total amount of social security taxes paid before and during such military service; and (2) any federal taxes paid on self-employment income.

Makes such increase payable through the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
