<bill session="117" type="s" number="1458" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cover Crop Flexibility Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to encourage the planting of cover crops following prevented planting, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cover Crop Flexibility Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2022-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2021-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2359-2360" label="text"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2360" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-25T22:21:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cover Crop Flexibility Act of 2021

This bill modifies the federal crop insurance program to address the planting of cover crops following prevented planting.

Specifically, the bill allows a producer that is prevented from planting its first crop to plant a second crop and receive an indemnity equal to the full guarantee for the first crop if the second crop (1) is an approved cover crop, and (2) cannot be harvested for grain or other uses unrelated to livestock forage or conservation. Under current law, if a producer plants a second crop it can only get an indemnity worth at most 35% of the prevented planting guarantee for the first crop.

For a producer planting a cover crop following prevented planting, the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC) may provide separate prevented planting coverage factors that include preplanting costs and the cost of cover crop seed.

Further, the FCIC must conduct research and development regarding a policy to insure crops on fields that regularly utilize cover crops, including research to examine the extent that cover crops reduce risks of prevented planting and other crop insurance losses.</summary>
</bill>
