<bill session="116" type="h" number="5923" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Access to Co-ops for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve and make permanent the Department of Veterans Affairs loan guarantee for the purchase of residential cooperative housing units, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Access to Co-ops for Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2020-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cooperative and condominium housing"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-05T16:49:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Access to Co-ops for Veterans Act

This bill reauthorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to guarantee a loan for a veteran's purchase of stock or membership in a cooperative housing corporation for the purpose of entitling the veteran to occupy a single family residential unit. The VA must ensure a loan for the purchase of stock or membership in a cooperative housing corporation is not denied if it has been reviewed and approved by a lender approved by Fannie Mae.

The bill also requires the VA to advertise the availability of loan guarantees for housing cooperative share loans to notify eligible veterans, participating lenders, and interested realtors of the availability of such loan guarantees and the procedures and requirements that apply to the obtaining of such guarantees.</summary>
</bill>
