<bill session="119" type="s" number="912" updated="2025-10-07T11:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing American Agriculture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to publish, on an annual basis, an assessment of United States dependency on critical agricultural products or inputs from the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing American Agriculture Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2025-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2025-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-07T18:38:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing American Agriculture Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to assess, on an annual basis, U.S. dependency on critical agricultural products or inputs that could be exploited in the event that China weaponizes such a dependency.&#160;USDA must submit a report to Congress on the assessment, which must&#160;include recommendations to reduce U.S. dependency on China to supply critical agricultural products or inputs.

Under the bill, critical inputs include all farm management, agronomic, and field-applied production inputs (e.g., agricultural equipment, fertilizers, veterinary drugs, and seed).

The bill specifies that, in conducting the assessment, USDA may not require a private entity to provide information to USDA. Further, the bill requires USDA to comply with certain confidentiality requirements and restricts disclosures of the information.</summary>
</bill>
