<bill session="117" type="h" number="2243" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Pay Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to prohibit discrimination in the payment of wages on account of sex, race, or national origin, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Pay Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2021-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E307"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-27T18:27:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Pay Act of 2021

This bill requires employers to provide equal pay to employees for comparable or equivalent work.

Specifically, employers may not discriminate against employees on the basis of sex, race, or national origin with respect to payment of wages or other conditions of employment for jobs that, although dissimilar, the requirements of which are equivalent, when viewed as a composite of skills, effort, responsibility, and working conditions. However, employers may pay different wages in accordance with seniority systems, merit systems, systems that measure earnings by quantity or quality of production, or factors that the employer demonstrates are reasonably job-related, or further legitimate business interests. The bill allows compensatory or punitive damages for violations of this prohibition.

The bill prohibits an employer from (1) discriminating against any individual who opposes any act or practice made illegal by this bill or for assisting in an investigation, or (2) discharging or discriminating against any employee who inquires about or discusses another employee's wages.

The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission must assist employers, labor organizations, and the general public in implementing these provisions.</summary>
</bill>
