<bill session="117" type="s" number="2369" updated="2023-01-01T23:43:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water on Tribal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7632" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-13T22:01:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2021

This bill provides funding for and expands access to water resources for Native communities (i.e., Indian tribes and Native Hawaiian communities).

First, the bill provides funding for the Indian Health Service to (1) plan, design, construct, modernize, improve, and renovate water, sewer, and solid waste sanitation facilities; (2) provide technical assistance; and (3) operate and maintain water facilities that serve Native communities.

 Next, the bill provides funding for the Department of Agriculture to provide water and wastewater facility grants to eligible entities (e.g., Native communities) that have residents facing significant health risks due to inadequate water supply systems. An eligible entity shall not be required to provide a matching contribution in order to receive a grant.

In addition, the bill reauthorizes through FY2031 the Bureau of Reclamation's Rural Water Supply Program. Further, the bill provides funding for and establishes a grant program for tribal clean water access projects. It also provides funding for the Native American Affairs Technical Assistance Program.

The bill also provides funding for the Environmental Protection Agency to provide grants to Indian tribes and Alaska Native villages for drinking water and clean water.</summary>
</bill>
