<bill session="117" type="s" number="768" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Better PLAN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 5303 of title 49, United States Code, to consider housing in metropolitan transportation planning, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better PLAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Planning and Land-Use for Accessible Neighborhoods Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-27T16:03:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Better Planning and Land-Use for Accessible Neighborhoods Act or the Better PLAN Act 

This bill revises the metropolitan transportation planning process for a metropolitan area to consider projects and strategies that will enhance the integration and connectivity of the transportation system by better connecting housing to employment.

Additionally, the transportation planning process must address the integration of housing, transportation, and economic development strategies through a process that provides for effective integration, based on a cooperatively developed and implemented strategy, of new and existing transportation facilities.

In carrying out the planning process, a metropolitan planning organization must (1) consult with state and local entities responsible for land use, economic development, housing, management of road networks, or public transportation; and (2) coordinate with such entities to align the goals of the process with the goals of any comprehensive housing affordability strategies established within the metropolitan planning area.</summary>
</bill>
