<bill session="108" type="s" number="3030" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:28Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Trade Commission Consumer Advocacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Office of Consumer Advocacy and Outreach within the Federal Trade Commission to protect consumers from certain unfair or deceptive acts or practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Trade Commission Consumer Advocacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11900"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-07T20:07:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Trade Commission Consumer Advocacy Act - Establishes within the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) an Office of Consumer Advocacy and Outreach to protect minority consumers, disabled consumers, and other targeted consumers from unfair or deceptive acts or practices.

Requires the head of the Office to: (1) assist law enforcement personnel in investigating unfair or deceptive acts or practices that affect such consumers and in increasing the amount of information available about such conduct through the Consumer Sentinel or equivalent database system; (2) provide such consumers with information regarding the detection of unfair or deceptive acts or practices; (3) administer a program permitting the anonymous reporting of information concerning unfair or deceptive acts or practices that affect such consumers; (4) carry out a program of monetary rewards for reports of such conduct if such reports result in civil penalties; and (5) carry out a public awareness campaign in Spanish.</summary>
</bill>
