<bill session="111" type="h" number="5336" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:10Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Teacher and Principal Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve teacher quality, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Teacher and Principal Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2010-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3242" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-29T23:30:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Teacher and Principal Improvement Act - Amends title II (Preparing, Training, and Recruiting High Quality Teachers and Principals) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to create a new Part E: Building School Capacity for Effective Teaching and Leadership.

Directs the Secretary of Education to allot grants to states for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to improve teacher and principal quality through a system of teacher and principal induction, professional development, and evaluation that is developed, implemented, and evaluated in collaboration with local teacher, principal, and school leader organizations and preparation programs.

Requires LEAs to include in such system: (1) a comprehensive, coherent, high quality formalized induction program for beginning teachers during their first two years of full-time employment; (2) high-quality effective professional development for teachers, principals, school librarians, and other school leaders at their lowest achieving schools; (3) a rigorous, transparent, and equitable teacher and principal evaluation system for all their schools; (4) ongoing high-quality support, coaching, and professional development for principals and other school leaders at their lowest achieving schools; (5) opportunities for teachers to assume new school leadership roles and training regarding such roles; and (6) significant and sustainable stipends above a teacher's base salary for teachers that serve as mentors, instructional coaches, teacher leaders, or evaluators under these programs.

Directs LEA grantees to conduct a valid and reliable full population survey of teaching and learning, at the school and LEA level, the results of which are to inform and be integrated into such systems.

Requires a formal evaluation of each system to be conducted by the state, an institution of higher education, or an external agency and the results disseminated widely.</summary>
</bill>
