<bill session="116" type="h" number="7555" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to add a new medical research component to the credit for increasing research activities.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to add a new medical research component to the credit for increasing research activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Revenue Measures.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM05" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Tax" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-07T12:10:07Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill allows a new research tax credit amount for 14% of specified medical research expenditures. It defines specified medical research expenditures as amounts paid for any qualified research with respect to any qualified countermeasure. A qualified countermeasure is a drug, biological product, or device that is determined to be a priority (1) to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, or treat harm from any biological agent (including organisms that cause an infectious disease) or toxin, chemical, radiological, or nuclear agent that may cause a public health emergency affecting national security; (2) to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, or treat harm from a condition that may result in adverse health consequences or death and may be caused by administering a drug, biological product, or device; or (3) is a product or technology intended to enhance the use or effect of a drug, biological product, or device.

The bill also sets forth a special rule for treatment of specified medical research expenditures paid or incurred in taxable years beginning before January 1, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
