<bill session="111" type="h" number="3094" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alexander L. Booker Child Protection Construction Site Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 by revising regulations to increase worker safety on construction sites and, consequently, to protect child trespassers from unforeseen dangers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alexander L. Booker Child Protection Construction Site Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-29T21:31:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Alexander L. Booker Child Protection Construction Site Safety Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor, in order to increase worker safety and protect child trespassers from unforeseen dangers on construction sites, to revise regulations under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to require: (1) signs and symbols be prominently displayed to warn adults and children of danger or a hazard at construction sites (even during non-working hours); (2) all equipment left unattended at night near a highway, construction areas, or schools or other areas where children are known to congregate to have sufficiently visible barricades to prevent access to such equipment as well as to require the equipment's parking brakes to be set when not in use and be equipped with devices that set off an alarm when tampered with or broken; and (3) all motorized vehicles to be equipped with safety lock systems, including latches or other devices to prevent accidental starting.</summary>
</bill>
