<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1718</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:26:19Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-12T10:33:01Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2005-09-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Flexibility for Displaced Workers Act</title>
        <congress>109</congress>
        <number>3761</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2005-09-23</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 109-72.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-09-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 215.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-09-19</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-09-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>E000285</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Enzi, Michael B. [R-WY]</fullName>
        <firstName>MICHAEL</firstName>
        <lastName>ENZI</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>WY</state>
        <middleName>B.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000105</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kennedy, Edward M. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>EDWARD</firstName>
        <lastName>KENNEDY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>MOORE</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2005-09-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see H.R.3761, which became Public Law 109-72 on 9/23/2005.]]></text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R.3761</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/109th-congress/house-bill/3761</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Labor and Employment</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alabama</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disaster relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Dislocated workers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Displaced persons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency Management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency housing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment agencies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Floods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Grants-in-aid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hurricane aftermath legislation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hurricanes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Job hunting</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Louisiana</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mississippi</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public service employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Temporary employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Unemployment insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Labor and Employment</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-09-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-09-22T21:00:36Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Hurricane Katrina Employment and Training Assistance Act - Allows national emergency grant funds to states under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (WIA) for addressing the effects of Hurricane Katrina (HK) to be used to provide disaster relief employment on projects that provide assistance in areas outside of the HK-disaster area.</p><P>Allows such funds to be used to provide disaster relief employment and other WIA assistance, or temporary general public sector employment, to HK-affected individuals, including those who have relocated from states in the disaster area, who were unemployed at the time of the disaster, or who are without employment history, in addition those who meet WIA eligibility requirements. </P><P>Limits such general public sector employment to not more than six months in addition to such disaster relief employment. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor, however, to extend the duration of employment under this Act and WIA for up to an additional six months due to extraordinary circumstances. </P><P>Directs the Secretary, in awarding WIA national emergency grants for disaster relief employment, to give priority: (1) first, to states with major disaster areas; and (2) second, to the remaining states that have been most heavily impacted by the demand for services by HK-affected workers.</P><P>Prohibits an entity that is providing such disaster relief employment from denying such employment because of an HK-affected worker's inability, due to HK's effects, to provide documentation of eligibility.</P><P>Allows any state, with the Secretary's approval, to use available WIA national emergency grant funds to assist HK-affected workers, including those who have relocated from states in the HK-disaster area.</P><P>Authorizes the Secretary to award a WIA national emergency grant for employment and training assistance (ETA) for dislocated workers to an eligible entity to provide ETA to HK-affected workers, including workers who have relocated from HK-disaster areas.</P><P>(Sec. 3) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) states operating one-stop centers should make them available for use in HK-affected areas and areas where large numbers of HK's victims have been relocated; and (2) one-stop operators should increase access for HK-affected individuals, including through expanded operational hours and on-site services for those in temporary housing locations.</P>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Hurricane Katrina Employment and Training Assistance Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Hurricane Katrina Employment and Training Assistance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Hurricane Katrina Employment and Training Assistance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide special rules for disaster relief employment under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 for individuals displaced by Hurricane Katrina.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2005-09-20T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s1718pcs/xml/BILLS-109s1718pcs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2005-09-20</actionDate>
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 215.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
