<bill session="118" type="s" number="2862" updated="2025-11-19T04:49:19Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Farmers Feed the World Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food for Peace Act to restore the original intent of commodity transfers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Farmers Feed the World Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2024-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2023-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2024-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4293" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-05T18:04:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Farmers Feed the World Act of 2023

This bill imposes limits and requirements on international food assistance provided under Title II of the Food for Peace Act and makes other changes to the assistance program.

First, the bill eliminates the use of food procured outside of the United States, food vouchers, or cash transfers as food as assistance under the program.

Second, the bill restricts the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) from using more than 50% of its annual appropriations for program expenses other than the procurement of agricultural commodities and ocean transportation.

Additionally, the bill limits the amount that USAID may provide to qualified organizations to be used for purposes such as administration, personnel, and program evaluation. Under current law, USAID must spend a minimum of 7.5% and a maximum of 20% of its annual appropriations for these purposes. The bill reduces the minimum to 5% and the maximum to 10%. The bill also cancels the Local and Regional Procurement assistance program, which funds field-based (i.e., outside the United States) agricultural projects.

The bill also modifies some of the respective powers of USAID and the Department of Agriculture (USDA). For example, the bill transfers from USAID to USDA the authority to approve drawing emergency food aid from the Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust.

The bill also renames the assistance program as the Peter O'Brien Food for Peace Program. &#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
