<bill session="116" type="s" number="2786" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Arctic Shipping Federal Advisory Committee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arctic Shipping Federal Advisory Committee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Arctic Shipping Federal Advisory Committee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Federal advisory committee to provide policy recommendations to the Secretary of Transportation on positioning the United States to take advantage of emerging opportunities for Arctic maritime transportation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2019-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2019-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2019-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-16">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Wicker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-295.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-11-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="588">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 588.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arctic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-20T18:20:37Z" status="Reported to Senate">Arctic Shipping Federal Advisory Committee Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish an Arctic Shipping Federal Advisory Committee to advise DOT on matters related to Arctic maritime transportation, including Arctic seaway development.

The committee must

 develop a set of policy recommendations that would enhance the leadership role played by the United States in improving the safety and reliability of Arctic maritime transportation in accordance with customary international maritime law, consider establishing a congressionally chartered seaway development corporation modeled on the St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation, and provide advice and recommendations to DOT on Arctic marine transportation. The bill requires any Special Representative for the Arctic Region appointed by the Department of State to coordinate any activities recommended by the committee's implementation plan and to facilitate multilateral dialogues with member and observer nations of the Arctic Council.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-295</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
