<bill session="117" type="s" number="676" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Higher Education Espionage and Theft Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address foreign threats to higher education in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Higher Education Espionage and Theft Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1777" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-22T16:11:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Higher Education Espionage and Theft Act of 2021

This bill establishes a process for designating foreign actors as foreign intelligence threats to higher education.

Specifically, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) must designate a foreign actor as a foreign intelligence threat to higher education if the foreign actor has committed, attempted to commit, or conspired to commit certain actions in connection with an institution of higher education (IHE), such as espionage, misuse of visas, or theft of trade secrets. Prior to making such a designation, the FBI must submit notice to Congress and the Department of Justice.

Upon the designation of a foreign actor as a threat, the Department of State must revoke the nonimmigrant visa issued to the foreign actor present in the United States, and the Department of Homeland Security must initiate removal proceedings against the foreign actor.

Additionally, the bill provides for judicial review and a process for revoking a foreign actor's designation as a threat.

Finally, the bill also requires an IHE to disclose to the Department of Education any gift or contract with a foreign intelligence threat, including the fair market value of the gift or contract.</summary>
</bill>
