<bill session="111" type="h" number="5063" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:07Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LT WARRIOR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a joint task force to improve the research and development of lighter weight body armor.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Light Weight Armor Research Requirements for Individual Operational Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LT WARRIOR Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000465"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000369" joined="2010-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-30T15:45:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Light Weight Armor Research Requirements for Individual Operational Readiness Act or LT WARRIOR Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to establish the Joint Task Force Light Weight Armor Research Requirements for Individual Operational Readiness, or JTF-LT WARRIOR, to: (1) synchronize efforts among the military departments to identify and examine the requirements for lighter weight body armor; and (2) serve as the centralized body for determining and coordinating issues regarding such armor and other personal protective equipment, including its development and procurement.

Requires the Task Force to report to the Secretary semiannually over a two-year period recommending ways to more effectively address the research, development, and procurement requirements regarding reducing the weight of body armor.</summary>
</bill>
