<bill session="119" type="s" number="60" updated="2025-04-09T14:44:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Write the Laws Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Write the Laws Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to end the unconstitutional delegation of legislative power which was exclusively vested in the Senate and House of Representatives by article I, section 1 of the Constitution of the United States, and to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to issue a report to Congress detailing the extent of the problem of unconstitutional delegation to the end that such delegations can be phased out, thereby restoring the constitutional principle of separation of powers set forth in the first sections of the Constitution of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-09T14:42:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Write the Laws Act

This bill prohibits an act of Congress from containing any delegation of legislative powers, whether to any component within the legislative branch, the President or any other member of the executive branch, the judicial branch, any agency or quasi-public agency, any state or state instrumentality, or any other organization or individual.

The Government Accountability Office must identify to Congress all statutes enacted before the date that is 90 days after this bill's enactment that contain any delegation of legislative power.

Any act of Congress, presidential directive, adjudicative decision, rule, or regulation that is enacted 90 days or more after this bill's enactment and is noncompliant with this bill shall have no force or effect.</summary>
</bill>
