<bill session="118" type="s" number="620" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Offshore Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Alaska Offshore Parity Act</title>
    <title type="display">Alaska Offshore Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the distribution of certain outer Continental Shelf revenues to the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="578">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 578.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-19T17:44:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alaska Offshore Parity Act

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to share more revenues derived from energy and mineral development in the Alaska Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) region with Alaska and its coastal political subdivisions. Currently, only revenue generated by certain nearshore areas of the OCS is shared with Alaska. The bill requires Treasury to share a specified portion of revenue derived from all areas in the Alaska OCS region. Alaska may use the funding from such revenue for coastal protection, coastal infrastructure, systems to reduce energy costs and greenhouse gas emissions, programs at institutions of higher education, and other related purposes.</summary>
</bill>
