<bill session="119" type="h" number="382" updated="2025-04-03T19:39:36Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Exported Carbon Emissions Report Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Exported Carbon Emissions Report Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to collect, calculate, and publish information regarding emissions of carbon dioxide and methane outside the boundaries of the United States that are associated with exports of fossil fuels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001117"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects/>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-03T19:39:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Exported Carbon Emissions Report Act of 2025

This bill directs the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to annually collect, calculate, and publish information on certain emissions of carbon dioxide and methane from fossil fuels. Specifically, the EPA must publish information, for each of the previous 10 years, on the total emissions of carbon dioxide and methane that are released (1) within the boundaries of the United States that are the result of the extraction, processing, transportation, combustion, and other use of fossil fuels; and (2) outside the boundaries of the United States that are the result of leakage and combustion of fossil fuels produced or refined in the United States and subsequently exported.</summary>
</bill>
