<bill session="116" type="h" number="8576" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:32Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAID Study Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAID Study Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Auto Insurance Discrimination Study Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Government Accountability Office to conduct biennial studies of personal private automobile insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000481"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2020-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2020-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2020-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-25T14:50:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Auto Insurance Discrimination Study Act of 2020 or the PAID Study Act of 2020 

This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report on discrimination in private passenger automobile insurance coverage. Specifically, the GAO must report every two years on

 the use of non-driving related underwriting factors; controls and practices in use by insurers to prevent discriminatory pricing of coverage; how premiums are impacted by zip code, race, religion, and other factors; and state insurance regulatory oversight and enforcement regarding discriminatory pricing. State insurance regulatory bodies must take into consideration these reports in establishing and approving premium rates for private passenger automobile insurance coverage.</summary>
</bill>
