<bill session="117" type="s" number="2718" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify that an authorization to use military force, a declaration of war, or any similar authority shall not authorize the detention without charge or trial of a citizen or lawful permanent resident of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Due Process Guarantee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Due Process Guarantee Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2021-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2021-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2021-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6458-6459" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6459" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-23T18:11:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Due Process Guarantee Act

This bill limits the detention authority of the United States.

Current law prohibits the indefinite detention of a U.S. citizen unless it is authorized by an act of Congress.

This bill prohibits the indefinite detention of a U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident unless it is authorized by an act of Congress that (1) is consistent with the Constitution, and (2) expressly authorizes the detention.

Additionally, the bill specifies that no U.S. citizen or lawful permanent resident who is apprehended in the United States may be imprisoned or otherwise detained without charge or trial unless such imprisonment or detention is expressly authorized by an act of Congress.

Finally, it specifies that a general authorization to use military force or similar measure, on its own, does not authorize the indefinite detention of a person who is arrested in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
