<bill session="117" type="h" number="4666" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modernize and improve the public service loan forgiveness program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Public Service Loan Forgiveness Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Service Loan Forgiveness Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000613"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000588" joined="2022-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-06T21:50:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Service Loan Forgiveness Modernization Act

This bill revises provisions related to the Public Service Loan Forgiveness (PSLF) program.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish and regularly update a comprehensive database identifying each qualified public service employer and each position offered by such employer that is a public service job. ED must also establish a process whereby an employer may submit a certification that it is a qualified public service employer.

In addition, the bill prohibits ED from requiring a borrower to apply for and be denied loan cancellation pursuant to the PSLF program as a condition of eligibility for loan forgiveness under the Temporary Expanded Public Service Loan Forgiveness program. ED must also develop and make publicly available an online tool for borrowers to learn more about the expanded program, determine their eligibility for forgiveness, and identify any requirements for participation.</summary>
</bill>
