<bill session="112" type="h" number="3696" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:46Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Football Playoff Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">College Football Playoff Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit, as an unfair and deceptive act or practice, the promotion, marketing, and advertising of any post-season NCAA Division I football game as a national championship game unless such game is the culmination of a fair and equitable playoff system.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-01-03T21:24:23Z" status="Introduced in House">College Football Playoff Act of 2011 - Prohibits promoting, marketing, or advertising a post-season National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division Football Bowl Subdivision (FBS) game as a championship or national championship game (or any merchandise that refers to the game as a championship or national championship game) unless such game is the final game of a single elimination post-season playoff system for which all NCAA Division I FBS conferences and unaffiliated Division I FBS teams are eligible.

Treats a violation as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act.

Makes this Act applicable to any game that occurs after January 31, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
