<bill session="117" type="h" number="4235" updated="2022-12-31T04:58:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to award grants to certain entities for purposes of carrying out climate-resilient living shoreline projects that protect coastal communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Living Shorelines Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Living Shorelines Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2021-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000591" joined="2022-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY18" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3764" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2633" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Seashores and lakeshores"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-04T21:01:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Living Shorelines Act

This bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish grant programs to support living shoreline projects and research on nature-based infrastructure.

NOAA must award grants to state or local governments, nonprofit organizations, and Indian tribes to (1) implement climate-resilient living shoreline projects; and (2) encourage innovation in the use of natural materials to protect coastal communities, habitats, and natural system functions.

NOAA shall establish an engineering standard applicable to living shoreline projects for each region of the United States and use such standard to select eligible entities to receive such grants.

A grant to carry out a living shoreline project may be used only to

 carry out the project, including administration, design, permitting, entry into negotiated indirect cost rate agreements, and construction; monitor, collect, and report data on the performance of the project, in accordance with the engineering standard; or incentivize landowners to engage in such projects. NOAA shall award competitive research grants to eligible entities, including U.S. territories, to carry out projects focused on developing and assessing the effectiveness of innovative approaches to nature-based infrastructure for specified climate-related purposes. NOAA shall award grants to such entities for projects that focus on, among other things

 assessing the effectiveness of installed nature-based infrastructure, or novel approaches to nature-based infrastructure and living shorelines.</summary>
</bill>
