<bill session="117" type="s" number="359" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Feed Emergency Enhancement During Disasters with Cover Crops Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to modify prevented planting coverage.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feed Emergency Enhancement During Disasters with Cover Crops Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEEDD Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2021-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1240" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-07T19:11:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Feed Emergency Enhancement During Disasters with Cover Crops Act of 2021 or the FEEDD Act of 2021

This bill expands relief under the federal crop insurance program for agricultural producers that harvest second crops as a result of a prevented planting.

Specifically, a producer may collect 100% of the prevented planting guarantee for the acreage of the first crop if (1) the acres planted are in an area with low hay or forage supplies due to widespread excessive moisture, flood, or drought; (2) the second crop will be planted with an intended use of animal feed that is hayed, gazed, or chopped; and (3) the second crop will be donated or used by the producer.

Additionally, the Department of Agriculture may not reduce the amount of a payment collected by a producer that hays, grazes, or chops over crops on prevented planting acres after the harvest date that it establishes for each region of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
