<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1451</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T07:03:00Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T07:03:00Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-07-24</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2003-09-25T17:33:49Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2003-09-25T16:42:27Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-07-24T20:06:05Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <number>1925</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2003-10-10</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 108-96.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-30</actionDate>
        <actionTime>18:29:31</actionTime>
        <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H15000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-30</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-30</actionDate>
        <actionTime>12:30:15</actionTime>
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S12099-12101; text as passed Senate: CR S12100-12101)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-26</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.(consideration: CR S12099-12101; text as passed Senate: CR S12100-12101)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-25</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 289.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Hatch without amendment. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-25</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Hatch without amendment. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-24</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9906)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000338</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hatch, Orrin G. [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>ORRIN</firstName>
        <lastName>HATCH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <middleName>GRANT</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000174</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Leahy, Patrick J. [D-VT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patrick</firstName>
        <lastName>Leahy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-07-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-09-30T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1451, Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/14784</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on the Judiciary&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-09-30T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1451, Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/14784</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on the Judiciary</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see H.R. 1925, which became Public Law 108-96 on 10/10/2003.]]></text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 1925</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/108th-congress/house-bill/1925</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Families</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Homeless</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Missing children</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Runaway children</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Youth</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-07-24</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-09-26T20:15:32Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act - Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (RHYA) and the Missing Children's Assistance Act (MCAA) to reauthorize and revise programs under such Acts. <p>Amends RHYA part A (Runaway and Homeless Youth Grant Program) to: (1) rename it as the Basic Center Grant Program; (2) include testing for sexually transmitted diseases, at the request of runaway and homeless youth, among the services which local basic centers may provide; and (3) provide for an exception to a 20-youth-maximum-capacity requirement for funding a runaway and homeless youth center or a locally controlled temporary shelter if the applicant assures that there is a State or local law or regulation that requires a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for children and youth serving facilities. <p>Includes maternity group homes among the types of transitional living youth projects eligible for grants under part B (Transitional Living Grant Program) of RHYA.. <p>Extends an individual youth's eligibility to remain in a part B shelter beyond the regular 540-day period, until the earlier of the youth's 18th birthday or the 180th day after the end of the 540-day period. <p>Revises RHYA part A coordination assurance and part B coordination agreement requirements to provide for coordinating services with school district liaisons designated under the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to assure that runaway and homeless youth are provided information about the educational services available to them. Requires part B plan development to include referral of homeless youth to postsecondary education, to training services and programs under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998, and welfare programs under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996. <p>Sets 18 years as the maximum age limit for youth seeking shelter in RHYA part A centers. <p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) report on strategies to end youth homelessness; and (2) evaluate RHYA part B programs to report on long-term housing outcomes for youth 12 to 18 months after exiting the program. <p>Prohibits use of RHYA funds for any program of distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug. Requires RHYA funds recipients who carry out such distribution programs to account for such program funds separately from RHYA funds. <p> <p>Requires NCMEC to coordinate the operation of a cyber tipline for reporting Internet-related child sexual exploitation in the areas of: (1) distribution of child pornography; (2) online enticement of children for sexual acts; and (3) child prostitution.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>80</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-09-26T20:24:05Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act - Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (RHYA) and the Missing Children's Assistance Act (MCAA) to reauthorize and revise programs under such Acts.</p> <p><b>Title I: Amendments to Runaway and Homeless Youth Act</b> - (Sec. 102) Renames RHYA part A as the Basic Center Grant Program (currently Runaway and Homeless Youth Grant Program).<p>(Sec. 103) Includes testing for sexually transmitted diseases, at the request of runaway and homeless youth, among the services which local basic centers may provide.<p>(Sec. 106) Provides for an exception to a 20-youth-maximum-capacity requirement for funding a basic center, or a locally controlled temporary shelter, if the applicant assures that there is a State or local law or regulation that requires a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for children and youth serving facilities.<p>(Sec. 107) Includes maternity group homes among the types of transitional living youth projects eligible for grants under part B (Transitional Living Grant Program) of RHYA.. <p>(Sec. 108) Extends an individual youth's eligibility to remain in a transitional shelter beyond the regular 540-day period until the earlier of the youth's 18th birthday or the 180th day after the end of the 540-day period. <p>(Sec. 109) Revises RHYA part A coordination assurance requirements to provide for coordinating services with school district liaisons designated under the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to assure that runaway and homeless youth are provided information about the educational services available to such youth under such Act. <p>(Sec. 110) Requires part B coordination agreements to also provide for coordinating services with McKinney-Vento school district liaisons. <p>(Sec. 111) Requires part B plan development to include referral of homeless youth to: (1) postsecondary education; (2) training services and programs under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998; and (3) welfare programs under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996. <p>(Sec. 112) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to consult the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to ensure coordination of programs and services for homeless youth.<p>(Sec. 116) Sets 18 years as the maximum age limit for youth seeking shelter in RHYA part A centers.<p>(Sec. 117) Extends through FY 2008 the authorization of appropriations for programs under: (1) RHYA part E, Sexual Abuse Prevention Program; and (2) all other parts of RHYA. Increases to a minimum 45 percent, and a maximum 55 percent under certain conditions, the part B portion of funds allocated to parts A and B.<p>(Sec. 118) Directs the Secretary to report on strategies to end youth homelessness.<p>(Sec. 119) Directs the Secretary to evaluate RHYA part B programs to report on long-term housing outcomes for youth 12 to 18 months after exiting the program.<p>(Sec. 120) Prohibits use of RHYA funds for any program of distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug. Requires RHYA funds recipients who carry out such distribution programs to account for such program funds separately from RHYA funds. <p><b>Title II: Amendments to Missing Children's Assistance Act</b> - Amends MCAA to extend through FY 2008 the authorization of appropriations for: (1) an annual grant by the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention (in the Department of Justice) to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC); and (2) other programs under MCAA.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>82</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-09-29T18:59:08Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.)</b></p> <p>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act - Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (RHYA) and the Missing Children's Assistance Act (MCAA) to reauthorize and revise programs under such Acts.</p> <p><b>Title I: Amendments to Runaway and Homeless Youth Act</b> - (Sec. 102) Renames RHYA part A as the Basic Center Grant Program (currently Runaway and Homeless Youth Grant Program).<p>(Sec. 103) Includes testing for sexually transmitted diseases, at the request of runaway and homeless youth, among the services which local basic centers may provide.<p>(Sec. 106) Provides for an exception to a 20-youth-maximum-capacity requirement for funding a basic center, or a locally controlled temporary shelter, if the applicant assures that there is a State or local law or regulation that requires a higher maximum to comply with licensure requirements for children and youth serving facilities. <p>(Sec. 107) Includes maternity group homes among the types of transitional living youth projects eligible for grants under part B (Transitional Living Grant Program) of RHYA. <p>(Sec. 108) Extends an individual youth's eligibility to remain in a transitional shelter beyond the regular 540-day period until the earlier of the youth's 18th birthday or the 180th day after the end of the 540-day period. <p>(Sec. 109) Revises RHYA part A coordination assurance requirements to provide for coordinating services with school district liaisons designated under the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to assure that runaway and homeless youth are provided information about the educational services available to such youth under such Act. <p>(Sec. 110) Requires part B coordination agreements to also provide for coordinating services with McKinney-Vento school district liaisons. <p>(Sec. 111) Requires part B plan development to include referral of homeless youth to: (1) postsecondary education; (2) training services and programs under the Workforce Investment Act of 1998; and (3) welfare programs under the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996. <p>(Sec. 112) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to consult the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to ensure coordination of programs and services for homeless youth.<p>(Sec. 116) Sets 18 years as the maximum age limit for youth seeking shelter in RHYA part A centers.<p>(Sec. 117) Extends through FY 2008 the authorization of appropriations for programs under: (1) RHYA part E, Sexual Abuse Prevention Program; and (2) all other parts of RHYA. Increases to a minimum 45 percent, and a maximum 55 percent under certain conditions, the part B portion of funds allocated to parts A and B.<p>(Sec. 118) Directs the Secretary to report on strategies to end youth homelessness.<p>(Sec. 119) Directs the Secretary to evaluate RHYA part B programs to report on long-term housing outcomes for youth 12 to 18 months after exiting the program.<p>(Sec. 120) Prohibits use of RHYA funds for any program of distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug. Requires RHYA funds recipients who carry out such distribution programs to account for such program funds separately from RHYA funds. <p><b>Title II: Amendments to Missing Children's Assistance Act</b> - Amends MCAA to extend through FY 2008 the authorization of appropriations for: (1) an annual grant by the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention (in the Department of Justice) to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC); and (2) other programs under MCAA.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reauthorize programs under the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act and the Missing Children's Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
        <title>Runaway, Homeless, and Missing Children Protection Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-09-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2003-09-25T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-07-24T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-09-30</actionDate>
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
      <actionTime>18:29:31</actionTime>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
