<bill session="118" type="s" number="1125" updated="2025-11-19T03:23:47Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EHR Program RESET Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EHR Program RESET Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Health Record Program Restructure, Enhance, Strengthen, and Empower Technology Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize an electronic health record modernization program of the Department of Veterans Affairs and increase oversight and accountability of the program to better serve veterans, medical professionals of the Department, and taxpayers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-217.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1659" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2809" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-28T20:57:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Electronic Health Record Program Restructure, Enhance, Strengthen, and Empower Technology Act of 2023 or the EHR Program RESET Act of 2023

This bill establishes within the Veterans Health Administration a program to modernize the electronic health record and other relevant health information technology systems of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). The bill also establishes the Electronic Health Record and Health Information Technology Modernization Program Management Office and a position of Deputy Chief Information Officer for Electronic Health Record and Health Information Technology to implement the program.

The VA must exceed or meet certain standards at its facilities that are using the Oracle Cerner product before it may initiate new deployments of the product.

The bill requires additional information to be included in the quarterly updates on the Electronic Health Record Modernization Program, such as data on retention, morale, and turnover at sites using the new electronic health record.

Within 275 days after the enactment of this bill, the VA must terminate all of its contracts with Oracle Cerner for training and change management related to electronic health record modernization and cease to issue task orders for such activities from Oracle Cerner or its subcontractors.

The VA must designate one senior official (GS-15 or higher) as the lead negotiator on all current and future contracts relating to the new electronic health record.

The Chief Acquisition Officer of the VA must contract with an entity to independently verify and validate the modernization efforts of certain VA programs (e.g., the Electronic Health Record Modernization Program).</summary>
</bill>
