<bill session="117" type="h" number="7356" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TPS Reform Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TPS Reform Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to modify the procedure to designate a foreign state, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2022-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2022-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2022-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2022-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2022-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2022-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-12T21:34:37Z" status="Introduced in House">TPS Reform Act of 2022

This bill changes the procedures for designating a country with temporary protected status (TPS). (Qualified nationals of a TPS-designated country shall have work authorization and may not be removed from the United States while the status is in effect.)

Specifically, the bill requires an act of Congress to designate a TPS country, whereas currently the Department of Homeland Security has such authority. The initial act of designating a TPS country must include a time period for the designation of up to 18 months and also contain certain information, including an estimate of the number of individuals who would benefit from the status. Congress may also pass an act to terminate or extend a designation.

The bill also establishes that an alien who lacks lawful immigration status may not receive the benefits of temporary protected status.</summary>
</bill>
