<bill session="119" type="h" number="4922" updated="2025-11-08T09:05:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-16T17:02:21-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-16T17:02:21-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-08-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">D. C. Criminal Reforms to Immediately Make Everyone Safe Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DC CRIMES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DC Criminal Reforms to Immediately Make Everyone Safe Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">D. C. Criminal Reforms to Immediately Make Everyone Safe Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit youth offender status in the District of Columbia to individuals 18 years of age or younger, to direct the Attorney General of the District of Columbia to establish and operate a publicly accessible website containing updated statistics on juvenile crime in the District of Columbia, to amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to prohibit the Council of the District of Columbia from enacting changes to existing criminal liability sentences, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001309" joined="2025-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2025-08-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000484" joined="2025-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000603" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2025-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-08-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-15T19:25:24-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 707 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4922, H.R. 5143, H.R. 5140, H.R. 5125, H.R. 1047, H.R. 3015 and H.R. 3062. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4922, H.R. 5143, H.R. 5140, H.R. 5125, H.R. 1047, H.R. 3015, and H.R. 3062 under a closed rule, and provides for a motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T15:05:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 707.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4333" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T15:05:30-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4922, H.R. 5143, H.R. 5140, H.R. 5125, H.R. 1047, H.R. 3015 and H.R. 3062. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4922, H.R. 5143, H.R. 5140, H.R. 5125, H.R. 1047, H.R. 3015, and H.R. 3062 under a closed rule, and provides for a motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T15:07:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4922.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T15:35:14-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T15:35:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate of H.R. 4922, the Chair put the question on passage of the bill and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Garcia (CA) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T16:30:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4345" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="270" datetime="2025-09-16T17:02:21-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 179 (Roll no. 270).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4333" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-09-16T17:02:22-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="707" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h103"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-09-09T15:38:47Z" status="Introduced in House">DC Criminal Reforms to Immediately Make Everyone Safe Act or the DC CRIMES Act

This bill limits the authority of the District of Columbia (DC) government over its criminal sentencing laws.&#160;

The bill eliminates the DC government&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s authority to enact any act, resolution, or rule to change any criminal liability sentence in effect on the date of the bill's enactment.

The bill also (1) reduces the maximum age of a youth offender from 24 years to 18 years, and (2) repeals a provision that allows a DC criminal court to issue a sentence to a youth offender that is less than the mandatory minimum term otherwise required by law. A DC criminal court currently has the discretion to reduce or modify certain criminal sentences for a youth offender under specified circumstances. For example, a DC court may sentence a youth offender to probation in lieu of confinement. (However, this discretion does not apply to several specified violent crimes.)&#160;

Additionally, the bill directs the Office of the Attorney General for DC to publish, and update monthly, certain youth offender crime data on a publicly accessible website.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
