<bill session="117" type="s" number="4176" updated="2023-05-26T18:30:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to modify the eligibility requirements for certain small water storage and groundwater storage projects and to authorize the use of funds for certain additional Carey Act projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to modify the eligibility requirements for certain small water storage and groundwater storage projects and to authorize the use of funds for certain additional Carey Act projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin under authority of the order of the Senate of 10/14/2022 with an amendment. With written report No. 117-188.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-10-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="539">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 539.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9518" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-24T18:32:25Z" status="Reported to Senate">This bill expands eligibility for the Bureau of Reclamation's competitive grant program for small water storage and groundwater storage projects. Under the bill, eligible projects must have a capacity of not less than 200 acre-feet (AF) of water. Current law requires an eligible project to have a capacity of not less than 2,000 AF of water.

The bill also allows Reclamation to provide additional grants to certain dam rehabilitation and reconstruction projects provided that projects previously eligible under the program have received the necessary funding.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-188</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
