<bill session="108" type="s" number="2154" updated="2023-01-15T10:47:53Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dru's Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National sex offender registration database, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Database Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Dru's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Sex Offender Registry Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2004-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000705" joined="2004-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2004-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2004-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2001"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2001-2002" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3255-3256"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11662-11663" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T11:24:35-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3929" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil commitment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4073"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2005-02-18T19:23:54Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Database Act of 2004 or Dru's Law - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) make publicly available in a registry via the Internet, from information contained in the National Sex Offender Registry, specified information about sexually violent predators and persons convicted of a sexually violent offense or a criminal offense against a minor, who are required to register with a minimally sufficient State sexual offender registration program; and (2) allow registry users to identity offenders who are currently residing within a radius of the location indicated by the user. Requires registry information to include the offender's name, address, date of birth, physical description, and photograph, the nature and date of commission of the offense, and the date on which the person is released from prison or placed on parole, supervised release, or probation

Requires: (1) any State that provides for a civil commitment proceeding to notify the State attorney general of the impending release of a sexually violent predator or a person has been deemed to be at high-risk for recommitting any sexually violent offense or criminal offense against a minor; (2) the State attorney general to consider instituting a civil commitment proceeding; and (3) each State to intensively monitor, for at least a year, any such person who has been unconditionally released by the State and who has not been civilly committed.

Makes a State that fails to implement Act requirements ineligible to receive 25 percent of funds that would otherwise be allocated to it under the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994.</summary>
</bill>
