<bill session="111" type="s" number="204" updated="2019-11-15T21:57:13Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NOPEC</title>
    <title type="display">No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Sherman Act to make oil-producing and exporting cartels illegal.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2009-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2009-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S311"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S311-312" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-02T14:37:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Oil Producing and Exporting Cartels Act of 2009 or NOPEC - Amends the Sherman Act to declare it to be illegal and a violation of the Act for any foreign state or instrumentality thereof to act collectively or in combination with any other foreign state or any other person, whether by cartel or any other association or form of cooperation or joint action, to limit the production or distribution of oil, natural gas, or any other petroleum product (petroleum), to set or maintain the price of petroleum, or to otherwise take any action in restraint of trade for petroleum, when such action has a direct, substantial, and reasonably foreseeable effect on the market, supply, price, or distribution of petroleum in the United States.

Denies a foreign state engaged in such conduct sovereign immunity from the jurisdiction or judgements of U.S. courts in any action brought to enforce this Act.

States that no U.S. court shall decline, based on the act of state doctrine, to make a determination on the merits in an action brought under this Act.

Authorizes the Attorney General to bring an action in U.S. district court to enforce this Act.

Amends the federal judicial code to make an exception to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state in an action brought under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
