<bill session="118" type="s" number="1343" updated="2025-11-19T03:37:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Adjudications for Immigrants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Adjudications for Immigrants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to alter the definition of "conviction", and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1421" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3043" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1392" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3194" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3050" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-05T00:28:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair Adjudications for Immigrants Act

This bill narrows the scope of certain crime-based grounds for barring or removing a non-U.S. national (alien under federal law) from the United States. (Generally, a conviction for certain crimes, such as a crime that carries a term of incarceration of a certain length, may constitute grounds for denying an individual certain immigration benefits.)

The bill redefines the term conviction to exclude convictions that have been dismissed, expunged, deferred, annulled, invalidated, withheld, vacated, or pardoned. The term must also exclude adjudications where a court issued a recommendation against removal, an order of probation without entry of judgment, or a similar disposition.

In addition, any reference to a term of imprisonment or sentence must, unless otherwise provided (1) only consider the period of incarceration ordered by a court, and (2) exclude any suspended portion of a sentence. Currently, for immigration purposes, a term of incarceration includes any part of the sentence that was suspended.

These provisions pertaining to the definition of conviction and terms of imprisonment shall apply to convictions and judgments entered either before or after this bill's enactment.

Furthermore, certain crime-based grounds for barring or removing a non-U.S. national shall not apply if the sentencing court issues a recommendation that the alien not be removed on the basis of the conviction.</summary>
</bill>
