<bill session="116" type="h" number="7560" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Guaranteeing Equipment Safety for Firefighters Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to conduct a study of personal protective equipment worn by firefighters to determine the prevalence and concentration of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guaranteeing Equipment Safety for Firefighters Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2020-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2525" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6395" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-21T18:22:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Guaranteeing Equipment Safety for Firefighters Act of 2020

This bill requires the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to study and report on the contents and composition of certain firefighting equipment.

Such study shall examine perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS, in new and unused personal protective equipment (PPE) worn by firefighters. PFAS are man-made substances that may have adverse human health effects, and which are contained in a variety of PPE. Specifically NIST must study (1) the identity, prevalence, and concentration of PFAS in such PPE; (2) the conditions and extent to which PFAS are released into the environment from the degradation of such PPE from normal use by firefighters; and (3) the relative risk of exposure to PFAS faced by firefighters.

NIST shall issue a solicitation for research proposals to carry out recommendations from its report and award grants to applicants that submit proposals to develop safe alternatives to PFAS in firefighters' PPE.</summary>
</bill>
