<bill session="118" type="s" number="1914" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Air Traffic Control Workforce Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Traffic Control Workforce Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the air traffic controller staffing report, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-30T14:50:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Air Traffic Control Workforce Transparency Act

This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to provide Congress with information on specific air traffic controller staffing standards and data.

Currently, the FAA must submit an annual report to Congress that contains the staffing standards used to determine the number of air traffic controllers needed to operate the U.S. air traffic control system. The bill requires the FAA report to specifically contain the Collaborative Resource Workgroup (CRWG) staffing standards used to determine the number of fully certified air traffic controllers needed. (The CRWG consists of participants from&#160;the FAA Air Traffic Organization who&#160;work with the National Air Traffic Controllers Association to survey facilities to support validation of or changes to the staffing targets for certified professional controllers.)&#160;

The bill also directs the FAA to provide Congress with specific information for each FAA-operated air traffic control facility. For example, the FAA must provide information on the current certified professional controllers' staffing levels and the CRWG operational staffing targets for certified professional controllers.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
