<bill session="119" type="h" number="1402" updated="2025-11-19T23:01:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-29T14:13:27-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-29T14:13:27-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TICKET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">TICKET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">TICKET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">TICKET Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act</title>
    <title type="display">TICKET Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require sellers of event tickets to disclose comprehensive information to consumers about ticket prices and related fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000601" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2025-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-24">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 119-66.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-04-24" calendar="Union" number="43">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 43.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T14:49:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T14:49:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1640: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T14:49:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1402.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T15:00:17-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29T14:06:17-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1706: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="107" datetime="2025-04-29T14:13:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 409 - 15 (Roll no. 107).</text>
      <reference ref="04/28/2025 CR H1640-1641" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29T14:13:28-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="163">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 163.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="281" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1768" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-25T15:30:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency In Charges for Key Events Ticketing Act or the TICKET Act

This bill requires ticket sellers (including sellers on the secondary market) for concerts, performances, sporting events, and similar activities to clearly and prominently disclose the total ticket price for the event&#160;at the time the ticket is first displayed to an individual (and anytime thereafter during the purchasing process). Prior to completing a purchase, ticket sellers also must provide an itemized list of the base ticket price and each fee (e.g., service fee, processing fee, or other charge). The total ticket price must also be disclosed in any advertisement, marketing, or price list.

Additionally, a ticket seller, secondary market seller, or ticket exchange that does not have actual or constructive possession of an event ticket is prohibited from selling or advertising a ticket for the event. However, a secondary market seller or exchange may sell or advertise a service to obtain an event ticket for an individual&#160;if the seller or exchange (1) does not market the service as an event ticket, (2) maintains a clear separation between the provided service and the event tickets throughout the entire purchasing process, and (3) clearly discloses that the service is not an event ticket.

The bill establishes additional disclosure requirements for&#160;ticket sellers, secondary market sellers, and ticket exchanges, and requires such entities to issue a refund for the total ticket price if an event is canceled or postponed.

The Federal Trade Commission must enforce these requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-66</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
