<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="55" updated="2022-02-09T04:35:42Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1187" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-06-16T16:57:22-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001216"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-06-16"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 117-59 to require the Commission, in conjunction with the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and the Office of the Investor Advocate, to conduct a study and issue a report on the issues small businesses face in reporting ESG disclosures with the report including recommendations for the Commission to consider, and should be completed within 1 year of the enactment of the bill.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires the Securities and Exchange Commission, in conjunction with the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and the Office of the Investor Advocate, to conduct a study and issue a report on the issues small businesses face in reporting ESG disclosures.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-06-16T16:57:22-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="167">
      <text>On agreeing to the Schrier amendment (A005) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 47 (Roll no. 167).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16T14:22:49-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A005) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16T14:15:45-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) offered by Ms. Schrier.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2853-2854, H2861-2862" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2853-2854" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16T16:57:22-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Schrier amendment (A005) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 47 (Roll no. 167).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16T16:57:22-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Schrier amendment (A005) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 47 (Roll no. 167).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16T14:15:45-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A005) offered by Ms. Schrier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16T16:57:22-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
