<bill session="111" type="h" number="4477" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Personnel Toxic Exposure Registry Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Defense to establish a medical surveillance system to identify members of the Armed Forces exposed to chemical hazards resulting from the disposal of waste in Iraq and Afghanistan, to prohibit the disposal of waste by the Armed Forces in a manner that would produce dangerous levels of toxins, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Personnel Toxic Exposure Registry Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2010-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000370" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2010-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2010-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2419" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-09T15:35:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Personnel Toxic Exposure Registry Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to establish and administer a system to identify members of the Armed Forces who were potentially exposed to a hazardous disposal site, as well as any negative health effects that may be related to such exposure.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) administer the system using existing medical surveillance systems; (2) notify a member and his or her commanding officer of a potential exposure; (3) for each member notified, collect information for purposes of the system; (4) for each member notified, annually provide a complete physical examination and related consultation and counseling; and (5) report annually to the congressional defense committees on the status of system implementation and incidences of illnesses which may have been caused by such exposure.

Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 to: (1) include solid waste containing plastics within the definition of "covered waste" for purposes of a prohibition against the disposal by the Armed Forces of covered waste in open-air burn pits during contingency operations; and (2) include in a required report concerning the use of such pits those situations in which such pits were used to dispose of waste during military exercises and operations worldwide during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
