<bill session="118" type="h" number="3877" updated="2025-06-25T03:09:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Office of Small Farms Establishment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of Small Farms Establishment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to establish an Office of Small Farms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000148" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2023-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2023-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2023-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2023-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2023-08-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1809" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-17T19:59:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Office of Small Farms Establishment Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Office of Small Farms within the farm production and conservation mission area.

The office must coordinate, review, and implement various programs and activities related to small farms, ranches, and forest operations. Under the bill, a small farm, ranch, or forest operation (1) is less than 180 acres or meets another USDA-determined, acreage-based definition of small; and (2) has an annual gross cash farm income of less than $350,000.

Activities of the office related to small farms, ranches, and forest operations must include

 coordinating USDA efforts to improve support for these operators; reviewing and recommending changes to USDA statutory, regulatory, and administrative provisions, guidance, and policies that disadvantage these operators; providing or coordinating technical assistance for these operators for USDA grant, cost-share, and loan programs; and providing grants of not more than $25,000 to these operators directly or through cooperative agreements with other entities for areas including equipment and infrastructure repairs and upgrades, uninsured losses, business planning, and conservation practice adoption.</summary>
</bill>
