<bill session="117" type="s" number="4558" updated="2022-12-29T18:48:40Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 51, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to establish an initiative to conduct research, development, and demonstration on technologies capable of reducing greenhouse gas emissions and noise emissions from aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2022-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8097" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-08T00:00:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act

This bill directs the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish an initiative to research, develop, and demonstrate new technologies and concepts to reduce emissions and noise from aircraft. Emissions to be addressed include carbon dioxide (CO2), nitrogen oxides (NOx), water vapor, black carbon, and sulfate aerosols.

The goals and objectives of the initiative shall include (1) ensuring U.S. leadership in research and technology innovation leading to substantial reductions in aviation noise and emissions; (2) reducing greenhouse gas emissions from new and replacement aircraft to the extent necessary to achieve net-zero greenhouse gas emissions from U.S. aviation by 2050; and (3) noise levels from aircraft throughout all phases of flight that do not exceed ambient noise levels in the absence of flight operations in the vicinity of the flight route.</summary>
</bill>
