<bill session="117" type="h" number="831" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:53Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health STATISTICS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to encourage the rapid development of certain public health data standards, authorize epidemiological surveillance grants, and authorize a data linkage demonstration project, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Standards To Advance Transparency, Integrity, Science, Technology Infrastructure, and Confidential Statistics Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health STATISTICS Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2021-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2021-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2021-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-18T15:44:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Standards To Advance Transparency, Integrity, Science, Technology Infrastructure, and Confidential Statistics Act of 2021 or the Health STATISTICS Act of 2021

This bill requires efforts to standardize reporting of public health data, including for COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) data. It also expands access to federal databases for health research.

Specifically, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must develop uniform standards for health departments and other entities that report public health data. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) may award grants to entities for adopting the uniform standards and otherwise improving their reporting capabilities.

Furthermore, the CDC must, in consultation with the National Institutes of Health, establish specific standards within 30 days for reporting COVID-19 data. HHS must also disseminate this data subject to privacy and other requirements.

Additionally, the Office of Management and Budget must issue guidance on federal health data collection that covers, for example, ensuring data quality and increasing access to health data for research.

The National Center for Health Statistics (NCHS) must carry out a demonstration program to expand an existing program that links different federal data sets for statistical public health research, including research on food insecurity, housing instability, and other social determinants of health. In particular, the program must link to the National Death Index, a database of death records maintained by the NCHS.

Finally, the bill requires the CDC to award grants to research entities and public health departments to increase their capacity for conducting statistical public health research.</summary>
</bill>
