<bill session="111" type="s" number="3310" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:01Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tony Dean Cheyenne River Valley Conservation Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain wilderness areas in the National Forest System in the State of South Dakota.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tony Dean Cheyenne River Valley Conservation Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000177"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3166"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-730.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-28T14:08:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tony Dean Cheyenne River Valley Conservation Act of 2010 - Designates specified lands in South Dakota as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Sets forth requirements for the administration of the wilderness areas, including with respect to military overflight activities, fish and wildlife management, access to private property, U.S. acquisition of lands and interests, protective perimeters and buffer zones, and nonwilderness activities and uses outside of the wilderness areas.

Withdraws such areas from specified public land laws, mining laws, and mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.

Permits livestock grazing and the maintenance of related facilities to continue in the wilderness areas in which grazing is established.

Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to undertake necessary measures for the control and prevention of fire, insects, invasive species, and diseases.

Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) diminishing the rights of Indian tribes to access federal land for tribal activities; or (2) enhancing or diminishing the authority of the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior to manage prairie dog populations and habitats.</summary>
</bill>
