<bill session="110" type="hr" number="738" updated="2023-01-11T14:51:16Z">
  <state datetime="2007-10-15T18:54:49-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-10-15T18:54:49-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the Government of Syria's continued interference in the internal affairs of Lebanon.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the Government of Syria's continued interference in the internal affairs of Lebanon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2007-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2007-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T14:29:58-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ackerman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T14:30:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11501-11504" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T14:30:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 738.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T14:50:43-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T18:32:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11531" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="961" datetime="2007-10-15T18:54:49-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 375 - 5, 1 Present (Roll no. 961).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11501" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-10-15T18:54:50-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-10-18T19:48:19Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Condemns the campaign of murder, terror, and intimidation aimed at overthrowing Lebanon's democratically-elected government and establishing a new Lebanese government subservient to Syria and Iran.

 Condemns Syria and Iran for their gross interference in Lebanon's internal political affairs and gross violations of U.N. Security Council resolutions protective of Lebanon's sovereignty and independence.

Condemns Lebanese political parties and actors who have allied themselves with Syria and Iran to the detriment of their own country.

Condemns efforts by some Lebanese political figures to impede the legal and established processes of their country for the selection of a new president.

Affirms the House of Representatives' support for Lebanon's democratically-elected government, people and national sovereignty, and its readiness to provide material support.

Calls on all nations to recognize and support Lebanon's sovereignty and independence.

Urges the President to use all peaceful means at U.S. disposal to help safeguard Lebanon's sovereignty and independence.</summary>
</bill>
