<bill session="119" type="s" number="102" updated="2025-06-27T20:30:28Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ROOMIE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinforce Occupancy Obligations for Maximized Interagency Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROOMIE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal agencies to impose in-person work requirements for employees of those agencies and to occupy a certain portion of the office space of those agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-27T20:29:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reinforce Occupancy Obligations for Maximized Interagency Efficiency Act or the ROOMIE Act

This bill establishes occupancy requirements for federal office buildings and directs agencies to sell or terminate leases on unused office space.&#160;

The bill directs agencies to amend their policies within 120 days of the bill's enactment to require not less than 80%&#160;of the agency's employees to work on site. The policies must also ensure that at least&#160;60% of the usable square feet of the agency's office space is occupied by agency employees.&#160;

Agencies that do not employ enough individuals to occupy 60%&#160;of the agency's office space must provide an occupancy plan to the General Services Administration and Congress detailing how it will meet that goal, particularly by working with other federal agencies. The plan must be submitted within one year of the bill's enactment.

The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress regarding agencies' compliance with these requirements.

Agencies that do not comply with these requirements must sell their properties, terminate leases, or not renew leases, as applicable.</summary>
</bill>
