<bill session="117" type="h" number="1103" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CABLE Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit franchising authorities from requiring approval for the sale of cable systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CABLE Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Access to Broadband for Local Economies and Competition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2021-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3435" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-11T16:31:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Consumer Access to Broadband for Local Economies and Competition Act or the CABLE Competition Act

This bill revises the valuation of a cable system upon its sale or transfer, and it modifies the process for transferring a cable franchise to a person to whom such franchise was not initially granted.

Specifically, the bill requires that after the denial of a franchise renewal or the revocation of a franchise for cause, any subsequent acquisition or transfer must be at fair market value.

Further, the bill prohibits a cable franchising authority from (1) precluding the transfer of a cable franchise from a cable operator to a person to whom such franchise was not initially granted, or (2) requiring a cable operator that was initially granted a franchise to receive approval from the franchising authority for such a transfer. However, a franchising authority is authorized to require a cable operator to notify the authority of such a transfer.</summary>
</bill>
