<bill session="116" type="s" number="2180" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Border Zone Reasonableness Restoration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Zone Reasonableness Restoration Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide oversight of the border zone in which Federal agents may conduct vehicle checkpoints and stops and enter private land without a warrant, and to make technical corrections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2020-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2019-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2019-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4952" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3852" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-13T15:46:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Border Zone Reasonableness Restoration Act of 2019

This bill limits&#160;the ability of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct searches and related activities without a warrant.

DHS may without warrant board a vehicle for border enforcement purposes within 25 miles of any U.S. border, whereas currently DHS has statutory authority to do so within a reasonable distance of a U.S. border. DHS may exercise such authority in a sector that extends up to 100 miles from a U.S. border upon certifying to Congress the necessity of such an extension.

DHS may not establish warrantless vehicle checkpoints beyond 10 miles from a U.S. border. Such checkpoints may not use race, gender, religion, or sex to any degree, except as descriptions of a specific suspect.

DHS may without warrant access private lands, but not dwellings, for border enforcement purposes within 10 miles of any U.S. border, whereas currently DHS has statutory authority to do so within 25 miles of a U.S. border. DHS may exercise such authority in a sector that extends up to 25 miles from a U.S. border upon certifying to Congress the necessity of such an extension.

An individual harmed by an extension of a maximum distance limitation under this bill may sue in federal district court.

DHS authority to conduct various border enforcement activities without warrant must be consistent with the Fourth Amendment.</summary>
</bill>
