<bill session="109" type="h" number="334" updated="2022-02-03T05:26:33Z">
  <state datetime="2005-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Angolan Temporary Protected Status Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Angolan Temporary Protected Status Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate Angola under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act in order to make nationals of Angola eligible for temporary protected status under such section.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Angola"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil War"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-10T13:40:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Angolan Temporary Protected Status Act of 2005 - Expresses the sense of Congress that Angola qualifies for designation under the Immigration and Nationality Act as a nation with an ongoing conflict pursuant to which Angolan nationals would be eligible for temporary protected status (TPS) in the United States.

Amends the Act to so designate Angola for an initial one-year period. Sets forth TPS eligibility requirements for Angolan nationals, including: (1) continuous physical presence in the United States since the date of enactment of this Act; (2) admissibility as an immigrant (with certain exceptions) and eligibility for TPS; and (3) registration for TPS in a manner established by the Secretary of Homeland Security.

Requires the Secretary to give prior consent to such aliens for brief, temporary trips abroad in emergency and extenuating circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
