<bill session="112" type="h" number="1359" updated="2019-11-15T20:53:44Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Temporary CDBG Public Services Flexibility Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Temporary CDBG Public Services Flexibility Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 105 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to temporarily increase the limit on the portion of community development block grants amounts for certain entitlement communities that may be used for public services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000590" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2011-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2011-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-07T20:06:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Temporary CDBG Public Services Flexibility Act of 2011 - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to revise requirements for activities eligible for community development block grant (CDBG) assistance.

Increases from 15% to 25% the limitation on the amount of CDBG assistance that may be used to provide public services (e.g., those concerned with employment, crime prevention, child care, health, drug abuse, education, energy conservation, welfare or recreation needs) for FY2011-FY2012 to any local government that, based on information of the U.S. Bureau of the Census for 2009, has a population of between 250,000 and 800,000, has a land area of less than 75 square miles, and among cities having a population exceeding 250,000 ranks among the 25 having the highest poverty rates.</summary>
</bill>
