<bill session="111" type="h" number="5115" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:05Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FSS Retirement Fairness Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To recognize the key contributions of flight support specialists to our Nation's aviation safety by restoring the retirement treatment of flight support specialists whose functions were outsourced by the Federal Government in 2005.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FSS Retirement Fairness Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000006" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000572" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2010-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO25" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-30T21:33:12Z" status="Introduced in House">FSS Retirement Fairness Act of 2010 - Allows certain flight service station (FSS) controllers, employed by Department of Transportation (DOT), to elect to treat qualified service in the same manner as if it had been performed as an FSS controller for purposes of determining eligibility for immediate retirement and computation of annuity under either the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS).

Limits the application of this Act, with specified exclusions, to FSS controllers who were separated from government service (other than for cause), or were transferred from an FSS controller position to a different government position (other than as an air traffic controller), during the period from February 1-October 3, 2005, and had completed at least five years of qualified service (as an employee of a contractor or an otherwise creditable position other than as an air traffic controller) as of the date of such separation or reassignment.

Requires certain individuals who make such election to make contributions to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund with respect to qualified service performed after the effective date of such election.

Prescribes special rules relating to: (1) immediate retirement, including continued enrollment in a Federal Employee Health Benefits Plan; and (2) recomputation of the annuity of any individual (or survivor) otherwise excluded from application of this Act because of entitlement to a CSRS or a FERS annuity based on the individual's government service.</summary>
</bill>
