<bill session="109" type="s" number="3534" updated="2023-01-31T21:41:22Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-22">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">YouthBuild Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">YouthBuild Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">YouthBuild Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to provide for a YouthBuild program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2006-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6014"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="472">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 472.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-08-03">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8879" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2006-08-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-08-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T14:04:24-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T15:42:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Castle moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T15:43:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6259-6265" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T15:43:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3534.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2006-09-06T15:56:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6259-6263" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06T15:56:38-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-09-22" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="109-281" type="public" datetime="2006-09-22">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-281.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5837" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1999" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4879"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-11-29T22:22:50Z" status="Public Law">YouthBuild Transfer Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to establish a revised YouthBuild program in the Department of Labor (previously, in the Department of Housing and Urban Development). Redefines "YouthBuild program" as any program assisted under this Act that provides disadvantaged youth with opportunities for employment, education, leadership development, and training through the rehabilitation or construction of housing for homeless individuals and low-income families, and of public facilities. Allows an individual to participate in a YouthBuild program only if such individual is between 16 and 24 years of age, is a member of a low-income family, is in foster care, is a youth offender, is a youth with a disability, is a child of incarcerated parents, is a migrant youth, and is a school dropout.

Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to make grants to eligible entities to carry out a YouthBuild program. Includes as eligible entities: (1) a community-based organization; (2) a faith-based organization; (3) a local board or community action agency; (4) a state or local housing development agency; (5) an Indian tribe or agency primarily serving Indians; (6) a community development corporation; (7) a state or local youth service or conservation corps; and (8) any other entity eligible to provide education or employment training.

Specifies program activities for which grant funds may be used, including: (1) education and workforce investment activities; (2) supervision and training for participants in the rehabilitation or construction of housing for homeless individuals and low-income families; (3) adult mentoring; (4) payment of wages to program participants; and (5) ongoing training and technical assistance for developing and carrying out YouthBuild programs. Sets forth minimum requirements for grant applications and selection criteria for awarding grants to an eligible entity.

Restricts the use of residential housing rehabilitated or constructed under a YouthBuild program to: (1) sales or rentals to homeless individuals or low-income families; (2) transitional or permanent housing to help homeless individuals to achieve independent living.

Authorizes the Secretary to contract for management and technical assistance in administering a YouthBuild program.

Authorizes appropriations for FY2007-FY2012.

Repeals the authority for the YouthBuild program under the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act.

(Sec. 3) Provides for the transfer to the Secretary of Labor all functions performed by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under the YouthBuild program prior to the enactment of this Act. Allows YouthBuild program grants awarded under prior law to continue until funding for such grants expires.</summary>
</bill>
