<bill session="109" type="h" number="1383" updated="2019-11-15T21:11:42Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Strategy Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Strategy Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to transmit to the Congress each year a comprehensive report on the national homeland security strategy of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000262"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2005-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential messages"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-20T21:58:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Homeland Security Strategy Act of 2005 - Requires the President to annually transmit to Congress a comprehensive report on the homeland security strategy of the United States (the strategy), which shall include a description and discussion of: (1) worldwide interests, goals, and objectives of the United States that are vital to national homeland security; (2) foreign policy, worldwide commitments, and national defense, economic, diplomatic, and information capabilities of the United States necessary to deter aggression and implement the strategy; (3) proposed short-term and long-term uses of such capabilities and other elements of U.S. national power to protect or promote the interests of, and achieve the goals and objectives vital to, national homeland security; and (4) the adequacy of U.S. capabilities to carry out the strategy.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, to comprehensively examine the strategy, force structure, resources, threat assessment, infrastructure, budget plan, and other elements of the U.S. homeland security program and policies every four years in order to determine and express the strategy for the next 20 years.

Establishes the National Commission on Quadrennial Homeland Security Reviews to: (1) make recommendations relative to the Secretary's examination; and (2) submit required reports to the President and Congress.

Requires the Commission to submit its final report no later than June 30, 2006.</summary>
</bill>
