<bill session="117" type="s" number="3172" updated="2022-12-30T08:33:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended, to require registration statements filed under that Act to be filed in a structured data format to enable the statements to be digitized for purposes of the publicly available electronic database maintained under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2021-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-28T18:08:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2021 

This bill modifies requirements related to the electronic database that contains the registrations that an agent of a foreign principal must file with the Department of Justice (DOJ).

Specifically, DOJ must establish and maintain the free and publicly accessible National Foreign Agents Database, which must make such foreign agent registrations searchable, sortable, and downloadable. The database must also make filed registrations and supplements immediately available for public inspection. (Currently, DOJ is required maintain a database with these features, but only to the extent that the features are technically practicable.)

The database must also meet federal standards for making digital information accessible to individuals with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
