<bill session="118" type="s" number="1971" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Streamlining Accountability and Value in Education for Students Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Accountability and Value in Education for Students Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for loan repayment simplification and income-driven repayment reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1972" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-16T17:50:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Streamlining Accountability and Value in Education for Students Act

This bill addresses options for student loan repayment and access to federal student loans.

Specifically, the bill reduces the number of repayment options for federal student loans. Currently, a borrower may choose among nine plans for student loan repayment. This bill reduces those options to two: a standard 10-year repayment plan and an income-driven repayment plan.

The bill also requires an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs to certify that no federal student aid funds may be used by students for certain educational programs offered by the IHE. In particular, these funds may not be used by (1) an undergraduate student for enrollment in an educational program in which half of the graduates do not earn more than the median high school graduate, and (2) a graduate student for enrollment in an educational program in which half of the graduates do not earn more than the median bachelor's degree recipient.</summary>
</bill>
