<bill session="117" type="s" number="4719" updated="2023-09-05T18:46:57Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Child Sex Abuse Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Child Sex Abuse Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Preventing Child Sex Abuse Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect children against sexual abuse and exploitation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2022-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7304-7305" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-12-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7304" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:04:02-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:47:01-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9616" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s6549"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-09-05T18:41:38Z" status="Passed Senate">Preventing Child Sex Abuse Act of 2022

This bill makes changes to the federal law prohibiting child sexual tourism.

First, the bill revises the specific intent required for certain offenses involving interstate or foreign travel to engage in or facilitate illicit sexual conduct. Specifically, this bill requires the government to prove that an individual traveled (or facilitated travel) with the intent to engage in illicit sexual conduct (currently, with a motivating purpose of engaging in illicit sexual conduct). Further, it specifies that the term intent is to be construed as any intention to engage in illicit sexual conduct at the time of the travel.

Second, the bill establishes new criminal offenses for acts in furtherance of illicit sexual conduct by an officer, director, employee, or agent of an organization through his or her connection to or affiliation with the organization. A violation is subject to a fine, a prison term of up to 30 years, or both.

Finally, the bill specifies that the term sexual activity for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense does not require interpersonal physical contact.</summary>
</bill>
