<bill session="115" type="s" number="2337" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:52Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Continental Divide Recreation, Wilderness and Camp Hale Legacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the designation of certain wilderness areas, recreation management areas, and conservation areas in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continental Divide Recreation, Wilderness and Camp Hale Legacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4883" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="688" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="689" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="285" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-04T19:56:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Continental Divide Recreation, Wilderness and Camp Hale Legacy Act

This bill amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to designate the following federal lands in the White River National Forest in Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: the Proposed Ptarmigan Wilderness Additions; the Holy Cross Wilderness Addition; the Hoosier Ridge Wilderness; the Tenmile Wilderness; and the Eagles Nest Wilderness Additions. The bill also designates the Proposed Williams Fork Wilderness in such forest as a potential wilderness area.

The bill finally designates certain federal lands in such forest as:

 the Tenmile Recreation Management Area, the Porcupine Gulch Conservation Area, the Williams Fork Wildlife Conservation Area, and the Camp Hale National Historic Landscape. The bill modifies the Rocky Mountain National Park Wilderness in Colorado to adjust the park's boundaries to exclude 15.5 acres of land identified as potential wilderness to non-wilderness.

The bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to permit nonmotorized access and use of the Bolts Ditch headgate and the Bolts Ditch within the Holy Cross Wilderness in Colorado for the diversion of water and use, maintenance, and repair of the ditch and headgate by the town of Minturn, Colorado.

The bill adjusts the boundary of the Arapaho National Forest in Colorado to incorporate 92.95 acres of land. USDA shall include all federal land within the boundary in the Bowen Gulch Protection Area.</summary>
</bill>
