<bill session="108" type="s" number="2443" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:06Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness in Immigration Litigation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the judicial review process of orders of removal for purposes of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Immigration Litigation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2004-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5802-5803"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4406" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Habeas corpus"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Punishment"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-07T15:38:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness in Immigration Litigation Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to preclude aliens, including criminal aliens, from seeking judicial review of removal orders or the denial of specified discretionary relief through habeas corpus, mandamus, or other extraordinary petitions.

 Declares that this Act does not preclude circuit court review on appeal of constitutional claims or pure questions of law.

Establishes the INA's judicial review provisions as the sole avenue for challenging removal orders and reviewing claims arising under the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Forms of Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment.

Limits judicial authority to grant stays of removal.

Requires all petitions for review of removal orders to be filed in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.

Expands the list of alternative countries to which an alien may be removed in the event that the country otherwise designated is unwilling to accept the alien.

Requires asylum applicants to: (1) show that one of five statutory bases was the central motive for persecution in order to establish refugee status; and (2) submit corroborating evidence where it is reasonable for the trier of fact to expect such evidence. Lists factors relevant to credibility determinations in asylum cases. Precludes the reversal of determinations concerning the availability of corroborating evidence unless the court finds that a reasonable adjudicator is compelled to conclude that such corroborating evidence is unavailable.</summary>
</bill>
