<bill session="112" type="h" number="2610" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:43Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Asset Forfeiture Fund Reform and Distribution Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to reform procedures for the payment of funds from the asset forfeiture fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asset Forfeiture Fund Reform and Distribution Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000339"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000570" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000266" joined="2011-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1304" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-10-03T13:16:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Asset Forfeiture Fund Reform and Distribution Act of 2011 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) or the Secretary of the Treasury, after September 30, 2011, to use each of the sums received as fines, penalties, and forfeitures of property for violations of any provisions of such Act, or of any other fishery resource law enforced by the Secretary, to make a payment to: (1) the state in which the violation occurred, (2) the state in which the vessel involved in the violation is homeported if the violation did not occur in a state, or (3) the state most directly affected by a violation neither occurring in a state nor involving a vessel. (Current law authorizes using such sums for certain civil and criminal enforcement costs.)

Directs states to use such amounts for specified research and monitoring activities.

Sets forth transitional rules authorizing the Secretary to use such amounts received before October 1, 2011, to reimburse appropriate legal fees and costs, up to $200,000 per person, to specified persons the Secretary directed to receive a remittance of at least a portion of a fisheries enforcement penalty.

Prohibits the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) from assigning specified rulemaking or adjudication proceedings to an individual who has served as an NOAA administrative law judge for at least a five-year period if such proceeding pertains to the same fishery management region to which the majority of such proceedings that the individual presided over within the period pertained.</summary>
</bill>
