<bill session="109" type="h" number="3988" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:56Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gulf Coast Small Business Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for priority in Federal contracting for businesses in areas adversely affected by Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita and treatment of small business concerns adversely affected by Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita as HUBZone small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Coast Small Business Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000361" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000072" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000388" joined="2005-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-20T18:53:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Gulf Coast Small Business Recovery Act - Requires, for any contract for the procurement of goods or services related to any damage caused as a result of Hurricane Katrina or Rita, or any reconstruction related to such damage, a federal agency to give priority to a business that as of August 28, 2005, had a significant presence in a Gulf hurricane disaster-affected area. Requires an agency to award not less than 30 percent of amounts expended for prime contracts, and not less than 40 percent of amounts expended for subcontracts, on procurements to small businesses that, as of such date, had such a presence. Requires an agency to provide the maximum practicable opportunity for small business participation in all such contracts and subcontracts.

Requires a Gulf hurricane disaster-affected small business to be treated as if it were located in a HUBZone (heavily underutilized business zone) for purposes of favorable loan status under the Small Business Act.

Prohibits, until two years after the enactment of this Act, any federal government facility from being permanently relocated from a location in a Gulf hurricane disaster-affected area to a location outside that area.</summary>
</bill>
