<bill session="117" type="s" number="73" updated="2023-03-08T19:59:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Security Drone Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ban the Federal procurement of certain drones and other unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Security Drone Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">American Security Drone Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2021-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2021-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2021-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters without amendment. With written report No. 117-267.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="666">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 666.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5640" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4521" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-03T17:41:23Z" status="Reported to Senate">American Security Drone Act of 2021

This bill bans the procurement or use by the federal government of unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) that are manufactured or assembled by certain entities, including entities subject to influence or control by China, with exceptions.

The ban includes associated elements that are required for the operator to operate safely and efficiently in the national airspace system.

The Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, and the Department of Justice are exempt from the restriction under specified circumstances. The bill sets forth further exemptions regarding the Federal Aviation Administration, the National Transportation Safety Board, and the National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration.

Federal funds may not be used to procure certain UAS from a foreign entity, with exceptions. All executive agencies must account for existing inventories of UAS manufactured or assembled by a foreign entity in their personal property accounting systems. Inventory data related to UAS manufactured or assembled by a foreign entity may be tracked at a classified level.

The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall prescribe regulations or guidance to implement this bill's requirements pertaining to federal contracts.

Government-issued purchase cards may not be used to procure any UAS from a foreign entity.

The Office of Management and Budget shall (1) establish a government-wide policy for the procurement of UAS, taking into account information security; and (2) contract with a federally funded research and development center to study certain UAS-related issues.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-267</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
