<bill session="117" type="s" number="1601" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Future of Local News Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Future of Local News Committee to examine and report on the role of local news gathering in sustaining democracy in the United States and the factors contributing to the demise of local journalism, and to propose policies and mechanisms that could reinvigorate local news to meet the critical information needs of the people of the United States in the 21st century.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Future of Local News Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3169" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporation for Public Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-22T11:22:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Future of Local News Act of 2021

This bill establishes the Future of Local News Committee to examine, report on, and make recommendations related to the state of local news and the ability of local news to meet the information needs of the people of the United States.

The duties of the committee include (1) examining the implications of the loss of local newspapers, digital news outlets, and broadcasting outlets; (2) assessing the impact of the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic and whether the Paycheck Protection Program has had beneficial effects on local news organizations; and (3) assessing and examining existing and potential means of supporting local news production.

The committee must recommend mechanisms that the federal government can create and implement to support the production of local news, such as the possible creation of a new national endowment for local journalism or the reform and expansion of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting.</summary>
</bill>
