<bill session="118" type="h" number="1268" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Special Envoy for the Abraham Accords Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Envoy for the Abraham Accords Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish the position of Special Envoy for the Abraham Accords, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001217" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2023-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3099" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-20T21:11:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Special Envoy for the Abraham Accords Act

This bill establishes the position of Special Envoy for the Abraham Accords within the Department of State. (The Abraham Accords are agreements to normalize or improve relations between Israel and four members of the Arab League: the United Arab Emirates, Bahrain, Morocco, and Sudan.)

The Special Envoy shall seek to expand and strengthen the Abraham Accords. The Special Envoy's responsibilities include (1) serving as the primary advisor to the U.S. government for expanding and strengthening the Abraham Accords, (2) discussing the Abraham Accords with officials from counties lacking official diplomatic relations with Israel, and (3) consulting with representatives of nongovernmental organizations that have attempted to expand and strengthen the Abraham Accords.

The Special Envoy shall have the rank of ambassador.</summary>
</bill>
