<bill session="108" type="h" number="5324" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:39Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nurse Education, Expansion, and Development Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize capitation grants to increase the number of nursing faculty and students, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nurse Education, Expansion, and Development Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2004-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Student enrollment"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-06T15:56:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Nurse Education, Expansion, and Development Act of 2004 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award a grant to each eligible school of nursing to increase the number of nursing faculty and students at the school.

Requires such schools to formulate and implement a plan to accomplish at least two of specified goals, which include: (1) establishing or significantly expanding an accelerated baccalaureate degree nursing program designed to graduate new nurses in 12 to 18 months; (2) establishing cooperative interdisciplinary training between schools of nursing and other specified health related fields; (3) increasing admissions, enrollment, and retention of qualified individuals who are financially disadvantaged; (4) increasing enrollment of minority and diverse student populations; (5) increasing enrollment of new graduate baccalaureate nursing students in graduate programs that educate nurse faculty members; (6) developing post-baccalaureate residency programs to prepare nurses for practice in specialty areas where nursing shortages are more severe; and (7) increasing integration of geriatric content into the core curriculum.

Requires the Comptroller General of the United States to study ways to increase participation in the nurse faculty profession and to submit a report to Congress that includes: (1) a discussion of the master's degree and doctoral degree programs that are successful in placing graduates as faculty in schools of nursing; and (2) an examination of compensation disparities throughout the nursing profession and between higher education instructional faculty generally and higher education instructional nursing faculty.</summary>
</bill>
