<bill session="111" type="s" number="4018" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:07Z">
  <state datetime="2010-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Life Sciences Jobs and Investment Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for life sciences research.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Life Sciences Jobs and Investment Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="6165" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-15T20:05:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Life Sciences Jobs and Investment Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) an increased research tax credit for qualified initial life sciences research expenses; and (2) certain corporations a tax deduction for dividends received which are reinvested in the United States to hire scientists and researchers engaged in life science research, fund life science research at research consortia, eligible small businesses, universities, and federal laboratories, or build or lease new facilities to be used primarily for qualified life sciences research. Terminates such tax incentives after 2015.

 Defines "qualified initial life sciences research expenses" as amounts, up to $150 million, attributable to the study of biology, biochemistry, biophysics, bioengineering, microbiology, genetics, or physiology, but excluding sociology or psychology.

Directs the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to take necessary steps to ensure full compliance with the provisions of this Act and to report to Congress on the status of such compliance and related enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
