<bill session="116" type="s" number="4007" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:12Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Women&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Economic Empowerment in Trade Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Economic Empowerment in Trade Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to modify the eligibility requirements for the Generalized System of Preferences to strengthen worker protections and to ensure that beneficiary developing countries afford equal rights and protection under the law, regardless of gender, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2020-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2020-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-16T14:47:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Women's Economic Empowerment in Trade Act of 2020

This bill modifies eligibility requirements for the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP), requires the President to collect specified information on beneficiary developing countries that receive preferential trade treatment under the GSP, and requires the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to review the laws of each country that receives such preferential trade treatment.

Specifically, the bill makes ineligible for designation as a beneficiary developing country any country that (1) does not substantially afford equal rights and protection under the law, regardless of gender; or (2) engages in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights.

The President must take into account the extent to which a country engages in such practices when determining whether to designate any country as a beneficiary developing country. The President must also collect and publish information on the extent to which a country meets these eligibility criteria, and the USTR must publish a notice of, and the rationale for, any determination with respect to a petition for review of a country's eligibility for designation.

The USTR must annually review the laws of each beneficiary developing country relating to their compliance with internationally recognized worker rights and the affording of equal rights and protection under the law, regardless of gender. If a country fails to meet these eligibility criteria for five consecutive years, the benefits provided to that country shall be commensurately reduced.</summary>
</bill>
