<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>657</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T23:03:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T23:03:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-03-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-03-19T16:08:26Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-03-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-03-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001233</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bayh, Evan [D-IN]</fullName>
        <firstName>EVAN</firstName>
        <lastName>BAYH</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IN</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000304</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lieberman, Joseph I. [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOSEPH</firstName>
        <lastName>LIEBERMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>I.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-03-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Families</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Block grants</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Career education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Charities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child abuse</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child support</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Church and social problems</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Contraceptives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Counseling</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Divorce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment of the disadvantaged</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment subsidies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evaluation research (Social action programs)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Family violence</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fathers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to Indians</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Financial planning</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government publicity</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Grants-in-aid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian children</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Job creation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Job hunting</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marriage</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marriage counseling</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nonprofit organizations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parent and child</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Personal budgets</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Poor children</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Preventive medicine</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public service advertising</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Religion</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sex education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sexual abstinence</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sexually transmitted diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Teenage pregnancy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Vocational guidance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Welfare work participation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Families</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-03-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Strengthening Families Act of 2003 - Amends part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary to award grants to eligible States and entities to conduct demonstration programs to promote responsible fatherhood.<p>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to contract with a nonprofit fatherhood promotion organization to: (1) develop and distribute a media campaign that addresses the issue of responsible fatherhood to States, local governments, public agencies, and private entities; and (2) develop a national clearinghouse to assist States and community efforts to promote and support marriage and responsible fatherhood by disseminating information regarding media campaigns and programs instituted by States using grant funds under this Act.<p>Directs the Secretary to make grants to States desiring to conduct policy reviews and develop recommendations with the goals of: (1) obtaining and retaining employment, increasing child support payments, and increasing the involvement of low-income, noncustodial parents with their children; and (2) coordinating policies and services for low-income, noncustodial parents among the different systems or programs in which such parents are involved, including the criminal justice system, the State program funded under SSA title IV part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families), the State program funded under SSA title IV part D, and job training or employment programs.<p>Requires the Secretary to make grants to States desiring to conduct a demonstration project for the purpose of: (1) testing innovative policies and to better coordinate policies and services for low-income, noncustodial parents to accomplish such goals; or (2) if the State conducted a policy review with such a grant and desires to implement the recommendations of that review, implementing such recommendations.<p>Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor jointly to award grants to eligible States for the purpose of establishing, in coordination with counties and other local governments, court- supervised employment programs for noncustodial parents who have a history of nonpayment of child support obligations, as determined by a court, and who are determined by the court to be in need of employment services or placement in order to pay such child support obligations.<p>Amends SSA title IV part A to replace provisions on  bonus grants to States to reward a decrease in illegitimacy ratio with provisions on grants to States to States to prevent teen pregnancy.<p>Directs the Secretary to make a grant to a nationally recognized, nonpartisan, nonprofit organization that meets specified contractor requirements to establish and operate a national teen pregnancy prevention resource center.<p>Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 with respect to establishing national goals to prevent teen pregnancy.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Strengthening Families Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Strengthening Families Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title IV of the Social Security Act to provide grants to promote responsible fatherhood, to encourage teen pregnancy prevention strategies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Strengthening Families Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-03-19T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-03-19</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
