<bill session="117" type="h" number="2343" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting American Voters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Commissioner of Social Security to provide information to States upon request which will enable States to verify the citizenship status of applicants for voter registration in elections for Federal office in the State and remove individuals who are not citizens of the United States from the list of individuals registered to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting American Voters Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2021-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2021-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2021-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-04T12:52:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting American Voters Act

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Social Security Administration (SSA) to provide certain information to a state election official, upon the official's request, to verify citizenship status for the purpose of voting in federal elections.

Specifically, the agencies must provide the state election official with such information necessary to verify that an applicant for voter registration or a registrant on the official list of eligible voters is a U.S. citizen.

DHS may respond to a request by using the Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements program, which is used to verify immigration status. DHS may not charge a fee for this information.

DHS must comply with any safeguards that the SSA determines are necessary to protect the confidentiality of an individual's Social Security number.

Finally, the bill requires states to remove the names of noncitizens from their official lists of eligible voters.</summary>
</bill>
