<bill session="116" type="s" number="4604" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SUSPEND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strongly and Unambiguously Sanctioning Proliferators Exploiting Nuclear Diplomacy Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUSPEND Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the imposition of sanctions with respect to certain persons in the defense sectors of nuclear weapons states that are not fulfilling their obligations under article VI of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-10T23:09:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strongly and Unambiguously Sanctioning Proliferators Exploiting Nuclear Diplomacy Act of 2020 or the SUSPEND Act

This bill establishes reporting and sanctions requirements related to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT).

 Specifically, the bill requires the Department of State to report on whether parties to the NPT are fulfilling their responsibility to pursue negotiations in good faith relating to cessation of the nuclear arms race and to nuclear disarmament. Further, it requires the President, on the basis of this report, to impose sanctions against certain parties that are not meeting this responsibility.</summary>
</bill>
