<bill session="116" type="h" number="8634" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:30Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HACKED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HACKED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve United States cybersecurity through STEM scholarships, prize competitions, and other STEM activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001083"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3712" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4049" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-28T19:49:56Z" status="Introduced in House">HACKED Act

This bill expands and coordinates federal agencies' cybersecurity recruitment and education initiatives.

Specifically, the bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to (1) support efforts to identify cybersecurity workforce skill gaps in public and private sectors; (2) facilitate efforts for federal programs to advance cybersecurity education, training, and workforce development; and (3) consider any specific needs of the cybersecurity workforce of critical infrastructure.

NIST is authorized to award grants of up to $200,000 for cooperative agreements between the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) and regional alliances or partnerships for cybersecurity education and workforce. Additionally, NIST must identify and develop standards and guidelines for improving the cybersecurity workforce for agencies as part of the NICE Cybersecurity Workforce Framework.

The bill also expands the National Science Foundation (NSF) Federal Cyber Scholarship-for-Service Program by allowing up to 10% of scholarship recipients to fulfill their service obligation as educators in the field of cybersecurity at qualified institutions of higher education. Further, the NSF must give priority to cybersecurity education when awarding grants for (1) computer science education research, (2) scientific and technical education, and (3) low-income scholarship programs.

The Department of Energy may carry out a program to support the development of a cybersecurity workforce, and NIST must establish national cybersecurity challenges in order to achieve high-priority breakthroughs in cybersecurity.</summary>
</bill>
