<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>410</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T22:18:43Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T22:18:43Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-02-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>slin00</systemCode>
        <name>Intelligence (Select) Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Select</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-02-13T23:19:35Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-02-13</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slin00</systemCode>
            <name>Intelligence (Select) Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-02-13</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2487-2488)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-02-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>E000286</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Edwards, John [D-NC]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>EDWARDS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>EBB Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive reorganization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-02-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Foreign Intelligence Collection Improvement Act of 2003 - Homeland Intelligence Agency Act of 2003 - Establishes the Homeland Intelligence Agency as an element of the Department of Homeland Security, with the primary mission of supporting the Director of Central Intelligence in the collection and dissemination of foreign intelligence and counterintelligence in the United States, including the plans, intentions, and capabilities of international terrorist groups operating in the United States. Establishes within the Agency: (1) a Director, Deputy Director, and Inspector General; (2) an Office of Privacy and Civil Liberties Protection; and (3) an Office of Federal, State, and Local Law Enforcement Coordination.<p>Requires the Agency Director to: (1) establish and implement personnel training programs; (2) disseminate collected intelligence to other elements of the intelligence community and appropriate Federal, State, and local departments and agencies; (3) establish guidelines on the collection of foreign intelligence and counterintelligence inside the United States; and (4) coordinate overseas intelligence activities with the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA). Transfers to the Agency all homeland intelligence functions currently performed by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), CIA, National Security Agency, and Office of the National Counterintelligence Executive. Replaces the FBI with the Agency as an element of the U.S. intelligence community.<p>Establishes in the FBI the Office of Foreign Intelligence Coordination.<p>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Public Reporting Act - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to: (1) require additional matters within annual reports on foreign intelligence surveillance; and (2) authorize the undisclosed participation of an Agency official or agent in the activities of a religious or political organization in order to obtain foreign intelligence information or information concerning international terrorism.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Foreign Intelligence Collection Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Foreign Intelligence Collection Improvement Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish the Homeland Intelligence Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Foreign Intelligence Collection Improvement Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Public Reporting Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Homeland Intelligence Agency Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-02-13T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-02-13</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
