<bill session="117" type="s" number="5181" updated="2023-08-22T18:45:26Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Indian and Alaska Native Veterans Mental Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Indian and Alaska Native Veterans Mental Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make certain improvements relating to mental health and suicide prevention outreach to minority veterans and American Indian and Alaska Native veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2022-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="912" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-22T18:44:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Indian and Alaska Native Veterans Mental Health Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide mental health and suicide prevention outreach to American Indian and Alaska Native veterans.

Specifically, the bill requires that each VA medical center have a full-time minority veteran coordinator. The coordinator must receive training in the delivery of culturally appropriate mental health and suicide prevention services to American Indian and Alaska Native veterans.

Further, the suicide prevention coordinator and minority veteran coordinator of each VA medical center must develop and disseminate a written plan for conducting mental health and suicide prevention outreach to all tribes and urban Indian health organizations within the area of the medical center.</summary>
</bill>
