<bill session="108" type="s" number="1600" updated="2023-01-15T07:02:59Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian Needs Assessment and Program Evaluation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for periodic Indian needs assessments, to require Federal Indian program evaluations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Needs Assessment and Program Evaluation Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2003-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2003-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11251"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11251-11252" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-16T17:42:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Needs Assessment and Program Evaluation Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to develop a uniform method, criteria, and procedures for determining, analyzing, and compiling the program and service assistance needs of Indian tribes and Indians.

Requires Federal agencies to conduct Indian needs assessments to determine the actual needs of tribes and Indians eligible for programs and services administered by such departments and agencies. Directs the Secretary to develop a uniform method, criteria, and procedures for compiling, maintaining, keeping current, and reporting to Congress all information concerning: (1) annual Federal expenditures for programs and services for which Indians are eligible; (2) services or programs specifically for the benefit of Indians; and (3) methods of delivery of services and funding. Requires Federal departments and agencies responsible for providing services or programs to or for the benefit of tribes or Indians to: (1) file annual Indian program evaluations with specified congressional committees; and (2) publish annual listings in the Federal Register of all agency programs and services for which Indian tribes may be eligible. Directs the Secretary to file a strategic plan for the coordination of Federal assistance for Indians.</summary>
</bill>
