<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1782</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T20:54:29Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T20:54:29Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-03-30</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-03-30T16:30:41Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Fairness for Homeowners Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>863</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-04-22</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-30</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
            <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-30</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-30</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>E000288</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Ellison, Keith [D-MN-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>Keith</firstName>
        <lastName>Ellison</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <district>5</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000984</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Cummings, Elijah E. [D-MD-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>ELIJAH</firstName>
        <lastName>CUMMINGS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <district>7</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-04-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer credit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing finance and home ownership</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Interest, dividends, interest rates</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-03-30</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-06-12T23:07:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Fairness for Homeowners Act of 2009 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit a creditor or mortgage broker from arranging a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of a consumer without first verifying the consumer's reasonable ability to to make the scheduled payments of principal, interest (including variable interest), real estate taxes, homeowner's insurance, assessments, and mortgage insurance premiums. </p> <p>Prescribes criteria to: (1) determine such consumer's reasonable ability to pay a variable interest rate; and (2) verify the consumer's income and financial resources. Declares a consumer's statement of income or financial resources insufficient evidence of the consumer's financial status.</p> <p>Prohibits consumer equity in the principal dwelling that secures the consumer credit transaction from being used to establish ability to make payments.</p><p>Prohibits a mortgage broker or creditor from: (1) steering, counseling, or directing a consumer to rates, charges, principal amount, or prepayment terms that are more expensive than those for which the consumer qualifies; (2) arranging for any consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of a consumer that is more expensive than that for which the consumer qualifies; (3) engaging in certain mischaracterizations.</p> <p>Prohibits prepayment penalties. Limits finance points, charges, and fees. Cites duties owed to a consumer by a mortgage broker.</p> <p>Requires creditors and mortgage brokers to obtain independent verification that a borrower seeking to refinance a special mortgage has received counseling on the transaction's advisability. Defines &quot;special mortgage&quot; as one that: (1) was originated, subsidized, funded, or guaranteed by or through a state, tribal, or local government, or nonprofit organization; and (2) bears one or more specified nonstandard payment terms which substantially benefit the consumer.</p> <p>Prescribes minimum financial requirements for mortgage brokers.</p> <p>Excludes reverse mortgages from coverage by this Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Fairness for Homeowners Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Fairness for Homeowners Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Fairness for Homeowners Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Truth in Lending Act to protect consumers from certain practices in connection with the origination of consumer credit transactions secured by the consumer's principal dwelling, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2009-03-30T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr1782ih/xml/BILLS-111hr1782ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-03-30</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
