<bill session="119" type="h" number="766" updated="2025-04-09T19:57:52Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SEWER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEWER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surveilling Effluent Water for Epidemic Response Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to establish, maintain, or improve activities related to the detection and monitoring of infectious diseases through wastewater for public health emergency preparedness and response purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-09T19:57:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Surveilling Effluent Water for Epidemic Response Act or the SEWER Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) National Wastewater Surveillance System (NWSS) program, which detects and monitors pathogens in wastewater. It requires the CDC to expand and intensify the activities of the NWSS, including with respect to SARS-CoV-2&#160;(the virus that causes&#160;COVID-19), influenza, mpox, dengue, West Nile virus, and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV).&#160;

The&#160;NWSS&#160;provides funding and guidance to public health departments for wastewater surveillance activities.&#160;Under the NWSS, health departments and other partners coordinate on wastewater&#160;surveillance at sampling sites and share data with the CDC. The NWSS was initially&#160;implemented&#160;to monitor&#160;SARS-CoV-2&#160;and has since expanded to include influenza A, avian influenza A,&#160;mpox, and RSV. &#160; &#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
