<bill session="118" type="s" number="1396" updated="2025-11-19T02:59:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Research Advancing to Market Production for Innovators Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Research Advancing to Market Production for Innovators Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Research Advancing to Market Production for Innovators Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve commercialization activities in the SBIR and STTR programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2023-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Reported by Senator Cardin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="169">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 169.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3056" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-25T14:18:24Z" status="Reported to Senate">Research Advancing to Market Production for Innovators Act

This bill provides commercialization services for federally funded small business research and development under the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs.

Specifically, the bill (1) expedites the application and award process for SBIR proposals and STTR solicitations, (2) requires determinations of commercialization potential for projects undertaken through SBIR and STTR awards, (3) provides continued flexibility of technical and business assistance for SBIR and STTR awardees, (4) instructs participating federal agencies to designate a technology commercialization official to help awardees commercialize, and (5) requires the Small Business Administration and the U.S. Patent Office to reach an interagency agreement to help SBIR and STTR awardees with intellectual property protection.</summary>
</bill>
