<bill session="117" type="h" number="4098" updated="2022-12-31T04:59:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To develop a non-opioid pain management directive indicating to health care professionals and emergency medical services personnel that an individual with respect to whom a form has been executed must not be administered an opioid or offered a prescription for an opioid, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Non-Opioid Directive Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Non-Opioid Directive Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000465" joined="2022-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2021-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000171" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1292" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-29T20:36:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Non-Opioid Directive Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a non-opioid pain management directive. This is a form that an individual may use to inform health care providers of the individual's choice to avoid opioid medications for pain management. The bill also sets out requirements for the execution, use, and revocation of these forms.

HHS must make the form available on its website, and health insurers must make it available to their plan enrollees. Insurers must also share an enrollee's choice about opioid treatment with health care providers during pre-authorization processes.

The bill allows health care providers to override a patient's form in specified circumstances. It also extends liability protections for providers who reasonably and in good faith administer or prescribe an opioid to a patient with an executed form in place.</summary>
</bill>
