<bill session="116" type="s" number="4693" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Evaluation of Science and Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide requirements for agency decision making based on science.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-30T14:26:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Better Evaluation of Science and Technology Act or the BEST Act

This bill requires federal agencies to use the best available scientific information during rulemaking and publish specified documentation of the rulemaking process.

Specifically, the bill requires a federal agency, to the extent it is making a decision based on science when issuing a rule, to use scientific information, technical procedures, methods, protocols, methodologies, or models in a manner that is consistent with the best available science and the intended use of the information, based on the weight of the scientific evidence.

Each federal agency shall make available to the public (1) all of its notices, determinations, findings, rules, consent agreements, and orders in connection with a rule; (2) a nontechnical summary of each risk evaluation conducted in connection with a rule; and (3) a list of the studies considered by the agency in carrying out each evaluation, along with the results of those studies.</summary>
</bill>
