<bill session="116" type="h" number="3940" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:25Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protection of Children Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to provide for the expedited removal of unaccompanied alien children who are not victims of a severe form of trafficking in persons and who do not have a fear of returning to their country of nationality or last habitual residence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protection of Children Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="574" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="586" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-01T19:08:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Protection of Children Act of 2019

This bill requires the removal of unaccompanied alien children in certain instances and amends related provisions.

An immigration officer must return an unaccompanied child apprehended at a land border to the child's country of nationality or last habitual residence if the child (1) is not a victim of severe trafficking, and (2) does not have a credible fear of persecution. Currently, an immigration officer may return the child only if such criteria is met and the child is from a contiguous country and able to make an independent decision to withdraw a petition for admission into the United States.

If the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) has determined that an unaccompanied child is a victim of severe trafficking or has a credible fear of persecution and DHS seeks to remove that child, removal proceedings with a hearing before an immigration judge shall be held within 14 days of the determination. Such a child shall have access to counsel, to the greatest extent practicable, and at no expense to the government. (Currently, the statute does not prohibit the government from bearing the expenses for such counsel.)

The bill extends and removes certain deadlines for transferring an unaccompanied alien child to Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) custody.

HHS, before placing a child with an individual, shall provide DHS with certain information about the individual. If the individual's immigration status is unknown, DHS shall investigate and initiate removal proceedings if the individual is unlawfully present.</summary>
</bill>
