<bill session="116" type="s" number="4089" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Employees and Retirees in Business Bankruptcies Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Employees and Retirees in Business Bankruptcies Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, to improve protections for employees and retirees in business bankruptcies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2020-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2020-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2020-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2020-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3314-3319" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7370" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-10T14:21:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Employees and Retirees in Business Bankruptcies Act of 2020

This bill modifies provisions related to&#160;Chapter 11 bankruptcy, which typically involves the reorganization of&#160;a debtor company's assets and debts. Specifically, the bill (1) expands available claims and priorities for employees and retirees, and (2) places additional restrictions on the compensation of executives and other high level employees.

With respect to employee and retiree&#160;recoveries and losses, the bill

 increases the maximum&#160;value and age&#160;of specified wage and benefit claims entitled to priority payment; allows certain claims for losses&#160;related to&#160;defined contribution plans, if the employer or plan sponsor has committed fraud or otherwise breached its fiduciary duty; allows, as an administrative expense of the estate, severance pay owed to employees and contributions to an employee benefit plan; establishes&#160;certain restrictions&#160;regarding the rejection or amendment of a collective bargaining agreement; revises specified procedures related to the reduction or denial of retiree benefits; requires a court, in approving a sale of business assets, to consider the extent to which a bidder has offered to maintain existing jobs and assume benefit obligations; and allows claims related to pension losses. With respect to&#160;executive compensation, the bill

 establishes&#160;specified limitations related to executive compensation enhancements, prohibits executives from receiving certain retiree benefits if such benefits were reduced or eliminated for other employees or retirees, and revises other requirements related to court approval of such compensation.</summary>
</bill>
