<bill session="117" type="s" number="446" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:31Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Informed Consent Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United State Code, to criminalize any abortion or sterilization procedure performed without the informed consent of the person on whom such procedure is performed, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Informed Consent Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1382" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-29T16:00:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Informed Consent Act

This bill establishes new federal criminal offenses related to the performance of abortions and sterilization procedures.

First, the bill prohibits knowingly performing an abortion or sterilization procedure without obtaining informed consent. It provides exceptions, including for an abortion or sterilization procedure that is necessary to save a mother whose life is endangered by a physical (but not psychological or emotional) disorder, illness, or condition.

An individual who performs a prohibited abortion or sterilization procedure is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 10 years, or both.

Second, the bill requires federal employees and contractors, as well as employees and contractors of certain federally funded entities, who know about a prohibited abortion or sterilization procedure to report it as soon as possible. An individual who knows about a prohibited abortion or sterilization procedure but fails to report it is subject to a fine, a prison term of up to three years, or both.</summary>
</bill>
