<bill session="118" type="s" number="2807" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Help Our Kelp Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to establish and carry out a grant program to conserve, restore, and manage kelp forest ecosystems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help Our Kelp Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5487" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-16T18:52:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Help Our Kelp ActThis bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish a grant program to fund projects to conserve, restore, or manage kelp forest ecosystems. (A kelp forest is a dense grouping of large brown algae which also serves as a habitat for marine life.)

Eligible projects include those that address the greatest relative regional declines in kelp forest ecosystems, focus on kelp forest seeding and connectivity, or integrate Indigenous knowledge and cultural practices into the restoration and monitoring of kelp forest ecosystems.

The bill specifies that members of the fishing industry, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, Indian tribes, state agencies, and local governments are eligible to receive grants.

The bill prohibits a grant&#160;from exceeding 85% of the total project cost. However, NOAA may waive this restriction in limited circumstances.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
