<bill session="108" type="s" number="3014" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:30Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-10">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act of 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2004-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2004-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2004-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2004-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11584-11586" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11584-11586" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T11:24:38-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T14:05:44-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T16:05:09-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ehlers asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T16:05:19-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10209-10211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2004-11-20T16:05:29-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10210-10211" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T16:05:50-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-29">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-10" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-456" type="public" datetime="2004-12-10">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-456.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="937" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1856" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="247" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Algal blooms"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Asian American ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Freshwater resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine biology"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="National Sea Grant Program"/>
    <term name="Oceanographic research"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-04T15:35:11Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.)

Title I: Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004 - Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Amendments Act of 2004 - (Sec. 102) Amends the Harmful Algal Bloom and Hypoxia Research and Control Act of 1998 to remove the President's authority to disestablish the Interagency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia. Requires the Task Force, in developing its assessments, reports, and plans, to consult with the coastal States, Indian tribes, local governments, appropriate industries, academic institutions, and nongovernmental organizations with expertise in coastal zone science and management.

(Sec. 103) Directs the President, in consultation with the chief executive officers of the States and other specified entities, to develop and submit to Congress a report that describes and evaluates the effectiveness of measures that may be utilized to protect the environment and public health from the impacts of harmful algal blooms. Requires a period of public comment prior to submission of the report.

(Sec. 104) Requires the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to provide for local and regional scientific assessments of hypoxia and harmful algal blooms, as requested by States, Indian tribes, and local governments, or for affected areas as identified by the Secretary.

Directs the Task Force to complete and submit to Congress scientific assessments of: (1) current knowledge about harmful algal blooms in freshwater, including a research plan for coordinating Federal efforts to better understand freshwater algal blooms; (2) hypoxia in U.S. coastal waters including the Great Lakes; and (3) harmful algal blooms in U.S. coastal waters.

Requires the Task Force to develop and submit to Congress a plan providing for a comprehensive and coordinated national research program to develop and demonstrate prevention, control, and mitigation methods to reduce the impacts of harmful algal blooms on coastal ecosystems (including the Great Lakes), public health, and the economy.

(Sec. 105) Authorizes appropriations.

Title II: Miscellaneous - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the Secretary to make available to the University of Miami, by easement, lease, license, or long-term agreement, real property under the administrative jurisdiction of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) on Virginia Key, Florida, for development by the University of a Marine Life Science Center.

Authorizes the use of such property by the University for the development and operation of facilities for multidisciplinary environmental and fisheries research, assessment, management, and educational activities, subject to agreement with the Secretary.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into an agreement to occupy facilities constructed by the University on such property and to participate with the University in collaborative research at, or administered through, such facilities.

(Sec. 202) Authorizes the Secretary to convey to the Government of Mexico, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the NOAA vessel WHITING: (1) for use as a hydrographic survey platform in support of activities of the U.S.-Mexico Charting Advisors Committee; and (2) to enhance coordination between the United States and Mexico regarding hydrographic surveying and nautical charting activities in the border waters of both countries in the Gulf of Mexico and the Pacific Ocean.</summary>
</bill>
