<bill session="117" type="s" number="5303" updated="2023-08-28T18:15:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Marketplace for All Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Marketplace for All Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to allow health marketplace pools to be deemed an employer under section 3(5) of such Act for purposes of offering a group health plan or group health insurance coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-28T18:01:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Health Marketplace for All Act of 2022 This bill permits entities such as self-employed companies and membership organizations to form health marketplace pools to offer large group health insurance plans as a single employer. (In general, large group health plans cover employees of an employer that has 51 or more employees; in some states, large groups are defined as 101 employees or more.) Subject to specified nondiscrimination rules related to preexisting conditions and health status, health marketplace pools must offer plans to all members or employees of the pool on an equal basis. Health marketplace pools are not considered joint employers for the purpose of other federal labor or employment laws.</summary>
</bill>
