<bill session="119" type="h" number="948" updated="2025-07-25T14:22:47Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE HOME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE HOME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Affordable Fire Emergency Hardening through Optimized Mitigation Efforts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a refundable credit against tax for wildfire mitigation expenditures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T14:19:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Affordable Fire Emergency Hardening through Optimized Mitigation Efforts Act or the SAFE HOME Act

This bill establishes a new refundable tax credit (through 2032) for costs incurred by an individual to improve the fire resistance of a primary residence. (Certain requirements and limitations apply.)

The amount of the tax credit is 25% of unreimbursed qualified wildfire mitigation expenses up to $25,000. The tax credit begins to phase out for individuals with an adjusted gross income exceeding $200,000, such that the tax credit is completely phased out for individuals with an adjusted gross income of $300,000 or more.

 Wildfire mitigation expenses that qualify for the tax credit include

property to improve the fire-resistance of a roof;installation of ignition-resistant property (e.g., sheathing, flashing, roof and attic vents, or certain exterior elements) or structure-specific water hydration systems;services or equipment to create a buffer around the residence or to replace flammable vegetation with less flammable vegetation;services or equipment for certain fire maintenance procedures; andservices or equipment to prevent smoke inhalation (e.g., air filters).Further, such expenses must be incurred with respect to a primary residence located (1) in the United States; and (2) in an area that, due to a wildfire, received a federal disaster declaration within the prior 10 years or that is adjacent to such area, that received certain hazard mitigation assistance in the tax year or the&#160;prior 10 years, or that is a community disaster resilience zone (or received such designation for any tax year).</summary>
</bill>
