<bill session="118" type="s" number="2139" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ALERT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability of Leaders in Education to Report Title IX Investigations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that certain incidents involving a covered employee that are reported to the title IX coordinator at an eligible institution of higher education have been reviewed by the president of the institution and not less than 1 additional member of the institution's board of trustees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4354" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-17T15:42:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accountability of Leaders in Education to Report Title IX Investigations Act or the ALERT Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student-aid programs to certify annually with the Department of Education that they have reviewed reports of misconduct by their employees involving domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking. The certification must include a confirmation that the IHE's president and board members involved in the review did not interfere with or influence investigations or dispositions.</summary>
</bill>
