<bill session="117" type="h" number="3033" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Resilient Ports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, with respect to the projects eligible for certain port and intermodal improvement grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resilient Ports Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-05T12:01:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Resilient Ports Act

This bill revises the Port Infrastructure Development Program with respect to port and intermodal improvement grants.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of Transportation (DOT) to provide grants for projects that will be used to improve the safety, efficiency, or reliability of emissions mitigation measures directly related to reducing the overall carbon footprint from port operations.

Additionally, the bill increases from 18% to 25% the set-aside that DOT must reserve for grants for port projects that request the lesser of (1) 10% of the grant amounts made available for a fiscal year, or (2) $10 million.

In selecting projects for funding, the bill requires DOT to give substantial weight to projects that increase the port's resilience to sea-level rise, flooding, and extreme weather events, including events related to climate change.</summary>
</bill>
