<bill session="118" type="s" number="3059" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REAL Health Providers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REAL Health Providers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requiring Enhanced &amp; Accurate Lists of Health Providers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish provider directory requirements, and to provide accountability for provider director accuracy, under Medicare Advantage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3430" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7708" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-07T19:58:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requiring Enhanced &amp; Accurate Lists of Health Providers Act or the REAL Health Providers Act

This bill requires Medicare Advantage (MA) organizations to maintain directories of in-network providers and continually ensure their accuracy.

Specifically, MA organizations must publish on their websites an accurate directory of in-network providers and regularly update these directories. The bill additionally specifies that if a provider is listed as in-network in this directory when a beneficiary selects and makes an appointment with the provider, but the provider is not actually in-network, the beneficiary is still only responsible for paying in-network cost-sharing requirements.

MA organizations must annually evaluate and report on the accuracy of their directories; the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and MA organizations must publish this information on their websites. The bill provides funds for these purposes.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the bill's implementation.</summary>
</bill>
