<bill session="119" type="h" number="84" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Education Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Education Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand opportunity for Native American children through additional options in education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-06T18:14:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Native American Education Opportunity Act

This bill addresses education savings account programs and charter schools for tribal students.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Education and the Department of the Interior, at the request of federally recognized Indian tribes, to&#160;provide funds to tribes for tribal-based education savings account programs. Tribes must use these funds to award grants to education savings accounts for students who (1)&#160;attended or will be eligible to attend a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Education (BIE); or (2) will not be attending a school operated by the BIE, receiving an education savings account from another tribe, or attending public elementary or secondary school while participating in the program.

Funds may be used for items and activities such as costs of attendance at private schools, private tutoring and online learning programs, textbooks, educational software, or examination fees.

The Government Accountability Office must review the implementation of these education savings account programs, including any factors impacting increased participation in such programs.

Additionally, the bill authorizes the BIE to approve and fund charter schools at any school that it operates or funds.</summary>
</bill>
