<bill session="118" type="s" number="4280" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Essential Caregivers Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Essential Caregivers Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to require skilled nursing facilities, nursing facilities, intermediate care facilities for the intellectually disabled, and inpatient rehabilitation facilities to permit essential caregivers access during any period in which regular visitation is restricted.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2024-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2024-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2024-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2024-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2024-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2024-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2024-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2024-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2024-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2024-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2024-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2024-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2024-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2024-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2024-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2024-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2024-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2024-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8331" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-26T21:39:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Essential Caregivers Act of 2024

This bill prohibits certain health care facilities from limiting the access of essential caregivers to residents of those facilities, including during designated emergency periods. Essential caregivers are individuals who are designated by facility residents to provide them with daily living assistance or emotional support or companionship.&#160;

Specifically, the bill generally prohibits Medicare skilled nursing facilities, Medicaid nursing facilities, Medicaid intermediate care facilities, and associated inpatient rehabilitation facilities from restricting the access of essential caregivers to residents of the facilities, including during emergency periods in which visitation rights are otherwise restricted. During emergency periods, facilities may restrict access for an initial period of up to seven days and for one additional maximum seven-day period (if the additional period is approved by the state health department). Facilities may restrict access for a total of 7 days (or 14 days with the approval of the state health department) during an emergency period.

Essential caregivers must agree to comply with any safety protocols set by the facility, which may be no more stringent for caregivers compared to those for staff. Caregivers who fail to comply with these requirements may be denied access, subject to an appeals process.</summary>
</bill>
