<bill session="118" type="h" number="5478" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Teacher Diversity and Retention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Teacher Diversity and Retention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish the Honorable Augustus F. Hawkins Centers of Excellence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2024-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-18T15:37:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Teacher Diversity and Retention Act

This bill revises certain grant programs related to teacher recruitment and training.

First, the bill reauthorizes through FY2029 and otherwise revises the Augustus F. Hawkins Centers of Excellence program, which provides grants to establish teacher preparation programs at minority-serving institutions. It allows grants to be used for school leader preparation programs.

 In addition, the bill consolidates certain grant programs for teacher preparation into a single grant program. In particular, the Department of Education must award grants to eligible partnerships (e.g., high-need local educational agencies and certain programs at institutions of higher education) to expand teacher preparation programs that embed dual certification in special education and training on social and emotional learning competencies and behavior management practices.</summary>
</bill>
