<bill session="117" type="s" number="2912" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen United States oversight of the Biological Weapons Convention and to advance non-proliferation objectives related to biological weapons, dual-use technologies, and life sciences research, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Biological Weapons Policy Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biological Weapons Policy Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-16T21:12:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Biological Weapons Policy Act of 2021

This bill modifies the Department of State's authorities related to biological and virological weapons and addresses related issues.

The State Department's authority to engage in certain activities (e.g., conduct research and provide grants) related to detecting and reducing certain weapons shall include activities directed at biological and virological weapons.

The bill prohibits using federal funds for research that increases the pathogenicity, contagiousness, or transmissibility of viruses or bacteria if the research involves a foreign entity subject to the jurisdiction of certain countries, including China and Russia.

The President must carry out certain activities related to China's compliance with the Biological Weapons Convention, including engaging with other governments about concerns about such compliance.

The U.S. representative to the United Nations (UN) must advocate to bar representatives from certain countries, including China and Russia, from serving in leadership positions in any UN agency or program with a nexus to certain subjects, such as global health and biosecurity.

The U.S. mission to certain countries must complete an assessment of whether each U.S. government-supported project involving life sciences dual-use research of concern aligns with U.S. national interests.

The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on (1) U.S. government authorities and processes related to cooperation with other nations in life sciences research that could be weaponized or pose dual-use concerns; and (2) coordination between federal agencies responsible for public health, biomedical research, and national security in the assessment of the security implications of cooperation with other nations on life sciences research.</summary>
</bill>
