<bill session="116" type="h" number="6591" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To ensure that veterans receive timely and effective health care under the Veterans Community Care Program and Veterans Care Agreements during the COVID-19 emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that veterans receive timely and effective health care under the Veterans Community Care Program and Veterans Care Agreements during the COVID-19 emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2020-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2020-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2020-08-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2020-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3888" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-01T16:26:15Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill sets forth policies and procedures related to medical care for veterans covered under the Veterans Community Care Program and Veterans Care Agreements during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency period.

Specifically, the bill authorizes covered veterans to receive care for COVID-19 diagnosis or treatment under the Veterans Community Care Program and Veterans Care Agreements during the COVID-19 emergency period, regardless of whether such care is for a service-connected disability. Emergency medical care and COVID-19 care shall not require Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) preauthorization during the emergency period.

The bill prescribes how the VA shall administer claims for payments relating to emergency COVID-19 care, depending on whether the community care provider is (1) an eligible provider under the Veterans Community Care Program, (2) party to a Veterans Care Agreement, or (3) not eligible under the Veterans Community Care Program or part of a Veterans Care Agreement.

The bill classifies emergency treatment for COVID-19 as emergency treatment eligible for coverage by the VA.

The VA shall determine whether a veteran who receives emergency care for COVID-19 is an active VA health care participant without regard to whether the veteran has received VA medical care in the two years preceding such emergency care.

Finally, the bill specifies that, during the emergency period, community care providers that furnish emergency COVID-19 care are required to submit a claim for payment to the VA within 180 days of such care.</summary>
</bill>
