<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="485" updated="2022-02-03T04:59:05Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1375" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-03-18T13:45:18-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  <description>Page 83, line 4, strike the closing quotation marks and the 2nd period. \   Page 83, after line 4, insert the following new subparagraph: \   "(C) SENSE OF THE CONGRESS.--It is the sense of the Congress that, when a requesting agency requires expeditious action on an application for a merger transaction, consideration should be made as to the impact the merger transaction will have on corporate and individual customers in an effort to ensure that no harmful effects will result from the merger transaction.".</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 5 printed in House Report 108-439 to express the sense of Congress that in situations where a requesting agency obtains expedited action to approve a merger transaction application between multiple depository institutions, that careful consideration is placed on the impact that the transaction will have on affected communities and customers of any or all of the applicant institutions.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-03-18T13:45:18-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="67">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 194 - 225 (Roll no. 67).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18T12:54:22-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1267-1268, H1272" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1267" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18T12:54:22-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A005) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1267-1268, H1272" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1267" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18T13:45:18-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 194 - 225 (Roll no. 67).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18T13:45:18-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18T13:45:18-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
