<bill session="118" type="s" number="1163" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Aviation Minority Workforce Development Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Minority Workforce Development Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a grant program to increase racial and gender minority access and representation in the aviation workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T18:48:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Aviation Minority Workforce Development Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Transportation to establish a grant program to increase racial and gender minority access and representation in the aviation workforce. Grants may be provided to minority-serving institutions (e.g., historically Black colleges and universities) and a consortium of one or more institutions of higher education that has a partnership with an aviation company or industry association, a labor-management organization, or other specified entity.

The grants must be used to

 facilitate the creation of programs that educate and train students; increase access to, and the availability of, resources at existing aviation workforce programs; assist students with education, apprenticeship, internship, transportation, and certification costs; and increase student outreach and recruitment.</summary>
</bill>
