<bill session="118" type="h" number="9024" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Extreme Weather and Heat Response Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Extreme Weather and Heat Response Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="display">Extreme Weather and Heat Response Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to take certain actions relating to incident periods and extreme weather, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2024-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2024-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 44 - 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 118-813.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-05" calendar="Union" number="665">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 665.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-05T21:43:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Extreme Weather and Heat Response Modernization Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to specifically address extreme heat in hazard mitigation and disaster recovery, including reviewing the time frame for when extreme weather is an emergency or major disaster.

FEMA must issue guidance relating to hazard mitigation and disaster recovery for extreme heat or extreme temperature events. FEMA must also&#160;convene an advisory panel to review its process for determining when an emergency- or disaster-causing incident begins and ends. Additionally,&#160;FEMA must conduct a study on the impacts of extreme heat, recommend guidance on mitigating and responding to extreme heat, and submit a report to Congress on these actions.

The bill also&#160;authorizes FEMA to consider extreme heat preparedness and mitigation projects eligible under its Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities program and Hazard Mitigation Grant Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-813</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
