<bill session="118" type="h" number="3871" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Research for Healthy Soils Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Research for Healthy Soils Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to include as a high-priority research and extension area research on microplastics in land-applied biosolids on farmland.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3623" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-08T17:59:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Research for Healthy Soils Act

This bill includes research on the agricultural impacts of microplastics in land-applied biosolids on farmland as a Department of Agriculture (USDA) high-priority research and extension area. Microplastic is a plastic or plastic-coated particle that is less than 5 millimeters in size.

The bill specifically allows grants for carrying out or enhancing research in this area (e.g., the development or analysis of wastewater treatment techniques to filter out or biodegrade microplastics from biosolids intended to be used for agricultural purposes).

Further, the bill reauthorizes USDA grants to support competitive specialized research and extension activities, including high-priority areas, through FY2028. The bill also specifically reauthorizes through FY2028

 the Pulse Crop Health Initiative; the Comprehensive Food Safety Training Network; pollinator protection research and extension grants; increased USDA capacity and infrastructure to address and conduct research on colony collapse disorder and other pollinator issues; and a USDA-conducted nationwide honey bee pest, pathogen, health, and population status surveillance program.</summary>
</bill>
