<bill session="118" type="s" number="1778" updated="2025-04-23T10:58:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agrivoltaics Research and Demonstration Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agrivoltaics Research and Demonstration Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a study and research and demonstration on agrivoltaic systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7391" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1840" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1016" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2931" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-23T10:56:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agrivoltaics Research and Demonstration Act of 2023

This bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to study and establish research and demonstration sites on agrivoltaic systems. The bill defines agrivoltaic system as a system under which solar energy production and agricultural production, including crop or animal production, occur in an integrated manner on the same piece of land through the duration of a project.

Specifically, the bill directs USDA to study agrivoltaic systems, which includes conducting a review of current research and identifying research gaps. USDA must also develop a five-year plan for using USDA's research, extension, outreach, conservation, and renewable energy activities to better support agrivoltaic systems that do not displace agricultural production.

USDA must also develop a definition for agrivoltaic system for the purposes of incorporating these systems into federal agriculture and energy programs, and investment tax credits.

In addition, the Agricultural Research Service must establish and maintain a network of agrivoltaic systems research and demonstration sites in multiple U.S. regions to investigate increasing agricultural productivity and profitability, enhancing agricultural resilience, protecting biodiversity, and increasing economic opportunities in rural communities.</summary>
</bill>
