<bill session="117" type="h" number="9602" updated="2023-08-28T14:45:19Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maternal Health Pandemic Response Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maternal Health Pandemic Response Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the public health response to addressing maternal mortality and morbidity during the COVID-19 public health emergency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5284" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-28T14:33:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Maternal Health Pandemic Response Act of 2022

This bill addresses data collection, public education, workplace safety, and other matters related to maternal health during public health emergencies.

Specifically, the bill supports (1) the collection of maternal data (including racial, ethnic, and other demographic data) through surveillance systems of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), and (2) research activities of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development.

Additionally, the CDC and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must make publicly available and periodically update pregnancy and postpartum data that is collected across COVID-19 surveillance systems. The data must be disaggregated by factors such as race, ethnicity, insurance status, and location.

The bill also requires

 the CDC to educate pregnant people, their employers, and their health care providers about evidenced-based health information concerning COVID-19 and pregnancy; the Department of Health and Human Services to convene a task force to develop recommendations on the provision of maternity care during the COVID-19 (and future) public health emergencies with a particular focus on communities of color and rural populations; the Occupational Safety and Health Administration to issue an emergency temporary standard to protect employees who are at risk from occupational exposure to COVID-19 that considers the risks and needs of pregnant and postpartum employees; and the Government Accountability Office to report on maternal health and public health preparedness, including prenatal, labor and delivery, and postpartum care during the COVID-19 emergency.</summary>
</bill>
