<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3466</number>
    <updateDate>2023-08-04T17:30:26Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-08-04T17:30:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-01-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-01-18</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 246.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-01-10</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-01-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001098</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cruz, Ted [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ted</firstName>
        <lastName>Cruz</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-01-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2023-08-04T17:29:05Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Stopping Censorship, Restoring Integrity, and Protecting Talkies Act or the SCRIPT Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits federal support for a U.S. company that alters political content in its motion pictures (e.g., movies and television shows) in response to or in anticipation of a request from China's government. </p> <p>Under this bill, <em>political content </em>is content relating to issues considered sensitive by the Chinese Communist Party or China's government, such as Taiwan or the Tiananmen Square massacre.</p> <p>To be eligible to receive federal support (e.g., a contract for production or access to a federally controlled asset) for a motion picture, a U.S. company must provide to the Department of State a list of motion pictures it has submitted to China's government for approval for dissemination during the reporting period (the previous 10 years or since this bill was enacted, whichever period is shorter). The U.S. company must also agree in writing to not (1) alter political content in its motion picture in response to or in anticipation of a request from China's government, or (2) coproduce the motion picture with an entity located in China that is subject to political content restrictions from China's government. </p> <p>A U.S. company that has taken such actions during the reporting period shall be prohibited from receiving federal support. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>SCRIPT Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>SCRIPT Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>SCRIPT Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Stopping Censorship, Restoring Integrity, and Protecting Talkies Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to prohibit the use of Federal funds for the production of programs by United States companies that alter political content for screening in the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2022-01-18T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s3466pcs/xml/BILLS-117s3466pcs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-01-18</actionDate>
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 246.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
