<bill session="117" type="h" number="7288" updated="2022-12-29T22:18:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affordable Loans for Any Student Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Loans for Any Student Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 in order to increase usage of the Federal student loan income-based repayment plan and improve repayment options for borrowers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2022-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2022-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3953" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4459" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-13T21:35:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Affordable Loans for Any Student Act

This bill addresses repayment options, loan disclosures, and loan counseling for student loans.

The bill revises requirements concerning repayment options for student loan borrowers. For instance, the bill terminates interest capitalization and origination fees for Federal Direct Loans, provides assistance to low-income borrowers or borrowers who are delinquent on loan payments, and replaces the existing income-based repayment plans with two new plans. Under the new plans, borrowers may choose (1) a fixed repayment plan with equal monthly payments paid over a period of 10 years, or (2) an income-based repayment plan with monthly payments equal to 10% percent of their income above the poverty level. The income-based plan is capped at 20 years of payments.

The bill also revises requirements concerning student loan disclosures and student loan counseling for borrowers. For instance, the bill requires the Department of Education to maintain online counseling tools that provide borrowers with entrance and exit student loan counseling.</summary>
</bill>
