<bill session="118" type="s" number="1327" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consumer Credit Control Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Credit Control Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require that a consumer authorize the release of certain information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1390" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-05T20:20:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Credit Control Act of 2023

This bill requires a consumer's affirmative informed consent before a consumer reporting agency may share that consumer's report with third parties for specified purposes. A consumer reporting agency must verify a consumer's identity when obtaining this consent. (Currently, this sharing is generally allowed unless a consumer opts out.)

If the consumer provides consent, a consumer reporting agency may share information with a third party for an extension of credit or the underwriting of insurance.

Additionally, in connection with transactions not initiated by the consumer, a consumer reporting agency may provide a consumer report with the consumer's consent only if the transaction consists of a firm offer of credit or insurance.

Furthermore, consumer reporting agencies may not charge consumers fees in connection with furnishing consumer reports.

The bill also requires consumer reporting agencies to use reasonable efforts to prevent data breaches of consumer reports.

The Government Accountability Office must report on how best to protect information collected in consumer files.</summary>
</bill>
