<bill session="116" type="s" number="154" updated="2022-11-01T14:17:31Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA CLEAR Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Contract, Leadership, and Ensuring Accountability and Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA CLEAR Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve oversight of contracts for services and financial processes of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2019-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-30T17:00:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Contract, Leadership, and Ensuring Accountability and Reform Act of 2019 or the VA CLEAR Act of 2019

This bill addresses oversight of financial processes of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and also requires implementation of systems for maintaining specified records.

Among other elements, the bill requires the VA to

 include specified elements in contracts it enters for services (e.g., measurable metrics to ascertain the performance of the provider of the service), submit a justification and plan for contracts for services that would incur an obligation of more than $2 billion, contract with a third party to review and audit the VA's financial processes and provide recommendations for improvement, and submit a justification for requests for supplemental appropriations. Additionally, the Inspector General of the VA and the Government Accountability Office must complete a review of a contract for services that would result in the VA incurring an obligation of more than $2 billion.

The bill authorizes the Inspector General of the VA, in the performance of the functions assigned to such office, to subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses.

Finally, the bill requires the VA to implement a centralized system to maintain and record completed reviews of administrative investigation boards, and the Veterans Health Administration must implement a centralized system for tracking instances where the VA has referred a clinician to a state's licensing board because of behavior or clinical outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
