<bill session="109" type="h" number="2571" updated="2020-02-10T16:51:02Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reduced Asthma Through Air Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Reduced Asthma Through Air Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the establishment of programs by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to improve indoor air quality in schools and other buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-24T19:22:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Reduced Asthma Through Air Quality Improvement Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH), and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish programs to improve indoor air quality in schools and in buildings where there are private or public sector employees.Requires EPA to: (1) enter into an agreement with nongovernmental organizations to establish a permanent program to provide information to school administrators on methods of improving indoor air quality; or (2) publish notice of such an existing program or combination of programs.Requires NIOSH to implement a Building Health Assessment Program to provide building assessments, upon request, to employers and employees on measures to reduce significant indoor air health risks.Requires HHS to establish a grant program to assist schools and employers, respectively, to implement such indoor air quality recommendations from EPA and NIOSH.</summary>
</bill>
