<bill session="116" type="s" number="4110" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hong Kong Safe Harbor Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hong Kong Safe Harbor Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate residents of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region as Priority 2 refugees of special humanitarian concern, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2020-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2020-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2020-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2020-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2020-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2020-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7415" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4631" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-23T19:26:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hong Kong Safe Harbor Act

This bill designates certain Hong Kong residents with priority status for refugee consideration and contains other related provisions.

An individual and certain family members shall have such priority status if the individual (1) is a Hong Kong resident who suffered persecution or has a well-founded fear of persecution as a result of peaceful political activity; or (2) has been formally charged, detained, or convicted for certain peaceful actions. An individual receiving refugee status under this bill shall not be counted against various numerical limitations.

When determining whether an individual shall be admitted as a refugee under this bill, an individual whose citizenship, nationality, or residency was revoked for submitting a nonfrivolous application for a U.S. immigration benefit shall be considered to have suffered persecution on account of political opinion.

The general presumption that an alien is seeking immigrant status shall not apply to certain Hong Kong residents seeking asylum into the United States. (Typically, an alien seeking admission as a nonimmigrant must establish that the alien does not intend to immigrate to the United States.) This exception to the presumption shall apply to certain individuals involved in the 2019 and 2020 protests against China's encroachment into Hong Kong's autonomy (Hong Kong is a part of China but has a separate legal and economic system).

An individual from Hong Kong may not be denied admission into the United States if the primary reason for the denial is a politically motivated government action against the individual's involvement in protests.</summary>
</bill>
