<bill session="116" type="h" number="7501" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to foster efficient markets and increase competition and transparency among packers that purchase livestock from producers.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to foster efficient markets and increase competition and transparency among packers that purchase livestock from producers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000467" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2020-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3693" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-05T14:16:28Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill establishes that a minimum of 50% of a covered packer's weekly volume of livestock slaughter must be purchased through spot market sales from nonaffiliated producers. (The term covered packer applies to a packer that is required to report to the Department of Agriculture each reporting day information on the price and quantity of livestock purchased by such packer and does not include a packer that owns only one livestock processing plant.)

A spot market sale is a purchase and sale of livestock by a packer from a producer under (1) an agreement that specifies a firm base price that may be equated with a fixed dollar amount on the date the agreement is entered into, (2) which the livestock are slaughtered not more than 14 days after the date on which the agreement is entered into, and (3) circumstances in which a reasonable competitive bidding opportunity exists on the date on which the agreement is entered into.</summary>
</bill>
