<bill session="118" type="s" number="3988" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GRATS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Getting Rid of Abusive Trust Schemes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GRATS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify rules for grantor trusts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-13T16:50:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Getting Rid of Abusive Trust Schemes Act or the GRATS Act

This bill imposes new requirements on grantor retained annuity trusts (GRATs) to discourage tax avoidance schemes by wealthy taxpayers. Specifically, such trusts must have a minimum term of 15 years and a maximum term of the life expectancy of the annuitant plus 10 years. The bill also prohibits any decrease in a GRAT during its term and requires that the remainder interests in such trusts at the time of their transfer must have a minimum value for gift tax purposes.&#160;

The bill also treats a transfer of property between a GRAT and its deemed owner as a sale or exchange for income tax purposes, with specified exceptions.

The bill designates any income tax paid on the income of a GRAT as a gift for purposes of the gift tax unless the owner of the trust is reimbursed during the same calendar year. The amount of the gift may not be reduced through the use of certain deductions, including the charitable or marital deduction, or gifts of tuition or medical care.&#160;&#160; &#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
