<bill session="116" type="h" number="8310" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CCTARI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CCTARI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering China&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Theft of American Research and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for enhanced visa security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2020-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2020-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000302" joined="2020-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2020-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8309" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-14T13:08:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Countering China's Theft of American Research and Innovation Act or the CCTARI Act

This bill modifies provisions related to reviewing visa applications for risks, including the illicit transfer of sensitive research from U.S. research institutions, and contains other related provisions.

A previously established interagency working group to coordinate the protection of federally-funded research from foreign interference shall report to Congress on a review of current Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and Department of State policies for preventing the illicit transfer of sensitive research from U.S. higher education and research institutions, including visa issuance procedures and national security reviews of certain nonimmigrant students.

The bill also modifies provisions authorizing DHS to assign its employees to diplomatic and consular posts to conduct visa application reviews and related tasks. When making such an assignment, DHS shall do so in a risk-based manner based on certain criteria, such as the number of nationals in a country identified as known or suspected terrorists and the number of cases involving illicit technology transfer. Such employees shall review visa applications to improve detection of cases that pose a substantial risk of illicit technology transfers.

DHS shall also prioritize establishing new overseas assignments with the goal of countering the exploitation or illicit transfer of sensitive technologies by student and exchange visitor visa holders.

DHS and the State Department shall jointly carry out a pilot program to evaluate the use of machine-readable technology to improve visa application and security vetting processes.</summary>
</bill>
