<bill session="118" type="s" number="3054" updated="2025-11-19T03:10:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Name, Image, and Likeness for International Collegiate Athletes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Name, Image, and Likeness for International Collegiate Athletes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide F visas and employment authorization for international student athletes who enter into endorsement contracts for the commercial use of their names, images, and likenesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7982" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-23T14:57:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Name, Image, and Likeness for International Collegiate Athletes Act

This bill makes nonimmigrant student visas (F visas) available to college athletes who enter into endorsement contracts involving the individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s name, image, or likeness.

The visa is available to individuals enrolled in a U.S. institution of higher education who intend to contract for the commercial use of their name, image, or likeness (i.e., endorsement contracts).&#160;

The bill authorizes the visa holder to obtain employment authorization for the purpose of engaging in activities related to such contracts.&#160;(Under current law, student visa holders must obtain employment authorization to perform off-campus work. The off-campus work must either be related to the student&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s field of study or in response to severe economic hardship due to unforeseen circumstances, subject to further requirements.)

The Department of Homeland Security may engage the student's institution of higher education in oversight of the student's employment activity.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
