<bill session="111" type="h" number="3038" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:45Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Justice for Wards Cove Workers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Civil Rights Act of 1991 with respect to the application of such Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Wards Cove Workers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000404"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-10T14:12:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for Wards Cove Workers Act - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1991 to remove a provision excluding from application of the Act any disparate impact case filed before March 1, 1975, and decided after October 30, 1983. (Wards Cove Packing Co. v. Atonio, 1989, held that, in cases brought under title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the burden is on the plaintiff to prove an employer had no business necessity for a practice with discriminatory effects.) Applies the amendments made by the Civil Rights Act of 1991 to a case that is subject to the removed provision in the same way such amendments apply to any other case brought under the employment discrimination provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.</summary>
</bill>
