<bill session="111" type="h" number="321" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:54Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SCHIP Plus Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to expand coverage options under the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) through premium assistance.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCHIP Plus Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001232" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2009-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2009-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-17T15:26:43Z" status="Introduced in House">SCHIP Plus Act of 2009 - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to require a state child health plan to provide for the offering of any qualified alternative coverage that a qualified entity seeks to offer targeted low-income children through the plan.

Revises requirements with respect to authority for payments to a state for the purchase of family coverage under an employer-sponsored group health plan that includes coverage of targeted low-income children.

Prohibits a state child health plan from requiring a targeted low-income child to enroll in such coverage in order to obtain child health assistance under this Act. (Thus requires enrollment to be voluntary.)

Requires a state health plan to provide at least one opportunity per fiscal year for beneficiaries to switch SCHIP coverage from an employer-sponsored plan to the coverage otherwise available under SCHIP. Requires such plan also to permit beneficiaries to switch coverage under other circumstances, such as change in employment, birth of a child, or change in households, as the Secretary specifies.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Public Health Service Act to require employers that maintain a group health plan in a state that provides child health assistance under SCHIP in the form of premium assistance to give each employee written notice of potential opportunities for such premium assistance for health coverage of the employee's dependents.</summary>
</bill>
