<bill session="118" type="h" number="1585" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prohibiting Parental Secrecy Policies In Schools Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibiting Parental Secrecy Policies In Schools Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a State receiving funds pursuant to title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to implement a State policy to prohibit a school employee from conducting certain social gender transition interventions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-28T15:43:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Prohibiting Parental Secrecy Policies In Schools Act of 2023

This bill requires each state, in order to receive specified federal funds for elementary and secondary education, to implement a state policy prohibiting school employees from certain actions regarding a minor's gender identity without parental consent.

In particular, a state policy must prohibit employees from the following activities without the consent of a minor student's custodial parent or legal guardian:

 using pronouns for a minor that are inconsistent with the minor's biological sex for the purpose of recognizing or promoting a self-professed gender identity that is incongruent with their biological sex; providing, promoting, referring to, or otherwise assisting in the use of medical or other devices that promote changes to the minor's physical appearance so that it aligns with the opposite biological sex for the purpose of recognizing or promoting a self-professed gender identity that is incongruent with their biological sex; and carrying out any other action designed to assist a minor in the promotion or adoption of their self-professed gender identity and denial of their biological sex.</summary>
</bill>
