<bill session="111" type="h" number="3110" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FACE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide United States citizenship for children adopted from outside the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FACE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Adopted Children Equality Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000794"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2009-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001174" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2010-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1359" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-12T19:40:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Adopted Children Equality Act or the FACE Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to set forth automatic citizenship criteria for a child adopted outside the United States by a U.S. citizen parent.

Deems such an adopted child to be a U.S. citizen at birth.

Deems to be a U.S. citizen at birth, after the approval of an application filed within the United States or with a U.S. Embassy, a person who: (1) is older than 18 years of age; (2) was born outside the United States and was adopted by a U.S. citizen parent before such person reached 18 years of age; and (3) was adopted under 16 years of age and has lived with the adoptive parents for at least two years, was abused, or is an orphan who was under 16 years of age at the time an immediate relative status petition was filed on his or her behalf.

Includes within the definition of nonimmigrant an individual brought to the United States as a child to be adopted by a U.S. citizen.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the government of each foreign country from which children are adopted by U.S. citizens should provide the adoptive family with birth history documentation.</summary>
</bill>
