<bill session="112" type="h" number="1214" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:17Z">
  <state datetime="2011-05-04T16:40:58-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-05-04T16:40:58-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To repeal mandatory funding for school-based health center construction.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal mandatory funding for school-based health center construction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2011-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-27">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-66, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Education and Labor discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-04-27" calendar="Union" number="34">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 34.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02T19:51:17-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 236 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1213 and H.R. 1214 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against provisions in the bills are waived. In the case of H.R. 1214, the resolution makes in order only those amendments that are received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated May 2, 2011, and pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T13:46:54-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 236 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:54:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 236.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2969-2977" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:54:59-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1213 and H.R. 1214 with 1 hour of general debate for each bill. In both cases, the previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The measures will be considered read. In the case of H.R. 1213, specified amendments are in order. In the case of H.R. 1214, the resolution makes in order only those amendments that are received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated May 2, 2011, and pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:55:19-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 236 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:55:21-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T15:55:36-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1214.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:05:53-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Burgess moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:06:15-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T17:06:28-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1214 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:25:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2983-2984" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2983" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:26:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:28:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson Lee (TX) amendment No.1 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:37:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:39:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 236, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Pallone amendment numbered 2 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:42:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pallone amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:43:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Burgess moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:43:21-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03T18:43:32-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 1214 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T15:25:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3037-3041" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T15:25:38-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T15:26:39-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:02:26-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1214.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:03:03-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3038" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:04:23-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. McCarthy (NY) moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3038-3039" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3038-3039" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:05:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the McCarthy (NY) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment adding a new paragraph directing the Secretary to publish, not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the names and locations of each school based health center or sponsoring facility that will not receive a grant.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:16:53-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3040" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:33:29-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 230 (Roll no. 289).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="290" datetime="2011-05-04T16:40:58-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed by recorded vote: 235 - 191 (Roll no. 290).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/3/2011 H2983" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04T16:40:58-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="290" datetime="2011-05-04T16:40:58-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 235 - 191 (Roll no. 290).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/3/2011 H2983" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h266"/>
    <amendment number="h265"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2011-05-16T21:07:16Z" status="Reported to House without amendment, Part I">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to repeal the program requiring the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to school-based health centers or their sponsoring facilities to support the operation of such health centers.

Rescinds unobligated appropriations for the program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-66</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
