<bill session="110" type="s" number="1440" updated="2023-01-11T16:47:40Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unfair Foreign Competition Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for judicial determination of injury in certain cases involving dumped and subsidized merchandise imported into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unfair Foreign Competition Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2007-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6403-6404"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-06-12T19:57:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Unfair Foreign Competition Act of 2007 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize a petitioning party, in an antidumping or countervailing duty investigation, to elect, within 30 days after the investigation has started, to bring a civil action in a U.S. district court for determination that a U.S. industry is materially injured or is threatened with material injury, or the establishment of an industry in the United States is materially retarded, by reason of imports, or sales (or the likelihood of sales) for importation, of the merchandise subject to the investigation, and that imports of the subject merchandise are not negligible.

Authorizes such a petitioning party, within 30 days after a five-year review of an antidumping or countervailing duty order is initiated, to bring a civil action in a U.S. district court for determination of whether revocation of the antidumping or countervailing duty order, or termination of a suspended investigation, would likely lead to continuation or recurrence of material injury.

Provides for preliminary relief and expedited action.

Applies this Act to goods from Canada and Mexico.</summary>
</bill>
