<bill session="117" type="h" number="6914" updated="2022-12-29T21:48:16Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMALL GOVT Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMALL GOVT Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Mandates And Limiting Large Government Overreach by Valuing Truth Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of Federal funds to discriminate, directly or indirectly, against an individual on the basis of whether such individual has been vaccinated or acquired natural immunity against SARS-CoV-2, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2022-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2022-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-10T19:43:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Stopping Mandates And Limiting Large Government Overreach by Valuing Truth Act of 2022 or the SMALL GOVT Act of 2022

This bill prohibits discrimination against individuals on the basis of their COVID-19 vaccination status or natural immunity to the virus. It also sets out informed consent requirements for COVID-19 vaccines.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the use of federal funds to discriminate against (or induce discrimination against) an individual on the basis of COVID-19 vaccination status or natural immunity to the virus by, for example, restricting access to employment or health care.

The bill prohibits the use of federal funds to administer COVID-19 vaccines without a patient's informed consent. The informed consent must comply with applicable requirements for the state in which the vaccine is administered, and patients must confirm their consent in writing.</summary>
</bill>
