<bill session="111" type="h" number="4846" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bleeding Disorder Screening, Awareness, and Further Education (SAFE) Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct programs to screen adolescents, and educate health professionals, with respect to bleeding disorders.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bleeding Disorder Screening, Awareness, and Further Education (SAFE) Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2010-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2010-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2010-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2010-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-08-31T20:43:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Bleeding Disorder Screening, Awareness, and Further Education (SAFE) Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to carry out the following activities: (1) development of a new, or identification of an existing, screening questionnaire that is evidence-based and in accordance with clinical guidelines for use in the diagnosis of bleeding disorders in adolescents and young adults; and (2) as widely as possible in adolescent populations, dissemination and implementation of the screening questionnaire and other screening tools relevant to the diagnosis of bleeding disorders, ensuring referrals as specified. Directs the Secretary to give priority to grant or contract applicants proposing to provide screening to high school or higher education students.

Requires the Secretary to conduct an education campaign to increase awareness about bleeding disorders among health professionals.

Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award grants or contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to: (1) augment existing research efforts to evaluate, improve, and standardize methods for diagnosing bleeding disorders; and (2) expand ongoing efforts to determine the prevalence of bleeding disorders in the general population, identify symptoms, risk factors, and co-morbidities associated with bleeding disorders, and implement female-specific surveillance systems and conduct related research to improve bleeding symptoms and quality of life among adolescent and adult women with bleeding disorders.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on the results of activities under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
