<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="162" updated="2024-03-18T20:27:56Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-03-30T11:18:08-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000175"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 31 printed in Part B of House Report 118-30 to provide that any entity subject to the jurisdiction of the Government of the Peoples Republic of China, or any entity that is owned by the Government of the Peoples Republic of China may not acquire any interest with respect to lands leased for oil or gas under the Mineral Leasing Act, the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, and may not acquire claims subject to the General Mining Law of 1872.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment provides that any entity subject to the jurisdiction of the Government of the People's Republic of China, or any entity that is owned by the Government of the People's Republic of China may not acquire any interest with respect to lands leased for oil or gas under the Mineral Leasing Act, the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, and may not acquire claims subject to the General Mining Law of 1872.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-03-30T11:18:08-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="177">
      <text>On agreeing to the Ogles amendment (A031) Agreed to by recorded vote: 405 - 24 (Roll no. 177).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1674-1675" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T09:22:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A031) offered by Mr. Ogles.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1663-1664" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1663-1664" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T09:22:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A031) offered by Mr. Ogles.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1663-1664" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1663-1664" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T11:18:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Ogles amendment (A031) Agreed to by recorded vote: 405 - 24 (Roll no. 177).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1674-1675" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T11:18:08-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30T11:18:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
