<bill session="110" type="s" number="2945" updated="2020-02-10T17:01:59Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Pay Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Pay Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, to clarify that a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice occurs on the date on which the aggrieved person knew or should have known that the person was affected by the decision or practice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination against the disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-07-21T16:29:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair Pay Act of 2008 - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to declare that an unlawful employment practice occurs when the aggrieved person knew or should have known that the person was affected by the discriminatory compensation decision or other practice involved. Applies that amendment to claims of compensation discrimination under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.

Amends the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 to declare that an unlawful practice occurs when the aggrieved person knew or should have known that the person was affected by the discriminatory compensation decision or other practice involved.</summary>
</bill>
