<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>103</number>
    <updateDate>2019-04-11T15:40:39Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-04-11T15:40:39Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-01-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssra00</systemCode>
        <name>Rules and Administration Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-01-06T20:46:53Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssra00</systemCode>
            <name>Rules and Administration Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>V000127</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Vitter, David [R-LA]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <lastName>Vitter</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Aviation and airports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional officers and employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elections, voting, political campaign regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Members of Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation costs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-01-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-03-09T19:22:50Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Amends Rule XXXV (Gifts) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require a Member, officer, or employee of the Senate to: (1) disclose a flight taken in connection with official duties on an aircraft that is not licensed by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to operate for compensation or hire (unless it is owned, operated, or leased by a governmental entity); (2) reimburse the aircraft's owner or lessee for the pro rata share of the flight's fair market value; and (3) report to the Secretary of the Senate specified information about the trip, including its purpose and the persons on it (other than the pilot).</p> <p>Declares that the fair market value of noncommercial air travel is the fair market value of the normal and usual charter fare or rental charge for a comparable plane of appropriate size.</p> <p>Amends Rule XXXVIII (Prohibition of Unofficial Office Accounts) to prescribe the value for reimbursement purposes of the use of an aircraft that is not licensed by the FAA to operate for compensation or hire.</p> <p>Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to require a principal campaign committee disclosure report of such a flight by a federal office candidate (other than one for President or Vice President).</p> <p>Excludes from the FECA definition of &quot;contribution&quot; any travel expense for such a flight if within seven days the candidate (or the candidate's authorize committee) pays the owner, lessee, or other individual providing the airplane the pro rata share of the flight's fair market value.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>A bill to require disclosure and payment of noncommercial air travel in the Senate.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require disclosure and payment of noncommercial air travel in the Senate.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require disclosure and payment of noncommercial air travel in the Senate.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-01-06T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s103is/xml/BILLS-111s103is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-01-06</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
