<bill session="116" type="h" number="5928" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:41Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIRST RESPONDER Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the requirement to reallocate and auction the T-Band spectrum, to amend the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 to clarify acceptable 9-1-1 obligations or expenditures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fee Integrity and Responsibilities and To Regain Essential Spectrum for Public-safety Operators Needed to Deploy Equipment Reliably Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRST RESPONDER Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000791"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2165" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="451" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-17T18:49:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Fee Integrity and Responsibilities and To Regain Essential Spectrum for Public-safety Operators Needed to Deploy Equipment Reliably Act of 2020 or the FIRST RESPONDER Act of 2020

This bill repeals a provision requiring the reallocation of spectrum currently used by public safety entities and otherwise addresses 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 fees and charges collected for the purpose of supporting 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 services.

Specifically, the bill repeals the requirement for the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to reallocate and auction the 470-512 MHz band (referred to as the T-Band spectrum). The T-Band spectrum is a frequency range currently utilized by public safety entities in certain urban areas.

The bill also requires the FCC to issue rules designating acceptable purposes and functions for the obligation or expenditure of 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 fees or charges. Such purposes and functions shall be limited to the support and implementation of 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 services and the operational expenses of public safety answering points (i.e., the points where emergency calls are routed).

In addition, the bill establishes the Ending 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Fee Diversion Now Strike Force, to which the FCC must submit any evidence it obtains that a state or taxing jurisdiction is diverting 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 fees or charges. The strike force must (1) study how the federal government can end such diversion through a determination of the effectiveness of laws and other constraints, and (2) consider whether criminal penalties should be implemented to prevent further diversion.</summary>
</bill>
