<bill session="108" type="h" number="5405" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oil Price Safeguard Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide the Secretary of Energy with authority to draw down the Strategic Petroleum Reserve when oil and gas prices in the United States rise sharply because of anticompetitive activity, and to require the President, through the Secretary of Energy, to consult with Congress regarding the sale of oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oil Price Safeguard Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000557"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 E2110-2111"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy shortages"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-03T20:32:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Oil Price Safeguard Act - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to declare that a severe energy supply interruption, warranting a drawdown from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), shall be deemed to exist if the President determines that: (1) there is a significant reduction in the supply of petroleum of significant scope and duration that has caused a significant increase in the price of petroleum products; (2) the price increase is likely to cause a significant adverse impact on the national economy; and (3) a substantial cause of the reduction in supply is the anticompetitive conduct of foreign countries or international entities.

Requires the President to report to certain congressional committees if the price of a barrel of crude oil exceeds $35 for a period greater than 14 days.</summary>
</bill>
