<bill session="116" type="s" number="4973" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to authorize the provision of compensation to personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency who incur disabilities resulting from certain injuries to the brain, to authorize the provision of compensation to personnel of the Department of State who incur similar disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to authorize the provision of compensation to personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency who incur disabilities resulting from certain injuries to the brain, to authorize the provision of compensation to personnel of the Department of State who incur similar disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2020-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-19T16:39:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides statutory authority for the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) and the Department of State to compensate employees and certain family members for qualifying brain injuries sustained while stationed in a foreign country.

Under the bill, the CIA and the State Department may provide compensation for a covered individual who has a partial or total disability resulting from a qualifying brain injury for which the individual is not receiving disability payments from the United States.

Existing requirements and limitations related to compensation for injuries sustained by CIA and State Department employees shall apply to compensation provided under the bill.

The bill shall apply to qualifying injuries sustained before or after the bill's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
