<bill session="119" type="s" number="37" updated="2025-09-17T19:53:00Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VALOR Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VALOR Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Venezuela Advancing Liberty, Opportunity, and Rights Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote democracy in Venezuela, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2025-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2025-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-15T18:34:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Venezuela Advancing Liberty, Opportunity, and Rights Act of 2025 or the VALOR Act of 2025

This bill requires or authorizes various actions, including sanctions, targeting the current government of Venezuela and any nondemocratic successor government. The bill also authorizes certain types of assistance for the people of Venezuela and to support democracy-building efforts.

Under the bill, the President

must impose property-blocking sanctions on the Venezuelan government and persons supporting the Venezuelan government;may deny U.S.&#160;nonhumanitarian&#160;foreign assistance, arms-related assistance, and debt forgiveness to any country that provides assistance to the Venezuelan government;may provide support to individuals and independent nongovernmental organizations to support democracy-building efforts in Venezuela;must develop a plan to provide assistance to Venezuela under a democratically elected government, which may include food, medicine, and emergency energy assistance to meet the basic needs of Venezuelans;must take steps to terminate sanctions under this bill once the President determines that a democratically elected government is in power (criteria for such a determination include a Venezuelan government that is the result of free and fair elections, is making progress in establishing an independent judiciary and respecting human rights, and has released all political prisoners).The Department of the Treasury must oppose the seating of Venezuelan representatives at certain international financial institutions such as the International Monetary Fund.

Additionally, the bill prohibits U.S. persons (individuals or entities) from engaging in transactions involving Venezuela's debt or any digital currency issued by Venezuela.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
