<bill session="117" type="h" number="4836" updated="2022-12-31T05:04:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to require the safe storage of firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Firearm Owners Responsibility and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Firearm Owners Responsibility and Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2022-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2814" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1338" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-18T14:47:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Firearm Owners Responsibility and Safety Act

This bill establishes a framework to regulate the storage of firearms at the federal, state, and tribal levels. The bill also removes limitations on the civil liability of gun manufacturers and the disclosure of gun trace data in civil actions.

Among its provisions, the bill

 generally requires firearms to be kept, left, or stored in a secure gun storage or safety device; requires the Department of Justice to award grants to states and tribes to implement firearms safe storage requirements that are functionally identical to the requirements established by this bill; repeals the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act, which prohibits civil actions against a firearm or ammunition manufacturer, seller, importer, dealer, or trade association for damages resulting from the criminal or unlawful misuse of a firearm; and allows firearms trace data maintained by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to be discoverable, admissible as evidence, and used, relied on, or disclosed in a civil action or administrative proceeding.</summary>
</bill>
