<bill session="108" type="h" number="1009" updated="2023-01-15T21:49:02Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clear Your Good Name Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Federal law enforcement agencies to expunge voidable arrest records, to provide incentive funds to States that have in effect a system for expunging such records, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clear Your Good Name Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2003-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Court records"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Police records"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Clear Your Good Name Act - Requires that a reference in any Federal law enforcement agency record to an arrest of a person living after the effective date of this Act, and any Federal law enforcement record (such as fingerprint records or photographs) generated pursuant to that arrest, be expunged: (1) within 30 days after the date on which that arrest becomes a "voidable arrest" (i.e., an arrest resulting in the release of the person without the filing of formal charges, dismissal of proceedings against the person, or a determination that the arrest was without probable cause); and (2) to the extent provided in a Federal expungement order, if the arrest occurred before this Act's effective date. Permits individuals to petition for a Federal expungement order.Makes it a class B misdemeanor to release or to knowingly fail to expunge a reference or record required to be expunged by this Act. Allows the person arrested to respond to any inquiry as though the voidable arrest did not occur.Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to increase the percentage of funding under the drug control and system improvement (Byrne) grant program if a State has in effect a law which provides substantially similar expungement procedures, criminal penalties, and individual rights regarding voidable arrests.</summary>
</bill>
