<bill session="117" type="h" number="938" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildland Firefighter Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to create a classification that more accurately reflects the vital role of wildland firefighters.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildland Firefighter Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2021-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1221" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-12T19:01:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildland Firefighter Recognition Act

This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management to develop a distinct wildland firefighter occupational series. The series must apply to the following positions

 forestry technician; range technician; other positions related to significant prevention, preparedness, control, suppression, or management activities for wildland firefighters; and other positions conducting activities necessary to meet any other emergency incident. The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture must use the series in the advertising and hiring of a wildland firefighter.

The bill requires an employee in a wildland firefighter occupational series to receive a pay differential based on the unusual physical hardship or hazardous nature of the position.

An individual employed as a wildland firefighter on the date on which the occupational series takes effect may (1) remain in the occupational series in which the individual is working, or (2) be included in the wildland firefighter occupational series.</summary>
</bill>
