<bill session="108" type="h" number="4791" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:15Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a feasibility study to design and construct a three-reservoir intertie system for the purposes of improving the water supply reliability and water yield of San Vicente, El Capitan, and Loveland Reservoirs in San Diego County, California in consultation and cooperation with the Sweetwater Authority, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000981"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1347-1348"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-10T18:47:19Z" status="Introduced in House">San Diego Water Storage and Efficiency Act of 2004 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the Sweetwater Authority public water agency in San Diego, to undertake an appraisal investigation of opportunities for construction of a three-reservoir intertie system to improve water supply reliability and water yield of the existing non-Federal water storage system. Directs that: (1) the appraisal report include a determination of whether to recommend the initiation of a feasibility study for the proposed intertie system; and (2) Federal obligations for costs of the investigation conform with reclamation policy.

Authorizes the Secretary to determine the feasibility of the reservoir and intertie system recommended. Directs that the feasibility report: (1) document the Secretary's engineering, environmental, and economic investigation of the proposed reservoir and intertie project, taking into consideration the range of potential solutions and the circumstances and needs of the area to be served, the potential benefits to the people of that area, and improved operations of the proposed reservoir and intertie system; and (2) indicate whether the proposed project is recommended for implementation.

Limits the Federal cost share to 50 percent. Directs the Secretary to submit a feasibility report and to seek appropriate construction and development authority for any recommended project.</summary>
</bill>
