<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2976</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:22:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:22:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-09-20</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. ROTHMAN of New Jersey:H.R. 2976.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 1: The Congress shall havePower to lay and collect Taxes, Duties, Imposts and Excises,to pay the Debts and provide for the common Defense andgeneral Welfare of the United States; but all Duties, Impostsand Excises shall be uniform throughout the United States.Article I, Section 8, Clause 18: The Congress shall havePower to make all Laws which shall be necessary and properfor carrying into Execution the forgoing Powers, and allother Powers vested by this Constitution in the Government ofthe United States or in any Department or Officer thereof.[Page H6272]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif16</systemCode>
            <name>Communications and Technology Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2011-09-26T13:56:55Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-09-20T16:01:05Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-09-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif16</systemCode>
            <name>Communications and Technology Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-09-20</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-09-20</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-09-20</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000462</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rothman, Steven R. [D-NJ-9]</fullName>
        <firstName>STEVEN</firstName>
        <lastName>ROTHMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <district>9</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000210</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. King, Peter T. [R-NY-3]</fullName>
        <firstName>PETER</firstName>
        <lastName>KING</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>T.</middleName>
        <district>3</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-09-20</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency communications systems</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal Communications Commission (FCC)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government trust funds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-09-20</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-11-10T17:28:59Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Help Emergency Responders Operate Emergency Systems Act of 2011 or the HEROES Act of 2011 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to increase the electromagnetic spectrum allocation for public safety services by 10 megahertz within a specified range and reduce such allocation for commercial use by the same amount. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to license certain paired bands to the public safety broadband licensee (PSBL).</p> <p>Directs the FCC to establish rules to: (1) permit the PSBL to authorize public safety services providers to construct and operate a wireless public safety broadband network in the PSBL's spectrum, and (2) authorize the shared use of public safety broadband spectrum and network infrastructure by non-public safety services and the use of public safety broadband spectrum by emergency response providers.</p> <p>Requires: (1) the FCC to develop a public safety agency statement of requirements enabling nationwide interoperability and roaming across communications systems, and (2) the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish standards for meeting such requirements.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a grant program (a maximum 80% federal share of the costs for each project) to assist public safety entities in constructing a nationwide interoperable broadband network in the 700 megahertz band; (2) administer a program to reimburse up to 50% of network maintenance, operation, and improvement expenses; and (3) establish a narrowbanding compliance assistance program.</p> <p>Requires: (1) the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to reallocate for commercial use spectrum from a specified range, and (2) the FCC to establish rules for pairing spectrum within specified ranges and to auction licenses for such paired spectrum.</p> <p>Extends to September 30, 2020, the FCC's authority to grant a license or permit under applicable competitive bidding provisions.</p> <p>Prohibits a bidder from being deemed ineligible for or excluded from an auction on account of its size or the amount of its other spectrum holdings.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Help Emergency Responders Operate Emergency Systems Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Help Emergency Responders Operate Emergency Systems Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To enhance public safety by making more spectrum available to public safety agencies, to facilitate the development of a wireless public safety broadband network, to provide standards for the spectrum needs of public safety agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Help Emergency Responders Operate Emergency Systems Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>HEROES Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2011-09-20T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr2976ih/xml/BILLS-112hr2976ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-09-26</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
