<bill session="118" type="h" number="3233" updated="2025-11-19T04:23:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Diversify Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Diversify Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Diversifying by Investing in Educators and Students to Improve Outcomes For Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To remove college cost as a barrier to every student having access to a well-prepared and diverse educator workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000148" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001224" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001131" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2024-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2023-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001159" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1581" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-06T14:37:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Diversifying by Investing in Educators and Students to Improve Outcomes For Youth Act or the Diversify Act

This bill revises the Teacher Education Assistance for College and Higher Education (TEACH) grant program. The TEACH program awards grants to undergraduate and graduate students who commit to teaching in a high-need field and in an elementary or secondary school that serves low-income students.

First, the bill raises the maximum amount for TEACH grants.

Second, the bill allows TEACH grants to cover the full cost of attendance. Currently, these grants may be used only for tuition, fees, and on-campus housing.

The bill allows teaching in a high-need early childhood education program to count toward service requirements for the program.

Next, the bill eliminates the process for converting a TEACH grant to a loan if a recipient does not complete the requirements of the program. Further, the bill prohibits the Department of Education (ED) from instituting or creating a monetary penalty for failure or refusal to complete the service requirement.

In addition, the bill requires ED to send an electronic certificate to grant recipients who have completed their service requirement.

The bill also exempts the TEACH program from sequestration, which is a process of automatic, usually across-the-board spending reductions under which budgetary resources are permanently cancelled to enforce specific budget policy goals.</summary>
</bill>
