<bill session="116" type="h" number="8375" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Worker Flexibility and Small Business Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Worker Flexibility and Small Business Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a right to flexibility and to broaden and increase employee protections at work, to protect small businesses through shared responsibility for workers' rights, to provide public transparency on workers' rights violations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, House Administration, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, House Administration, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, House Administration, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, House Administration, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4738" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-17T18:49:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Worker Flexibility and Small Business Protection Act of 2020 This bill classifies certain workers as employees, permits employees to request work schedule flexibility, expands oversight mechanisms for certain labor protections, requires employers to post compliance ratings, and provides standards for interpreting and applying certain worker rights. First, the bill provides that workers only may be classified under various labor laws as independent contractors, and not employees, in specified circumstances. It also permits employees to continue, or request, work schedule flexibility. The bill also defines the term multiple employers under various labor laws and makes parent companies responsible for the labor requirements of subsidiary employers. Certain owners, officers, and managers of companies may be assessed civil penalties for violations of certain labor laws; the 10 largest shareholders of employers also may be jointly liable for damages and civil penalties against such employers. Employers also are responsible for the labor protections of employees provided through staffing companies (e.g., temporary employees), including providing wages comparable to direct employees performing similar work. Additionally, employers must post a rating of their compliance with applicable labor laws as determined by the Department of Labor. Finally, the bill requires that specified labor laws are interpreted to include as employees workers or individuals claiming such classification. Further, agencies may not take actions to reduce employee protections under such laws without approval by Congress, and the bill provides standards of interpretation for judicial review.</summary>
</bill>
