<bill session="119" type="h" number="696" updated="2025-11-19T03:29:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Unaccountable Amnesty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Unaccountable Amnesty Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform temporary protected status, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000603" joined="2025-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001228" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2025-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="225" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1589" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4201" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-30T21:24:25Z" status="Introduced in House">End Unaccountable Amnesty Act

This bill revises, restricts, and repeals various laws and programs addressing the admissibility and deportability of certain non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law). The bill includes changes to the Temporary Protected Status (TPS) program, the treatment of unaccompanied children, and removal proceedings.

Under current law, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may grant a foreign state Temporary Protected Status (TPS), which protects qualified nationals of that foreign state from removal from the United States. The bill instead requires an act of Congress to grant TPS to a foreign state. The bill limits TPS status to 12 months, subject to extension.

The bill also generally requires the return of unaccompanied inadmissible children to their country of nationality or last habitual residence, among other changes. Under current law,&#160;DHS is authorized (not required) to return these children, and only if their country of nationality or last habitual residence is contiguous to the United States.

The bill also repeals the law allowing for the cancellation of removal or adjustment of the immigration status of qualifying&#160;non-U.S. nationals.&#160;

Under the bill, certain forms of identification, including a Notice to Appear issued by&#160;DHS, are no longer valid documents for purposes of airport security checkpoints.

The bill also limits the ability of&#160;DHS to grant parole (temporary admission granted on a case-by-case basis). For example, the bill limits the granting of parole to a list of specific situations, such as the imminent death of a close family member.</summary>
</bill>
