<bill session="118" type="s" number="5624" updated="2025-08-06T18:46:47Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Veteran Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Veteran Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish an integrated project team to improve the process for scheduling appointments for health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2024-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-06T18:46:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Veteran Access to Care Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish an integrated project team to improve the process for scheduling VA health care appointments. Among other objectives, the team must (1) develop or continue the development of a scheduling system and platform that enables personnel and patients of the VA to view available appointments for VA care, (2) create a process through which patients can telephonically speak with a scheduler who can assist in determining availability and scheduling, and (3) carry out other functions with respect to health care appointments furnished by the VA.

In carrying out its objectives, the team must consult and coordinate with the deployment schedule and capabilities of the VA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Electronic Health Record Modernization Program.

If the VA determines a required objective or any feature or service in connection with an objective cannot be implemented or incorporated, the VA must report to Congress providing an explanation and setting forth a plan without that objective.&#160;

The VA must also report to Congress on the progress in fulfilling the team&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s objectives under the bill.</summary>
</bill>
