<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="1331" updated="2022-02-25T17:33:07Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2555" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-07-23">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-07-23"/>
  <description>To require a classified report to Congress on the security costs incurred by State and local government law enforcement personnel in each state in complying with requests and requirements of the United States Secret Service to provide protective services and transportation for foreign and domestic officials.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-07-23" how="roll" result="pass" roll="292">
      <text>Amendment SA 1331 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 79 - 19. Record Vote Number: 292.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Amendment SA 1331 proposed by Senator Boxer. (consideration:  CR S9751-9753, S9755-9756; text:  CR S9751) To require a classified report to Congress on the security costs incurred by State and local government law enforcement personnel in each state in complying with requests and requirements of the United States Secret Service to provide protective services and transportation for foreign and domestic officials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1331 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 79 - 19. Record Vote Number: 292.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 1331 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 79 - 19. Record Vote Number: 292.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1331 proposed by Senator Boxer.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9751-9753, S9755-9756" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S9751" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
