<bill session="117" type="h" number="7494" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bankruptcy Threshold Adjustment and Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Threshold Adjustment and Technical Corrections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 11, United States Code, to modify the eligibility requirements for a debtor under chapter 13, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2022-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5939" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2679" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3823" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-08T21:06:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Bankruptcy Threshold Adjustment and Technical Corrections Act 

This bill modifies provisions related to small business reorganization bankruptcies and wage earner's bankruptcies.

Specifically, the bill extends for two years the increase of the amount of debt allowed to be carried by debtors to qualify for small business reorganization bankruptcy and provides that this debt limit is subject to adjustment for inflation. Additionally, it provides that a small business debtor includes a debtor that is an affiliate of certain publicly traded companies. Further, it authorizes the bankruptcy trustee to operate the business of the debtor if the debtor ceases to be a debtor in possession.

The bill also increases for two years the debt limit for individuals filing for bankruptcy under Chapter 13 (i.e., the wage earner's plan) and allows both secured and unsecured debt to count towards this single limit. (Currently, separate limits apply to secured and unsecured debt.)</summary>
</bill>
