<bill session="118" type="s" number="1790" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Failed Bank Executives Clawback Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Failed Bank Executives Clawback Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to clarify that the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and appropriate Federal regulators have the authority to claw back certain compensation paid to executives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2023-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2972" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1045" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-17T14:52:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Failed Bank Executives Clawback Act 

This bill requires the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to claw back compensation from specific responsible parties in case of a large insured depository institution's insolvency, resolution, or receivership. This clawback requirement applies to an entity (including a director, shareholder, or other person who participates in the conduct of the institution's affairs) that caused more than a minimal financial loss to, or a significant adverse effect on, the insured depository institution. The compensation subject to the clawback requirement includes salary, bonuses, awards, and any profits realized from the buying or selling of securities during the preceding three years.

The bill also expands the authority of the FDIC to claw back compensation of parties responsible for financial losses incurred by a financial company regardless of the process by which it is appointed receiver.</summary>
</bill>
