<bill session="108" type="hc" number="244" updated="2023-01-15T17:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the Government of Saudi Arabia's lack of protection of internationally recognized human rights and the absence of religious freedom in Saudi Arabia.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the Government of Saudi Arabia's lack of protection of internationally recognized human rights and the absence of religious freedom in Saudi Arabia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000409"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2003-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Islamic fundamentalism"/>
    <term name="Judicial reform"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Muslims"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-29T22:05:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Calls on the Government Saudi Arabia to: (1) uphold its international commitments by respecting and protecting the human rights of citizens and foreigners of both sexes in Saudi Arabia; (2) ratify and comply fully with international human rights instruments and cooperate with United Nations human rights mechanisms, and to sign, ratify, and implement the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights; (3) implement immediately promised judicial, political, economic, and educational reforms; (4) permit the establishment of independent nongovernmental organizations to advance human rights and promote tolerance, and to take action to create an independent human rights commission for the same purposes; (5) safeguard the freedom of non-Muslims, and of those Muslims who do not follow the Wahhabi interpretation of Islam, to worship in private; (6) permit non-Wahhabi places of worship, such as churches, to function openly in special compounds or zones for foreigners or in unadorned buildings designated for this purpose; and (7) permit the broadcasting of Radio Sawa throughout the country.

Urges the U.S. Government to: (1) to raise concerns at the highest levels, in both public and private fora, with the Government of Saudi Arabia regarding its ongoing and repeated human rights violations; (2) designate Saudi Arabia a "country of particular concern" under the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 for its systematic and ongoing violations of religious freedom; (3) encourage the Government of Saudi Arabia to implement expeditiously its publicly stated plans for judicial, political, economic, and educational reform; (4) develop and expand specific initiatives and programs in Saudi Arabia to advance human rights, including religious freedom, the rights of women, and the rule of law; and (4) report publicly to Congress on its efforts to raise concerns regarding human rights, including religious freedom, with the Government of Saudi Arabia, including the results of those efforts.</summary>
</bill>
