<bill session="108" type="s" number="2279" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:33Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 46, United States Code, with respect to maritime transportation security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="popular">Port Security bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000725"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2004-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3583-3585"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3585-3588" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-274.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="530">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 530.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8625"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9460-9468" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S9460-9467" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9467-9468" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T10:05:11-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Passenger ships"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Port authorities"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3669"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-12-27T20:53:18Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Amends Federal shipping law to grant U.S. district courts jurisdiction to restrain violations of certain port security requirements. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to refuse or revoke port clearance to any owner, agent, master, officer, or person in charge of a vessel that is liable for a penalty or fine for violation of such requirements. Allows any refused or revoked clearance to be granted upon filing of a bond or other surety satisfactory to the Secretary.

Directs the Secretary to require uncleared, unladen imported merchandise remaining on a wharf or pier for more than seven calendar days (not including any time held in Federal custody) to be removed and deposited in a public store or general order warehouse for inspection, after which a delivery permit may be granted. Authorizes the Secretary to impose an administrative penalty of $5,000 on the consignee for each bill of lading for general order merchandise remaining on a wharf or pier in violation of such requirement (except if the violation was a result of force majeure).

(Sec. 3) Shifts from the Secretary to the Administrator of the Maritime Administration responsibility for assessing antiterrorism measures in foreign ports and notifying foreign government authorities of deficiencies and the steps necessary to improve such measures.

Requires the Administrator to identify foreign assistance programs that could facilitate implementation of port security antiterrorism measures in foreign countries. Directs the Administrator and the Secretary to establish a program to utilize those programs that are capable of implementing port security antiterrorism measures at ports in foreign countries that the Secretary finds to lack effective antiterrorism measures.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS Secretary) to report to specified congressional committees on the security of ports in the Caribbean Basin.

(Sec. 4) Amends the Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary to: (1) establish a curriculum to educate and instruct Federal and State officials on commercial maritime and intermodal transportation; and (2) coordinate with the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center in the curriculum development and the provision of training opportunities for Federal and State law enforcement officials at appropriate law enforcement training facilities.

(Sec. 5) Directs the DHS Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) recommendations to coordinate background checks for all individuals engaged in transportation activities; and (2) a timeline for implementation of the Transportation Worker Identification Credential in seaports.

(Sec. 6) Directs the DHS Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on the security of ships and facilities used in the cruise line industry, including an assessment of certain security measures employed by the industry.

(Sec. 7) Amends Federal shipping law to direct the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Border and Transportation Security to establish a maritime transportation security plan grant program to implement Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans and help fund compliance with Federal security plans among port authorities, facility operators, and State and local agencies required to provide security devices.

(Sec. 8) Directs the DHS Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on the design of maritime security grant programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-274</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
