<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>953</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:18:58Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:18:58Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-05-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-05-01T16:50:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-05-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-05-01</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5019-5020)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-05-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000206</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Harkin, Tom [D-IA]</fullName>
        <firstName>THOMAS</firstName>
        <lastName>HARKIN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IA</state>
        <middleName>RICHARD</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health facilities and institutions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health promotion and preventive care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infectious and parasitic diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-05-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-07-23T22:13:13Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Seasonal Influenza and Pandemic Preparation Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a national voluntary influenza vaccination program for adults and children under which any individual may receive an influenza vaccine at no cost at any federally qualified health center, public or private hospital, physician office, clinic, or other entity determined appropriate by the Secretary. Sets forth provisions governing reimbursements for the costs of administering such vaccines. Declares that participation by an entity in such program is voluntary.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to award grants to state and local health departments, public hospitals, and other entities to facilitate the establishment of influenza vaccination programs in partnerships with private entities, including pharmacies and private employers. Requires vaccines provided under a grant to be at no cost to the individual. Authorizes an entity participating in the grant program to seek reimbursement from the Secretary.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to award grants to facilitate the development of influenza vaccination programs for students and families of students in partnership with local primary and secondary educational institutions.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, under Medicare, Medicaid, and the State Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP, formerly known as SCHIP), to develop an immunization plan with immunization target numbers for the respective populations served under such programs. Requires the Secretary to provide bonus payments to eligible health care providers and other entities who meet immunization targets established by the Secretary in such plans.</p> <p>Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish and implement a national public affairs campaign to increase influenza immunization rates.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Seasonal Influenza and Pandemic Preparation Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Seasonal Influenza and Pandemic Preparation Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the establishment of programs and activities to increase influenza vaccination rates through the provision of free vaccines.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Seasonal Influenza and Pandemic Preparation Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-05-01T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s953is/xml/BILLS-111s953is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-05-01</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
