<bill session="117" type="h" number="3375" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Sanctuary for Criminals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to modify provisions relating to assistance by States, and political subdivisions of States, in the enforcement of Federal immigration laws, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Sanctuary for Criminals Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001054" joined="2021-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2021-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-21T22:34:54Z" status="Introduced in House">No Sanctuary for Criminals Act

This bill addresses issues related to immigration enforcement.

A government entity may not prohibit its personnel or another government entity from cooperating with federal immigration enforcement efforts or making inquiries about an individual's immigration status. Currently, a government entity is only barred from prohibiting the sharing of immigration-related information with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

A noncomplying state or local government shall be ineligible for certain grants and assistance related to law enforcement, terrorism, and immigration.

DHS may (1) decline to transfer a detained alien to a noncomplying government entity even if that entity has issued a writ or warrant, and (2) issue a detainer if it believes that an individual arrested for any criminal or motor vehicle offense is inadmissible or deportable. DHS may not transfer an alien with a final order of removal to a noncomplying government entity.

The bill also allows a victim of certain felonies (including murder and rape) to sue a state or local government entity if that entity had refused to honor an immigration detainer request and released the individual who later committed the crime.

Furthermore, the bill (1) expands the categories of offenses requiring mandatory detention, (2) provides immunity for a state or local government entity or official temporarily detaining an alien under federal authority, (3) provides that an alien may be detained without time limitation while removal proceedings are pending, and (4) restricts a detained alien's release on bond.</summary>
</bill>
