<bill session="118" type="h" number="2942" updated="2025-11-19T03:56:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Conservation Reserve Program Amendments Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conservation Reserve Program Amendments Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to provide for the enrollment of citrus land in the conservation reserve program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001216" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2023-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1365" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-12T20:30:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Conservation Reserve Program Amendments Act of 2023

This bill amends the Conservation Reserve Program (CRP) of the Farm Service Agency to provide for the enrollment of citrus land in the program. CRP is a land conservation program that provides an annual rental payment to farmers in exchange for removing environmentally sensitive land from agricultural production and planting species that will improve environmental health and quality.

Specifically, the bill allows the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to include cropland in the program that is otherwise ineligible if the land has been used to plant a citrus crop during the 10-year period preceding the date of the bill's enactment. USDA must enroll citrus land using existing continuous enrollment procedures.

USDA may give priority to citrus land that is at risk of conversion or development, is of ecological significance, or is affected by huanglongbing (i.e., citrus greening, a bacterial disease spread by an insect that is known as the Asian citrus psyllida and feeds on citrus). The total acreage of citrus land enrolled in the conservation reserve must not exceed 100,000 acres for each of FY2024-FY2028.

Further, the bill excludes citrus land from existing adjusted gross income limitations for payments or benefits under CRP.</summary>
</bill>
