<bill session="117" type="h" number="3664" updated="2022-12-30T21:29:29Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 35, United States Code, to provide for an exception from infringement for certain component parts of motor vehicles.</title>
    <title type="display">SMART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Money on Auto Repair Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2021-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-11T17:16:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Save Money on Auto Repair Transportation Act or the SMART Act

This bill limits design patent infringement liability for component parts used to repair the exterior of a motor vehicle.

Specifically, the bill limits liability for infringement of a design patent that claims the appearance of a component part of a motor vehicle's exterior, such as a hood or fender.

The act of making, offering to sell within the United States, or importing into the United States an article of manufacture (such as an exterior component part from an aftermarket manufacturer) that would otherwise infringe such a design patent shall not constitute infringement if the purpose of the article of manufacture is to repair and restore a motor vehicle to its original appearance.

In addition, 30 months after a motor vehicle with an exterior component part covered by a design patent is offered for sale in any country, it shall not constitute design patent infringement to use or sell within the United States an otherwise-infringing article of manufacture if the purpose of that article of manufacture is to repair and restore the motor vehicle to its original appearance.</summary>
</bill>
