<bill session="116" type="h" number="2944" updated="2022-11-01T06:02:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TALENT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish a public-private exchange program for the acquisition workforce.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TALENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Training Acquisition Leaders and Elevating New Talent Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001123"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-12-05T21:28:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Training Acquisition Leaders and Elevating New Talent Act of 2019 or the TALENT Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish a program to temporarily assign a member of the acquisition workforce to a private-sector organization or an employee of such an organization to DOD. Such an arrangement would require the consent of the individual who is assigned, extend for a period no more than two years, and be renewable to a total of four years.

 A member of the acquisition workforce who is assigned to a private-sector organization shall be considered to be on detail to a regular assignment in DOD. The agreement will address specific terms related to continued status as a federal employee, as well as&#8212;for nine-month or longer assignments&#8212;eligibility for placement in a new position allowing priority placement.

DOD shall consider how assignments under this bill might best be used to help meet its needs concerning training of the acquisition workforce.</summary>
</bill>
