<bill session="117" type="s" number="2105" updated="2022-12-31T05:27:07Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance mental health and psychological support within United States foreign assistance programs.</title>
    <title type="display">MINDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health in International Development and Humanitarian Settings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MINDS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3988" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-22T18:07:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mental Health in International Development and Humanitarian Settings Act or the MINDS Act

This bill directs the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and the Department of State to integrate mental health and psychosocial support activities across all U.S. foreign assistance programs, with a particular focus on children and other vulnerable populations.

To facilitate this integration, the bill makes organizational changes at the USAID. It authorizes the USAID to appoint a coordinator to oversee and direct mental health and psychosocial support activities. The coordinator must ensure that these activities focus on children, adult caretakers and families, displaced populations, and other vulnerable groups. In addition, the bill establishes a working group comprised of representatives from every USAID bureau and the State Department to coordinate interagency efforts related to, promote best practices for, and ensure sustainability and continuity of mental health and psychosocial support activities.

The USAID and the State Department must brief Congress about the amount of foreign assistance spending on mental health and psychosocial support activities and related matters.</summary>
</bill>
