<bill session="117" type="h" number="5729" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GIFTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GIFTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Integrity is Not for Trade or Sale Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct any entity of the Federal Government accepting a gift or donation to include certain conditions in the contract or agreement to accept such gift or donation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000754"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2022-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2021-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-08T21:47:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Government Integrity is Not for Trade or Sale Act of 2021 or the GIFTS Act of 2021

This bill directs any federal entity accepting a gift or donation in exchange for naming rights to include certain conditions in the contract or agreement to accept such gift or donation.

The entity may revoke any rights to name, designate, or redesignate the subject of any gift or donation contained in the contract without incurring liability or creating an obligation to return the gift or donation if a certain period of time has elapsed and in the reasonable view of such entity

 a criminal act or an ethical violation has been committed; and because of the act, the revocation of such rights is necessary to protect the reputation or integrity of the federal government.</summary>
</bill>
