<bill session="118" type="s" number="926" updated="2025-11-19T03:07:29Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Agricultural Land from Foreign Harm Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Agricultural Land from Foreign Harm Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the purchase or lease of agricultural land in the United States by persons associated with certain foreign governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2024-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3357" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Grain"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-09T19:26:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting America's Agricultural Land from Foreign Harm Act of 2023

This bill prohibits persons associated with the governments of Iran, North Korea, China, or Russia from purchasing or leasing agricultural land in the United States.

Specifically, the President must prohibit any person (individual or entity) owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of these foreign governments from purchasing or leasing (1) public agricultural land that is owned by the United States and administered by a federal department or agency, or (2) private agricultural land that is located in the United States.

A person that violates or attempts to violate this prohibition is subject to civil and criminal penalties. This prohibition does not require a person that owns or leases agricultural land as of the date of this bill's enactment to sell that land.

Further, the President must prohibit a person associated with these foreign governments and who leases, or who has full or partial ownership of, agricultural land in the United States from participating in Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs. Exceptions are included to allow for participation in USDA programs related to food safety, the health and labor safety of individuals, or certain reporting and disclosure requirements.

The restrictions established by the bill do not apply to U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents.

The bill also amends the agriculture foreign investment disclosure reporting requirements to include reporting on security interests and leases.

Finally, USDA must submit a report every two years on foreign ownership of agriculture land in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
