<bill session="112" type="h" number="3726" updated="2019-11-15T21:12:42Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Area Security Initiative Modernization Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to improve efficiency and guarantee accountability in the Urban Area Security Initiative grant program.</title>
    <title type="display">Urban Area Security Initiative Modernization Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-19T20:28:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Urban Area Security Initiative Modernization Act of 2011 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to modify the Urban Area Security Initiative (UASI) to include within the initial assessment of the relative threat, vulnerability, and consequences from acts of terrorism faced by each eligible metropolitan area, consideration of each area's past performance, and each area's potential, to contribute to a reduction or mitigation of the relative threat, vulnerability, and consequences from acts of terrorism faced either within such area or nationally.

Directs the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to consider such past performance in allocating homeland security grant funds among states and high-risk urban areas.</summary>
</bill>
