<bill session="117" type="h" number="2887" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Climate Change Diplomacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for certain Department of State actions relating to global climate change, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Climate Change Diplomacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2022-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2021-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2022-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001159" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2021-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Energy, the Environment and Cyber.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA14" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3524" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-01T19:40:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Global Climate Change Diplomacy Act

This bill requires the Department of State to take specified actions to address global climate change.

Specifically, the State Department must establish and staff Climate Change Officer positions, the holders of which shall be assigned to U.S. embassies, consulates, or diplomatic missions. Each officer shall provide climate change mitigation expertise, engage with international entities concerned with addressing climate change, and facilitate U.S. engagement in bilateral and multilateral cooperation on climate change.

Each chief of mission in a foreign country must take certain climate change-related actions, including (1) developing a strategy to improve and increase studying, mitigating, and adapting to climate change; and (2) certifying that considerations related to climate change are incorporated in activities, management, and operations of the U.S. embassy or other diplomatic post under the director of the chief of mission.

The State Department must also establish a curriculum at its Foreign Service Institute to provide employees with specialized climate change training, and it must ensure that embassy personnel responsible for contracts, grants, or acquisitions are trained on evaluating such agreements for considerations related to sustainability and climate change.</summary>
</bill>
