<bill session="116" type="h" number="7462" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pedestrian and Bicyclist Safety Improvement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for nationwide, on-the-ground road safety assessments focused on pedestrian and bicycle safety.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pedestrian and Bicyclist Safety Improvement Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-07T12:47:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Pedestrian and Bicyclist Safety Improvement Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT), every two years, to conduct nationwide on-the-ground road safety assessments focused on pedestrian and bicycle safety in each state.

The purpose of the assessments is to

 identify and examine specific locations with documented or perceived problems with pedestrian and bicycle safety and access, examine barriers to providing safe pedestrian and bicycle access to transportation infrastructure, and develop and issue recommendations designed to effectively address specific safety and access issues and enhance pedestrian and bicycle safety in high-risk areas. DOT must maintain a national pedestrian and bicycle safety database that includes (1) a list of high-risk intersections, roads, and highways with a documented history of pedestrian or bicycle accidents or fatalities and details regarding those incidents; and (2) information on corrective measures that have been implemented at the state, local, or federal level to enhance pedestrian and bicyclist safety at those high-risk areas, including details on the nature and date of corrective action.</summary>
</bill>
