<bill session="116" type="h" number="846" updated="2022-11-01T15:02:55Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Serving Veterans Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Serving Veterans Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the VA Choice and Quality Employment Act to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a vacancy and recruitment database to facilitate the recruitment of certain members of the Armed Forces to satisfy the occupational needs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to establish and implement a training and certification program for intermediate care technicians in that Department, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001123" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001122" joined="2019-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2019-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2020-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2019-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2019-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2019-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2020-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001210" joined="2019-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2019-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2019-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-28T14:26:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Serving Veterans Act of 2019

This bill updates the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) current recruiting database by requiring the VA to maintain a single searchable database to be known as the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs Recruitment Database.

With respect to vacant positions for critical jobs or mental health professionals, the database must list (1) the military occupational specialty or skill that corresponds to the position, and (2) each qualified member of the Armed Forces who may be recruited to fill the position before such qualified member has been discharged and released from active duty. Qualified members of the Armed Forces are those service members who (1) are being separated or recently separated from active duty, (2) elect to be listed in the database, and (3) have been determined by the VA to have a military occupational specialty.

The database must list the following for each qualified member of the Armed Forces: name, contact information, expected discharge date, and military occupational specialty.

The VA must implement direct hiring and appointment procedures for vacant database positions and may authorize relocation bonuses.

The bill also requires the VA to train and certify veterans who served as basic health care technicians in the Armed Forces to work as VA intermediate care technicians.</summary>
</bill>
