<bill session="118" type="s" number="1072" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PREP for All Students Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREP for All Students Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Responsible Emergency Protocols for All Students Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a Council on Emergency Response Protocols to ensure the establishment of accessible, developmentally appropriate, culturally aware, and trauma-informed emergency response protocols in public schools, early child care and education settings, and institutions of higher education, and for other purposes</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-14T14:29:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Responsible Emergency Protocols for All Students Act or the PREP for All Students Act

This bill establishes the Council on Emergency Response Protocols. The council must, among other duties, provide guidelines for states, early child care and education settings, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education to use in developing and implementing emergency response protocols (e.g., gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, and fire drills) that are inclusive and accessible.</summary>
</bill>
