<bill session="119" type="s" number="536" updated="2025-11-19T03:43:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair SHARE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair SHARE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Sharing of Highways and Roads for Electric Vehicles Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a tax on the sale of electric vehicles and batteries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1253" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-24T18:51:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair Sharing of Highways and Roads for Electric Vehicles&#160;Act of 2025

This bill imposes a new excise tax in the amount of $1,000 on the sale of an electric vehicle and a new excise tax in the amount of $550 on the sale of a battery module weighing over 1,000 pounds for use in an electric vehicle. The bill also requires the Department of the Treasury to transfer amounts collected from the new excise taxes to the Highway Trust Fund. (The Highway Trust Fund, which supports surface transportation programs and projects, is funded by transportation-related&#160;excise&#160;taxes.)

The bill defines electric vehicle as a light-duty vehicle (a motor vehicle weighing less than 8,500 pounds that is manufactured for use on public roads) that is powered by a battery with a capacity of at least seven kilowatt hours and is recharged through an external source of electricity. Under the bill, the excise tax&#160;does not apply to hybrid vehicles, which are powered by a combination of fuel and a rechargeable energy storage system.

The bill defines battery module as a module with&#160;two or more battery cells configured to create voltage or current (or no battery cells) and with an aggregate capacity of at least seven kilowatt hours (or one kilowatt hour for a hydrogen fuel cell vehicle).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
