<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="267" updated="2022-07-15T07:16:23Z">
  <amends type="h" number="7900" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-07-14T13:22:44-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000592"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 79 printed in Part A of House Report 117-405 to require the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sust ainment to submit a report to Congress on the progress of the Department's implementation of on-site PFAS destruction technologies not requiring incineration and extends the moratorium on PFAS incineration enacted in the FY22 NDAA.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sust ainment to submit a report to Congress on the progress of the Department's implementation of on-site PFAS destruction technologies not requiring incineration and extends the moratorium on PFAS incineration enacted in the FY22 NDAA.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-07-14T13:22:44-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="330">
      <text>On agreeing to the Levin (MI) amendment (A023) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 196 (Roll no. 330).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6589" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13T22:57:50-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A023) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13T22:49:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A023) offered by Mr. Levin (MI).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6303-6305" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6303-6304" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13"/>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13T22:49:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A023) offered by Mr. Levin (MI).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T13:22:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Levin (MI) amendment (A023) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 196 (Roll no. 330).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T13:22:44-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T13:22:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Levin (MI) amendment (A023) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 233 - 196 (Roll no. 330).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
