<bill session="117" type="h" number="4926" updated="2023-01-01T20:19:43Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish that no Federal statute is intended to preempt a cause of action against an airport maintained in any State small claims or superior court by any individual or city within 5 miles of an airport when an action is brought for noise or nuisance caused by ground-based noise in violation of a State statute as specified, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Low-frequency Energetic Acoustics and Vibrations Exasperate Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Low-frequency Energetic Acoustics and Vibrations Exasperate Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-22T20:17:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Low-frequency Energetic Acoustics and Vibrations Exasperate Act or the LEAVE Act

This bill establishes standards and remedies related to ground-based noise (GBN).

Specifically, the bill

 permits one or more states to conduct studies of GBN from aircraft operations at an airport within a state, requires any study conducted to identify a baseline value of GBN above which an airport in the study is presumed to be permitting an excess of noise to a community within five miles of such airport, allows a state cause of action for GBN if a state has undertaken a study of GBN at an airport, and establishes that no federal statute is intended to preempt a cause of action against an airport in any state small claims or superior court when an action is brought for GBN in violation of state standards.</summary>
</bill>
