<bill session="116" type="s" number="3879" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:18Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Read the Bills Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Read the Bills Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve the constitutional authority of Congress and ensure accountability and transparency in legislation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-14T11:26:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Read the Bills Act

This bill establishes requirements relating to the introduction and consideration of any bill or resolution in either chamber of Congress.

Specifically, the bill requires any measure introduced in either chamber to contain a provision citing the specific powers granted to Congress in the Constitution to enact the proposed measure, including all of its provisions. Further, the text must also set forth the current law such measure is amending and the proposed modifications to the law.

Additionally, a vote on final passage of a measure (except private bills) may not occur in either chamber unless (1) the full text of the measure is published on an official website of each chamber at least seven days before the vote, (2) public notice of the specific calendar week during which the vote is scheduled to take place is posted on the respective website at least six days before the Monday of such week, and (3) there is a reading of its full text verbatim by the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate to the respective chamber.</summary>
</bill>
