<bill session="118" type="h" number="5016" updated="2025-11-19T02:31:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Water Efficiency, Conservation, and Sustainability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Efficiency, Conservation, and Sustainability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase efficiency and conservation in public water systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2654" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-14T19:22:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Water Efficiency, Conservation, and Sustainability Act of 2023

This bill establishes three grant programs within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to address water efficiency and water losses.

First, the EPA must establish a grant program to assist states, local governments, tribal governments, public water systems, and nonprofit organizations in carrying out their water efficiency incentive programs.

Second, the EPA must establish and carry out a program that provides grants and technical assistance for conducting annual audits of public water systems, implementing controls to address losses identified in the audits, and helping public water systems that have conducted and validated audits to establish water loss control programs.

Third, the EPA must establish a grant program to assist states, tribal governments, and local governments in adopting and implementing certain water-efficient plumbing codes.</summary>
</bill>
