<bill session="116" type="h" number="8379" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Cybersecurity of Small Organizations Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Cybersecurity of Small Organizations Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency to establish cybersecurity guidance for small organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2020-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2020-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E892-893"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4731" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-24T17:00:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Cybersecurity of Small Organizations Act of 2020

This bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to maintain and promote cybersecurity guidance for use by small organizations.

Specifically, the bill requires CISA to maintain cybersecurity guidance that documents and promotes evidence-based cybersecurity policies and controls for use by small organizations to improve their cybersecurity. This guidance must be publicly available at no cost, and CISA, the Small Business Administration (SBA), and the Department of Commerce must promote the guidance through relevant resources that are regularly used by small organizations.

Commerce must report on methods of incentivizing small organizations to improve their cybersecurity, including through the adoption of policies, controls, products, and services that have been demonstrated to reduce cybersecurity risk. Every two years, the SBA must submit and make publicly available specified data on the state of small businesses' cybersecurity.</summary>
</bill>
