<bill session="116" type="h" number="4473" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:52Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Assets for Independence Act, to provide for the approval of applications to operate new demonstration programs and to renew existing programs, to enhance program flexibility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Worker and Family Support.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-17T22:18:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2019

This bill reauthorizes through FY2024 and otherwise makes changes to certain demonstration projects that fund individual development accounts (IDAs). (IDAs are matched savings accounts through which low-income individuals may save targeted amounts for qualifying purposes such as first-time home ownership or post-secondary education.)

Specifically, the bill (1) expands qualifying expenses for purposes of education and home replacement, repair, or improvement; (2) allows public housing agencies to participate in demonstration projects; (3) increases income eligibility limits; and (4) makes other changes with respect to terminated projects, reporting, and other requirements.

The Department of Health and Human Services must give special consideration to applications from certain categories of individuals, including individuals who are or have been in foster care. In addition, an individual who is a recent or current victim of domestic violence shall not, for purposes of project participation, fail to qualify as a first-time homebuyer by reason of having a co-ownership interest in a principal residence with a person who committed domestic violence against the individual.</summary>
</bill>
