<bill session="117" type="s" number="1211" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture National Historic Park in Collinsville, Illinois, Monroe, Madison, and St. Clair Counties, Illinois, and St. Louis City County, Missouri, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture National Historical Park Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2037" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2642" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="General Native American affairs matters"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-04T19:48:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture National Historical Park Act

This bill provides for the establishment of the Cahokia Mounds Mississippian Culture National Historical Park in Collinsville, Illinois; Monroe, Madison, and St. Clair Counties, Illinois; and St. Louis City County, Missouri, as a unit of the National Park System.

The Department of the Interior may acquire lands and interests within the boundary of the park by donation, purchase, or exchange, except that any land owned by such states or a political subdivision of one the states may be acquired only by donation.

Interior may enter into cooperative agreements with such states and their political subdivisions, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, Indian tribes, and individuals to (1) identify, interpret, and restore nationally significant historical or cultural and natural resources related to the life of the Mississippi culture within the park, subject to the condition that such an agreement must provide for reasonable public access; and (2) conduct research related to Mississippian culture.</summary>
</bill>
