<bill session="119" type="h" number="709" updated="2025-03-14T13:36:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Training Center for Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Training Center for Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, to establish counter-UAS system training and require the Attorney General and Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to establish related standards for initial and recurrent training programs or certifications for individuals seeking to operate counter-UAS detection and mitigation systems, equipment, or technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001220"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-14T13:32:04Z" status="Introduced in House">National Training Center for Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act

This bill requires&#160;the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish training and qualification standards for counter-unmanned aircraft systems, commonly referred to as counter-drone systems.

Specifically, DHS&#160;and&#160;DOJ, in coordination with the Federal Aviation Administration, must establish standards for initial and recurrent training programs or certifications for individuals seeking to operate counter-drone detection and mitigation systems, equipment, or technology.

Further, DOJ, in coordination with&#160;DHS's Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, may provide&#160;training related to&#160;counter-drone systems, including detecting, identifying, monitoring, tracking, disrupting, and seizing&#160;control of&#160;drones. DOJ may establish or designate one or more facilities or training centers to provide such training related to counter-drone systems.</summary>
</bill>
