<bill session="108" type="s" number="1370" updated="2023-01-15T06:02:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consumer Credit Score Disclosure Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide for disclosure of credit-scoring information by creditors and consumer reporting agencies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Credit Score Disclosure Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2003-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer behavior"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Home equity conversion"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-10T20:37:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Credit Score Disclosure Act of 2003 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to cite specified consumer credit scoring information that a consumer reporting agency must disclose upon consumer request in connection with an application for an extension of consumer credit secured by a dwelling, including a credit score: (1) derived from a model widely distributed to users of credit scores; or (2) that assists the consumer in understanding the credit scoring assessment of the consumer's credit behavior and predictions about future credit behavior. Requires any person that makes or arranges extensions of consumer credit that are to be secured by a dwelling, and that uses credit scores for that purpose, to provide the consumer with a copy of: (1) the information obtained from a consumer reporting agency or that was developed and used by that user of the credit score information; or (2) a copy of the information provided to the user by a third party that developed the credit score, plus a general description of credit scores, their use, and the sources and kinds of data used to generate credit scores. Declares void any contract provision that prohibits such mandated disclosures. Exempts from contractual liability any user of a credit score for making such a disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
