<bill session="117" type="h" number="3262" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GUARD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to submit a report on cybersecurity risks to motor vehicle safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GUARD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guarding against Unauthorized Attacks Related to Driving Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2022-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-10T21:55:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Guarding against Unauthorized Attacks Related to Driving Act or the GUARD Act

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to study the state of cybersecurity regarding motor vehicles, including by developing a comprehensive list of federal agencies with jurisdiction over cybersecurity and a brief description of the jurisdiction or expertise of such agencies.

DOT must also report on the results of the study and make recommendations to enable the exchange of information and lessons learned across the industry, and across relevant federal agencies, regarding cybersecurity incidents, threats, and potential vulnerabilities in a timely manner with respect to motor vehicle safety.</summary>
</bill>
