<bill session="118" type="s" number="1933" updated="2025-01-31T11:36:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DCA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DCA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Direct Capital Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance flight options for consumers flying to and from Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000790"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3185" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-31T11:33:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Direct Capital Access Act or the DCA Act

This bill increases the number of daily round-trip flights allowed at Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport (DCA).

Specifically, this bill adds 56 new slots at DCA to allow for 28 additional daily round-trip flights. (Airlines flying to and from DCA are subject to slot and perimeter rules set by federal law and regulation. The slot rules determine the total number of flight slots that can be handled in a given time period. In addition, a statutory perimeter rule limits nonstop flights to a 1,250-mile radius unless they are granted an exemption in law.)

Current law limits DCA to a maximum of 67 hourly slots for flights both within- and beyond-perimeter; a round-trip flight serving DCA requires two slots (or a slot pair). Of those slots, 40 daily slots are exempt from the perimeter rule.

Under the bill's slot increase, operations at DCA may not increase by more than eight flights per hour.</summary>
</bill>
