<bill session="118" type="h" number="9076" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:38Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-04">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children by Strengthening Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Protecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children by Strengthening Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children and Families Act</title>
    <title type="short">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children and Families Act</title>
    <title type="short">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children and Families Act</title>
    <title type="display">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children and Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize and modernize part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to strengthen child welfare services, expand the availability of prevention services to better meet the needs of vulnerable families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To reauthorize child welfare programs under part B of title IV of the Social Security Act and strengthen the State and tribal child support enforcement program under part D of such title, and for other purposes</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001126" joined="2024-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2024-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2024-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2024-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2024-08-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000470" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2024-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2024-08-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001213" joined="2024-08-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2024-08-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2024-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2024-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001135" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2024-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000134" joined="2024-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000815" joined="2024-08-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 38 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 118-679.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-17" calendar="Union" number="574">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 574.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-09-17T15:50:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (MO) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-17T15:50:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5259-5270" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-17T15:50:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 9076.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-17T16:22:48-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18T14:09:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5341-5342" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="423" datetime="2024-09-18T14:12:54-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 10 (Roll no. 423).</text>
      <reference ref="09/17/2024 CR H5259-5266" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18T14:12:55-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18T14:12:59-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2024-12-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7317" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-12-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2025-01-04" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-258" type="public" datetime="2025-01-04">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-258.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8621" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5336" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8799" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-27T20:20:59Z" status="Public Law">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Children and Families Act

TITLE I--CHILD WELFARE REAUTHORIZATION AND MODERNIZATION

Protecting America's Children by Strengthening Families Act

This title reauthorizes through FY2029 certain child and family services and modifies programs related to prevention services, youth in foster care, parental substance use disorder, and kinship caregiving, which are generally administered by the Administration for Children and Families (ACF).First, the title reauthorizes funding through FY2029 for the&#160;Stephanie Tubbs Jones Child Welfare Services and the MaryLee Allen Promoting Safe and Stable Families programs. It also requires 3% of allocated funding to be paid directly to Indian tribes.&#160; The title also reauthorizes through FY2029 the Court Improvement Program and requires the ACF to issue guidance for technological changes necessary to conduct proceedings remotely.

The title reauthorizes through FY2029 and revises regional partnership grants for services to families affected by substance use disorders.The ACF also must review administrative requirements for state child welfare agencies and explore&#160;ways to reduce the compliance&#160;time.The title also authorizes grants to states and other specified organizations to&#160;evaluate&#160;child and family services and kinship navigator programs.Further, state plans for child welfare services must describe how states may offer virtual caseworker visits to youth in care who are over 18 and have consented to such visits.

The title also authorizes family preservation and family support services for youth under the age of 26. It also includes within the definition of family preservation services nonrecurring, short-term benefits that address immediate needs related to a specific crisis, such as supports for housing or food assistance.The title also&#160;reauthorizes grants to states for caseworker support and&#160;authorizes demonstration grants to support relationships between foster children and their&#160;incarcerated parents.Finally, the title modifies certain requirements regarding data collection and technical assistance for programs relating to behavioral health services, and it requires the ACF to report on post-adoption and guardianship services.

The title takes effect on October 1, 2025.

TITLE II--STRENGTHENING STATE AND TRIBAL CHILD SUPPORT

Strengthening State and Tribal Child Support Enforcement Act

This title permits tribal child support enforcement agencies to access the Federal Tax Refund Offset Program to collect past-due child support payments from the federal tax refunds of noncustodial parents.

Additionally,&#160;the title authorizes the Internal Revenue Service and the Social Security Administration to disclose certain tax return information to tribal child support enforcement agencies. Such information may be disclosed to establish and collect child support obligations from, and to locate, those individuals owing such obligations. The title also explicitly authorizes state and tribal child support enforcement agencies to disclose necessary information to contractors for these purposes.

The title also permits the ACF to reimburse tribal agencies for certain reporting costs related to the Federal Parent Locator Service.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-679</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
