<bill session="111" type="h" number="4642" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:36Z">
  <state datetime="2010-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance Federal efforts focused on public awareness and education about the risks and dangers associated with Shaken Baby Syndrome.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2010-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3003" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-04T15:24:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through various federal agencies, to develop a national Shaken Baby Syndrome public health campaign. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a National Action Plan and effective strategies to increase awareness of opportunities to prevent Shaken Baby Syndrome; and (2) coordinate the Plan and strategies with evidence-based strategies and efforts that support families with infants and other young children.

Directs the Secretary to carry out communication, education, and training about Shaken Baby Syndrome prevention, including efforts to communicate with the general public, such as by: (1) disseminating effective prevention practices and techniques to parents and caregivers; (2) producing evidence-based educational and information materials; and (3) carrying out training.

Requires the Secretary to work to ensure that the parents and caregivers of children are connected to effective supports through the coordination of existing programs and networks or the establishment of new programs.

Establishes a Shaken Baby Awareness Advisory Council to develop recommendations: (1) regarding the National Action Plan and effective strategies; and (2) related to support services for families and caregivers of young children.

Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to conduct a study on the collection of data related to Shaken Baby Syndrome.</summary>
</bill>
