<bill session="117" type="h" number="3654" updated="2022-12-30T17:32:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ROBUST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand access to electromagnetic spectrum for the provision of broadband service in rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROBUST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Opportunities for Broadband in Underserved Settlements and Towns Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001104"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000388" joined="2021-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-20T16:18:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Opportunities for Broadband in Underserved Settlements and Towns Act or the ROBUST Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to determine whether spectrum usage rights under covered licenses are unutilized or underutilized in rural areas. A covered license is an FCC-issued license for the use of electromagnetic spectrum (1) whereby a licensee may use such spectrum for the provision of broadband service, and (2) that includes a rural area in any part of its geographic scope.

If the FCC determines that a licensee's spectrum usage rights are unutilized or underutilized in a rural area, it must recommend that the licensee lease the rights to other entities to provide broadband service in that area.

The bill also establishes prioritization and eligibility requirements for funding provided under the Department of Agriculture's Broadband ReConnect Program, which furnishes loans and grants for the costs of infrastructure needed to provide broadband service in rural areas.</summary>
</bill>
