<bill session="118" type="s" number="1411" updated="2025-11-19T03:44:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prove It Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to require greater transparency for Federal regulatory decisions that impact small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prove It Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-90.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee)"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7198" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-05T15:10:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prove It Act of 2023

This bill expands the requirements for federal agency rulemaking with respect to small businesses, organizations, and governmental jurisdictions.

Specifically, when conducting an initial regulatory flexibility analysis, agencies must include, where feasible, any reasonably foreseeable potential indirect costs the proposed rule may impose on such small entities.

Further, if an agency certifies that an initial regulatory flexibility analysis is not required because the rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, the agency must provide such certification within 10 days to the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration. A small entity or group of small entities may petition the Office of Advocacy to review such certification. The petition must include specified information, such as the issues the petitioner believes should be addressed and a proposed solution to the issues raised.

If the Office of Advocacy ultimately determines, upon a full review of the petition, that the proposed rule would have a significant economic impact on a&#160;substantial number of small entities, the agency promulgating the rule must perform an initial&#160;and final regulatory flexibility analysis for the rule. Additionally, if the agency does not participate or assist in the full review process, the finalized rule shall not apply to small entities.

The bill also requires agencies to publish, and allow for comments on, all guidance documents with respect to any rule an agency determines is likely to have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</summary>
</bill>
