<bill session="117" type="s" number="5234" updated="2023-02-23T09:21:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PANIC Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PANIC Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting America from Narcotics and Illicit Chemicals Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify statutory definitions relating to narcotics and drug trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2022-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7103-7104" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7776" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1160" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4315" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-17T16:13:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting America from Narcotics and Illicit Chemicals Act of 2022 or the PANIC Act of 2022

This bill expands the definition of major illicit drug producing country to include a country that is a significant direct source of certain drugs (or precursor chemicals for producing such drugs) that are significantly affecting the United States. The bill also expands the definition of major drug-transit country to include countries through which certain synthetic drugs are transported.

(Under current law, a country designated a major illicit drug producing country or major drug-transit country may be eligible for certain U.S. foreign assistance, including transfers of excess defense articles. However, a designated country that fails to adhere to commitments related to drug control measures may be barred from receiving other forms of foreign assistance and may also be subject to trade restrictions.)</summary>
</bill>
