<bill session="116" type="h" number="7740" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MICRO Business Success Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MICRO Business Success Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Microbusiness Improvement and Coronavirus Recovery Opportunities for Business Success Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prioritize support for small business concerns with 10 or fewer employees by setting aside funds and increasing access to funding and other assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001306" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-19T12:30:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Microbusiness Improvement and Coronavirus Recovery Opportunities for Business Success Act of 2020 or the MICRO Business Success Act

This bill provides designated Small Business Administration (SBA) assistance for small businesses with 10 or fewer employees.

Specifically, out of the Paycheck Protection Program established to support small businesses in response to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019), the bill allots $20 billion of remaining program funds for small businesses with 10 or fewer employees.

Additionally, the bill raises the aggregate amount for SBA loans to such small businesses from $6 million to $10 million. The bill adds the expansion of such small businesses to the list of economic development objectives from which a small business development company must demonstrate at least one in order to qualify for SBA assistance. It also requires a participating small business development company to provide specified assistance to such small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
