<bill session="119" type="s" number="348" updated="2025-06-13T18:44:47Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STABLE Trade Policy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STABLE Trade Policy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Tariffs on Allies and Bolstering Legislative Exercise of Trade Policy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the authority of the President to impose new or additional duties with respect to articles imported from countries that are allies or free trade agreement partners of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2025-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-13T18:39:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stopping Tariffs on Allies and Bolstering Legislative Exercise of Trade Policy Act or the STABLE Trade Policy Act

This bill requires the President to receive congressional approval in order to proclaim or increase the rates of duty (i.e., tariffs) on articles imported into the United States from covered countries. Under the bill, a covered country is (1) a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), (2) a country that has been designated as a major non-NATO ally under the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961 (e.g., Australia, Israel, and Japan), or (3) a country that has in effect a free trade agreement with the United States.

Specifically, the President may proclaim a new or additional covered duty (e.g., a duty proclaimed pursuant to Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962) on an article imported into the United States from a covered country only if (1) the President submits to Congress a request for authorization to proclaim or increase the duty and the request contains specified information, such as a description of the objective the President seeks to achieve with the&#160;action and an assessment of the likely impact on the U.S. economy; and (2) a joint resolution of approval is enacted into law.</summary>
</bill>
