<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="572" updated="2021-09-30T00:34:09Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1054" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-05-15">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-05-14"/>
  <description>To improve access to higher education for middle-income families by making resources available to expand the Hope and Lifetime Learning Scholarship Credits and for lower-income families by making resources available to increase the maximum Pell Grant to $4500 and to provide an equal amount for deficit reduction by eliminating the 10 percent dividend tax exclusion for amounts above $500 and eliminating acceleration of the 38.6 percent income tax rate education.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-05-15" how="roll" result="fail" roll="174">
      <text>Amendment SA 572 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 174.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Amendment SA 572 proposed by Senator Dodd. (consideration: CR S6438; text: CR S6438) To improve access to higher education for middle-income families by making resources available to expand the Hope and Lifetime Learning Scholarship Credits and for lower-income families by making resources available to increase the maximum Pell Grant to $4500 and to provide an equal amount for deficit reduction by eliminating the 10 percent dividend tax exclusion for amounts above $500 and eliminating acceleration of the 38.6 percent income tax rate education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 572 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 174.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 572 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 174.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 572 proposed by Senator Dodd.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6438" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6438" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
