<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>703</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T20:54:24Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T20:54:24Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-01-27</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-01-27T15:33:48Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-27</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
            <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-27</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-27</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000339</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Frank, Barney [D-MA-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>BARNEY</firstName>
        <lastName>FRANK</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Bank accounts, deposits, capital</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Financial crises and stabilization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing finance and home ownership</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-01-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-03-24T21:39:16Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) to make permanent the increase in the standard maximum deposit insurance amount from $100,000 to $250,000.</p> <p>Extends from five years to eight years after implementation of a Deposit Insurance Fund (DIF) restoration plan the deadline by which the DIF reserve ratio must meet or exceed the required minimum of 1.15% of estimated insured deposits.</p> <p>Increases the borrowing authority of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) from a maximum $30 billion to $100 billion.</p> <p>Extends to depository institution holding companies liability for special assessments to recover loss to the DIF arising from certain actions taken or assistance provided to avoid serious adverse effects on economic conditions or financial stability.</p> <p>Amends the National Housing Act to revise certain requirements for the HOPE for Homeowners Program.</p> <p>Repeals the requirement that the current borrower have, or is likely to have, a mortgage debt-to-income ratio greater than 31% (or any higher amount the Federal Home Loan Bank Board determines appropriate).</p> <p>Increases from 90% to 93% of a property's appraised value the cap on the principal obligation amount of a refinanced eligible insured mortgage.</p> <p>Repeals the prohibitions on: (1) second liens; and (2) payment of insurance benefits to a mortgagee in any case in which a mortgagor fails to make the first payment on a refinanced eligible mortgage.</p> <p>Reduces the annual premium for a refinanced eligible insured mortgage, and allows its further reduction or termination during the mortgage term.</p> <p>Repeals the entitlement of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the mortgagor of an eligible insured mortgage, upon any sale or disposition of the subject property, to 50% of any appreciation in the property's appraised value since the date that the mortgage was insured.</p> <p>Authorizes the Federal Home Loan Bank Board to establish a payment to the servicer of the existing senior mortgage for every loan insured under the HOPE for Homeowners Program.</p> <p>Prescribes requirements (safe harbor) that will render a mortgage servicer not liable for entering into a loan modification or workout plan with respect to any mortgage on which: (1) default has occurred or is reasonably foreseeable; (2) the property securing it is occupied by the mortgagor; and (3) the servicer reasonably and in good faith believes that the anticipated recovery on the mortgage's principal outstanding obligation under a particular mortgage modification, workout plan, or other loss mitigation action will exceed, on a net present value basis, the anticipated recovery on the principal outstanding obligation to be realized through foreclosure.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to take prompt action to provide EESA Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) assistance to smaller community financial institutions, including privately held institutions.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To promote bank liquidity and lending through deposit insurance, the HOPE for Homeowners Program, and other enhancements.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To promote bank liquidity and lending through deposit insurance, the HOPE for Homeowners Program, and other enhancements.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To promote bank liquidity and lending through deposit insurance, the HOPE for Homeowners Program, and other enhancements.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2009-01-27T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr703ih/xml/BILLS-111hr703ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-01-27</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
