<bill session="112" type="h" number="4480" updated="2022-03-02T05:33:29Z">
  <state datetime="2012-06-21T13:06:47-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-06-21T13:06:47-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategic Energy Production Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strategic Energy Production Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Domestic Energy and Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Advancing Offshore Wind Production Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">BLM Live Internet Auctions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Gasoline Regulations Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">National Petroleum Reserve Alaska Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Planning for American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Providing Leasing Certainty for American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Strategic Energy Production Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Streamlining Permitting of American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development of a plan to increase oil and gas exploration, development, and production under oil and gas leases of Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Defense in response to a drawdown of petroleum reserves from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</title>
    <title type="display">Domestic Energy and Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001272" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001082" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2012-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000574" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000186" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000571" joined="2012-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000822" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2012-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held Prior to Introduction.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Agriculture, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-520, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-08">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-08" calendar="Union" number="367">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 367.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2012-06-19T18:10:50-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 691 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4480 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution makes in order as original text for purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 112-24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T14:16:05-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 691 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T16:30:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 691.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3875-3912" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3890-3895" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T16:31:04-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4480 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution makes in order as original text for purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 112-24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T16:31:07-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 691 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T16:31:08-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steve Womack to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T16:31:15-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with two hour of general debate on H.R. 4480.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T18:55:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hastings (WA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:02:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hastings (WA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Hastings (WA) amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:03:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:12:48-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced its understanding the amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 112-540 would not be offered.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:13:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Quigley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:20:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKinley amendment numbered 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:27:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKinley amendment numbered 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:34:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waxman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:45:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waxman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gardner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Waxman amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:46:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:51:05-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Connolly amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T19:52:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gene Green (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:00:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gene Green (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gene Green (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Gene Green (TX) amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:01:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Terry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:13:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rush amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:23:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rush amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rush demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Rush amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:24:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:35:04-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Holt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Holt amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:36:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:46:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Connolly amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:47:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Amodei amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:56:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amodei amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Amodei demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Amodei amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T20:58:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Markey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:08:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Markey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Markey amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:09:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Landry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:16:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Landry amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Landry amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:17:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rigell amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:23:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rigell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Rige11 amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:23:51-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:24:13-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-20T21:24:22-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4480 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:11:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3918-3930" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:12:22-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:13:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Holt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:21:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Holt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Holt demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Holt amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:22:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wittman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:34:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wittman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Markey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Wittman amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:36:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Westmoreland amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:44:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bass (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:52:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bass (CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Bass (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Bass (CA) amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:52:55-04:00">
      <text>The Chair announced its understanding the amendment numbered 22 printed in House Report 112-540 would not be offered.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T09:53:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Capps amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:01:55-04:00">
      <text>POSPTONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Capps amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Capps demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Capps amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:02:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hanabusa amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:05:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Speier amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:13:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Speier amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Speier demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Speier amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:13:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeLauro amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:23:14-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeLauro amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gardner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the DeLauro amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:24:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 691, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bass (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:32:58-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lamborn moved to rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:33:24-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:33:47-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4480 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:59:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3940-3945" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T10:59:45-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:31:23-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4480.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:32:04-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3942" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:32:14-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:33:10-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Slaughter moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3942-3944" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3942" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:33:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Slaughter motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prohibit the major integrated oil companies (Big 5) from receiving new drilling leases authorized under this bill unless they agree to not claim certain tax benefits: the percentage depletion allowance and the domestic production activities deduction (Sec. 199). The motion would also require that: all materials used to drill new leases issued under this bill be made in America, and that lease holders make efforts to reduce outsourcing of jobs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:40:51-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T12:59:01-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 166 - 243 (Roll no. 409).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3943-3944" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="410" datetime="2012-06-21T13:06:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 248 - 163 (Roll no. 410).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-21T13:06:48-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2150" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2173" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2752" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4136" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4381" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4382" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4383" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4471" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="398" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3445" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="hr" number="691" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1315"/>
    <amendment number="h1314"/>
    <amendment number="h1313"/>
    <amendment number="h1312"/>
    <amendment number="h1311"/>
    <amendment number="h1310"/>
    <amendment number="h1309"/>
    <amendment number="h1308"/>
    <amendment number="h1307"/>
    <amendment number="h1306"/>
    <amendment number="h1305"/>
    <amendment number="h1304"/>
    <amendment number="h1303"/>
    <amendment number="h1302"/>
    <amendment number="h1301"/>
    <amendment number="h1300"/>
    <amendment number="h1299"/>
    <amendment number="h1298"/>
    <amendment number="h1297"/>
    <amendment number="h1296"/>
    <amendment number="h1295"/>
    <amendment number="h1294"/>
    <amendment number="h1293"/>
    <amendment number="h1292"/>
    <amendment number="h1291"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2012-08-31T19:37:09Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Strategic Energy Production Act of 2012 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to direct the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to develop a plan to increase the percentage of federal lands leased for oil and gas exploration, development, and production under the jurisdiction of the Secretaries of Agriculture (USDA), of Energy, of the Interior, and of Defense (DOD) (Secretaries), including submerged lands of the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS).

Requires the percentage of the total amount of such federal lands to be the same as the percentage of petroleum in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) that was drawn down.

Prohibits the plan from providing more than 10% of such federal lands for oil and gas exploration, development, and production leasing.

Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) base the determination of present and future national energy needs upon information from the Energy Information Administration; and (2) consult with the Secretaries and the American Association of Petroleum Geologists and other state, environmentalist, and oil and gas industry stakeholders when developing the plan to determine the most geologically promising lands for production of oil and natural gas liquids.

Prohibits such plan from taking effect without the concurrence of each of the Secretaries with respect to elements of the plan within their respective jurisdictions.

Requires federal agency compliance with any requirements established by the Secretary of Energy pursuant to the plan; but prohibits any action that in the view of the Secretary of Defense would adversely affect national security or military activities, including preparedness and training.

Excludes lands managed under either the National Park System or the National Wilderness Preservation System from federal lands designated for increased oil and gas production.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-520</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
