<bill session="118" type="s" number="1471" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Truncating Onerous Regulations for Partners and Enhancing Deterrence Operations (TORPEDO) Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truncating Onerous Regulations for Partners and Enhancing Deterrence Operations (TORPEDO) Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to bolster the AUKUS partnership, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1093" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1006" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-08T22:11:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Truncating Onerous Regulations for Partners and Enhancing Deterrence Operations (TORPEDO) Act of 2023

This bill facilitates the transfer of certain U.S. equipment, technology, and services to and between the United States, Australia, Canada, and the United Kingdom (U.K.).&#160;For example, the bill

requires the Department of State to initiate regulatory changes to establish an open general export license for the export, reexport, transfer, and retransfer of certain defense articles and services to or between designated&#160;individuals, entities, and facilities&#160;of the United States, Australia, Canada, and the U.K.;requires the Department of Commerce to initiate regulatory changes to establish a license exception for the export, reexport, and in-country transfer of items on the Commerce Control List to or between designated individuals and entities in Australia, Canada, and the U.K.;directs the State Department to compile a list of available and emerging military platforms, technologies, and equipment that are pre-cleared and prioritized for sale and release to Australia, Canada, and the&#160;U.K. through the Foreign Military Sales program; andrequires the State Department to appoint a senior advisor to oversee implementation of the AUKUS agreement (a security partnership between Australia, the U.K., and the United States focused on the Indo-Pacific region).The bill also expands the definition of domestic source under the Defense Production Act, thereby making certain businesses in Australia, the U.K., and New Zealand eligible for financial incentives to increase production of critical components, critical technology items, materials, and industrial resources needed for U.S. national security.</summary>
</bill>
