<bill session="116" type="h" number="5449" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:53Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Road User Charge Advancement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the FAST Act to reauthorize the surface transportation system funding alternatives program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Road User Charge Advancement Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2019-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-19T14:30:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Road User Charge Advancement Act of 2019

This bill revises and reauthorizes through FY2025 the Department of Transportation's (DOT's) surface transportation system funding alternatives program. Under the program, DOT provides grants to states to demonstrate user-based alternative revenue mechanisms that utilize a user fee structure to maintain the long-term solvency of the Highway Trust Fund.

Specifically, the bill

 increases funding to carry out the program; authorizes DOT to provide grants for states to test solutions to ensure the privacy and security of data collected for the purpose of implementing a user-based alternative revenue mechanism; revises reporting requirements for DOT; and requires DOT to provide special consideration to projects that carry out activities not previously carried out to advance the knowledge and practice of surface transportation system funding alternatives or that collect revenues from pilot project participants.</summary>
</bill>
