<bill session="117" type="h" number="4734" updated="2023-02-21T15:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Director of the National Science Foundation from awarding grants and other forms of assistance to Chinese communist military companies and their affiliates, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Science First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Science First Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000372"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4792" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-07T15:20:46Z" status="Introduced in House">American Science First Act

This bill prohibits the National Science Foundation from providing grants or other forms of assistance to any individual or entity that is affiliated or otherwise has a relationship, including but not limited to a research partnership, joint venture, or contract with

 an entity included on the entity list under the Export Administration Regulations, which identifies foreign entities subject to license requirements for the export, reexport, or transfer of certain items; a Chinese military company operating in the United States or any of its territories or possessions on the list required under the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999, or required under the Mac Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021, or any successor list; or any parent, subsidiary, affiliate of, or entity owned by or controlled by any such entity.</summary>
</bill>
