<bill session="118" type="s" number="1525" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COLLUDE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COLLUDE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Curtailing Online Limitations that Lead Unconstitutionally to Democracy's Erosion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to address governmental interference in content moderation decisions by providers of interactive computer services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-13T01:34:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Curtailing Online Limitations that Lead Unconstitutionally to Democracy's Erosion Act or the COLLUDE Act

This bill limits federal liability protection, sometimes referred to as Section 230 protection, that generally precludes providers and users of an interactive computer service (e.g., a social media company) from being held legally responsible for content provided by a third party.

Specifically, the bill removes the protection if a provider restricts access to or availability of content containing political speech because of a governmental request unless the request serves a legitimate law enforcement or national security purpose.

In addition, the bill changes legal procedures for applying the protection. Currently, the protection serves as broad immunity that typically allows the early dismissal of lawsuits, thereby preempting lawsuits and statutes that impose liability for third-party content. This bill makes the protection an affirmative defense, which means the provider or user must prove that the protection applies before the lawsuit may be dismissed.</summary>
</bill>
