<bill session="117" type="s" number="5024" updated="2023-03-22T13:01:39Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Auto Recycling Theft Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent the theft of catalytic converters and other precious metal car parts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6394" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-27T18:55:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Auto Recycling Theft Act or the PART Act 

This bill establishes requirements for motor vehicles related to catalytic converters and other motor vehicle parts that contain precious metals.

The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration must revise the motor vehicle theft prevention standard for new motor vehicles to include catalytic converters among the parts that require an inscribed or affixed identifying number. Additionally, the Department of Transportation must establish a grant program through which law enforcement agencies and other entities can stamp vehicle identification numbers onto catalytic converters of existing vehicles.

The bill establishes retention requirements for the purchase of motor vehicle parts that contain precious metals. It also sets forth criminal penalties for the theft of catalytic converters or any precious metals removed from a vehicle.</summary>
</bill>
