<bill session="112" type="h" number="4265" updated="2019-11-15T21:46:49Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shared Responsibility in Preserving America's Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a 5 percent tax on so much of adjusted gross income of any individual as exceeds $1,000,000, and to provide incentive for Congress to pass a balanced budget amendment, or spending limit amendment, to the Constitution.</title>
    <title type="display">Shared Responsibility in Preserving America's Future Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-09T22:28:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Shared Responsibility in Preserving America's Future Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose, in taxable years beginning after 2012 and before 2023,&#160;an additional 5% tax on individual taxpayers whose modified adjusted gross income exceeds $1 million (adjusted for inflation after 2013). Defines "modified adjusted gross income" as adjusted gross income reduced by the excess of: (1) gross income from a trade or business which is not a passive activity and with respect to which wages are paid to at least one full-time equivalent employee, over (2) the tax deductions properly allocable to such income.&#160;

Makes this additional tax contingent upon the submission and ratification&#160;of a proposed amendment to the Constitution requiring a balanced budget or limiting spending.</summary>
</bill>
