<bill session="119" type="h" number="390" updated="2025-10-07T08:05:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACERO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACERO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response Operations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To utlitize the Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response to Operations project of NASA to improve aerial responses to wildfires, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2025-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000830" joined="2025-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 0.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-13T19:21:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response Operations Act or the ACERO Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Advanced Capabilities for Emergency Response Operations (ACERO) project. The ACERO project conducts research and development activities regarding aerial response to wildfires using uncrewed aircraft systems (UAS) and other advanced aviation technologies. It is administered by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA).&#160;

The bill directs the ACERO project to address airspace management and deconfliction during wildfire response efforts, including through real-time information sharing among response teams and the development of a platform to provide situational awareness of aerial assets. The bill also directs the ACERO project to establish a multiagency concept of operations to facilitate the coordination of aerial wildfire response among federal, state, and local government agencies. NASA must consult with other federal agencies and departments to avoid duplication of these efforts.&#160;

NASA generally may not procure UAS manufactured or assembled by specified foreign entities, including entities domiciled in or controlled by China, for use by the ACERO project.</summary>
</bill>
