<bill session="111" type="h" number="6110" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:36Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Telehealth Improvement and Expansion Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize telehealth and telemedicine grant programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telehealth Improvement and Expansion Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-19T14:34:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Telehealth Improvement and Expansion Act of 2010 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize appropriations for telehealth network and telehealth resource center grant programs. Includes state, local, and tribal health departments (currently, local health departments), skilled nursing facilities, community mental health centers, county mental health and public mental health facilities, and renal dialysis facilities as the entities that may be part of an eligible telehealth network.

Revises the preferences for telehealth network grants to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to give preference to an eligible entity that: (1) is a health care provider in a health care network that furnishes services in a medically underserved area or a health professional shortage area; (2) demonstrates broad geographic coverage in the rural or medically undeserved areas of the state or states in which the entity is located; and (3) demonstrates its ability to use the grant to establish or develop plans for telehealth systems that will link rural hospitals and rural health care providers to other hospitals, health care providers, and patients.

Reauthorizes appropriations for grants to state professional licensing boards to develop and implement state policies that will reduce statutory and regulatory barriers to telemedicine.</summary>
</bill>
