<bill session="119" type="h" number="1380" updated="2025-03-31T15:10:31Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Meat and Poultry Special Investigator Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Meat and Poultry Special Investigator Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, to establish the Office of the Special Investigator for Competition Matters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-31T15:09:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Meat and Poultry Special Investigator Act

This bill establishes&#160;the Office of the Special Investigator for Competition Matters within the Agricultural Marketing Service's Packers and Stockyards Division.

Specifically, the office must use all available tools (e.g., subpoenas) to investigate and prosecute violations of the Packers and Stockyards Act of 1921 (P&amp;S Act). Further, the bill grants the office the authority to bring any civil or administrative action authorized by that act.

Additionally, the office must

serve as a liaison to the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission with respect to competition and trade practices in the food and agricultural sector,consult with the Department of Homeland Security on national security and critical infrastructure security in the food and agricultural sector, andmaintain a staff of attorneys and other professionals with appropriate expertise.As background,&#160;the purposes of the P&amp;S&#160;Act are to&#160;assure fair competition and trade practices, safeguard farmers and ranchers, protect consumers, and protect livestock, meat, and poultry industry members from unfair, deceptive, unjustly discriminatory, and monopolistic practices.&#160;Those engaged in the business of marketing livestock, meat, and poultry in commerce are subject to the P&amp;S&#160;Act.</summary>
</bill>
