<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>132</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:20:48Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:20:48Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-01-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-01-25T21:08:46Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (text of measure as introduced: CR S195-202)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S194-195)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000174</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Leahy, Patrick J. [D-VT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patrick</firstName>
        <lastName>Leahy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Justice</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-03-30T15:30:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Criminal Justice and Forensic Science Reform Act of 2011 - Establishes an Office of Forensic Science (the Office) within the Office of the Deputy Attorney General in the Department of Justice (DOJ). Requires the Director of the Office (the Director) to: (1) establish, implement, and enforce standards for forensic science laboratory accreditation and forensic science personnel certification; (2) establish a comprehensive strategy for scientific research in the forensic sciences; (3) establish and implement standards and best practices for forensic science disciplines; (4) define "forensic science discipline" and "forensic science laboratory"; (5) establish and maintain a list of forensic science disciplines; and (6) establish committees to examine research needs, standards, best practices, and certification standards for the forensic science disciplines. </p> <p>Establishes a Forensic Science Board to promote confidence in the criminal justice system through standards and best practices and ensuring consistency, scientific validity, and accuracy regarding forensic testing, analysis, identification, and comparisons, the results of which may be used during the course of a criminal investigation or court proceeding.</p> <p>Prohibits a forensic science laboratory or covered entity (an entity that is not a forensic science laboratory and that conducts forensic testing) from receiving federal funds unless: (1) the Director has verified that the laboratory has been accredited in accordance with the standards and procedures established under this Act; and (2) all relevant personnel (individuals who conduct forensic testing or testify about evidence prepared by such individuals) of the laboratory or covered entity are certified under this Act. Requires the Director to establish standards for the certification of personnel and determine whether a laboratory or entity is eligible for federal funds. Authorizes the Director of the National Institute of Justice to make grants and provide technical assistance to laboratories and entities seeking accreditation.</p> <p>Requires the Board to recommend and the Director to establish: (1) a comprehensive strategy for fostering and improving peer-reviewed scientific research relating to the forensic science disciplines; and (2) a list of priorities for forensic science research funding. Directs: (1) the Board to submit to the Director a plan for encouraging collaboration among universities, nonprofit research institutions, state and local forensic science laboratories, private forensic science laboratories, private corporations, and the federal government to develop and perform cost-effective and reliable research in the forensic sciences; and (2) the Director to establish and disseminate uniform standards and best practices for the forensic science discipline. Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to make grants to eligible entities to conduct peer-reviewed scientific research in areas consistent with the Director's research priorities.</p> <p>Requires the Board to submit and the Director to implement: (1) a plan for supporting, and a standardized curriculum for, the education and training of judges, attorneys, and law enforcement personnel in the forensic sciences and fundamental scientific principles; (2) a plan for supporting the development of undergraduate and graduate educational programs in the forensic science disciplines and related fields, if deemed appropriate; and (3) a plan to encourage the federal government and state and local governments to implement systems to ensure that qualified individuals perform medical-legal death examinations and to encourage qualified individuals to enter the field.</p> <p>Directs the Board and the Director to regularly coordinate with: (1) relevant federal agencies to make efficient and appropriate use of research expertise and funding; and (2) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and other relevant federal agencies to determine ways in which the forensic science disciplines may assist in homeland security and emergency preparedness. </p> <p>Requires the Director to develop a system for any individual to provide information regarding lack of compliance with standards established under this Act.</p> <p>Requires the Board to submit and the Director to implement: (1) a plan to require interoperability among databases and technologies in each of the forensic science disciplines among all levels of government, in all states, and with the private sector; and (2) a recommended code of ethics for the forensic science disciplines.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Criminal Justice and Forensic Science Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Criminal Justice and Forensic Science Reform Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish an Office of Forensic Science and a Forensic Science Board, to strengthen and promote confidence in the criminal justice system by ensuring consistency and scientific validity in forensic testing, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Criminal Justice and Forensic Science Reform Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-01-25T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s132is/xml/BILLS-112s132is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (text of measure as introduced: CR S195-202)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
