<bill session="117" type="s" number="1264" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Resiliency for Ranching and Natural Conservation Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to improve the management of grazing permits and leases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resiliency for Ranching and Natural Conservation Health Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-27T01:30:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Resiliency for Ranching and Natural Conservation Health Act

This bill makes vacant grazing allotments temporarily available to holders of grazing permits or leases after a natural disaster.

The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall make available to the holder of a grazing permit or lease issued by either Interior or USDA the temporary use of a vacant grazing allotment if one or more grazing allotments covered by the grazing permit or lease of the holder are temporarily unusable because of resource conditions from unforeseen natural events or disasters (including an extreme weather event, drought, wildfire, infestation, or blight).

The bill allows investment of amounts in the Land and Water Conservation Fund. The bill allocates income generated by that investment to rangeland improvement projects and enhancing, expanding, or improving access to public lands or National Forest System land to benefit hunting and recreation activities.

The bill increases the maximum duration of grazing permits and leases from 10 years to 20 years.</summary>
</bill>
