<bill session="116" type="s" number="1239" updated="2022-02-08T23:25:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ROBO Calls and Texts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regulatory Oversight Barring Obnoxious Calls and Texts Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROBO Calls and Texts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Communications Commission to establish within the Enforcement Bureau of the Commission a division that specifically addresses the issue of robocalls, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2355" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-24T19:10:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Regulatory Oversight Barring Obnoxious Calls and Texts Act of 2019 or the ROBO Calls and Texts Act 

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to establish a Robocall Division within the Enforcement Bureau.

The Robocall Division shall be tasked with (1) ensuring consumer protection and compliance with federal laws relating to robocalls; (2) serving as a line of communication between the federal government and the communications industry, as well as between the FCC and related federal agencies, to coordinate efforts to eliminate robocalls; and (3) managing and addressing consumer complaints regarding robocalls.

Additionally, the bill requires the FCC to compel telecommunications providers to adopt technological standards for preventing robocalls.</summary>
</bill>
