<bill session="108" type="h" number="455" updated="2023-01-15T21:19:37Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Dairy Policy Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to use the Department of Agriculture's preferred Option 1B as the price structure for Class I fluid milk under Federal milk marketing orders, to provide emergency market loss payments to dairy producers for any calendar year quarter in which the national average price for Class III milk under Federal milk marketing orders is less than a target price of $11.50 per hundredweight, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Dairy Policy Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000545"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000570" joined="2003-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">National Dairy Policy Act of 2003 - Amends Federal law to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to use the Department of Agriculture's preferred Option 1B as the price structure for Class I fluid milk under Federal milk marketing orders.Directs the Secretary to make emergency market loss payments to dairy producers in the 48 contiguous States, including producers on farms not covered by milk marketing orders, whenever the national average for Class III milk under Federal milk marketing orders for a calendar year quarter is less than a specified target price.</summary>
</bill>
