<bill session="111" type="h" number="3438" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Access to Insurance for all Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish a national health program administered by the Office of Personnel Management to offer Federal employee health benefits plans to individuals who are not Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Insurance for all Americans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000365" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000461" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000456" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001179" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000074" joined="2010-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO25" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-04T16:40:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Access to Insurance for all Americans Act - Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to administer a health insurance program for non-federal employees and to apply to such program the provisions governing the federal employee health insurance program to the greatest extent practicable.

Requires OPM, for each calendar year, to enter into a contract with one or more carriers to make health benefits plans available to eligible individuals. Allows any individual to enroll in such a plan unless the individual: (1) is enrolled or eligible to enroll for coverage under a public health insurance program (including Medicaid or Medicare) or under the federal employee health insurance program; or (2) is a member of the uniformed services.

Allows rates and premiums for such a plan to differ among geographic regions. Makes such premiums tax deductible.

Provides that no government contribution shall be made for any individual enrolled in such a plan. Directs OPM to ensure that covered individuals are in a risk pool separate from that maintained for federal employees.



Requires the Director of OPM to submit a comprehensive plan to Congress that provides for the orderly implementation of the amendments made by this Act, including a schedule of actions to be taken to provide for that implementation.</summary>
</bill>
