<bill session="116" type="h" number="7226" updated="2022-08-10T23:26:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Agency Sunset Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Federal Agency Sunset Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Agency Sunset Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2020-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3708" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-10T16:15:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Agency Sunset Act

This bill establishes a Federal Agency Sunset Commission to evaluate the need for each agency or advisory committee.

The commission shall

 review and evaluate the efficiency and public need for each agency or advisory committee at least once every six years; recommend whether each agency or advisory committee should be continued, abolished, or reorganized; and propose legislative language based on its recommendations for abolishing or reorganizing an agency or advisory committee. When the commission is considering whether to recommend continuing, abolishing, or reorganizing an agency or advisory committee, the agency shall submit timely responses to a questionnaire provided by the commission, which shall include

 an explanation of why the functions of the agency or advisory committee continue to be necessary, what efficiencies taxpayers realize by the continued operation of the agency or advisory committee, and why the responsibilities of the agency or advisory committee cannot be better performed by the private sector or another agency or committee. Legislation proposed by the commission shall be granted expedited consideration.</summary>
</bill>
