<bill session="119" type="s" number="49" updated="2025-11-19T03:34:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expel Illegal Chinese Police Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expel Illegal Chinese Police Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to police departments in the People's Republic of China and other persons seeking to establish a Chinese police presence in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2127" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-14T19:30:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expel Illegal Chinese Police Act of 2025

This bill requires sanctions on certain foreign persons associated with the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) or Chinese law enforcement institutions, including those seeking to establish a Chinese police presence in the United States.&#160;

The bill requires the President to impose visa-blocking sanctions on certain non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law), including those&#160;who are (1) employees of Chinese law enforcement institutions or their immediate family members, or (2) directly associated with a Chinese police or United Front Work Department (UFWD) presence in the United States. (The CCP's UFWD seeks to win support for the CCP from non-CCP groups at home and abroad, with a focus on ethnic-Chinese diaspora communities.)

The President must also impose property-blocking sanctions on foreign individuals or entities that are (1) Chinese law enforcement institutions, their senior leaders, or those acting under the control of such institutions; (2) directly associated with establishing or maintaining a Chinese police presence in the United States; or (3) acting under the control of the UFWD with the intention of covertly monitoring or intimidating those living in the United States.

Additionally, the bill requires the President to prohibit federal agencies from participating in investigations into foreign persons subject to these sanctions unless the investigation is (1) initiated by the U.S. government; or (2) the President determines that such participation is vital to the health, safety, and well-being of U.S. citizens.</summary>
</bill>
