<bill session="116" type="s" number="1868" updated="2022-11-01T13:51:06Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Premium Reduction Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Premium Reduction Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide support to States to establish invisible high-risk pool or reinsurance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2019-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2019-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-25T17:43:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Premium Reduction Act of 2019

This bill provides funding for grants for states to establish invisible high-risk pool and reinsurance programs through applications for state innovation waivers from certain health insurance coverage requirements. A reinsurance program generally permits health insurance issuers to transfer a portion of the cost of the coverage for enrollees with large claims to the state, thus facilitating the enrollment of higher-risk individuals, including those with preexisting conditions. Similarly, an invisible high-risk pool generally identifies and enrolls higher-risk individuals and the state program pays a percentage of any insurance claims of such enrollees that exceed a predetermined amount.

In states that do not establish such programs, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must make market stabilization payments to health insurance issuers.

The bill further directs HHS to expedite the review of state innovation waiver applications that include a high-risk pool or reinsurance program. States may model a waiver application on the application of a state that has an approved waiver for such a program.</summary>
</bill>
