<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1257</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T16:48:43Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T16:48:43Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-06-12</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-06-12T23:12:53Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7841-7842)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001057</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Coleman, Norm [R-MN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Norm</firstName>
        <lastName>Coleman</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Governmental investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Managed care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical economics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Quality of care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-06-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Medicare Payment for Quality and Value Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish demonstration projects to improve care provided to Medicare beneficiaries with high-volume and high-cost conditions and for which payment is made under Medicare. Directs the Secretary to increase payments under Medicare to health care providers in low-cost high-quality States that adhere to quality standards identified by the Secretary. Defines a low-cost high-quality State as a State meeting certain cost and quality efficiency standards.<p>Directs the Secretary to accept proposals for projects in low-cost high-quality States from entities planning to include multiple public and private payers and a majority of practicing physicians in the State.<p>Allows the Secretary to waive compliance with such requirements of the Medicare program to the extent and for the period necessary to conduct demonstration projects under this Act.<p>Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences under which the Institute shall conduct a study on clinical outcomes, performance, and quality of care under the Medicare+Choice program under the Social Security Act.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Medicare Payment for Quality and Value Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Medicare Payment for Quality and Value Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to conduct statewide demonstration projects to improve health care quality and to reduce costs under the medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act and to conduct a study on payment incentives and performance under the Medicare+Choice program under such title.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Medicare Payment for Quality and Value Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-06-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-06-12</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7841-7842)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
