<bill session="117" type="s" number="2152" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair and Clear Campaign Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Federal Communications Commission to promulgate regulations requiring material in the online public inspection file of a covered entity to be made available in a format that is machine-readable.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Clear Campaign Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5897" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-04T17:21:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair and Clear Campaign Transparency Act

This bill directs the Federal Communications Commission to require certain online public inspection files to be made available to the public in a machine-readable format that supports automated searching, bulk downloading, aggregation, manipulation, sorting, and analysis.

Online public inspection files (including political files that contain records of requests to purchase broadcast time by or on behalf of candidates for public office or to communicate a message relating to a political matter of national importance) are files that must be uploaded to the internet by certain television broadcast stations and television systems, AM or FM radio broadcast stations, cable operators, direct broadcast satellite service providers, or satellite digital audio radio service providers.</summary>
</bill>
