<bill session="108" type="h" number="1885" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:01Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Pay Comparability Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 37, United States Code, to ensure that military pay increases are comparable to private sector pay growth, as measured by the Employment Cost Index.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Pay Comparability Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000465" joined="2003-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E830-831"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Total Force.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS27" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Total Force" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business cycles"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Pay Comparability Act of 2003 - Requires the monthly rates of basic military pay to be adjusted effective January 1 of each year. (Currently, such rates are adjusted whenever the General Schedule (GS) of Compensation for Federal employees is adjusted.)Requires equal annual pay percentage increases for all military personnel to be based on percentage increases in the Employment Cost Index (currently on GS adjustments). Increases percentage adjustments by one-half percent for FY 2004 through 2006.Requires new annual rates of pay to be published in the Federal Register and the Code of Federal Regulations.Authorizes the President, upon determining that annual pay adjustments would be inappropriate because of national emergency or serious economic conditions, to prepare and transmit to Congress a plan for an alternative pay adjustment. Requires the President to consider under such plan the impact that the alternative adjustment would have on the Government's ability to recruit and retain well-qualified members of the armed forces.</summary>
</bill>
