<bill session="112" type="h" number="3075" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:13Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Limiting the Intrusive Miles of International Terrorist Sponsors Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict the diplomatic travel of officials and representatives of state sponsors of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limiting the Intrusive Miles of International Terrorist Sponsors Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LIMITS Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001262"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-12-01T13:35:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Limiting the Intrusive Miles of International Terrorist Sponsors Act of 2011 or LIMITS Act of 2011 - Directs the President to restrict to a specified designated area the travel of officials and representatives of countries that are designated as state sponsors of terrorism who are visiting the United Nations (U.N.) headquarters complex in connection with official business.

Authorizes presidential waiver of such restriction upon submission of a report to Congress explaining why it is in the national interest to do so.

Excludes from such restriction: (1) direct travel to and from John F. Kennedy International Airport or LaGuardia Airport to the designated area in connection with official business at the U.N. headquarters complex, (2) land travel to and from any lodgings or other hotel accommodations in which an official or representative is staying if such lodging or other hotel accommodation is within the designated area, and (3) travel to and from New York University medical center or Bellevue Hospital Center for emergency medical care.</summary>
</bill>
