<bill session="109" type="s" number="2771" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Housing Flexibility Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the types of Federal housing assistance available to individuals and households in response to a major disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Housing Flexibility Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency housing"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Floodplains"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-06-06T20:32:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disaster Housing Flexibility Act of 2006 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the President, in making any determination of housing disaster assistance cost effectiveness, to: (1) consider if manufactured modular housing can be provided at a cost to the government less than that of other readily fabricated dwellings; and (2) seek recipient consent before providing assistance for such housing. Declares that any individual or household rejecting manufactured modular housing assistance shall remain eligible for any other available disaster or emergency housing assistance.

Permits federal financial assistance for semi-permanent housing construction in any major disaster or emergency area declared in connection with Hurricane Katrina of 2005.

Permits permanent, semi-permanent, or temporary housing located in any area having special flood hazards under the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973.

Prescribes guidelines for individual sites for manufactured modular housing.

Instructs the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to develop and maintain detailed and comprehensive mass evacuation plans for assistance recipients.</summary>
</bill>
