<bill session="117" type="h" number="9539" updated="2023-09-25T19:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ARMAS Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ARMAS Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the development of an inter-agency strategy and the submission of certain reports relating to the illegal export and trafficking of firearms from the United States to recipients in Mexico and certain Central American and Caribbean countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2022-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T19:05:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2022 or the ARMAS Act of 2022

This bill (1) requires the Department of State to report to Congress on federal efforts to disrupt the illegal export or diversion of firearms from the United States to countries in North America, South America, and the Caribbean; (2) requires the State Department and the Department of Commerce to jointly develop an inter-agency strategy for the disruption of the trafficking of firearms exported from the United States to such countries; and (3) requires the Commerce Department to submit an annual report on the export of firearms to such countries.&#160;The bill also limits the Commerce Department from issuing export licenses for covered firearms until notifying Congress of the proposed transaction.</summary>
</bill>
