<bill session="117" type="s" number="3905" updated="2023-11-09T21:58:57Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent organizational conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2022-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2022-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2022-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-01">
      <text>Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3825-3826" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-08-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3825-3826" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02T15:02:58-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02T15:13:15-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T10:09:04-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1518 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1948, S. 3905 and S. 4003. Rule provides for one hour of general debate each for H.R. 1948, S. 3905, S. 4003. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437. Rule provides that H. Res. 1516 and H. Con. Res. 124 are adopted. Rule provides that the House shall be considered to have taken from the Speaker's table H.R. 2617, with the Senate amendments thereto, to have concurred in the Senate amendments numbered 1, 2, 3, and 5, and to have concurred in the Senate amendment numbered 4 with an amendment consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 117-73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:58:39-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1518.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9745-9752" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:58:44-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1948, S. 3905 and S. 4003. Rule provides for one hour of general debate each for H.R. 1948, S. 3905, S. 4003. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437. Rule provides that H. Res. 1516 and H. Con. Res. 124 are adopted. Rule provides that the House shall be considered to have taken from the Speaker's table H.R. 2617, with the Senate amendments thereto, to have concurred in the Senate amendments numbered 1, 2, 3, and 5, and to have concurred in the Senate amendment numbered 4 with an amendment consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 117-73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:59:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on S. 3905.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T19:17:02-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T19:18:03-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on S. 3905, the Chair put the question on passage of the bill and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Keller demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T20:11:27-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9840-9841" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="524" datetime="2022-12-14T20:22:39-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 205 (Roll no. 524).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9837" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T20:22:41-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-12-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2022-12-27" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-324" type="public" datetime="2022-12-27">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-324.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7602" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1518" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5187"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2022-12-28T20:58:29Z" status="Public Law">Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act

This act addresses conflicts of interest in federal acquisitions.

Specifically, the act directs the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to revise the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) to provide and update

 definitions related to specific types of organizational conflicts of interest; definitions, guidance, and illustrative examples related to relationships of contractors with public, private, domestic, and foreign entities that may cause contract support to be subject to potential organizational conflicts; and illustrative examples of situations related to the potential organizational conflicts identified. Further, the council must revise the FAR to

 provide executive agencies with solicitation provisions and contract clauses to avoid or mitigate organizational conflicts, for agency use as needed, that require contractors to disclose information relevant to potential organizational conflicts and limit future contracting with respect to potential conflicts with the work to be performed under awarded contracts; allow agencies to tailor such solicitation provisions and contract clauses as necessary to address risks associated with conflicts of interest and other considerations that may be unique to the agency; require agencies to establish or update agency conflict of interest procedures to implement the revisions to the FAR made under this act and periodically assess and update such procedures as needed to address agency-specific conflict issues; and update FAR procedures to permit contracting officers to take into consideration professional standards and procedures to prevent organizational conflicts of interest to which an offeror or contractor is subject.</summary>
</bill>
