<bill session="117" type="h" number="4231" updated="2023-05-25T16:30:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary concerned to coordinate with impacted parties when conducting a forest management activity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Proven Forest Management Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proven Forest Management Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001109" joined="2021-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2021-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2021-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-06T02:13:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Proven Forest Management Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA), when conducting a forest management activity on National Forest System land, to coordinate with impacted parties to increase efficiency and maximize the compatibility of management practices across such land.

USDA shall conduct such an activity on National Forest System land in a manner that attains multiple ecosystem benefits, including reducing forest fuels and maintaining biological diversity. However, a forest management activity shall not be conducted if the costs associated with attaining such benefits are excessive.

Additionally, the USDA shall (1) establish any post-program ground condition criteria for a ground disturbance caused by a forest management activity required by the applicable forest plan, and (2) provide for monitoring to ascertain the attainment of relevant post-program conditions.

The bill categorically excludes certain forest management activities for reducing forest fuels from certain environmental impact requirements.

USDA or the Department of the Interior, as appropriate, in conjunction with land adjustment programs, may enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with a qualified entity to provide for fuel reduction, erosion control, reforestation, Stream Environment Zone restoration, and similar management activities on federal lands and nonfederal lands within such programs.</summary>
</bill>
