<bill session="117" type="h" number="8292" updated="2022-12-29T18:05:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require a report on Puerto Rico's progress toward rebuilding the electric grid and detailing the efforts the Federal Government is undertaking to expedite such rebuilding, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a report on Puerto Rico's progress toward rebuilding the electric grid and detailing the efforts the Federal Government is undertaking to expedite such rebuilding, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2022-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-18T19:35:08Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to report to Congress on Puerto Rico's progress toward rebuilding the electric grid and on the federal government's efforts to expedite such rebuilding.

Such report must contain

 an analysis of the state of Puerto Rico's electric grid, an analysis of the state of Puerto Rico's renewable energy generation and storage capacities, recommendations for power companies and governments to reduce the number of outages and blackouts, proposals for legislative actions and funding needed to improve the process of fund disbursement for critical projects related to electric grids, and a plan for expediting such rebuilding by not later than three months after the report is submitted.</summary>
</bill>
