<bill session="111" type="h" number="3917" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Nuclear Medicine Payment Group Clarification Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modernize and improve the Medicare payment methodology for radiopharmaceuticals under the hospital outpatient prospective payment system and to ensure equitable payment and patient access to certain low volume, high cost radiopharmaceuticals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Nuclear Medicine Payment Group Clarification Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001045"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2009-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-24T19:27:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Nuclear Medicine Payment Group Clarification Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for treatment of certain costs for a nuclear medicine group in the prospective payment system (PPS) for hospital outpatient department services.

Declares that services classified within a nuclear medicine group shall not be treated as comparable with respect to the use of resources, and therefore shall be excluded from the group, if the highest median cost (or, at the Secretary's election, mean cost) of any associated diagnostic radiopharmaceutical included in the payment for the service within the group is more than two times greater than the lowest median cost (or mean cost, if so elected) for a service within the group.</summary>
</bill>
