<bill session="109" type="s" number="2110" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:18Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Collaboration for the Recovery of Endangered Species Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to enhance the role of States in the recovery of endangered species and threatened species, to implement a species conservation recovery system, to establish certain recovery programs, to provide Federal financial assistance and a system of incentives to promote the recovery of species, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaboration for the Recovery of Endangered Species Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Incentives for Species Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Priority for Listing and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">State Government Assistance in Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000162" joined="2005-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13677-13678"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3824" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Land banking"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-02-27T20:14:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Collaboration for the Recovery of Endangered Species Act - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) to revise the role of states and private landowners in the recovery of endangered species.

State Government Assistance in Recovery Act - Revises provisions of ESA allowing the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with states for the recovery of endangered species.

Priority for Listing and Recovery Act - Revises provisions of ESA relating to the determination of endangered and threatened species to require the Secretary to establish: (1) a revised system of priorities for making endangered and threatened species determinations; (2) a schedule for making such determinations; and (3) revised recovery programs for the preservation of endangered species and recovery teams to implement such programs.

Incentives for Species Recovery Act - Establishes a system of conservation banks for the exchange of conservation credits by private landowners engaged in the recovery of endangered species.

Allows the issuance of provisional permits for the continuation of certain activities on potential endangered species habitats until a habitat conservation plan is approved.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) a tax deduction for credits purchased from a conservation bank; and (2) a tax credit for ESA-related conservation and recovery costs.

Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to protect landowners enrolled in certain ESA recovery plans from liability for incidental takings of endangered species.</summary>
</bill>
