<bill session="110" type="s" number="2900" updated="2019-11-15T21:57:47Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Partnership for Children and Families Act</title>
    <title type="display">Partnership for Children and Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide States with the incentives, flexibility and resources to develop child welfare services that focus on improving circumstances for children, whether in foster care or in their own homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3901-3902" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="4207" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-28T15:25:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Partnership for Children and Families Act - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to revise the eligibility requirements for adoption assistance and foster care maintenance payments, eliminating certain income criteria.

Allows each state with an approved part E plan to apply to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) receive foster care maintenance payment savings achieved (in a "child welfare reinvestment fund") by reducing the total number of days children in the state experience in foster care during the fiscal year; and (2) use the savings to provide children with family preservation services, family support services, time-limited family reunification services, and adoption promotion and support services, and to train the staff of state and local child welfare agencies in effective service practices.</summary>
</bill>
