<bill session="117" type="h" number="2854" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Utility Resilience and Reliability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Power Act to require the Electric Reliability Organization to propose a reliability standard that addresses the resilience of the bulk-power system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utility Resilience and Reliability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2021-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-05T14:10:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Utility Resilience and Reliability Act

This bill addresses the reliability of electric energy provided by the bulk-power system, which includes facilities and control systems necessary for operating an interconnected electric energy transmission network.

Specifically, the Electric Reliability Organization must file with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission a proposed reliability standard that addresses the resilience of the bulk-power system. For example, the standard must address the system's ability to withstand and rapidly recover from disruptions, such as extreme weather conditions. The standard must take into account regional differences.

In addition, the Department of Energy (DOE) must establish a program to provide information and recommendations to states and electric utilities on how to improve the resilience of electric grids. DOE must also post on its website a report that provides recommendations on how to minimize the need for, effects of, and duration of planned electric power outages that are due to extreme weather conditions.</summary>
</bill>
