<bill session="117" type="h" number="7436" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the quality assurance program of the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the quality assurance program of the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-20T18:18:40Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill implements oversight procedures related to quality assurance in the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

Specifically, the bill requires the VA to implement a plan to strengthen oversight of the quality assurance program in the VBA. The VA must monitor the plan to address any deficiencies.

The VBA must annually compile a list of common recurring deficiencies and action items relating to disability compensation identified in its ongoing reviews of the functions of each of its principal organizational elements. Additionally, the VBA must develop and carry out a plan to address the recurring deficiencies and action items.

The Government Accountability Office must conduct a feasibility study of the VA entering a contract with a nongovernmental entity to carry out the quality assurance program in the VBA.</summary>
</bill>
