<bill session="111" type="h" number="6062" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Criminal Alien Removal Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To identify and remove criminal aliens incarcerated in correctional facilities in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Alien Removal Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000583"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-21T14:56:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Criminal Alien Removal Act of 2010 - Directs the the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a Criminal Alien Program to: (1) identify incarcerated criminal aliens; (2) ensure that such aliens are not released into the community; and (3) remove such aliens from the United States upon release.

Makes a state that does not cooperate with the Secretary to carry out the Program ineligible for Department of Justice (DOJ) law enforcement grant programs (including the criminal alien incarceration program under the Immigration and Nationality Act).

Authorizes appropriate state officials to: (1) hold an illegal alien for up to 14 days after completion of the term of incarceration in order to effectuate transfer to federal custody if the alien is removable or not lawfully present in the United States; and (2) issue a detainer permitting an alien who completes a term of incarceration to be held until U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement takes the alien into custody.

Directs the Secretary to carry out the Program as follows: (1) by December 31, 2012, identify each criminal alien incarcerated in a federal facility who will be deportable or removable upon release; and (2) by December 31, 2014, identify each criminal alien serving a term of three or more years in a state or local facility who will be deportable or removable upon release.</summary>
</bill>
