<bill session="117" type="h" number="4638" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:32Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a panel of constitutional experts to recommend to Congress an appropriate process for providing for the case of the death of a candidate in a contingent presidential or vice-presidential election.</title>
    <title type="display">Solving an Overlooked Loophole in Votes for Executives (SOLVE) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solving an Overlooked Loophole in Votes for Executives (SOLVE) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2460" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8528" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-12T16:51:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Solving an Overlooked Loophole in Votes for Executives (SOLVE) Act

This bill establishes the Twentieth Amendment Section Four Panel, which must recommend to Congress model legislation to resolve any vacancy created by the death of a candidate in a contingent presidential or vice-presidential election. Such panel terminates 90 days after submitting its final report.

(The Twelfth Amendment to the Constitution requires that presidential and vice-presidential candidates gain a majority of electoral votes to win an election. In the event that no candidate wins a majority of electoral votes, the Twelfth Amendment requires the House of Representatives to elect the President and the Senate to elect the Vice President, which is known as a contingent election. The Twentieth Amendment to the Constitution allows Congress to establish a process in the case of the death of a candidate in a contingent presidential or vice-presidential election.)</summary>
</bill>
