<bill session="117" type="s" number="5306" updated="2023-08-22T16:15:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting a Resolution to the Tibet-China Conflict Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting a Resolution to the Tibet-China Conflict Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tibetan Policy Act of 2002 to modify certain provisions of that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2022-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2022-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8365" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-22T16:00:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting a Resolution to the Tibet-China Conflict Act

This bill addresses issues relating to Tibet, including by establishing a statutory definition of Tibet that includes areas in Chinese provinces outside the Tibet Autonomous Region (TAR).

For the purposes of U.S. policies and activities relating to Tibet, this bill defines Tibet to include the TAR and the Tibetan areas of the Qinghai, Sichuan, Gansu, and Yunnan provinces. (Generally, when China's government refers to Tibet, it means only the TAR, while Tibetan exile groups consider historical Tibet to include the TAR as well as areas in the provinces included in this bill's definition. China's government formally established the TAR in 1965.)

Furthermore, the objectives of the Office of the U.S. Special Coordinator for Tibetan Issues shall include working to ensure that U.S. government statements and documents counter disinformation about Tibet by China's government and the Chinese Communist Party, including disinformation about Tibet's history and institutions. The bill also authorizes the office to take other actions to counter such disinformation.

This bill also states that it is U.S. policy that the conflict between Tibet and China is unresolved and that Tibet's legal status remains to be determined in accordance with international law.</summary>
</bill>
