<bill session="111" type="s" number="2727" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:09Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">START I Treaty Inspections and Monitoring Protocol Continuation Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for continued application of arrangements under the Protocol on Inspections and Continuous Monitoring Activities Relating to the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Reduction and Limitation of Strategic Offensive Arms in the period following the Protocol's termination on December 5, 2009.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">START I Treaty Inspections and Monitoring Protocol Continuation Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">START I Treaty Inspections and Monitoring Protocol Continuation Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001210" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000373" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2009-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11141-11142"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment. With written report No. 111-100.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-11-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="218">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-19T17:05:18Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

START I Treaty Inspections and Monitoring Protocol Continuation Act of 2009 - Authorizes the President, under conditions set forth by this Act, to accord to eligible officials of the Russian Federation the privileges and immunities provided for in Article II, paragraph 7 of the (July 1991) Protocol on Inspections and Continuous Monitoring Activities Relating to the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Reduction and Limitation of Strategic Offensive Arms in order to facilitate continued application of the arrangements provided for in the period following the Protocol's termination on December 5, 2009.

States that: (1) An official of the Russian Federation shall be eligible for such privileges and immunities only if the official has been invited by the U.S. government after December 5, 2009, to perform an inspection or continuous monitoring activity within U.S. territory consistent with Protocol procedures; (2) such privileges and immunities shall be accorded only to perform official inspection or monitoring activities and not for personal benefit; (3) such privileges and immunities may be accorded for the entire time the official is in U.S. territory and thereafter with respect to acts previously performed in the exercise of official functions; and (4) such official shall respect U.S. laws and regulations, not interfere in internal U.S. affairs, and not engage in any professional or commercial activity for personal profit.

Terminates such authority on the earlier of June 5, 2010, or on the date of the entry into force of a U.S.-Russian agreement that supersedes the Protocol.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-100</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
