<bill session="118" type="s" number="1292" updated="2025-11-19T04:31:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Flight Education Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flight Education Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase the Federal student loan limits for students in flight education and training programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2874" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-31T19:18:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Flight Education Access Act

This bill increases federal student loan limits for students in undergraduate flight education and training programs. It also establishes a grant program to support the education of future pilots and to diversify the pilot training workforce.

Specifically, the bill increases the maximum aggregate amount of Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans to $111,000 for dependent students and $137,500 for independent students. It also increases the maximum aggregate amount of Federal Direct Stafford Loans to $65,000.

The bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to collect data and annually calculate the completion rate of each undergraduate flight education and training program at each eligible institution.

The bill also requires the Government Accountability Office to (1) examine and review the implementation of this bill, (2) develop recommendations for ED on any changes to improve the bill's implementation, and (3) submit a report to Congress on its findings and recommendations.

The bill directs ED to award grants to eligible partnerships to (1) support the education of future airline and commercial pilots, (2) diversify the pilot training workforce, and (3) generate interest and support for a career as an airline and commercial pilot. An eligible partnership is a collaboration between at least one workforce partner (e.g., a labor organization representing aircraft pilots or an entity that employs pilots) and at least one educational partner (e.g., a local or state educational agency).</summary>
</bill>
