<bill session="119" type="h" number="179" updated="2025-10-09T08:05:58Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Proven Forest Management Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proven Forest Management Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary concerned to coordinate with impacted parties when conducting a forest management activity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2025-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2025-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2025-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 15.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-11T17:04:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Proven Forest Management Act of 2025

This bill sets forth provisions to expedite the approval and implementation of forest management activities and establishes related requirements.

First, the bill categorically excludes a forest management activity conducted on National Forest System land&#160;for reducing forest fuels from certain environmental review requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 if the activity (1) does not exceed 10,000 acres (including not more than 3,000 acres of mechanical thinning), (2) is developed in a collaborative manner, and (3) is consistent with the forest plan developed for the relevant National Forest System land.

Next, the bill directs the Forest Service to conduct&#160;forest management activities in a manner that attains multiple ecosystem benefits unless the costs associated with attaining such benefits are excessive.

Additionally, the Forest Service must (1) establish any post-program ground condition criteria for a ground disturbance caused by a forest management activity required by the applicable forest plan, and (2) provide for monitoring to ascertain the attainment of relevant post-program conditions.

The bill also allows the Forest Service or the Department of the Interior, as appropriate, to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with certain entities to provide for fuel reduction, erosion control, reforestation, and similar activities on federal and nonfederal lands within land adjustment programs.

Finally, the bill directs the Forest Service, when conducting a forest management activity on National Forest System land, to coordinate with impacted parties to increase efficiency and maximize the compatibility of management practices across such land.</summary>
</bill>
