<bill session="116" type="s" number="3700" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:41Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Utilizing and Supporting Evacuated Peace Corps Volunteers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utilizing and Supporting Evacuated Peace Corps Volunteers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Peace Corps Volunteers and Trainees whose service was terminated as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic with health insurance, an expedited redeployment process, and domestic service opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2020-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6833" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mongolia"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-11T16:26:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Utilizing and Supporting Evacuated Peace Corps Volunteers Act

This bill provides benefits for Peace Corps volunteers, including health insurance for volunteers whose service was terminated due to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) outbreak.

Such a terminated Peace Corps volunteer shall receive health insurance for two months upon return to the United States. The volunteer may elect to extend such insurance, at the volunteer's expense, until the last day in which the volunteer would be eligible for unemployment benefits under the Relief for Workers Affected by Coronavirus Act. The Department of Labor shall deem a terminated volunteer eligible for such unemployment benefits if the volunteer is unemployed and not eligible for regular or extended unemployment benefits.

Executive branch departments and agencies with hiring needs, as well as the Corporation for National and Community Service, shall establish expedited processes for hiring and enrolling such terminated Peace Corps volunteers.The Peace Corps shall (1) resume all programs, to the extent possible, as soon as the COVID-19 pandemic has subsided; and (2) establish an expedited process for reenrolling Peace Corps volunteers whose service was terminated due to COVID-19.

The Peace Corps shall inform exiting volunteers of various health care options available after leaving the Peace Corps.</summary>
</bill>
