<bill session="118" type="h" number="4855" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SNAP Ban Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Ban Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study to evaluate the effects of the post-incarceration ban under section 115 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 on participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program by drug felons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-07T17:20:17Z" status="Introduced in House">SNAP Ban Study Act

This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to conduct a study to evaluate the effects of provisions that ban individuals who are convicted of drug felonies from participating in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP). Specifically, GAO must evaluate the effects of (1) the post-incarceration ban on participation by&#160;individuals convicted of a drug felony, and (2) state waiver provisions allowing for participation by these individuals.&#160;(The Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 bars convicted drug felons from participating in SNAP; however, a state may opt to serve such felons by waiving or modifying the requirement.)

The GAO must submit a report to Congress on the study and make the report publicly available on the agency's website.</summary>
</bill>
