<bill session="118" type="h" number="2585" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hawaii Air Tour Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hawaii Air Tour Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to establish an air tour management plan for certain areas of Hawaii, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1093" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-01T18:24:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Hawaii Air Tour Management Act of 2023

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to establish an air tour management plan for areas of Hawaii that are not located within the National Park System. (Current law requires the FAA to establish air tour management plans for national parks and tribal lands that are within or abutting a national park.)

The FAA and Hawaii must enter into an agreement to establish (1) the content of an air tour management plan, (2) the procedure for establishing a plan, and (3) the responsibilities of each party in carrying out the plan.

Prior to the establishment of this air tour management plan, the FAA may grant an air tour operator that is operating within Hawaii, and not within the National Park System, interim operating authority.

The legal requirements of the Administrative Procedure Act do not apply to the establishment of an air tour management plan under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
