<bill session="119" type="hr" number="492" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-11T16:51:25-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-11T16:51:25-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make a correction in the engrossment of H.R. 1.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make a correction in the engrossment of H.R. 1.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000375"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2025-06-11T16:51:25-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 499, H. Res. 492 is considered passed House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2647" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2647" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="499" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-17T14:12:23Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives to make several corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1 (One Big Beautiful Bill Act).&#160;

Specifically, the corrections strike provisions from the bill that&#160;

make a conforming amendment to the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act;reauthorize,&#160;and extend funding for, the Department of Agriculture's biobased markets program (i.e., BioPreferred Program) through FY2031;provide funding to the Department of Defense (DOD) for various intelligence-related activities and equipment, including enhancements to military intelligence programs;provide funding to DOD for exportable low-cost cruise missiles;provide funding for DOD to convert Ohio-class submarine tubes to accept additional missiles;specify that revisions to a land use plan may not prevent or delay the Department of the Interior from leasing certain federal land for oil and natural gas development;&#160;nullify the Bureau of Land Management&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Public Land Order No. 7917 for Withdrawal of Federal Lands; Cook, Lake, and Saint Louis Counties, MN that was published on January 31, 2023;reinstate certain&#160;hardrock mineral leases in the Superior National Forest in Minnesota;&#160;increase the penalty for aiding and abetting the understatement of tax liability with respect to the employee retention tax credit (ERTC) by a COVID-ERTC promoter and make other changes related to the&#160;ERTC; andspecify that provisions in the bill&#160;regarding certain Department of Health and Human Services regulations also apply to successor regulations.</summary>
</bill>
