<bill session="112" type="h" number="3108" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:11Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congress Leads by Example Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to provide enhanced enforcement authority for occupational safety and health protections applicable to the legislative branch, to provide whistleblower protections and other antidiscrimation protections for employees of the legislative branch, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congress Leads by Example Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000266" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2011-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1777"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="586" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-06T17:19:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Congress Leads by Example Act of 2011 - Amends the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to grant the General Counsel of the Office of Compliance (OOC) subpoena authority for inspections and investigations in the legislative branch under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA).

Subjects each employing office in the legislative branch to OSHA recordkeeping requirements.

Prohibits retaliation by any employing office against an employee for requesting the OOC General Counsel to take authorized action related to, or for instituting or testifying in, any proceeding that arises from the application of OSHA to that office.

Applies the whistleblower rights, protections, and remedies of the Whistleblower Protection Act of 1989 to legislative branch employees, including those of the Government Accountability Office (GAO) or the Library of Congress.

Prohibits legislative branch employing offices from: (1) discharging any employee because the employee's earnings have been subjected to garnishment for any one indebtedness; or (2) denying or terminating the employment of, or otherwise discriminating against, an employee for being a debtor or a bankrupt under the bankruptcy code.

Requires employing offices to retain records necessary to administer certain rights and protections of employees under the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, and the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.

Requires each employing office to post conspicuously all notices describing the rights and protections applicable to its employees under federal law.

Amends the federal judicial code to cover legislative branch employees under prohibitions and requirements protecting jurors' employment.</summary>
</bill>
