<bill session="108" type="h" number="4362" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:00Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to accept a parcel of Federal land in the State of Washington in trust for the Nisqually Tribe, to ensure that the acceptance of such land does not adversely affect the Bonneville Power Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to accept a parcel of Federal land in the State of Washington in trust for the Nisqually Tribe, to ensure that the acceptance of such land does not adversely affect the Bonneville Power Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-582, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 6, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-06" calendar="Union" number="346">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 346.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-26T14:36:56Z" status="Reported to House without amendment, Part I">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to accept, in trust for the Nisqually Tribe, all right, title, and interest of the United States in two specified parcels of real property, including any improvements thereon, consisting of approximately 168 acres at Fort Lewis, Washington, in lieu of the conveyance of the parcels directly to the tribe under the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002. Directs the tribe to continue to comply with provisions of that Act specifying consideration for the transfer in the form of a land exchange. Requires such consideration to be free from all liens, encumbrances, or other interests except those, if any, acceptable to the recipient.

Requires the acceptance of real property in trust for the Nisqually Tribe pursuant to this Act to recognize and preserve to the Bonneville Power Administration, in perpetuity and without the right of revocation, rights in existence at the time of conveyance under a specified permit between the Department of the Army and the Administration with regard to any portion of such property upon which the Administration retains transmission facilities. Provides that the rights recognized and preserved include the right to upgrade those facilities.

Terminates such recognized and preserved permit rights only upon the Administration's relocation of such transmission facilities, and then only with regard to that portion of those facilities that are relocated.

Directs the Secretary, as trustee for the tribe, to grant to the Administration, without consideration and subject to the same rights recognized and preserved, such additional easements across the property accepted in trust for the tribe under this Act as the Administration deems necessary to accommodate relocation or reconnection of transmission facilities from property owned by the tribe and held in trust by the Secretary.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-582</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
