<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3103</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:22:11Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:22:11Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-10-05</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. FALEOMAVAEGA:H.R. 3103.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18--The Congress shall havePower * * * To make all Laws which shall be necessary andproper for carrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, andall other Powers vested by the Constitution in the Governmentof the United States, or in any Department or Officerthereof.[Page H6625]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii24</systemCode>
            <name>Indian and Insular Affairs Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2011-10-17T19:58:10Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-10-05T14:00:17Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii24</systemCode>
            <name>Indian and Insular Affairs Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-05</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000010</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Del. Faleomavaega, Eni F. H. [D-AS-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>Eni</firstName>
        <lastName>Faleomavaega</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AS</state>
        <middleName>F. H.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Native Americans</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian social and development programs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Native Americans</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-10-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-10-14T15:10:17Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act - Establishes the Commission on Recognition of Indian Tribes. Sets forth procedures for an Indian group to submit letters of intent and a petition to the Commission requesting federal recognition as an Indian tribe (effectively transferring the federal recognition process to the Commission from the Bureau of Indian Affairs [BIA]). </p> <p>Requires recognition petitions to: (1) show that the group's members have descended from an historical Indian group, or from historical Indian groups that combined and functioned as a single autonomous entity; (2) show that the group comprises a community of related members that has been distinct from surrounding communities since 1900; and (3) include the petitioner's membership criteria and current governing procedures.</p> <p>Requires the Commission to make an expedited decision or conduct a preliminary hearing as to whether a petitioner should be recognized as an Indian tribe. </p> <p>Gives petitioners a hearing before an adjudicatory panel of the Commission if: (1) an interested party rebuts an expedited decision in favor of the petitioner, or (2) the expedited decision or preliminary hearing does not result in the petitioner's recognition. </p> <p>Gives Indian groups previously denied recognition by the BIA the right to an adjudicatory hearing if this Act's recognition criteria affect the merits of their petitions.</p> <p>Authorizes a petitioner or any interested party to request the Commission to reconsider a final determination of an adjudicatory panel.</p> <p>Makes an Indian tribe that is recognized by the Commission: (1) eligible for the services and benefits from the federal government that are available to other federally recognized Indian tribes, and (2) subject to the same responsibilities, obligations, privileges, and immunities of those tribes. </p> <p>Allows the recognition or restoration of Indian tribes by: (1) federal law, (2) the Commission, (3) reorganization under the Indian Reorganization Act or the Alaska Indian Reorganization Act, and (4) any final decision of a U.S. court. </p> <p>Applies the Indian Reorganization Act to all tribes recognized by the Commission, even if they were not under federal jurisdiction when that Act was enacted. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to Indian groups seeking federal recognition as Indian tribes to enable them to conduct research to substantiate, and prepare the documentation necessary for submission of, petitions under this Act. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To establish a Commission on Recognition of Indian Tribes to review and act on petitions by Indian groups applying for Federal recognition, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Indian Tribal Federal Recognition Administrative Procedures Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2011-10-05T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr3103ih/xml/BILLS-112hr3103ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-10-17</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee Indian and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
