<bill session="116" type="s" number="1113" updated="2022-11-01T19:32:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Enhancing America's Core Diplomatic Capabilities Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing America's Core Diplomatic Capabilities Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect and enhance core diplomatic capabilities at the Department of State.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-28T22:27:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhancing America's Core Diplomatic Capabilities Act of 2019

This bill revises various provisions related to Foreign Service staffing and training, including by setting minimum staffing requirements.

The Department of State shall take all practicable measures to maintain within the service certain staffing levels at various experience levels, including at least 905 senior officers. The State Department shall (1) periodically report to Congress on service staffing levels, (2) explain reasons for any failure to meet minimum targets, and (3) provide a plan to address any deficiencies.

The State Department shall appoint a Director of Human Resources. The bill revises the qualifications for certain director positions within the service.

The State Department shall reestablish the Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy, which shall select participants based on past performance and future potential. The State Department may (1) suspend maximum in-class limits for a member of the service while the member is engaged in long-term training, and (2) establish an incentive program to encourage members of the service to maintain skills in critical foreign languages.

The State Department's entry-level appointments for the service shall be based on (1) long-term projections designed to provide for the regular and predictable recruitment and promotion of staff, and (2) career development patterns designed to meet the service's needs.</summary>
</bill>
