<bill session="118" type="h" number="6572" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:39Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-15T18:27:03-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-15T18:27:03-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="display">Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to take actions necessary and appropriate to promote the competitiveness of the United States related to the deployment, use, application, and competitiveness of blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001275"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2024-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2024-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 46 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-501.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-05-10" calendar="Union" number="417">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 417.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T15:32:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T15:32:13-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3040-3042" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T15:32:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6572.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-14T15:38:45-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15T18:23:39-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3256-3257" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="210" datetime="2024-05-15T18:27:03-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 334 - 79 (Roll no. 210).</text>
      <reference ref="5/14/2024 CR H3040-3041" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15T18:27:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-04T14:20:05Z" status="Passed House">Deploying American Blockchains Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Commerce to support the leadership of the United States in the use of blockchain technology and other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization. Generally, blockchain technology is a distributed digital ledger that uses cryptography to share verified information across a network of computers. Tokens refer to the transferrable, digital representation of information recorded on blockchain technology and tokenization is the process of creating a token.

Specifically, Commerce must advise the President on policies related&#160;to the deployment and use of blockchain technology and other distributed ledger technology, applications built on blockchain technology or other distributed ledger technology, tokens, and tokenization. Commerce also must establish advisory committees to support the adoption of blockchain technology to facilitate the development of best practices with respect to blockchain technology, applications built on blockchain technology, tokens, and tokenization.

Commerce must report annually on the activities under this bill and provide any recommendations for additional legislation to strengthen U.S. competitiveness with respect to blockchain technology.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-501</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
