<bill session="118" type="h" number="3404" updated="2025-11-19T03:53:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate regulations relating to the approval of foreign manufacturers of cylinders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2024-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2024-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2024-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000135" joined="2024-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000829" joined="2024-11-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1632" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-06T15:43:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2023 

This bill expands the application, testing, and inspection requirements for a foreign manufacturer of cylinders used for transporting hazardous materials in the United States (e.g., compressed gas cylinders).

Current regulations&#160;require a foreign manufacturer to apply for approval from the&#160;Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) of the Department of Transportation (DOT) for testing such cylinders outside of the United States.&#160;The bill requires that, to obtain an approval, a foreign manufacturer must answer in their application specified questions, including whether the manufacturer is or has been subject to various civil or criminal penalties.

Further, DOT must establish a process for any interested party to request a reevaluation of an approval for a foreign manufacturer's cylinders to review the accuracy and safety of the manufacturer's actions.

DOT must also revise the foreign inspection regulations to

require that annual inspections of foreign manufacturers be carried out if DOT determines there is good cause;specify that a refusal of inspection shall result in the loss of good standing;allow DOT to request testing and production records and random sample testing; andallow for the recovery of the costs of foreign inspections, including travel and time.The bill limits an approval to one year; however, DOT may extend an approval for five years for a manufacturer who meets certain requirements.

On an annual basis, DOT must publish a list of approved foreign manufacturers of cylinders on the department's website.</summary>
</bill>
