<bill session="119" type="h" number="597" updated="2025-08-02T08:05:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PURR Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pet Food Uniform Regulatory Reform Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PURR Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to clarify and update the authority of the Food and Drug Administration to ensure national uniformity in the regulation of the labels, labeling, and advertising of companion animal pet food, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000809"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2025-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000379" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2025-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2025-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000402" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001228" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2025-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-03T17:46:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Pet Food Uniform Regulatory Reform Act of 2025 or the PURR Act of 2025

This bill establishes the Food and Drug Administration's Center for Veterinary Medicine (CVM) as the sole regulatory authority over pet food for dogs and cats. It also provides certain flexibilities for pet food manufacturers with respect to the types of ingredients they may use and the associated labeling and marketing&#160;requirements.

The bill specifies that, with exceptions for certain existing oversight activities,&#160;no state or local government may establish, implement, or enforce any authority or requirement relating to pet food marketing or labeling and instead provides for oversight by the CVM.

The bill requires the CVM to review and act on pet food ingredient submissions within 90 days.&#160;Additionally, the bill provides a presumption that pet food ingredients are generally recognized as safe (GRAS) if they are recognized as acceptable per the Association of American Feed Control Officials and the&#160;CVM does not find otherwise. Manufacturers may voluntarily notify the CVM of ingredients that are considered GRAS but that have not yet been specifically recognized as such.

The bill also allows manufacturers to state, without prior approval, that their products (1) sometimes, but not always, have certain ingredients (e.g., flavors); (2) have certain health benefits (e.g., tartar control); or (3) are human grade or natural, if certain conditions are met.

&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
