<bill session="118" type="h" number="567" updated="2025-01-24T18:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SALVAGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALVAGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Salvaging American Lumber Via Action with Greater Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expedite certain activities related to salvage operations and reforestation activities on National Forest System lands or public lands in response to catastrophic events, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2023-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-14T20:40:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Salvaging American Lumber Via Action with Greater Efficiency Act or the SALVAGE Act 

This bill provides for certain activities related to salvage operations and certain reforestation activities conducted on National Forest System lands or public lands.

The bill categorically excludes salvage operations carried out by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior, on certain National Forest System lands or certain public lands, respectively, from the requirement to prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement.

Each salvage operation covered by the categorical exclusion may not contain treatment units that exceed a total of 10,000 acres.

An environmental assessment for a salvage operation or reforestation activity proposed to be conducted on National Forest System lands or public lands that are adversely impacted by a large-scale catastrophic event shall be completed within 60 days after the conclusion of the event. In the case of such reforestation activities USDA and Interior shall, to the maximum extent practicable, achieve reforestation of at least 75% of the impacted lands during the five-year period following the conclusion of the catastrophic event.

No later than 60 days after a wildfire is contained on National Forest System lands, USDA shall convert any timber sales on lands impacted by such wildfire to salvage sales.

No restraining order, preliminary injunction, or injunction pending appeal shall be issued by any U.S. court respecting any decision to prepare or conduct a salvage operation or reforestation activity in response to a large-scale catastrophic event.</summary>
</bill>
