<bill session="108" type="h" number="1656" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:07Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Employees Against Violence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Labor Relations Act to provide the National Labor Relations Board with expanded statutory authority with respect to employees and labor organizations engaged in or encouraging violent and other potentially injurious conduct.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Employees Against Violence Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Employees Against Violence Act - Amends the National Labor Relations Act to revise the authority of the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) with respect to employees and labor organizations engaged in or encouraging violent, coercive, or other potentially injurious actions.Prohibits the NLRB from ordering reinstatement of any employee who has engaged or is engaging in such actions.Directs the NLRB to revoke the exclusive bargaining status of any labor organization found to engage directly in or encourage the use of such actions.Provides for the seeking of injunctive relief if a labor organization is charged with directly engaging in or encouraging the use of violence.Requires that certain petitions for injunctive relief be sought within seven days after the filing of an unfair labor practice charge.</summary>
</bill>
