<bill session="109" type="h" number="4422" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:38Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding Explosives for Homeland Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance homeland security by preventing unauthorized access to explosive materials stored by State or local agencies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Explosives for Homeland Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000789" joined="2006-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-19T19:52:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding Explosives for Homeland Security Act - Requires each state to submit to the Attorney General a written report (and subsequent updates) that specifies each location at which any agency operating under state law stores or keeps explosive materials that have been transported in interstate or foreign commerce and the types and amounts of such materials. Directs the Attorney General to prescribe final regulations governing the storage of such materials by state or local agencies, including public safety and security standards and requirements for video surveillance or an alarm system.

Authorizes the Attorney General to enter during business hours any place where a state or local agency stores explosive materials that have been transported in interstate or foreign commerce, for the purpose of inspecting and determining whether they are stored in compliance with such regulations.

Authorizes the Attorney General to reduce by 10% the funds that an agency would otherwise receive under any Department of Justice grant program if it fails to comply. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to make matching grants to state and local law enforcement agencies to cover the cost of complying with such regulations.</summary>
</bill>
