<bill session="118" type="h" number="5055" updated="2025-11-18T21:26:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Office of Technology Assessment Improvement and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of Technology Assessment Improvement and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To rename the Office of Technology Assessment as the Congressional Office of Technology, to revise the functions and duties of the Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2023-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2023-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2024-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2023-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2024-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2023-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2618" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-18T22:51:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Office of Technology Assessment Improvement and Enhancement Act

This bill renames and revises the functions and duties of the Office of Technology Assessment which, composed of a Technology Assessment Board and a director, provides Congress with assessments of probable technology application impacts. (The office has not been funded since FY1996.)

Specifically, the bill renames the office the Congressional Office of Technology, and it requires the office to undertake additional duties, such as providing to Members of Congress (1) certain information without the need for board review, (2) certain technical assistance on legislation related to science and technology without the need for board review, and (3) objective policy options on how Members may achieve goals with respect to science and technology policy.

The bill authorizes individual Members of Congress to submit to the board a request that the office undertake an assessment activity. Additionally, the bill requires the Congressional Research Service and the Government Accountability Office to coordinate technology assessment activities with the office to avoid duplication or overlapping of research activities.

The bill also (1) allows the office to temporarily appoint specified technical and professional personnel to work for the office, (2) requires the office to make the findings of completed analyses publicly available, (3) revises the appointment of board members, (4) requires the board to hold an annual meeting at which Members of Congress may appear and present information regarding technology assessment activities, and (5) requires the board to report annually on the activities of the office.</summary>
</bill>
