<bill session="118" type="h" number="9488" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:57Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-16T14:22:40-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-16T14:22:40-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require the disclosure of the card verification value as a condition of the acceptance of online contributions made through the use of credit or debit cards in elections for Federal office and to prohibit the acceptance of contributions made through the use of gift cards and prepaid credit cards in such elections, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require the disclosure of the card verification value as a condition of the acceptance of online contributions made through the use of credit or debit cards in elections for Federal office and to prohibit the acceptance of contributions made through the use of gift cards in such elections, and for other purposes</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Handling of Internet Electronic Donations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Secure Handling of Internet Electronic Donations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Secure Handling of Internet Electronic Donations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="display">SHIELD Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2024-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2024-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000632" joined="2024-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000597" joined="2024-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2024-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 118-696.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-20" calendar="Union" number="590">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 590.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-12-16T14:12:26-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Steil moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-16T14:12:36-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7149-7151" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-16T14:12:37-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 9488.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-16T14:22:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7149-7150" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-16T14:22:42-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-16T14:22:44-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission (FEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-08T14:58:32Z" status="Reported to House">Secure Handling of Internet Electronic Donations Act or the SHIELD Act

This bill addresses campaign finance in federal elections.

Specifically, the bill requires political committees, when accepting a credit&#160;or debit card contribution over the internet, to collect the credit or debit card's verification value. The card's billing address must be in the United States, with an exception. For a contributor who is living outside of the United States and, at the time of the contribution, is a U.S.&#160;national or lawfully admitted for permanent residence,&#160;the bill requires the contributor to provide the political committee&#160;with his or her voter registration address or identification document (e.g., U.S. passport).

Additionally, the bill prohibits political committees from accepting a contribution made through the use of a general-use prepaid card, gift certificate, or store gift card.

The bill also&#160;prohibits&#160;knowingly directing, helping, or assisting any person in making a contribution in the name of another person.

The Federal Election Commission must, within 10 days, promulgate regulations to carry out this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-696</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
