<bill session="111" type="h" number="2081" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:31Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Park Educational Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a partnership between the Department of Education and the National Park Service to provide educational opportunities for students and teachers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Park Educational Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001229" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001060" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2009-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2009-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-28T21:21:19Z" status="Introduced in House">National Park Educational Partnership Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to establish the National Park Ranger School Partnerships program authorizing the Secretary of Education to award competitive, three-year grants to schools and local educational agencies (LEAs) to enter into partnerships with the National Park Service (NPS) to provide kindergarten through grade 12 (K-12) students with educational programs and K-12 teachers with professional development emphasizing science, the environment, natural resources, mathematics, civics, and history. Makes education service agencies eligible for grants to carry out such educational programs and professional development activities.

Deems schools and LEAs to be eligible for such a grant only if they: (1) have, are capable of, or will develop certain connections to the NPS; (2) have been identified as needing improvement under title I of the ESEA; and (3) serve a significant percentage of low-income students.

Permits: (1) the NPS to participate in the Mathematics and Science Partnerships program that provides training to teachers of such subjects under title II of the ESEA; and (2) educational service agencies, including federal agencies that serve as educational service providers, to partner with LEAs under such title's Teaching American History Grant Program.</summary>
</bill>
