<bill session="119" type="h" number="4229" updated="2025-09-26T16:16:05Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to require prior approval from Congress before the Comptroller General may pursue a civil action under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to require prior approval from Congress before the Comptroller General may pursue a civil action under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2025-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2025-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000603" joined="2025-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2025-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2025-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-26T16:14:56Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill prohibits the Government Accountability Office (GAO) from bringing a civil action under the Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (ICA) to compel the release of appropriated funds&#160;unless Congress has enacted a concurrent resolution authorizing GAO to bring the action.

The ICA generally limits the authority of the President to impound (i.e., withhold from obligation or expenditure) funds that have been appropriated by Congress and establishes related procedures. Under current law, GAO is authorized to bring a civil action to compel a federal agency to release budget authority for obligation if the budget authority is required to be released under the ICA, and the agency has not released the funds. This bill prohibits GAO from bringing such an action without prior congressional approval.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
