<bill session="116" type="h" number="6157" updated="2022-08-10T23:25:36Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency for Student Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to collect and include certain student outcome information in the GI Bill comparison tool of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency for Student Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000591"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2020-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-25T16:55:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency for Student Veterans Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide student outcome information to veterans and members of the Armed Forces under its comprehensive policy to provide education information on institutions of higher learning and training opportunities via the GI Bill comparison tool.

Specifically, the VA must enter into a memorandum of understanding with specified agencies (e.g., Department of Defense) to receive specified information from such agencies about student outcomes with respect to students who are veterans, members of the Armed Forces, or dependents of such veterans or members. The bill requires the agencies to provide information including, but not limited to, graduation rates, student loan default rates, and median earnings for graduates.

The VA must develop a plan to protect personally identifiable information when providing information on aggregate student outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
