<bill session="115" type="s" number="622" updated="2023-01-11T13:36:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair and Open Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve open competition and Federal Government neutrality towards the labor relations of Federal Government contractors on Federal and federally funded construction projects.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Open Competition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2017-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2017-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2017-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1552" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-11-07T17:19:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair and Open Competition Act

 This bill prohibits a federal executive agency that awards any construction contract after the enactment of this bill from requiring or prohibiting a contract bidder from entering into agreements with labor organizations (i.e., Project Labor Agreements [PLAs]) or otherwise discriminating against a bidder or contractor who signs, or refuses to sign, a PLA.

Agencies that award grants, provide financial assistance, or enter into cooperative agreements for construction projects after the enactment of this bill must ensure that the bid specifications, project agreements, or other controlling documents for such projects do not contain any requirements or prohibitions relating to PLAs.

An agency may exempt a particular project or grant from the prohibition of this bill if it determines that special circumstances exist requiring an exemption to avert an imminent threat to public health or safety or to serve the national security.</summary>
</bill>
