<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3555</number>
    <updateDate>2019-02-20T23:43:39Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-02-24T04:16:53Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-09-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-09-19T15:16:26Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>TAP Modernization Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>4051</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-03-28</actionDate>
          <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Veterans Jobs Corps Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>6563</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-10-19</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>TAP Modernization Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>2246</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-06-13</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Veterans' Small Business Opportunity Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3210</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-06-13</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-567.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require States to recognize the military experience of veterans when issuing licenses and credentials to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3353</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-06-28</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Veterans Small Business Protection Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3405</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-07-19</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-09-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-09-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001135</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Burr, Richard [R-NC]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Burr</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName>Mauze</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001268</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Scott P. [R-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Scott</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>P.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2012-09-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inhofe, James M. [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Inhofe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2012-09-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee hiring</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment and training programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Unemployment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-09-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-11-08T15:52:28Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Careers for Veterans Act of 2012 - Directs the head of each federal agency to develop a plan for exercising, during the five-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act, current Department of Defense (DOD) and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) authority to hire qualified veterans for positions within the federal government. Includes as qualified veterans those who: (1) are disabled or recently separated; (2) served on active duty during a war or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized; or (3) while serving on active duty, participated in a military operation for which an Armed Forces service medal was awarded. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to ensure that, under such plans, agencies shall appoint no less than 10,000 qualified veterans during the five-year period.</p> <p>Requires a state, as a condition for receipt of a grant or contract from the VA for support of disabled veterans' outreach specialists and local veterans' employment representatives, to establish a program which issues a license or credential to a veteran without requiring any training or apprenticeship if such veteran: (1) receives a satisfactory score on completion of an examination administered by that state, and (2) has at least 10 years of experience in a military occupational specialty that is similar to the civilian occupation for which such license or credential is required.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) furnish each one-stop (job search) center with a list of all Internet websites and applications identified as beneficial for veterans in pursuit of employment; and (2) coordinate with public and private entities to identify websites and applications not included on such list that match veterans seeking employment with available jobs based on skills acquired as members of the Armed Forces, and allow employers to post information about available jobs.</p> <p>Expands VA small business contracting goals to include small businesses fully, but conditionally, owned by one or more veterans.</p> <p>Treats the surviving spouse of a service-disabled veteran who acquires the ownership interest in a small business of the deceased veteran as such veteran, for purposes of eligibility for VA service-disabled small business contracting goals and preferences, for a period of: (1) 10 years after the veteran's death, if such veteran was either 100% disabled or died from a service-connected disability; or (2) 3 years after such death, if the veteran was less than 100% disabled and did not die from a service-connected disability.</p> <p>Treats a small business acquired by the surviving spouse or dependent from a member killed during active duty as a small business owned and controlled by a service-disabled veteran, for purposes of VA small business contracting goals and preferences. Continues such treatment for the period beginning on the date of the member's death and ending on the earlier of the date on which the surviving spouse remarries or relinquishes, or the date on which the surviving dependent relinquishes, such ownership interest or ten years after the member's death.</p> <p>Provides that if the Secretary determines, for purposes of VA small business contracting goals, that an individual would have had a greater degree of ownership of a small business in a state other than a community property state, then the Secretary shall treat such small business as licensed in a non-community property state.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Labor, during the three-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act, to provide the Transition Assistance Program (TAP) to veterans and their spouses at locations other than military installations in at least three, and up to five, states selected by the Secretary based on the highest rates of veteran unemployment.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Careers for Veterans Act of 2012</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Careers for Veterans Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Careers for Veterans Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require Federal agencies to hire veterans, to require States to recognize the military experience of veterans when issuing licenses and credentials to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2012-09-19T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s3555is/xml/BILLS-112s3555is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-09-19</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
