<bill session="118" type="h" number="773" updated="2024-07-25T08:05:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homelessness and Behavioral Health Care Coordination Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homelessness and Behavioral Health Care Coordination Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To help persons in the United States experiencing homelessness and significant behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, by authorizing a grant program within the Department of Housing and Urban Development to assist State and local governments, Continuums of Care, community-based organizations that administer both health and homelessness services, and providers of services to people experiencing homelessness, better coordinate health care and homelessness services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000631"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2023-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3165" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-26T18:21:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Homelessness and Behavioral Health Care Coordination Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to award competitive grants to improve coordination of health care and homelessness services for individuals who are homeless, have significant behavioral health issues (e.g., mental health and substance use disorders), and voluntarily seek assistance. Entities eligible for these five-year grants include local and tribal governments, public housing agencies that administer housing choice vouchers, and certain nonprofits.

The bill prohibits grant funds from being used to pay for rent or health care, except to increase the availability of Naloxone (i.e. medication that reverses opioid overdoses) and provide training for its administration.

Further, the bill requires HUD to establish an interagency working group to (1) consult on the grant program, and (2) develop and circulate materials for providers of health care and homelessness services that simplify the services each offers in order to help each sector better understand the other.</summary>
</bill>
