<bill session="116" type="s" number="1855" updated="2022-11-01T13:51:06Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ASPIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access, Success, and Persistence In Reshaping Education Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ASPIRE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve college access and college completion for all students.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2019-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-14T16:26:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Access, Success, and Persistence in Reshaping Education Act of 2019 or the ASPIRE Act

This bill revises the Pell Grant Program to provide incentives for&#160;institutions of higher education (IHEs) to increase (1) enrollment of students who receive Pell Grants, and (2) graduation rates of their students.

Specifically, the Department of Education (ED) must&#160;rank IHEs participating in student financial aid programs. First, ED must rank IHEs based on the percentage of first-time, full-time students who receive Pell Grants and are enrolled at the IHEs. The IHEs in the bottom 5% must improve the enrollment of those students by specific deadlines or pay a fee-per-student penalty.

Second, ED must rank&#160;IHEs based on the percentage of first-time, full-time students who enroll at the school and graduate within six years. The bill gives IHEs in the bottom 5% the option of receiving funding to improve student graduation rates. Those IHEs must improve those rates by specific deadlines or pay a penalty.

ED must&#160;use the fees to fund (1)&#160;grant programs for improving graduation rates; and (2) a bonus program for providing nonfinancial rewards to IHEs with proven records of affordability, access, and success for low- income,&#160;moderate-income, or working class students.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
