<bill session="117" type="h" number="3398" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FLUENT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the English language and literacy skills of English language learners and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Families Learning and Understanding English Together Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLUENT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-06T14:12:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Families Learning and Understanding English Together Act of 2021 or the FLUENT Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Education (ED) to establish a grant program to improve the literacy and English skills of English language learners.

Specifically, ED may award grants to providers of family literacy services to provide these services to families with English language learners. These services may only be provided to a family in which each caregiver is 16 years of age or older and at least one child is under the age of 8.

Further, ED must make grants to or enter into contracts with at least two national organizations with expertise in providing family literacy services to English language learners. These national organizations must provide grantees with technical assistance and training.</summary>
</bill>
