<bill session="117" type="s" number="3502" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Achieving Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Achieving Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Achieving Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Office of Civil Rights, Equity, and Community Inclusion at the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2022-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-133.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-07-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="450">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 450.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-05T14:30:21Z" status="Reported to Senate">Achieving Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2022 

This bill establishes an Office of Civil Rights, Equity, and Community Inclusion within the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).

The office shall be responsible for

 improving underserved community access to disaster assistance and improving the quality of assistance such communities receive; reviewing FEMA preparedness, response, and recovery programs and activities to ensure the elimination of disparities in the delivery of such programs and activities to underserved communities; and carrying out responsibilities of the previous Office of Equal Rights. The bill defines underserved community to mean an historically disadvantaged community, including the Native American, African-American, Asian, Hispanic, Pacific Islander, Middle Eastern and North African, and rural communities, as well as low-income and disability communities.

The bill establishes within the office a Disability Coordinator to ensure that the needs of disabled individuals are being addressed in emergency preparedness and disaster relief.

The office shall develop measures to evaluate the effectiveness of its activities aimed at reducing disparities in services provided to underserved communities.

During the period of time for which there is a major disaster or emergency declared by the President with respect to COVID-19, the office shall regularly consult with state, local, territorial, and tribal government officials and community-based organizations from underserved communities that it identifies as disproportionately impacted by COVID-19.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-133</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
