<bill session="119" type="h" number="2329" updated="2025-09-03T08:05:43Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Uzbekistan Normalized Trade Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uzbekistan Normalized Trade Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the extension of nondiscriminatory treatment (normal trade relations treatment) to products of Uzbekistan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2025-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2025-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2025-09-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-18T18:29:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Uzbekistan Normalized Trade Act

This bill addresses trade between the United States and&#160;Uzbekistan.&#160;

Specifically, the bill authorizes the President to determine that&#160;Section 402 of the Trade Act of 1974 (commonly known as the Jackson-Vanik amendment) does not apply to Uzbekistan. The Jackson-Vanik amendment&#160;denies normal trade relations (NTR) status to some current and former&#160;nonmarket economy countries unless they comply with certain freedom-of-emigration requirements. Under a provision of this amendment, the President may&#160;extend NTR status to a country affected by the amendment by waiving the freedom-of-emigration requirements or determining that the country is not in violation of those requirements, subject to an annual review.&#160;Uzbekistan has received temporary NTR status since 1992.

Additionally, the bill authorizes the President to extend&#160;permanent NTR status to Uzbekistan.

The bill shall take effect on the date on which the President certifies to Congress that Uzbekistan has acceded to the Marrakesh Agreement Establishing the World Trade Organization (WTO) and is a WTO member.</summary>
</bill>
