<bill session="118" type="s" number="2447" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Telehealth and Education for Rural Communities Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Telehealth and Education for Rural Communities Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the distance learning and telemedicine grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5308" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-15T20:05:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Telehealth and Education for Rural Communities Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 and modifies the Distance Learning and Telemedicine Loan and Grant Program that is administered by the Department of Agriculture (USDA). The program supports telemedicine and distance learning services in rural areas through telecommunications, computer networks, and other advanced technology by students, teachers, medical professionals, and residents of rural areas.

The bill expands the scope of the program to specifically allow the use of program funds for operational expenses associated with telemedicine programs. It also allows the USDA to waive matching fund requirements in certain circumstances and requires USDA to set aside a specific amount of funding allotments for programs that focus on substance use disorder treatment or mental health services.</summary>
</bill>
