<bill session="108" type="s" number="650" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-03">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the Food and Drug Administration to require certain research into drugs used in pediatric patients.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2003-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000439" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000445" joined="2003-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3897-3898"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3898-3900" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Gregg with an amendment. With written report No. 108-84. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="183">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 183.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9811-9819" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S9811-9813" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-07-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9816-9818" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24T10:04:19-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19T15:27:12-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19T15:27:29-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11567-11572" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19T15:27:31-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 650.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2003-11-19T15:55:05-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11567-11569" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19T15:55:22-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-12-03" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-155" type="public" datetime="2003-12-03">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-155.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2857" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Warning labels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1360"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2007-05-09T21:37:15Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Pediatric Research Equity Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require license applications for new drugs and biological products to assess such drug's or product's safety and effectiveness for relevant pediatric subpopulations, including dosage.

Permits deferral of such assessments under specified circumstances, including if the Secretary of Health and Human Services finds that the drug or biological product is ready for approval for use in adults before pediatric studies are complete. Permits full waiver of such assessments under certain conditions, including if: (1) studies are highly impractical or impossible; or (2) there is no meaningful therapeutic advantage or benefit in the pediatric population and the drug or biological product is not likely to be used in a substantial number of pediatric patients. Permits partial waivers at the request of an applicant for a specific pediatric subpopulation if any of the full waiver grounds apply to that subpopulation or reasonable attempts for a pediatric formulation for that subpopulation have failed.Requires labels to provide indication in cases in which a waiver has been granted due to evidence a product would be unsafe or ineffective in pediatric populations. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to specify a date for submission of pediatric assessments if: (1) the drug or biological product would represent a meaningful therapeutic benefit for pediatric patients for one or more claimed indications and the absence of adequate labeling could pose significant risks to pediatric patients; or (2) it is used for a substantial number of pediatric patients for the labeled indications and the absence of adequate labeling could pose significant risks to pediatric patients. Sets forth criteria for full waiver and partial waivers of such requirement. Requires labels to provide indication in cases in which a waiver has been granted due to evidence a product would be unsafe or ineffective in pediatric populations. Requires the Secretary to issue a written request for related pediatric studies under the Public Health Service Act or under this Act before requiring an assessment for a drug. Directs the Secretary, after determining that there is no agreement to such a written request, to certify whether the Secretary has sufficient funds to conduct the study under the Public Health Service Act, taking into account prioritization of drugs for which pediatric studies are needed. States that if a person fails to submit an assessment under this Act, or a request for approval of a pediatric formulation, the relevant drug or biological product may be considered misbranded solely because of that failure and subject to relevant enforcement action. Provides that the new authority under this Act to require pediatric studies shall only remain in effect so long as the pediatric exclusivity provisions under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act also remain in effect (until October 1, 2007). (Sec. 4) Declares that the provisions of this Act pertaining to research into pediatric uses for new drugs and biological products shall apply to license applications for such drugs and products submitted to the Secretary on or after April 1, 1999. Specifies procedures for the treatment of applications submitted between April 1, 1999, and the date of the enactment of this Act with respect to which waivers or deferrals were granted under previous regulations and with respect to which no waivers or deferrals were granted.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-84</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
