<bill session="116" type="s" number="3391" updated="2022-02-08T23:39:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Connecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Active Transportation System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Active Transportation System Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to carry out an active transportation investment program to make grants to eligible applicants to build safe and connected options for bicycles and walkers within and between communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2020-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2020-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2020-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5696" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-24T17:38:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Connecting America's Active Transportation System Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to carry out an active transportation infrastructure investment program to provide competitive grants for states, Indian tribes, multi-county special districts, and local or regional government organizations to construct certain projects to provide safe and connected active transportation facilities, including for sidewalks, bikeways, and trails that connect between destinations within a community or between communities, metropolitan regions, or states.

DOT must select grant recipients within 150 days after funds become available under this bill.

The bill sets forth various limitations on the use of funds, including that DOT must

 obligate at least 30% of funds to certain projects, including projects that connect people with public transportation, businesses, workplaces, schools, residences, recreation areas, and other community activity centers; set aside at least $3 million to provide planning grants for eligible organizations to develop plans for active transportation networks and active transportation spines; and set aside at least $2 million to cover the costs of administration, research, technical assistance, communications, and training activities under the program. The federal share of grants must not exceed 80% of the total project cost.</summary>
</bill>
