<bill session="118" type="h" number="6890" updated="2025-11-19T03:36:43Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MORE DOT Grants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MORE DOT Grants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">More Opportunities for Rural Economies from DOT Grants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the process for awarding grants under certain programs of the Department of Transportation to certain counties in which the majority of land is owned or managed by the Federal Government and to other units of local government and Tribal governments in those counties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001228"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1579" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3594" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-04T14:03:10Z" status="Introduced in House">More Opportunities for Rural Economies from DOT Grants Act or the MORE DOT Grants Act 

This bill revises the process for awarding grants to high-density public land counties and any units of tribal or local governments within such counties under certain Department of Transportation (DOT) programs. Examples of qualifying grant programs include the Infrastructure for Rebuilding America (INFRA) grant program and the Airport Improvement Program (AIP). A high-density public land county is a county that has a population of not more than 100,000 people and in which the federal government owns or manages more than 50% of the land.

For these jurisdictions, any requirement for local matching funds under a qualifying grant program must be reduced by 50%.

On request, DOT must provide additional technical assistance to such jurisdictions before and during the annual application period for each qualifying grant program.

DOT must also prioritize grant applications from such jurisdictions that have not received support under the qualifying grant program during the 10-year period preceding the date of the application.

In approving applications for a qualifying grant program, DOT must give special consideration to an application from a high-density public land county or unit of local government within such a county with respect to any rural-set aside designated for the program. DOT may give special consideration to an application from a tribal government within such a county.</summary>
</bill>
