<bill session="117" type="s" number="5349" updated="2023-05-10T03:45:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">International Competition for American Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Competition for American Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify certain provisions relating to the taxation of international entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2847" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5376" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-09T14:09:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">International Competition for American Jobs Act 

This bill modifies provisions relating to the taxation of foreign entities.

Among other provisions, the bill

 makes permanent the look-thru rule for controlled foreign corporations (CFCs). (A look-thru rule provides that dividends, interest, rents and royalties that one CFC receives or accrues from a related CFC are not treated as foreign personal holding company income); modifies the tax deduction for foreign-derived intangible income and global intangible low-taxed income; modifies the base erosion minimum tax (10% minimum tax imposed to prevent corporations operating in the United States from avoiding tax liability by shifting profits out of the United States); modifies tax rules allocating certain tax deductions for purposes of the foreign tax credit limitation; restores the limitation on the attribution of stock ownership for purposes of applying constructive ownership rules; and includes specified amounts in the gross income of CFC shareholders.</summary>
</bill>
