<bill session="118" type="h" number="1531" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:11Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for the renewed availability of funds to construct the border wall upon the deployment of the National Guard to the southern land border of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the renewed availability of funds to construct the border wall upon the deployment of the National Guard to the southern land border of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001220"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="989" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="422" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-24T22:34:57Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill addresses the construction of a border barrier system along the southern border, such as requiring construction activities to resume if certain conditions are met.

Specifically, during any period in which the Armed Forces or the National Guard are performing active service at the U.S. southern land border, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must resume all activities related to constructing physical barriers and accompanying infrastructure that were underway or planned prior to January 20, 2021.

DHS must also (1) expend all funds appropriated or explicitly authorized for constructing such a border barrier system on or after October 1, 2016; and (2) honor all agreements related to the construction of the border barrier system that were entered into before January 20, 2021, with the consent of all applicable parties to revive such agreements.

DHS may not cancel any contracts for the construction of the border barrier system entered into on or before January 20, 2021.

The bill also extends the availability of certain funds made available from FY2018 through FY2021 for construction of the border barrier system.</summary>
</bill>
