<bill session="117" type="s" number="1504" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:03Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sponsor Promote and Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to issue rules requiring enhanced disclosures for blank check companies during initial public offering and pre-merger stages, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sponsor Promote and Compensation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-04T15:20:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sponsor Promote and Compensation Act 

This bill establishes additional disclosure requirements for a blank check company (e.g., a special purpose acquisition company) during an initial public offering or prior to a merger. A blank check company is a development stage company that issues a penny stock and (1) has no specific business plan or purpose, or (2) has indicated that its business plan is to merge with a company or companies.

Specifically, the bill requires such a company to disclose

 the amount of cash per share expected to be held by the blank check company immediately prior to the merger under various redemption scenarios; side payments or agreements to pay sponsors, blank check company investors, or private investors in public equity for their participation in the merger; and fees or other payments to the sponsor, underwriter, and any other party.</summary>
</bill>
