<bill session="117" type="s" number="2568" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Open Access Evapotranspiration (OpenET) Data Program.</title>
    <title type="display">Open Access Evapotranspiration Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Access Evapotranspiration Data Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2022-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4832" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-23T17:14:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Open Access Evapotranspiration Data Act

This bill directs the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) to establish an Open Access Evapotranspiration (OpenET) Data Program under which the USGS shall provide for delivering satellite-based evapotranspiration data to advance the quantification of evaporation and consumptive water use. The bill defines Evapotranspiration as the process by which water is transferred from the land to the atmosphere by evaporation from soil and other surfaces and transpiration from plants.

As part of the program, the USGS shall

 provide data users with field-scale estimates of evapotranspiration data across large landscapes over certain periods of time, enter into cooperative agreements with program partners (e.g., institutions of higher education, states, private sector entities, or nongovernmental organizations) to provide for the efficient and cost-effective administration of the program, and provide nonreimbursable matching funding for programmatic and operational activities.</summary>
</bill>
