<bill session="118" type="s" number="931" updated="2025-11-19T04:08:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Agency Management and Oversight of Software Assets Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Strengthening Agency Management and Oversight of Software Assets Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Agency Management and Oversight of Software Assets Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the visibility, accountability, and oversight of agency software asset management practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-73.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="156">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 156.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1695" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-19T19:20:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Agency Management and Oversight of Software Assets Act

This bill addresses software asset management practices by federal agencies.

The bill requires each agency to complete a comprehensive assessment of the software entitlements and software inventories of the agency and submit the assessment to the head of the agency, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), the General Services Administration, the Government Accountability Office (GAO), and Congress.

Each agency must use the information developed pursuant to the assessment to develop a plan for the agency to (1) consolidate software licenses of the agency; and (2) adopt enterprise license agreements across the agency by type or category of software in order to improve the performance of, and reduce unnecessary costs across, the agency.

The OMB must submit to Congress a strategy that includes

 proposals to support the adoption of governmentwide enterprise licenses for software entitlements identified through the assessments and plans; opportunities to leverage government procurement policies and practices to increase interoperability of software entitlements acquired and deployed to reduce costs and improve performance; the incorporation of data on spending by agencies on, the performance of, and management by agencies of software entitlements as part of certain required information; and where applicable, directions to agencies to examine options and relevant criteria for transitioning to open-source software. The GAO must report on governmentwide trends, comparisons among agencies, and other analyses of plans and strategy.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-73</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
