<bill session="117" type="s" number="3880" updated="2023-09-01T16:15:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Copyright Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Copyright Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Measures to Advance Rights Technologies Copyright Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 17, United States Code, to define and provide for accommodation and designation of technical measures to identify, protect, or manage copyrighted works, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2022-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9541" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-01T16:07:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Measures to Advance Rights Technologies Copyright Act of 2022 or the SMART Copyright Act of 2022 

This bill authorizes the Library of Congress to designate technical measures (i.e., measures that identify, manage, or protect copyrighted works) and requires providers of internet-related services to make reasonable accommodations for applicable designated technical measures. A copyright owner may sue and receive monetary damages from a service provider that fails to make such reasonable accommodations.

The bill also modifies requirements relating to a provision that limits the liability of service providers for acts of copyright infringement committed by the service providers' users.</summary>
</bill>
