<bill session="111" type="h" number="5953" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:20Z">
  <state datetime="2010-11-30T20:22:27-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-11-30T20:22:27-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to display in each facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs a Women Veterans Bill of Rights and to display in each prosthetics and orthotics clinic of the Department an Injured and Amputee Veterans Bill of Rights, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to display in each facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs a Women Veterans Bill of Rights and to display in each prosthetics and orthotics clinic of the Department an Injured and Amputee Veterans Bill of Rights, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to display in each facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs a Women Veterans Bill of Rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30T20:04:28-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30T20:04:47-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7735-7739" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30T20:04:49-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5953.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2010-11-30T20:22:27-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7735-7736" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30T20:22:31-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-30T20:22:34-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-10T16:23:45Z" status="Passed House amended">Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that the Women Veterans Bill of Rights is printed on signs in accessible formats and displayed prominently in each VA facility and distributed widely to such veterans.

Enumerates health care rights to be included in the Bill of Rights, including the right to: (1) coordinated, comprehensive, primary women's health care at every VA medical facility; (2) treatment by clinicians with specific training and experience in women's health issues; and (3) gender equity in access to and the provision of clinical health care services.

Directs the Secretary to ensure that the Injured and Amputee Veterans Bill of Rights is printed on signs in accessible formats and displayed prominently in each VA prosthetics and orthotics clinic.

Enumerates rights to be included in such Bill of Rights, including the right to: (1) access the highest quality prosthetic and orthotic care; (2) select the practitioner that best meets their prosthetic and orthotic needs; and (3) timely and efficient prosthetic and orthotic care. Requires the Secretary to collect information relating to alleged mistreatment of injured and amputee veterans.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) ensure that all VA employees receive training on the Women Veterans Bill of Rights, and that appropriate VA employees receive training on the Injured and Amputee Veterans Bill of Rights; and (2) conduct outreach to inform veterans about both Bills of Rights, and to make them available on the VA Internet website.</summary>
</bill>
