<bill session="116" type="h" number="6630" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:05Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Critical Minerals Supply Chain Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an additional deduction for the cost of certain materials purchased directly from a domestic smelter or processor.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Critical Minerals Supply Chain Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2020-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2020-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2020-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-04T15:29:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing America's Critical Minerals Supply Chain Act

This bill allows a new tax deduction for 10% of the cost of specified domestically-produced materials if such materials are acquired directly from the domestic smelter or processor of the materials. The bill defines specified domestically-produced materials as materials that are smelted or processed in the United States by direct smelting of ore, from a mine product, by a taxpayer in the trade or business of smelting or processing such materials.

The term specified material includes minerals necessary for national defense and security, for U.S. energy infrastructure, for community resiliency, to support domestic manufacturing, agriculture, housing, telecommunications, healthcare, and transportation infrastructure, or for U.S. economic security and balance of trade. The term does not include fuel minerals, water, ice, or snow, or sand, stone, gravel, pumice, pumicite, cinders, or clay.</summary>
</bill>
