<bill session="117" type="s" number="1187" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Eliminating Global Market Distortions To Protect American Jobs Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to improve the administration of antidumping and countervailing duty laws, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminating Global Market Distortions To Protect American Jobs Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2022-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2022-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2022-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2022-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2022-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2022-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2022-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2021-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6121" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-30T16:19:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Eliminating Global Market Distortions To Protect American Jobs Act of 2021

This bill addresses unfair trade practices by making various changes to U.S. antidumping and countervailing duty law. Antidumping provides relief to U.S industries and workers that are materially injured or threatened with injury due to imports of like products sold in the U.S. market at less than fair value, while countervailing duty provides such relief from imports of products subsidized by a foreign government or public entity.

Specifically, the bill establishes a process for successive antidumping and countervailing duty investigations. Successive investigations may be concurrent (an ongoing investigation of the same product from different countries) or recently completed (not more than two years before the date of the initiation of the successive investigation). Further, the bill establishes a time line for the Department of Commerce to issue determinations in successive investigations.

Among other provisions, the bill authorizes Commerce to

 apply countervailing duty law to subsidies provided by a foreign government or public entity to a company operating in a different country, use another method for calculating the cost of production in specific circumstances, and require importers to provide a certification that the imported merchandise is not subject to an antidumping or countervailing duty order. Additionally, the bill establishes procedures for Commerce to conduct circumvention inquiries, including by specifying the deadlines for preliminary and final determinations.</summary>
</bill>
