<bill session="110" type="h" number="2016" updated="2023-01-11T19:43:09Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-09T18:10:22-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-04-09T18:10:22-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Landscape Conservation System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Landscape Conservation System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Landscape Conservation System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Landscape Conservation System Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001234" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001229" joined="2007-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001228" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2007-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001058" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2008-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2007-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000452" joined="2007-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2007-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000180" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001043" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000762" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000113" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2007-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2007-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000085" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2008-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2007-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000589" joined="2008-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2007-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2008-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000574" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2008-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000097" joined="2007-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2007-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2007-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001153" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000749" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2007-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2007-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000789" joined="2007-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2007-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000784" joined="2007-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-561.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-01" calendar="Union" number="344">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 344.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-08T18:56:19-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1084 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2016 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T13:08:30-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1084 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T13:15:57-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1084.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2099-2112" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T13:16:02-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2016 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T13:16:55-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1084 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T13:16:57-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Tim Holden to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T13:17:17-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:13:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Grijalva amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:13:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Grijalva amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:22:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Cannon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:27:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:33:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (UT) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:34:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:39:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:40:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:43:34-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop (UT) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:44:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Altmire amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:51:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Altmire amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Altmire demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:51:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Pearce amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T14:59:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the Pearce amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pearce demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T15:00:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1084, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Walden amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T15:06:05-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2016 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T16:27:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2112-2119" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T16:27:48-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T16:27:49-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:35:13-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2016.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:35:29-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:35:37-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2105" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:36:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Cannon moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:36:17-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The instructions contained in the motion seek to add language to the bill stating that nothing in this Act shall affect the right to bear arms under the Second Amendment within the National Landscape Conservation System.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:37:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Cannon motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T17:42:02-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2117" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T18:02:27-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 208 - 212 (Roll no. 173).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2117" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="174" datetime="2008-04-09T18:10:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed by recorded vote: 278 - 140 (Roll no. 174).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-09T18:10:22-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="174" datetime="2008-04-09T18:10:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 278 - 140 (Roll no. 174).</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="634">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 634.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="1139" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="110" type="hr" number="1084" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h987"/>
    <amendment number="h986"/>
    <amendment number="h985"/>
    <amendment number="h984"/>
    <amendment number="h983"/>
    <amendment number="h982"/>
    <amendment number="h981"/>
    <amendment number="h980"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2008-06-18T21:32:18Z" status="Passed House amended">National Landscape Conservation System Act - Establishes in the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) the National Landscape Conservation System (thus, enacting into law the National Landscape Conservation System [NLCS] created by BLM in 2000) in order to conserve, protect, and restore nationally significant landscapes that have outstanding cultural, ecological, and scientific values for the benefit of current and future generations.

Requires that the NLCS include each of the following areas administered by BLM: (1) each area that is designated as a national monument, a national conservation area, a wilderness study area, a national scenic trail or historic trail designated as a component of the National Trails System, a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, or a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System; and (2) any area designated by Congress to be administered for conservation purposes, including the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area (as designated under the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Act of 2000), the Headwaters Forest Reserve, the Yaquina Head Outstanding Natural Area, and any additional area designated by Congress for inclusion in the NLCS.









Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) being construed to enhance, diminish, or modify any law or proclamation under which the components of the NLCS specified above were established, or are managed, including, but not limited to, the Alaska National Interest Land Conservation Act, the Wilderness Act, the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, the National Trails System Act, and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976; (2) creating a federal cause of action based on inclusion within the NLCS; (3) intending to additionally restrict or hinder energy development within such system; (4) affecting the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of the several states to manage, control, or regulate fish and resident wildlife under state law or regulations, including the regulation of, or access to, hunting, fishing, trapping, and recreational shooting on BLM-managed public land; (5) limiting access to such activities; (6) affecting current grazing rights or operations due to inclusion in the NLCS; and (7) impeding any efforts by the Department of Homeland Security to secure U.S. borders.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-561</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
