<bill session="119" type="h" number="442" updated="2025-11-18T18:26:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Quality Loss Adjustment Improvement for Farmers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quality Loss Adjustment Improvement for Farmers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to modify a provision relating to quality loss adjustment coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1117" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-03T14:01:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Quality Loss Adjustment Improvement for Farmers Act

This bill directs the&#160;Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (FCIC) to review and revise quality loss adjustment coverage&#160;and provides for the establishment of a regional discount factor for soybeans, as needed.

The FCIC is a government corporation that&#160;finances and administers the federal crop insurance program (FCIP) operations. Under the FCIP, farmers may&#160;purchase insurance coverage against financial losses&#160;caused by certain adverse growing and market conditions,&#160;including for quality losses. The federal government subsidizes the premiums that farmers pay for these insurance policies.&#160;

The bill directs the FCIC to contract with a qualified entity to conduct a review at least once every five years&#160;of the quality loss adjustment procedures. Based on each review, the FCIC must make adjustments to the procedures. Each review must include engagement from regionally diverse industry stakeholders for each agricultural commodity for which a quality loss adjustment is offered.

The bill also directs the&#160;FCIC, in certain circumstances, to establish a&#160;state or regional discount factor for soybeans to reflect the average quality discounts applied to the local or regional market prices of the soybean crop. The FCIC must take this action&#160;in the event of (1) specific emergency or disaster declarations for a state or region, or (2) the occurrence of a salvage market for soybeans in a state or region.</summary>
</bill>
