<bill session="117" type="h" number="5716" updated="2023-09-28T16:00:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing Access for the central Valley and Enhancing (SAVE) Water Resources Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Access for the central Valley and Enhancing (SAVE) Water Resources Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Reclamation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote water supply reliability and improved water management for rural communities, the State of California, and the Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2021-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2021-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2021-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2021-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T13:00:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Access for the central Valley and Enhancing (SAVE) Water Resources Act

This bill authorizes assistance for water management and infrastructure projects and awards grants for water recycling and reuse projects.

The bill (1) establishes the Water Infrastructure and Drought Solutions Fund to finance various water-related projects; (2) modifies the grant program for the funding of water recycling and reuse projects to assign priorities, including to projects that provide a more reliable water supply for states and localities; and (3) reauthorizes through FY2026 the Rural Water Supply Program.

In addition, the Department of the Interior must establish a pilot program to provide financial assistance to certain water supply projects that contribute to a safe, adequate water supply for domestic, agricultural, environmental, municipal, or industrial use.

The Bureau of Reclamation must award prizes for achievements for certain applications of water technology.</summary>
</bill>
