<bill session="112" type="h" number="6132" updated="2019-11-15T21:34:33Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Clothing for American Olympians Act</title>
    <title type="display">American Clothing for American Olympians Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal charter of the United States Olympic Committee to require the United States Olympic Committee to ensure that goods donated or supplied to athletes are substantially made in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2012-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3387" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-08-30T20:26:28Z" status="Introduced in House">American Clothing for American Olympians Act - Requires the U.S. Olympic Committee to ensure that all goods to be donated or supplied to any amateur athlete, coach, trainer, manager, administrator, or official of the U.S. Olympic team, the Paralympic team, or the Pan-American team are substantially made in the United States, to the extent the goods are available in the United States. Defines "substantially made in the United States" to mean that the cost of the foreign products used in the materials in such goods constitutes less than 50% of the cost of all the products used in such materials.

Requires the Committee's quadrennial report on its operations to include data on the sources of the goods donated or supplied and a description of the steps taken to ensure the goods are substantially made in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
