<bill session="108" type="s" number="2186" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:09Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SBA Emergency Authorization Extension Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to temporarily extend the programs under the Small Business Act and the Small Business Investment Act of 1958, through May 15, 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SBA Emergency Authorization Extension Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2004-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000286" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2004-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2004-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2446-2448"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/10/2004 S2547-2548" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2709-2710, S2756"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4062" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Venture capital"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-22T19:52:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SBA Emergency Authorization Extension Act of 2004 - Extends through: (1) May 15 (currently March 15), 2004, any program, authority, or provision, including any pilot program, that is authorized under the Small Business Act or the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 as of September 30, 2003; and (2) FY 2004 the Small Business Administration (SBA) guaranteed loan programs authorized under such Acts.

Amends the Small Business Act with respect to the women's business centers program to provide SBA funding authority for nonprofit organizations conducting projects for the benefit of small businesses owned and controlled by women. Increases from 30 to 48 the percentage of appropriated women's business center funds to be used during FY 2004 for sustained women's business center projects.

Amends the SBA loan guarantee program to authorize a small business to combine an SBA-guaranteed loan with a loan not guaranteed by a Federal, State, or local government. Allows the nonguaranteed loan to be made by: (1) the lender that provided the financing under the guaranteed loan or a different lender; or (2) a lender in the Preferred Lenders Program. Requires the lender to pay a fee with respect to the nonguaranteed portion of a combination loan. Provides maximum amounts of the nonguaranteed loan when processed either under the Preferred Lenders Program or by SBA staff. Terminates, until the end of FY 2004, the authority of lenders to retain loan guarantee fees collected with respect to SBA-guaranteed loans. Directs the SBA to: (1) eliminate certain loan program shutdowns or restrictions imposed by policy notices (thereby allowing for the processing and approval of previous loan applications that were not considered or approved due to a shutdown or restriction); and (2) give priority to the processing of such loans. Requires all combination loan fee proceeds to be used only to administer such loans.

Authorizes the resubmission of certain small business disaster loan applications submitted before January 1, 2003, in response to the events associated with SBA Disaster Declaration 3364 with respect to areas of New York City and Westchester County, New York.</summary>
</bill>
