<bill session="108" type="s" number="1923" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:29Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Film Preservation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and amend the National Film Preservation Act of 1996.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Film Preservation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Film Preservation Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2004-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15418"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15418-15419" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8669"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3569" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-28T19:16:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Film Preservation Act of 2003 - Amends the National Film Preservation Act of 1996 to reauthorize appropriations to the Library of Congress for the National Film Preservation Board.

Directs the Librarian of Congress to: (1) coordinate the national film preservation program with other collection, preservation, and accessibility activities; and (2) the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center of the Library of Congress at Culpeper, Virginia, to ensure that preserved films included in the National Film Registry are stored in a proper manner, and disseminated to researchers, scholars, and the public as may be appropriate in accordance with U.S. copyright law and the terms of any agreements between the Librarian and persons who hold copyrights to such audiovisual works.

 Directs the Board to review special projects submitted for its approval by the National Film Preservation Foundation.

 National Film Preservation Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2003 - Amends specified Federal law to reauthorize appropriations to the Library of Congress for the National Film Preservation Foundation.

Allows the Foundation's board of directors to determine the location of its principal office.

Directs the Foundation to design and support cooperative film preservation and access initiatives, with the approval of the Librarian and the Board.</summary>
</bill>
