<bill session="109" type="s" number="3946" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:04Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Protection Against International Gangs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make an alien who is a member of a criminal gang removable from the United States and inadmissible to the United States, to permit the Secretary of Homeland Security to deny a visa to an alien who is a national of a country that has denied or delayed accepting an alien removed from the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Protection Against International Gangs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000439"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10289-10290"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10290" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-10T17:51:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Protection Against International Gangs Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make an alien inadmissible or deportable (provides the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General with waiver authority) if the Attorney General or the Secretary (or a consular officer regarding inadmissibility) knows or has reason to believe that such alien: (1) is or has been a member of a criminal street gang; or (2) has participated in a criminal street gang's activities, knowing or having reason to know that such activities furthered the criminal gang's illegal activity.

Authorizes the Secretary to instruct the Department of State to deny visas to individuals from a country that has denied or unreasonably delayed acceptance of a citizen, national, or resident of that country who has been ordered removed from United States until the country accepts such individual.</summary>
</bill>
