<bill session="118" type="h" number="6485" updated="2025-11-19T01:19:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Welfare Provider Inclusion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Welfare Provider Inclusion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that organizations with religious or moral convictions are allowed to continue to provide services for children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001091" joined="2024-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Work and Welfare.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3344" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-01T13:01:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Child Welfare Provider Inclusion Act of 2023

This bill generally prohibits the federal government, states, tribal nations, or localities from discriminating or taking adverse action against a child welfare provider that declines to provide services due to the provider's sincerely held religious beliefs or moral convictions. However, government entities may still take adverse action against a provider that declines to provide adoption or foster care services based on race, color, or national origin.

The Department of Health and Human Services must withhold a portion of federal funding for family services and child welfare activities from a government entity that discriminates against a child welfare provider in violation of this bill. Child welfare providers may also sue the government entity for such discrimination. A prevailing provider may recover reasonable attorney's fees and costs.

Furthermore, government entities that accept certain federal funding for family services and child welfare activities must waive sovereign immunity as a defense to lawsuits brought under this bill. (In many cases, sovereign immunity shields states, territories, tribal nations, and some localities against private suits.)</summary>
</bill>
