<bill session="115" type="h" number="3752" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PATIENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PATIENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Policies to Address Tragic Injuries Enabled by Never events Thoroughly Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop and implement plans to improve the safety of medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2017-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T14:58:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Policies to Address Tragic Injuries Enabled by Never events Thoroughly Act or the PATIENT Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), through the Veterans Health Administration (VHA), the National Surgery Office, and the National Center for Patient Safety, to develop: (1) a system-wide plan to decrease never events that incorporates technological tools; and (2) an operating room fire safety plan that requires the reporting of operating room fires, the inclusion of certain directives to mitigate fire-related risks, and a pilot project that tests new operating room fire safety technology at multiple VHA medical facilities.

"Never event" means an event involving the delivery of (or failure to deliver) hospital care or medical services at a VA medical facility in which there is a serious error in patient care or services that is identifiable, usually preventable, and that indicates a deficiency in the safety and process controls with respect to the physician or medical facility involved. Such term includes operating room fires.</summary>
</bill>
