<bill session="117" type="h" number="1044" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Broadband MAPS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create a task force at the Federal Communications Commission to ensure the policy and funding decisions of the Commission are informed by data collection and analysis required in title VIII of the Communications Act of 1934, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadband - Measuring Availability and Aligning Policies Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadband MAPS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001119"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-01T11:03:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadband - Measuring Availability and Aligning Policies Task Force Act or the Broadband MAPS Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to establish a task force that oversees implementation and use of broadband availability maps.

Specifically, the task force must (1) oversee specified data collection and analysis, including creating and updating broadband availability maps; (2) identify relevant FCC actions and ensure they are informed by the maps; (3) provide cost estimates for maintaining the maps; and (4) provide necessary recommendations to ensure the FCC can produce sufficiently granular and accurate maps to determine areas that lack broadband internet access service.</summary>
</bill>
