<bill session="116" type="s" number="1494" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:09Z">
  <state datetime="2019-08-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Secure and Protect Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Secure and Protect Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure and Protect Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to protect alien minors and to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to end abuse of the asylum system and establish refugee application and processing centers outside the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2019-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Graham under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/01/2019 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-08-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="181">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 181.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-13T16:30:50Z" status="Reported to Senate">Secure and Protect Act of 2019 

This bill makes changes to the handling of unaccompanied alien children and asylum applications.

The Flores settlement (a court settlement imposing conditions on the treatment of detained alien minors) shall not restrict any activities. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall have sole discretion as to detention standards of alien minors.

Statutory provisions governing the handling of unaccompanied alien children from U.S.-bordering countries shall now govern all unaccompanied alien children. The bill provides for requirements relating to the handling of such alien children. Certain immigration officer determinations relating to unaccompanied alien children shall be unreviewable.

DHS may detain accompanied alien children pending the completion of removal proceedings (some courts have ruled that Flores limits the detention of certain alien children to 20 days). States may not impose licensing requirements for family detention facilities.

An unaccompanied alien child shall not be released from custody while immigration or removal proceedings are pending, with some exceptions.

The bill limits asylum eligibility to aliens entering the United States at a designated port of entry and provides for additional grounds for asylum ineligibility. A credible fear of persecution is redefined to mean that it is more likely than not that the alien would be able to establish eligibility for asylum.

The Department of State shall establish refugee application and processing centers in Mexico and Central America. The bill requires the hiring of additional immigration judges, support staff, and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement attorneys.</summary>
</bill>
