<bill session="119" type="h" number="1191" updated="2025-11-19T04:26:42Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Access to Rural Community Hospitals Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Access to Rural Community Hospitals Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to waive certain distance requirements for certain hospitals electing to be designated as critical access hospitals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2025-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="521" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-11T20:53:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Access to Rural Community Hospitals Act of 2025

This bill temporarily allows additional hospitals to qualify as critical access hospitals (CAHs) that receive special payment under Medicare.

Currently, in order to qualify as a CAH under Medicare, a hospital must either (1) be located more than 35 miles (or 15 miles in mountainous regions or areas with only secondary roads) from another hospital, or (2) have been certified prior to January 1, 2006, by the state as a necessary provider of services in the area. Hospitals also must meet certain size and service requirements, including having no more than 25 acute care inpatient beds.

The bill allows, for one year, hospitals that are participating in the Rural Community Hospital Demonstration Program to also qualify as CAHs. (The program tests the feasibility&#160;of cost-based reimbursement for small rural hospitals that are too large to qualify as CAHs.)</summary>
</bill>
