<bill session="116" type="s" number="4200" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:25Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Information Technology Modernization Centers of Excellence Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Information Technology Modernization Centers of Excellence Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Information Technology Modernization Centers of Excellence Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program to facilitate the adoption of modern technology by executive agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2020-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-277.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-10-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="570">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 570.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5901" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-07T15:12:05Z" status="Reported to Senate">Information Technology Modernization Centers of Excellence Program Act

This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish an Information Technology Modernization Centers of Excellence Program to facilitate the adoption of modern technology by executive agencies on a reimbursable basis.

The bill lists program responsibilities, including to

 encourage the modernization of information technology used by an executive agency and how a customer interacts with the agency; improve cooperation between commercial and executive agency information technology sectors; encourage the adoption of commercial items; and upon request by the executive agency, to assist an agency with planning and adoption of technology in focus areas designated by the GSA, which may include artificial intelligence. The GSA shall (1) coordinate with the Department of Homeland Security in establishing the program to ensure that the technology, tools, and frameworks facilitated for executive agencies by the program provide sufficient cybersecurity and maintain the integrity, confidentiality, and availability of federal information; and (2) report to Congress on the program.

This bill shall cease to have effect seven years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-277</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
