<bill session="108" type="sr" number="177" updated="2023-01-15T17:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-25">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution to direct the Senate Commission on Art to select an appropriate scene commemorating the Great Compromise of our forefathers establishing a bicameral Congress with equal representation in the United States Senate, to be placed in the Senate wing of the Capitol, and to authorize the Committees on Rules and Administration to obtain technical advice and assistance in carrying out its duties.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A resolution to direct the Senate Commission on Art to select an appropriate scene commemorating the Great Compromise of our forefathers establishing a bicameral Congress with equal representation in the United States Senate, to be placed in the Senate wing of the Capitol, and to authorize the Committees on Rules and Administration to obtain technical advice and assistance in carrying out its duties.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to direct the Senate Commission on Art to select an appropriate scene commemorating the Great Compromise of our forefathers establishing a bicameral Congress with equal State representation in the United State Senate, to be placed in the lunette space in the Senate reception room immediately above the entrance into the Senate chamber lobby, and to authorize the Committee on Rules and Administration to obtain technical advice and assistance in carrying out its duties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/20/2003 S8306" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Senate Committee on Rules and Administration discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16053-16054" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-11-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16054" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Constitutional conventions"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2223"/>
    <amendment number="s2222"/>
    <amendment number="s2221"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-01-07T22:07:47Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Directs the Senate Commission on Art to select an appropriate scene commemorating the Great Compromise (which established a bicameral Congress with equal State representation in the Senate). Requires such scene to be placed in a location in the Senate wing to be determined by the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration (Committee).

Authorizes the Committee Chairman to seek technical advice and assistance in carrying out its duties from individuals from the public and private sectors, who shall serve without compensation, at the pleasure of the Chairman. Provides that such individuals are not to be deemed to be Senate members, officers, or employees, or to be providing services to the Senate, for purposes of the Senate Code of Official Conduct. Allows such individuals to be reimbursed for transportation expenses.</summary>
</bill>
