<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1724</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:58Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:58Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-10-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-10-17T22:56:16Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-17</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Academic performance and assessments</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska Natives and Hawaiians</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education of the disadvantaged</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Educational technology and distance education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Family relationships</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign language and bilingual programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian social and development programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minority education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rural conditions and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>School administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Special education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-10-17</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-10-26T15:53:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>School Accountability Improvements Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow local educational agencies (LEAs) that are unable to provide a small, rural, or remote school with a highly-qualified on-site classroom teacher for a core academic subject to use distance education provided by a teacher highly qualified in the subject, but only if a teacher highly-qualified in another subject is present in the classroom to assist students during the distance education.</p> <p>Allows states to use a growth model in calculating whether students are making adequately yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic performance standards if the state plan ensures their attainment of proficiency within certain periods of time.</p> <p>Gives schools which are identified as needing improvement an extra year to make AYP before being required to allow student transfers. Limits the transfer option to students who do not meet proficiency standards. </p> <p>Permits LEAs identified as needing improvement to provide supplemental educational services themselves.</p> <p>Allows schools and LEAs identified as needing improvement due to an underperforming disabled or limited English proficient (LEP) student subgroup to limit their improvement plan to such failing subgroup. Eliminates the requirements that schools face corrective action or restructuring and LEAs face corrective action because of such a subgroup's underperformance, if AYP can be shown using a growth model that counts students who are on track to attain proficiency by their final year in secondary school.</p> <p>Requires AYP measurements of certain schools providing Native language instruction to kindergarten through second grade children in states with no AYP assessment in such language to exclude grade three results and employ a growth model requiring progress toward proficiency by seventh grade.</p> <p>Allows partnerships receiving subgrants for preparing, recruiting, and training teachers and principals to include parent teacher organizations and use funds for activities enhancing parental involvement.</p> <p>Excepts teachers of American Indian, Alaska Native, or Native Hawaiian language, culture, or history from the requirement that teachers be highly qualified. Allows states to require a local tribe or tribal organization to verify their competency.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>School Accountability Improvements Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>School Accountability Improvements Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding highly qualified teachers, growth models, adequate yearly progress, Native American language programs, and parental involvement, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>School Accountability Improvements Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-10-17T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1724is/xml/BILLS-112s1724is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-10-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
