<bill session="117" type="h" number="936" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Delivery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency to assist States and local governments with the distribution and tracking of vaccines for COVID-19, to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a national program to oversee the collection and maintenance of all Federal and State data on vaccinations of individuals in the United States for COVID-19 to achieve mass vaccination saturation immunity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Delivery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delivering COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Vaccinations to All Regions and Vulnerable Communities Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2021-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="330" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-06T13:17:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Delivering COVID-19 Vaccinations to All Regions and Vulnerable Communities Act of 2021 or the COVID-19 Delivery Act

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to support COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) vaccination programs.

To assist state or local governments with vaccination efforts, FEMA must coordinate certain activities. Specifically, FEMA must

 manage vaccine deliveries, set up vaccination centers, design communication systems and software applications, and develop a public education program on vaccine safety and availability. Additionally, HHS must carry out a program to increase vaccination rates to achieve herd immunity. As part of this program, HHS must temporarily collect data on COVID-19 vaccine administrations. Data collected under this program is subject to relevant privacy protections that apply to other health data. HHS must report on its activities on a daily or weekly basis.

The CDC must also report on the effectiveness of state and local COVID-19 vaccination programs.</summary>
</bill>
