<bill session="117" type="s" number="1160" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FENTANYL Results Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prioritize efforts of the Department of State to combat international trafficking in covered synthetic drugs and new psychoactive substances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FENTANYL Results Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Emerging Narcotics Through Additional Nations to Yield Lasting Results Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">FENTANYL Results Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Fighting Emerging Narcotics Through Additional Nations to Yield Lasting Results Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-06-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="403">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 403.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2538" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4315" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5234" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-24T12:45:36Z" status="Reported to Senate">Fighting Emerging Narcotics Through Additional Nations to Yield Lasting Results Act or the FENTANYL Results Act

This bill creates two programs, establishes a reporting requirement, and otherwise modifies provisions to facilitate global cooperation against the trafficking of certain drugs, specifically synthetic controlled substances (such as fentanyl) and new psychoactive substances.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of State to establish a program to provide capacity-building assistance for law enforcement agencies of specified countries to identify, track, and detect such drugs. The State Department must also carry out an international exchange program for drug demand reduction experts to provide educational and professional development on demand-reduction matters relating to the illicit use of drugs, including synthetic drugs.

The bill requires the State Department to include new sections in its annual international narcotics control strategy report that contain (1) an assessment of the countries likely involved in the trafficking of synthetic controlled substances and new psychoactive substances, and (2) policies of responding to new psychoactive substances.

The bill also expands the definition of major illicit drug producing country to include countries that produce synthetic drugs. Under current law, foreign assistance may be withheld from such countries.</summary>
</bill>
