<bill session="117" type="s" number="370" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Local Processing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Poultry Products Inspection Act and the Federal Meat Inspection Act to support small and very small meat and poultry processing establishments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Local Processing Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1258" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-25T16:49:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Local Processing Act of 2021

This bill revises provisions related to meat and poultry processing establishments, including smaller establishments (i.e., those with between 10 and 500 employees) and very small establishments (i.e., those with fewer than 10 employees or annual sales of less than $2.5 million).

For example, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must establish a searchable database of peer-reviewed validation studies for use in developing Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points plans for smaller and very small establishments.

The bill increases the maximum federal cost share from 50% to 65% that USDA may provide to assist states in creating meat and poultry inspection programs.

Additionally, USDA must conduct outreach with states that have meat and poultry inspection programs, but that do not have Cooperative Interstate Shipment programs. The Cooperative Interstate Shipment program allows state-inspected facilities to operate as federally-inspected facilities and ship their products in interstate commerce and internationally.

USDA must also award competitive grants for activities to adapt production, processing, distribution, and sales systems to respond to and recover from the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, including activities that support (1) the health and safety of meat and poultry plant employees, suppliers, and customers; (2) increased processing capacity; and (3) the resilience of the small meat and poultry processing sector.

Further, the bill establishes grant programs to (1) establish or expand career training programs at community colleges, vocational schools, and universities related to meat and poultry processing; and (2) support smaller and very small establishments by offsetting the cost of training new meat and poultry processors.</summary>
</bill>
