<bill session="116" type="h" number="3994" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modern Television Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal certain provisions of the Communications Act of 1934, title 17 of the United States Code, and certain regulations, to allow for interim carriage of television broadcast signals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modern Television Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-08T17:58:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Modern Television Act of 2019

This bill establishes measures to prevent blackouts of television broadcast stations, including requiring good-faith negotiations in broadcast agreements and providing for outside arbitration of certain negotiation disputes.

Specifically, the bill requires a station and a cable or satellite service to negotiate in good faith when attempting to reach a marketplace agreement, and it requires the cable or satellite service to retransmit the signal of a station for up to 60 days while the parties renegotiate an expired agreement. The Federal Communications Commission may require a station and a cable or satellite service to submit to binding arbitration to resolve any dispute that may arise (the parties must be retroactively paid for content aired during this time). Further, a station is prohibited from requiring payment from a cable or satellite service for customers of the cable or satellite service who do not receive the signals of the station from that service.

Additionally, the bill repeals specified provisions, including those related to retransmission consent and compulsory copyright licenses. The bill also disallows federal, state, and local authorities from regulating the rates of a cable or satellite service.

The Government Accountability Office must assess the impact of the bill.</summary>
</bill>
