<bill session="118" type="h" number="1217" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DRILL Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Denying Regulatory Interference with Landowners and Legislatures Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRILL Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 with respect to certain regulatory actions related to hydraulic fracturing within the Susquehanna, Delaware, and Potomac River basins, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2023-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-23T15:36:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Denying Regulatory Interference with Landowners and Legislatures Now Act or the DRILL Now Act

This bill bars certain interstate river basin commissions from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing any regulation relating to hydraulic fracturing unless it is issued by the state in which the regulation is to be implemented or enforced. These commissions are

 the Susquehanna River Basin Commission (New York, Pennsylvania, and Maryland), the Delaware River Basin Commission (Delaware, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and New York), and the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin (Maryland, Pennsylvania, Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia).</summary>
</bill>
