<bill session="118" type="s" number="2898" updated="2025-11-19T04:35:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Farmworkers' Mental Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Farmworkers' Mental Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to authorize the use of certain grants to deliver peer-to-peer mental health support to individuals who are engaged in farming, ranching, farm work, and other occupations relating to agriculture.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4657" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5637" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-04T13:41:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supporting Farmworkers' Mental Health Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 and modifies the Farm and Ranch Stress Assistance Network (FRSAN) Program. (The FRSAN Program funds projects that aim to maintain a network connecting individuals engaged in farming, ranching, and other agriculture-related occupations to stress assistance programs.)

Specifically, the bill makes individuals engaged in farm work eligible for assistance under the FRSAN Program.

The bill also expands the types of programs eligible for FRSAN grants to include those that deliver peer-to-peer mental health support to individuals who are engaged in farming, ranching, farm work, and other agriculture-related occupations.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
