<bill session="118" type="s" number="595" updated="2025-11-19T02:51:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rio San Jos&#195;&#169; and Rio Jemez Water Settlements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Rio San Jos&#195;&#169; and Rio Jemez Water Settlements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rio San Jos&#195;&#169; and Rio Jemez Water Settlements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to approve the settlement of water rights claims of the Pueblos of Acoma and Laguna in the Rio San Jose Stream System and the Pueblos of Jemez and Zia in the Rio Jemez Stream System in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Schatz without amendment. With written report No. 118-131.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="274">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 274.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1304" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-18T16:25:03Z" status="Reported to Senate">Rio San Jos&#233; and Rio Jemez Water Settlements Act of 2023

This bill recognizes and settles certain water rights claims in New Mexico of (1) the Pueblos of Acoma and Laguna, and (2) the Pueblos of Jemez and Zia. It also establishes and provides funding for settlement trust funds.

Specifically, the bill authorizes, ratifies, and confirms a specified water rights settlement agreement entered into by the Pueblo of Acoma, the Pueblo of Laguna, the United States, New Mexico, and others, thus satisfying claims to water rights in the Rio San Jos&#233; Stream System in New Mexico.

With respect to the water settlement for the Pueblos of Acoma and Laguna, the bill establishes and provides funding for the Pueblo of Acoma Settlement Trust Fund, the Pueblo of Laguna Settlement Trust Fund, and the Acomita Reservoir Works Trust Fund.

Additionally, the bill authorizes, ratifies, and confirms a specified water rights settlement agreement entered into by the Pueblo of Jemez, the Pueblo of Zia, the United States, New Mexico, and others, thus satisfying claims to water rights in the Jemez River Stream System in New Mexico.

With respect to the water settlement for the Pueblos of Jemez and Zia, the bill establishes and provides funding for the Pueblo of Jemez Settlement Trust Fund and the Pueblo of Zia Settlement Trust Fund.

For both of these agreements, the bill (1) specifies the water rights of the pueblos; and (2) outlines waivers, releases, and retentions of claims by the pueblos and the United States.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-131</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
