<bill session="118" type="s" number="1391" updated="2025-11-19T02:56:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Election Mail Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Mail Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 39, United States Code, and the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to improve procedures and requirements related to election mail.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2987" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-12T17:44:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Election Mail Act

This bill addresses the delivery and processing of election mail for federal elections, including by establishing certain standards for mail-in ballots.

Specifically, the bill requires the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) to

 ensure (to the maximum extent practicable) same-day processing of mail-in ballots, postmark each ballot, carry election mail (e.g., voter registration applications and mail-in ballots) as first-class mail that is free of postage, appoint an election mail coordinator at each area office and district office, and consult annually with Indian tribes regarding barriers to voting for eligible voters living on Indian lands. The bill prohibits the USPS, within 120 days of a federal election, from making any operational change that would restrict the prompt and reliable delivery of election mail.

Each state and jurisdiction must provide with each mail-in ballot a return envelope with an intelligent mail barcode. This requirement does not apply to a state or jurisdiction that uses an alternative system that enables voters to track the ballot through the mail.

The bill requires election officials to count mail-in ballots that are postmarked by election day and arrive within seven days after the election.</summary>
</bill>
