<bill session="118" type="h" number="8046" updated="2025-09-04T10:15:55Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rosatom Sanctions Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rosatom Sanctions Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions with respect to Rosatom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000398"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2024-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2024-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2024-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2024-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2024-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2024-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2024-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2024-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-04T10:06:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Rosatom Sanctions Enforcement Act

This bill requires the President to take actions against Russian nuclear suppliers (e.g., Rosatom). (Rosatom is Russia's state nuclear power conglomerate.)

Specifically, the bill requires the President to impose property-blocking sanctions on Rosatom and others, including foreign persons involved in&#160;Rosatom&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s construction of nuclear reactors.

Additionally, the President must submit to Congress a strategy to (1) replace Rosatom and other Russian nuclear suppliers with those from the United States and U.S. allies and partners, and (2) effect a permanent&#160;decoupling from the Russian nuclear industry. Within 60 days of submitting this strategy, the President must issue a directive prohibiting U.S. persons from engaging in any significant transaction with&#160;Rosatom and others involved with&#160;Rosatom.

The bill also requires the President to prescribe regulations to prohibit or impose strict conditions with respect to certain financial accounts held by foreign financial institutions.

The bill allows the President to waive the aforementioned sanctions under specified circumstances.

The President must, within 60 days of receiving a request from Congress, determine whether a person or foreign financial institution described in the request meets the criteria to be subject to sanctions imposed in two specified regulations relating to Russia. The President must submit a report to Congress stating whether the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions on persons or institutions described in the request from Congress.

The President must also pause the issuance of export licenses granted under a civil nuclear cooperation agreement with Russia until certain conditions are met.</summary>
</bill>
