<bill session="118" type="s" number="164" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:43Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Doss's Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Doss's Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GIVE LIFE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guarding against Injustice based on Vaccine-status, Ensuring Lifesaving Intervention For Everyone Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the consideration of COVID-19 vaccination status in determining eligibility for organ donation or transplantation, and in providing services to Medicare or Medicaid beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-07T20:25:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Guarding against Injustice based on Vaccine-status, Ensuring Lifesaving Intervention For Everyone Act or the GIVE LIFE Act or Doss's Act

This bill generally prohibits an individual's COVID-19 vaccination status from being taken into account for purposes of organ donation or receipt. The bill also prohibits (1) the incidence rate of COVID-19 in a geographic area from being considered in such decisions, and (2) the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network from establishing standards that incorporate any of these factors.

Additionally, as a condition of Medicare and Medicaid participation, health care providers, with specified exceptions (e.g., skilled nursing facilities), may not deny services to individuals based on COVID-19 vaccination status.</summary>
</bill>
