<bill session="111" type="s" number="3020" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:31Z">
  <state datetime="2010-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HUBZone Improvement Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to reform and improve the HUBZone program for small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HUBZone Improvement Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2010-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2010-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S702"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S702-703" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-14T19:07:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">HUBZone Improvement Act of 2010 - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to ensure that the map used by the SBA to identify HUBZones (historically underutilized business zones) is accurate, up-to-date, and revised as new data is made available.

Requires the Administrator to: (1) implement policies for ensuring that only qualified HUBZone small businesses are participating in the HUBZone program; (2) report to the congressional small businesses concerning qualification for, and recertification of, a HUBZone small business; and (3) develop measures and implement plans to assess HUBZone program effectiveness.

Amends the Small Business Act to prohibit the Administrator, during the period beginning on the date that a small business is determined qualified as a HUBZone small business and ending the day before a HUBZone program contract for which such small business submits a bid is awarded, from determining that the small business is no longer qualified based on a failure to meet the applicable employment percentage unless, among other things, the small business has not attempted to maintain such percentage.</summary>
</bill>
