<bill session="117" type="s" number="3168" updated="2023-03-08T19:59:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the White Mountain Apache Tribe Water Rights Quantification Act of 2010 to modify the enforceability date for certain provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the White Mountain Apache Tribe Water Rights Quantification Act of 2010 to modify the enforceability date for certain provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000377"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-23">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 117-360.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Schatz with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="683">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 683.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7291-7292" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7292"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-12-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7314-7315" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:03:57-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:46:32-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T15:38:32-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Peltola moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T15:38:43-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9937-9939" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T15:38:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T15:44:23-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>By Senator Schatz from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report. Report No. 117-285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T22:50:30-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9979-9980" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="537" datetime="2022-12-21T23:10:04-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 378 - 33 (Roll no. 537).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9937-9938" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T23:10:05-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-12-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2023-01-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-342" type="public" datetime="2023-01-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-342.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5880" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s6546"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-01-19T02:23:23Z" status="Public Law">This act revises the White Mountain Apache Tribe Water Rights Quantification Act of 2010, including by extending certain deadlines and establishing reporting requirements. (The quantification act approved the White Mountain Apache Tribe Water Rights Quantification Agreement, settling the tribe's water rights in Arizona. It authorized the design and construction of a rural water system to address the water infrastructure needs on the tribe's reservation.)

Specifically, the act extends the enforceability deadline, from 2023 to 2027, for the Department of the Interior to publish a statement of findings required by the quantification act. In particular, the act repeals the settlement agreement on December 31, 2027, if Interior does not publish by December 30, 2027, a statement of findings that specified conditions have been fulfilled (including that funds necessary to construct the rural water system have been deposited into a specified subaccount).

The act makes changes to cost indexing for the funds and subaccounts established under the quantification act, including by allowing adjustments for construction costs.

The act also requires annual reports to Congress describing all expenditures and including additional information, such as progress and cost accounting on the planning, design, and construction of the Miner Flat Dam and any additional water supply facilities resulting from expenditures.

Finally, the act establishes requirements for determining whether the rural water system is substantially complete. In particular, the rural water system shall be determined to be substantially complete if (1) the infrastructure is capable of storing, diverting, treating, transmitting, and distributing a supply of water as set forth in the final project design; or (2) Interior has expended all available funding and cannot complete construction due solely to the lack of additional authorized funding.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-285</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
