<bill session="117" type="s" number="3272" updated="2022-12-30T02:48:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Arctic Focus Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arctic Focus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prioritize icebreaker deployments to the Arctic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-17T16:11:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Arctic Focus Act

This bill directs the Coast Guard to undertake various efforts to maintain a persistent presence in the Arctic to advance the national security interests of the United States.

The Coast Guard must

 prioritize icebreaker deployments to the Arctic; provide sufficient icebreaking activity to keep the Northwest Passage sea lanes open for commerce, national defense, rescue and recovery operations, and scientific exploration by 2030; permanently station at least one ice-breaking vessel within the Arctic by the earlier of one year after the delivery of the first Polar Security Cutter, or 2030; and continuously patrol the Arctic with at least one major Coast Guard cutter that is able to execute search and rescue operations, fisheries enforcement, pollution response, and support for national defense operations. The department in which the Coast Guard is operating must submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the ability and time line to conduct a transit of the Northern Sea Route and periodic transits of the Northwest Passage, and that includes a plan to implement the activities set forth in this bill.</summary>
</bill>
