<bill session="108" type="hr" number="687" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:20Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Recognizing United Nations International Day in Support of Victims of Torture and reaffirming the commitment of the United States to eliminate torture in all countries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing United Nations International Day in Support of Victims of Torture and reaffirming the commitment of the United States to eliminate torture in all countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000284" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2004-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2004-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000005" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2004-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-07-08T18:09:27Z" status="Introduced in House">States that the House of Representatives: (1) recognizes the United Nations International Day in Support of the Victims of Torture and expresses support for all victims (and families) of torture and other forms of cruel, inhumane, or degrading treatment or punishment who are struggling to overcome such practices' physical scars and psychological effects; (2) condemns the use of torture and other forms of cruel, inhumane, or degrading treatment or punishment in the United States and all countries; (3) encourages the training of law enforcement and military personnel and private contractors in the prevention of torture and other forms of cruel, inhumane, or degrading treatment or punishment; (4) reaffirms the commitment of the United States to eliminate torture in all countries and to ensure that no individual in the employment of the United States Government or under contract with the United States Government engages in torture or any act of physical or mental abuse that is cruel, inhumane, or degrading; and (5) reaffirms the commitment of the United States to the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, the Convention Against Torture, the Torture Victims Relief Reauthorization Act of 2003, the prohibitions against war crimes in title 18, Untied States Code, and any international convention or law that protects individuals from torture or other cruel, inhumane, or degrading punishment or treatment.</summary>
</bill>
