<bill session="117" type="h" number="4455" updated="2022-12-31T05:07:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to extend certain certification periods for the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to extend certain certification periods for the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2022-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2021-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2022-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-02T18:09:43Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill makes changes to enrollment processes and other aspects of the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC).

 Under current law, an individual who participates in Medicaid and other specified means-tested programs automatically meets applicable income eligibility for WIC. The bill extends this automatic income eligibility to participants in Head Start programs, certain nutrition programs (e.g., the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations), and the Children's Health Insurance Program. It also extends income eligibility to individuals who reside in a household in which a member receives assistance from such a program.

Other changes in the bill include (1) allowing states to certify a child's eligibility for WIC for up to two years, and (2) requiring states to address benefits for infants and children under the care of kinship families in WIC plans.</summary>
</bill>
