<bill session="116" type="s" number="2692" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School MEALS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School MEALS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Modernization and Efficient Access to Lunches for Students Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve direct certification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5283" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-03T18:59:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Modernization and Efficient Access to Lunches for Students Act of 2019 or the School MEALS Act of 2019

 This bill establishes programs and revises requirements relating to direct certification processes for the National School Lunch Program. Direct certification allows schools to use data matching procedures to approve school meals without the need for applications for children who receive assistance under other programs, such as the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program).

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Agriculture to provide grants and technical assistance for states and tribal organizations to improve their direct certification processes, including with respect to children who receive assistance under a food distribution program on Indian reservations.

The bill also expands the time frame for schools to elect and gather eligibility data for the Community Eligibility Provision that permits schools in high-poverty areas to serve free meals to all enrolled students without the need for applications.</summary>
</bill>
