<bill session="118" type="h" number="2631" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MINAJ Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Information Nuanced Accountability Judgement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MINAJ Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Federal Government from imposing any mandate requiring an individual to receive a vaccine that has not been authorized for marketing for at least 10 years, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001222"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2044"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-08T15:21:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Medical Information Nuanced Accountability Judgement Act of 2023 or the MINAJ Act of 2023

This bill generally prohibits federal agencies from requiring an individual to receive a vaccine unless the required vaccine has been approved or authorized by the Food and Drug Administration for at least 10 years.

During a declared public health emergency, however, a federal agency may require that individuals receive a vaccine with fewer years of approval or authorization if the agency provides Congress with (1) adequate notice of the requirement, (2) data about the safety and efficacy of the required vaccine, and (3) sufficient time to review the data and deliberate about the requirement. Under the bill, sufficient time for review and deliberation is the lesser of three months or the period of time during which the House Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions each complete three hearings related to matters in the report.</summary>
</bill>
