<bill session="117" type="s" number="3401" updated="2022-12-30T03:34:01Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ABC Safe Drug Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ABC Safe Drug Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anyone But China Safe Drug Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to maintain a list of the country of origin of all drugs marketed in the United States, to ban the use of Federal funds for the purchase of drugs manufactured in the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7121" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2495" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-27T11:08:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Anyone But China Safe Drug Act or the ABC Safe Drug Act 

This bill requires the federal government to maintain a registry of certain foreign-sourced drugs, prohibits federal health care programs from purchasing drugs containing ingredients manufactured in China, and requires drugs to be labeled for country of origin.

The Food and Drug Administration shall maintain (1) a list of foreign-sourced drugs and active ingredients that are critical for consumer health and safety, and (2) another list identifying such drugs that are produced exclusively in China or use ingredients produced in China.

The bill phases in a restriction on federal health care programs purchasing drugs with active ingredients manufactured in China. By January 1, 2026, such programs may not purchase a drug with any active ingredients from China. The Department of Health and Human Services may issue a waiver for an agency or program that is unable to meet this requirement, but no waiver may apply to drugs purchased in or after 2027.

Each drug must have labeling listing the country of origin of each active ingredient, and a drug without this labeling shall be deemed misbranded.</summary>
</bill>
