<bill session="116" type="h" number="7554" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Farmers, Food Banks, and Families Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to promote an American agriculture first agenda and establish the position of Domestic Agriculture Supply Chain Administrator in the Office of the Secretary of Agriculture to connect United States farmers with food banks, grocers, and nonprofit food distributors during periods of food scarcity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Farmers, Food Banks, and Families Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2020-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2020-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E619"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3970" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-27T17:52:02Z" status="Introduced in House">American Farmers, Food Banks, and Families Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the position of Domestic Agriculture Supply Chain Administrator.

The Administrator must

 carry out activities in the interest of assisting farmers in entering their products into the domestic market; act as a liaison to connect farmers with food banks, schools, grocers, restaurants, and nonprofit organizations to expand domestic market access for organizations that are in need of agricultural products; identify barriers, either regulatory or legal, that prevent or inhibit farmers from entering their products into the domestic market through food distribution networks or other entities; and make recommendations to USDA regarding the means by which to remove such barriers. Additionally, USDA must establish a catalog or data resource that is capable of recording (1) farms that have excess agricultural products, and (2) food distribution organizations that are in need of certain agricultural products.</summary>
</bill>
