<bill session="117" type="s" number="1515" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a pay incentive for border patrol agents to complete emergency medical technician and paramedic training, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REMOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Remote, Emergency, Medical, Online Training, Telehealth, and EMT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1177" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="348" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-06T19:10:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Remote, Emergency, Medical, Online Training, Telehealth, and EMT Act or the REMOTE Act

This bill requires U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to take actions to improve CBP medical services along the southern border.

CBP shall make emergency medical technician (EMT) and paramedic training available to selected border patrol agents along the southern border. Agents that complete the training or already have EMT or paramedic certifications shall receive specified pay increases.

The bill imposes requirements related to (1) the percentage of agents with EMT or paramedic training assigned in each sector, and (2) minimum levels of various medical supplies in each sector.

Furthermore, CBP shall require all border patrol agents and officers to complete online training on how to (1) identify common signs of medical distress in children, and (2) timely transfer sick children to medical care.

CBP shall also ensure that all remote stations, forward operating bases, and remote ports of entry on the southern border have voice access to a medical command physician.</summary>
</bill>
