<bill session="117" type="h" number="1604" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP Straw Purchases Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to combat straw purchases of firearms.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP Straw Purchases Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000668" joined="2022-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2021-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2022-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000317" joined="2021-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2022-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2021-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2021-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2022-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-01T21:41:17Z" status="Introduced in House">STOP Straw Purchases Act

This bill establishes new criminal offenses and penalties to deter straw purchases of firearms (i.e., firearm purchases from a licensed gun dealer by one person on behalf of another person).

Current law prohibits and imposes penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 10 years, or both&#8212;for making false statements in connection with the acquisition of a firearm from a federally licensed dealer.

This bill increases the statutory maximum prison sentence&#8212;from 10 years to 25 years&#8212;for a violation by a person who is acting as a straw purchaser. Under this bill, a straw purchaser is a person who makes false statements involving deception about the identity of the actual buyer and knows or has reasonable cause to believe the actual buyer intends the firearm to be (1) used in a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime, or (2) transferred to a prohibited person.

Additionally, the bill establishes new related criminal offenses. Specifically, it prohibits and imposes penalties for

 inducing another person, as a leader of a straw purchasing ring, to act as a straw purchaser in a continuing series of transactions from which the person obtains income or resources; or obtaining a firearm by inducing another person to act as a straw purchaser. Finally, the bill directs the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to include in the Firearms Transaction Record form a statement outlining penalties for acting as a straw purchaser.</summary>
</bill>
