<bill session="108" type="s" number="2016" updated="2023-01-15T09:32:49Z">
  <state datetime="2004-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Infant Crib Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for infant crib safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Infant Crib Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000442" joined="2004-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2004-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2004-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S186"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Furniture industry"/>
    <term name="Hotels, motels, etc."/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-04T21:05:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Infant Crib Safety Act - Makes it unlawful for any commercial user to: (1) manufacture, sell, or contract to sell any full-size or nonfull-size crib which is unsafe for any infant; or (2) sell, contract to sell or resell, lease, sublet, or otherwise place in the stream of commerce any such crib which is not new and is unsafe for any infant. Makes it unlawful for any lodging facility to offer or provide such an unsafe crib. Presumes as unsafe a crib which does not conform to specified standards in the Code of Federal Regulations and the American Society for Testing Materials Voluntary Standards, unless labeled as dangerous for an infant and not intended to be used for one.

Grants the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) enforcement powers as if this Act were a consumer product safety standard promulgated by it under the Consumer Product Safety Act.

Declares a violation of this Act shall be considered a prohibited act within the meaning of the CPSA, and subject to its penalties and remedies.</summary>
</bill>
