<bill session="118" type="h" number="2866" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:32Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Critical Technology Security Centers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Critical Technology Security Centers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish Critical Technology Security Centers in the Department of Homeland Security to evaluate and test the security of critical technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2023-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Management and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-23T02:57:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Critical Technology Security Centers Act of 2023

This bill directs the Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), to support the establishment of at least two cybersecurity-focused Critical Technology Security Centers to evaluate and test the security of critical technology.

The centers shall leverage risk-based evaluations to focus on activities that have the greatest effect on the security of the critical technologies within each center's scope.

Each center must establish, in coordination with CISA, coordinated vulnerability disclosure processes. Vulnerabilities discovered by a center must be reported to the National Vulnerability Database of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.

Any center addressing open source software security may award grants to individual open source software developers and maintainers, nonprofit organizations, and other nonfederal entities to fund improvements in the security of the open source software ecosystem. Open source software is defined as software for which the human-readable source code is made available to the public for use, study, re-use, modification, enhancement, and redistribution.

Each center must report to the directorate on a biennial basis. The directorate shall then report to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
