<bill session="117" type="h" number="4930" updated="2023-01-01T20:19:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to continue processing the proposed SFO NIITE Departure Southbound Transition and the OAK HUSSH Departure Southbound Transition, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SHHH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHHH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southbound HUSSH and NIITE Help Households Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2021-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-04T14:12:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Southbound HUSSH and NIITE Help Households Act or the SHHH Act

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to continue processing the proposed San Francisco International Airport NIITE Departure Southbound Transition and the Oakland International Airport HUSSH Departure Southbound Transition and render a determination as to adoption of the proposal.

The FAA may not prevent the San Francisco International Airport/Community Roundtable from initiating their own proposed NIITE Departure or HUSSH Departure Southbound Transition procedures through the Instrumental Flight Procedures Gateway or other process unless it is necessary for safety reasons that cannot be remedied.</summary>
</bill>
