<bill session="112" type="h" number="5814" updated="2019-11-15T21:11:31Z">
  <state datetime="2012-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Poll Tape Transparency Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Poll Tape Transparency Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish standards for the publication of the poll tapes used in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA08" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="Elections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="5799" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3608" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-29T21:37:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Poll Tape Transparency Act of 2012 - Amends the Help America Vote Act with respect to the requirements for each voting system used in a federal election.

Requires the appropriate election official, upon the closing of the polls at each polling place, and under the observation of the certified tabulation observers admitted to the polling place, to: (1) announce the vote orally; (2) post a copy of the poll tape reflecting the totals from each voting machine in the polling place upon which votes were cast; (3) prepare and post a statement of the total number of individuals who appeared at the polling place to cast ballots; and (4) display by noon the following day, at a prominent public location, a copy of each poll tape and statement.

Requires display of such information also on the official public websites of the applicable local election official and chief state election official.

Specifies similar treatment of ballots cast at early voting sites, absentee ballots, and the daily count of provisional ballots.</summary>
</bill>
