<bill session="118" type="s" number="553" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HUD Health and Safety Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HUD Health and Safety Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to reform policies and issue guidance related to health and safety accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-08T11:09:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">HUD Health and Safety Accountability Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to make changes to policies and procedures applicable to HUD multifamily housing programs, including Section 8 project-based rental assistance (PBRA).

 The bill requires management and occupancy reviews conducted by the Office of Multifamily Housing Programs to include specified graded factors, including (1) responsiveness to local code violations; and (2) remediation of health, sanitation, and structural integrity issues.

Additionally, the bill establishes or changes requirements regarding

 local code enforcement response, HUD oversight of individual units that receive PBRA assistance, tenant surveys issued by performance-based contract administrators, and the disclosure of program contact information to tenants.</summary>
</bill>
