<bill session="118" type="h" number="3626" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:54Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EMS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Management Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EMS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 to set training requirements on eligibility for certain emergency management performance grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2023-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-19T13:45:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Management Support Act or the EMS Act

This bill establishes additional eligibility requirements to receive emergency management performance grants.

Specifically, to be eligible to receive a grant, a state must require local emergency management directors to successfully complete Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) provided baseline emergency management training developed in accordance with the National Incident Management System by one year after this bill's enactment and recurrently at an interval determined by FEMA to strengthen local emergency management capacity.

Further, a state must submit certifications to FEMA annually regarding compliance. A state that cannot certify that all local emergency management directors have completed the training must submit a certification that includes (1) an identification of all barriers to achieving the baseline emergency management training requirement, and (2) an approach to overcoming the barriers identified with an anticipated timeline for full compliance.</summary>
</bill>
