<bill session="118" type="s" number="2703" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Our Farm and Food System Workforce Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Our Farm and Food System Workforce Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to establish the Office of the Farm and Food System Workforce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2024-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3765-3766" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-24T18:08:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supporting Our Farm and Food System Workforce Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Office of the Farm and Food System Workforce to improve awareness of and access to USDA programs for farm and food system workers.

USDA must also establish the Farm and Food System Worker&#160;Advisory Committee. The advisory committee must include farm and food system workers, civil rights representatives, and representatives from&#160;nonprofit organizations, labor unions, and institutions of higher education.&#160;

The bill further requires USDA to establish the Farm and Food System Workforce&#160;Interagency Council&#160;to facilitate interagency, cabinet-level leadership in planning, policymaking, coordination, and program development for services available to farm and food system workers.&#160;&#160;

The advisory committee and interagency council must each submit an annual report to USDA and Congress that is publicly available on USDA's website. The annual reports must include&#160;recommendations for legislative or administrative action for the following year.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
