<bill session="116" type="h" number="172" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Source Review Permitting Improvement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend sections 111, 169, and 171 of the Clean Air Act to clarify when a physical change in, or change in the method of operation of, a stationary source constitutes a modification or construction, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Source Review Permitting Improvement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2019-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2019-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2019-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2662" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-10T16:26:55Z" status="Introduced in House">New Source Review Permitting Improvement Act of 2018 [sic]

This bill modifies terminology for purposes of the New Source Review (NSR) permitting program of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA).

In order for a change to a stationary source to be a modification (a change to a stationary source that increases the air pollutant emissions or results in new pollutants) for purposes of the NSR permitting program, the maximum hourly emission rate achievable by such source must be higher than the maximum hourly rate achievable by such source during any hour in the 10-year period preceding the change.

A change at a stationary source is not considered to be a modification under the bill if it is designed to (1) reduce the amount of any air pollutant emitted; or (2) restore, maintain, or improve the reliability of operations at, or safety of, the source. However, such changes are not excepted if the EPA determines the increase in the maximum achievable hourly emission rate from such change would cause an adverse effect on human health or the environment.

Construction for a major emitting facility (a type of stationary source) does not include a change at such a facility that does not result in a significant emissions increase or a significant net emissions increase.

In relation to major emitting facilities in nonattainment areas, the terms modifications and modified do not include changes at such facilities that do not result in a significant emissions increase or a significant net emissions increase.</summary>
</bill>
