<bill session="119" type="h" number="2558" updated="2025-11-19T02:58:52Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFETY Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding American Food and Export Trade Yields Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFETY Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to preserve foreign markets for goods using common names, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000301"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000300" joined="2025-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000470" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000829" joined="2025-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1230" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-27T10:20:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding American Food and Export Trade Yields Act of 2025 or the SAFETY Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to secure foreign markets for goods using common names.

In general, the bill defines common name as a name that (1) is ordinarily or customarily used for an agricultural commodity or food product, (2) is typically placed on the packaging and product label of the agricultural commodity or food product, and (3) the use of which is consistent with standards of the Codex Alimentarius Commission. The bill includes a list of names that will be considered common names for (1) food products (e.g., basmati, bratwurst, and parmesan); (2) wine, including grape varietal terms, grape variety designations, and non-varietal descriptors such as chateau and vintage; and (3) beer (e.g., bitter, pale ale, and hefeweizen).

Specifically, USDA must coordinate efforts with the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to secure the right of U.S. agricultural producers, processors, and exporters to use common names for agricultural commodities or food products in foreign markets. Through the negotiation of bilateral, plurilateral, or multilateral agreements, memoranda of understanding, or exchanges of letters, USDA and the USTR must assure the current and future use of each common name in connection with U.S. agricultural commodities or food products.

USDA and the&#160;USTR must jointly brief Congress on these efforts on a semi-annual basis.</summary>
</bill>
