<bill session="117" type="h" number="7125" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:49Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stopping the Spread of Taxpayer-Funded Bioweapons Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping the Spread of Taxpayer-Funded Bioweapons Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Act to prevent the proliferation of biological weapons under the Cooperative Threat Reduction Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-14T13:48:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Stopping the Spread of Taxpayer-Funded Bioweapons Act of 2022

This bill prohibits the Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program from engaging in certain activities related to biological threats. (The program works with foreign countries to address the risks from weapons of mass destruction, including by securing such weapons and detecting the spread of especially dangerous pathogens.)

Specifically, the program may not engage in (1) cooperative biological engagement; or (2) activities for facilitating the detection and reporting of diseases that could be used as an early warning detection mechanism for outbreaks, regardless of whether such diseases are caused by biological weapons.</summary>
</bill>
