<bill session="116" type="h" number="4048" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Automatic Listening Exploitation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the use, recording, or transmission of any speech or sound captured by a smart speaker, or any video or image captured by a video doorbell, and to prohibit, as an unfair or deceptive act or practice, such use, recording, or transmission without the express consent of the consumer.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Automatic Listening Exploitation Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-24T19:55:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Automatic Listening Exploitation Act of 2019 This bill limits the capturing and use of recordings through smart speakers and video doorbells. Specifically, it prohibits providers of services through smart speakers (e.g., Alexa, Google Home, Apple HomePod) from capturing or storing voice recordings unless the speaker is intentionally activated by the user. Further, the bill prohibits providers of services through video doorbell systems (e.g., Nest, Ring, SimpliSafe) from recording or storing video or audio from such systems unless the doorbell has been activated by (1) pressing the doorbell, (2) a remote user, or (3) the doorbell&#8217;s sensor. When such a device has been activated, the video recording must be provided to the remote user via smart phone or similar device at the time the recording is being made. Except for specified purposes, the use, or transfer to a third party, of such recordings from smart speakers or video doorbells is prohibited unless the user (1) is given clear notice, (2) provides express consent for the specific use or transfer, and (3) has the ability to delete such recordings at any time.

The Federal Trade Commission must enforce the requirements of this bill and treat violations as unfair or deceptive practices and state attorneys general may bring civil actions to (1) enjoin violations, (2) enforce compliance with the requirements of this bill, or (3) obtain fines not to exceed $40,000 for each violation.</summary>
</bill>
