<bill session="118" type="s" number="44" updated="2025-11-19T04:52:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ONSHORE Manufacturing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Obtaining National and Secure Homeland Operations for Rare Earth Manufacturing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ONSHORE Manufacturing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to incentivize investment in facilities that carry out the metallurgy of rare earth elements and the production of finished rare earth products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2888" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-22T18:17:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Obtaining National and Secure Homeland Operations for Rare Earth Manufacturing Act of 2023 or the ONSHORE Manufacturing Act of 2023

This bill sets forth provisions to support secure supply chains of rare earth elements. A rare earth element means a natural element associated with (1) the metallic element scandium, with atomic number 21; (2) the metallic element yttrium, with atomic number 39; or (3) any of the series of 15 metallic elements between lanthanum, with atomic number 57, and lutetium, with atomic number 71, on the periodic table.

The Department of Energy (DOE) must establish a program that provides financial assistance for facilities located in the United States that produce finished rare earth products from purified rare earth elements. Financial assistance may be provided to (1) construct such facilities, (2) support workforce development for the facilities, or (3) support site development and technological upgrade for facilities.

The Department of the Treasury may establish the Minerals Security Partnership Fund to support the development and adoption of a secure supply chain for rare earth elements.

DOE must also establish an initiative with educational, workforce training, and apprenticeship programs relating to advanced rare earth element mining, separation, processing, metallurgy, and advanced equipment maintenance capabilities.

In addition, the President must develop a plan of action for using the authorities available under the Defense Production Act of 1950 to establish or enhance a domestic production capability for finished rare earth products and related technologies.</summary>
</bill>
