<bill session="115" type="s" number="1555" updated="2023-01-11T13:37:06Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Education Experience Improvement Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the administration of Post-9/11 Educational Assistance by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Experience Improvement Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2017-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1331" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1391" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2549" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="3205" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="3218" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="1598" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T14:44:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Education Experience Improvement Act of 2017 

This bill revises the administration of certain veterans educational benefits.

The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) shall establish training requirements for school certifying officials (SCOs) employed by educational institutions offering approved veterans education courses. An institution shall employ one SCO for every 500 unduplicated veteran's enrollment certifications made during a fiscal year. The VA may disapprove any course of education offered by an institution that does not meet such requirements.

The bill increases: (1) the VA reporting fee paid to an institution for each individual using veterans educational benefits at such institution,and (2) resources available to SCOs and state approving agencies.

The VA shall provide: (1) veterans with on-campus educational and vocational counseling services, and (2) institutions with educational assistance information regarding enrolled veterans.

A course that begins within seven days of the beginning of an academic term shall be treated as beginning on such date for purposes of certifying a veteran's eligibility for educational benefits.

The Veterans' Advisory Committee on Education is extended to December 31, 2022.</summary>
</bill>
