<bill session="117" type="h" number="7568" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Courts and Public Defender Service Employment Non-Discrimination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Courts and Public Defender Service Employment Non-Discrimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for coverage of employees of the District of Columbia courts and the District of Columbia Public Defender Service under the District of Columbia Human Rights Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E401-402"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-28T20:15:41Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia Courts and Public Defender Service Employment Non-Discrimination Act

This bill provides for coverage of certain employees of the District of Columbia under the District of Columbia Human Rights Act of 1977. The act prohibits discrimination in the District on the basis of certain protected characteristics (e.g., race) in a variety of settings, including employment.

The bill specifies that nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts and employees of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service shall be considered to be employees, and the courts and public defender service shall be considered to be employers, under the act.

The bill also excludes complaints of discrimination that are filed against the courts or public defender service from the District's procedures for handling complaints of governmental discrimination.</summary>
</bill>
