<bill session="117" type="s" number="3186" updated="2022-12-30T08:33:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PATRIA Y VIDA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PATRIA Y VIDA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Against Tyrants by Restoring Internet Access and Yielding Vital Interconnectivity in Designated Areas Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the United States Government to obtain and maintain the capacity to transmit internet access service abroad and domestically in case of emergency-related disruptions, and to strengthen support for circumvention technologies that allow users to evade government-backed censorship.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-08T19:28:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Against Tyrants by Restoring Internet Access and Yielding Vital Interconnectivity in Designated Areas Act or the PATRIA Y VIDA Act

This bill requires activities to expand the capacity of the U.S. government to transmit internet access and counter foreign internet censorship.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must obtain the capacity to transmit internet access domestically in the event of emergency-related network disruptions, while the Department of State must obtain the capacity to transmit internet access in foreign countries with repressive regimes. FEMA and the State Department must consult with other federal agencies on their efforts, including the National Telecommunications and Information Administration and the Federal Aviation Administration. Consulted agencies must provide necessary authorizations and support to allow FEMA and the State Department to transmit internet access.

In addition, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) must identify effective tools to counter large-scale internet censorship by foreign governments. In the event of increased demand for the tools, the FCC must rapidly provide funding to U.S. companies capable of deploying the tools to significant numbers of simultaneous users to circumvent internet censorship.

The FCC and the U.S. Agency for Global Media must jointly report on matters concerning the capacity to domestically and globally transmit internet access and tools to circumvent internet censorship by foreign governments.</summary>
</bill>
