<bill session="118" type="s" number="882" updated="2025-11-19T03:31:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">State and Local General Sales Tax Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State and Local General Sales Tax Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to clarify the use of certain taxes and revenues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000790"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2351" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="695" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-01T16:22:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State and Local General Sales Tax Protection Act

This bill specifies that certain requirements for aviation fuel tax revenue are limited to excise taxes on aviation fuel.

Current law requires that an Airport Improvement Program (AIP) grant recipient provide assurances that the proceeds from state and local taxes on aviation fuel will be used for the capital or operating costs of the airport or local airport system. Under current Federal Aviation Administration policy, this requirement applies to any tax on aviation fuel, regardless of whether the tax is imposed only on aviation fuel or is imposed on other products as well as aviation fuel.

This bill specifies that the AIP grant requirements apply only to state and local excise taxes on aviation fuel. The requirements do not apply to (1) state or local general sales taxes, or (2) state or local generally applicable sales taxes.</summary>
</bill>
