<bill session="112" type="s" number="2166" updated="2019-02-20T23:26:05Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grassroots Rural and Small Community Water Systems Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="display">Grassroots Rural and Small Community Water Systems Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to reauthorize technical assistance to small public water systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000705"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2012-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2012-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="1427" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-14T21:18:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Grassroots Rural and Small Community Water Systems Assistance Act - Calls for the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to prioritize the types of technical assistance to enable small public water systems to comply with national primary drinking water regulations that are the most beneficial to small and rural communities, based on their input.

Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to: (1) authorize appropriations to the Administrator of EPA for FY2012-FY2017 for such assistance; and (2) allow the Administrator to use such funds to provide technical assistance to nonprofit organizations that provide to small public water systems onsite technical assistance, circuit-rider technical assistance programs, onsite and regional training, assistance with implementing source water protection plans, and assistance with implementation monitoring plans, rules, regulations, and water security enhancements. Directs the Administrator to give preference to nonprofit organizations that are determined to be the most qualified and experienced and that the small community water systems find to be the most beneficial and effective.</summary>
</bill>
