<bill session="119" type="h" number="5780" updated="2025-11-05T09:05:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Emergency Management Continuity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Emergency Management Continuity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to continue to obligate and disburse covered funds in the Disaster Relief Fund during a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2025-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001103" joined="2025-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2025-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000830" joined="2025-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-23T18:56:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Emergency Management Continuity Act of 2025

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to continue using certain funds in the Disaster Relief Fund (DRF) during a lapse in appropriations (i.e., government shutdown).

Specifically, FEMA must continue obligating and disbursing funds in the DRF that were appropriated before the lapse in appropriations and remain available to be expended. The funds may be used for any disaster relief, emergency assistance, and recovery program authorized under the Robert&#160;T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, including individual assistance, public assistance, and other disbursements and obligations&#160;for&#160;programs or activities necessary to protect life and property during a lapse in appropriations.

The bill also requires employees who are necessary to carry out these disbursements or related program activities to be treated as excepted employees under the Anti-Deficiency Act. (Excepted employees are required to work during a lapse in appropriations.) The bill also prohibits these employees from being subject to a furlough or a reduction in force due to a lapse in appropriations.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
