<bill session="118" type="h" number="1554" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">INVEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Incentives for our Nation&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Veterans in Energy Sustainability Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide the work opportunity tax credit with respect to the hiring of veterans in the field of renewable energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2023-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-29T18:55:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Incentives for our Nation's Veterans in Energy Sustainability Technologies or the INVEST Act

This bill allows the work opportunity tax credit to be used for the hiring of a specified veteran who works in a field of renewable energy. A specified veteran means any veteran who is certified as (1) having received a credential or certification from the Department of Defense of a military occupational specialty or skill in a field of renewable energy or with respect to advanced manufacturing, machinist or welding, or engineering; (2) having completed a vocational degree in a field of renewable energy; or (3) having completed a LEED (Leadership in Energy &amp; Environmental Design) certification with the United States Green Building Council.

The Department of the Treasury shall compensate specified U.S. possessions for their losses resulting from this bill.</summary>
</bill>
