<bill session="110" type="s" number="1733" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:44Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Fairness Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize funds to prevent housing discrimination through the use of nationwide testing, to increase funds for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Fairness Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2007-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2008-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2007-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2007-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8707"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8707-8708" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="2926" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-09-13T19:12:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Housing Fairness Act of 2007 - Instructs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to conduct, and report to Congress on, a nationwide testing program to: (1) detect and document differences in the treatment of persons seeking to rent or purchase housing or obtain or refinance a home mortgage loan; (2) measure patterns of adverse treatment because of the race, color, religion, sex, familial status, disability status, or national origin of a renter, home buyer, or borrower; and (3) measure the prevalence of such discriminatory practices across housing and mortgage lending markets.



Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 to reauthorize the fair housing initiatives program.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary should: (1) fully comply with such Act's requirements to establish, design, and maintain a national education and outreach program for the development and dissemination of the fair housing rights of individuals who seek to rent, purchase, sell, or facilitate the sale of a home; (2) use all amounts appropriated for such program; and (3) promulgate regulations on the fair housing obligations of each recipient of federal housing funds to affirmatively further fair housing.

Directs the Secretary to implement a competitive matching grant program to assist private nonprofit organizations in: (1) conducting comprehensive studies of specified aspects of the causes and effects of housing discrimination and segregation; and (2) implementing pilot projects that test solutions to help prevent or alleviate housing discrimination and segregation.</summary>
</bill>
