<bill session="119" type="hc" number="5" updated="2025-03-07T21:12:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Legislative Proxy and Absence Accommodation Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Proxy and Absence Accommodation Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Establishing grounds under which Members of Congress may vote by proxy and remotely attend committee proceedings in the event of illness, a death in the family, jury service, military service, and other emergency situations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000788"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-07T21:12:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Legislative Proxy and Absence Accommodation Resolution

This concurrent resolution authorizes proxy voting and remote appearances by Members of&#160;Congress&#160;who are&#160;absent due to an&#160;illness, military service,&#160;jury duty, or other circumstances.&#160;

The concurrent resolution establishes grounds and procedures by which an absent Member of the House of Representatives or the Senate may (1) designate another Member to cast a vote or record the presence of the absent Member; and (2) remotely appear at a committee proceeding.

The concurrent resolution authorizes proxy voting and remote appearances for absences due to

jury duty;the death of a family member;a family member who has a serious health condition;the Member's own&#160;illness or serious health condition; the birth, adoption, or foster placement of a son or daughter;the Member serving in the armed services;a family member being called to active duty;&#160;ora condition preventing the Member from safely traveling to or performing work at the proceeding.Certain purposes are time-limited; for example, an absence due to a Member's own illness is limited to seven days in a calendar year.

Further, a Member must provide to the Clerk of the House or the Secretary of the Senate, respectively&#160;(1) a written proxy designation or notice of remote appearance, (2) the grounds for the absence, and (3) such documentation as they may require.&#160;The Clerk and Secretary must maintain and make publicly available a list of the grounds, time frames, and other details about Members&#160;using these provisions.</summary>
</bill>
