<bill session="108" type="s" number="2210" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:08Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tax Shelter and Tax Haven Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restrict the use of abusive tax shelters and offshore tax havens to inappropriately avoid Federal taxation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Shelter and Tax Haven Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2004-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2778-2783"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2783-2790" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Tax consultants"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax havens"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-29T14:59:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tax Shelter and Tax Haven Reform Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to add or increase penalties for: (1) promoting abusive tax shelters; (2) aiding and abetting the understatement of tax liability; (3) failing to provide required information on a tax shelter; (4) failing to maintain a client list of tax shelter investors; (5) failing to disclose potentially abusive tax shelters; and (6) failing to report certain interests in foreign financial accounts. Extends the expiration period for assessing and collecting tax for failure to disclose information relating to a potentially abusive tax shelter. Expands the types of tax shelter activity for which the Secretary of the Treasury can obtain injunctive relief.

Authorizes the Secretary to censure or fine tax practitioners who violate standards of behavior for practice before the Department of the Treasury. Directs the Secretary to impose specified standards for issuing professional tax shelter opinions. Expands provisions denying privilege for communications between a tax shelter promoter and a corporate client to include any person directly or indirectly participating in tax shelter activities. Authorizes the Secretary to share certain tax return information with the Securities and Exchange Commission and other agencies relating to tax shelter and tax evasion activities. Revises rules allowing disclosure of tax return information by tax practitioners to certain governmental agencies, including congressional committees.

Imposes a penalty on tax practitioners who make a fee agreement with a taxpayer contingent upon actual or projected tax savings.

Expresses the sense of the Senate that additional funds should be appropriated for Internal Revenue Service enforcement efforts against abusive tax shelter activities and that the IRS should devote more of its enforcement funds for that purpose.

Sets forth rules for the application of the economic substance doctrine. Imposes additional penalties for underpayment of taxes resulting from abusive tax shelter activities and from transactions lacking economic substance.

Requires disclosure of payments of $10,000 or more to accounts or persons located in an uncooperative tax haven (a foreign country that imposes no or nominal taxation and that has rules and practices that impede disclosure of tax information). Directs the Secretary to publish an annual list of uncooperative tax havens. Denies certain tax benefits for income attributable to activities in an uncooperative tax haven.</summary>
</bill>
