<bill session="118" type="h" number="3276" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy Future Students and Earth Pilot Program Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Future Students and Earth Pilot Program Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a pilot grant program to make grants to school food authorities to provide 100 percent plant-based food and milk options, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2023-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000400" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2024-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-23T18:44:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Future Students and Earth Pilot Program Act of 2023 

This bill establishes pilot programs for providing 100% plant-based food and milk options in school meals and expands access to nondairy beverages in school meals.

Specifically, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must carry out a pilot program to award grants for purposes such as training food service personnel on serving 100% plant-based food options and covering additional costs of buying plant-based foods. USDA&#160;must give priority in awarding pilot program grants to school food authorities that will use the funds to serve a high proportion of children who are eligible for free or reduced-price meals.&#160;

The bill also requires a school participating in the school lunch program to substitute a nondairy beverage that is nutritionally equivalent to fluid milk, and meets USDA-established standards, if the student's parent or legal guardian submits a written request for such substitution. Further, a school has the option to offer each student a nondairy beverage as a substitute for fluid milk if it&#160; meets these same standards. &#160;

USDA must also establish a pilot program to reimburse eligible schools for the cost of providing a nondairy beverage as a substitute for fluid milk. Eligible schools are those where at least 50% of the students served are eligible for free or reduced-price meals.&#160;&#160; &#160;</summary>
</bill>
