<bill session="116" type="h" number="5561" updated="2022-02-09T02:12:22Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WIRED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to require one-stop delivery systems under such Act to offer services through internet websites and to direct the Secretary of Labor to develop standards and best practices for such websites, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Widening Internet Readiness for Employment Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIRED Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2020-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-16T16:34:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Widening Internet Readiness for Employment Development Act or the WIRED Act

This bill expands one-stop delivery system requirements to include online access. (One-stop delivery systems provide comprehensive career and employment training services.)

The Department of Labor must establish certain standards and best practices for the provision of employment and training services through electronic means by one-stop delivery systems. The services provided online must include addresses, hours, and services&#160;of physical one-stop centers in a local area; incorporate social media and networking capabilities; be accessible to mobile devices; and provide other employment-seeking assistance.</summary>
</bill>
