<bill session="117" type="h" number="3323" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Home Loan Banks&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Mission Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the ability of the Federal Home Loan Bank system to provide critical financing to address the economic crisis caused by the COVID-19 and to meet the short- and long-term housing and community economic development needs of low-income communities, including Tribal communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Home Loan Banks&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Mission Implementation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1684" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-21T15:02:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Home Loan Banks' Mission Implementation Act 

This bill generally expands the ability of Federal Home Loan Banks (FHLBs) to provide advances and grants for activities related to small businesses, affordable housing, and community development. The 11 regional FHLBs serve as government-sponsored enterprises to support mortgage lending and related community investment through advances to member financial institutions. These advances are secured by assets such as mortgages and other loans.

Specifically, the bill allows FHLBs to provide advances that are secured by (1) loans guaranteed by the Small Business Administration, and (2) certain loans made in response to the economic impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and guaranteed or insured by the federal government.

The bill also expands the availability of advances to certain community development financial institutions and credit unions. It also gives the Federal Housing Finance Agency discretion in setting the average asset maximum for certain community financial institutions to qualify for an advance. However, this maximum must not be more than $10 billion. Currently, a community financial institution must have less than $1 billion in average total assets to qualify.

Furthermore, the bill exempts from taxation for two years after the conclusion of the COVID-19 emergency period certain municipal bonds guaranteed by an FHLB.

The bill also increases the percentage of earnings FHLBs must annually contribute to the Affordable Housing Program and sets aside a specified percentage to benefit tribes under this program.</summary>
</bill>
