<bill session="108" type="s" number="1903" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:29Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">North Korean Freedom Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote human rights, democracy, and development in North Korea, to promote overall security on the Korean Peninsula and establish a more peaceful world environment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Korean Freedom Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2003-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-25T20:35:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">North Korean Freedom Act of 2003 - Requires the Secretary of State to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the North Korean prison and labor camp system. Urges the United Nations to prepare similar reports, and the U.S. Commission of International Religious Freedom to hold extended informational hearings in the United States on the status of religious persecution in North Korea.

Requires the Director of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to report to the appropriate congressional committees on use of Federal resources by entities providing humanitarian and food assistance to North Korea.

Declares the sense of Congress about: (1) a first asylum policy for North Koreans arriving in the United States; (2) adoption of North Korean children by Americans; and (3) funding for the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.

Makes the case-by-case basis and alien specific requirements of the Immigration and Nationality Act inapplicable to the parole of any North Korean native or citizen seeking entry to the United States. Provides for adjustment to permanent resident status of any such alien paroled into the United States at the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security (HS).

Declares that extraordinary and temporary conditions shall be considered to exist in North Korea that prevent North Korean aliens from returning to North Korea in safety, thereby entitling them to temporary protected status.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to extend S visa (nonimmigrant alien) classification to individuals possessing critical reliable information concerning the activities of governments or other organizations with respect to weapons of mass destruction, and willing to supply such information to the U.S. Government. Increases the number of individuals provided S visas during a fiscal year. Directs the HS Secretary to issue regulations entitling North Koreans applying for political asylum to employment authorization, without the 180-day limitation.

Establishes within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a Weapons of Mass Destruction Informant Center.

Authorizes the USAID Director to make three-year grants to nongovernmental, non-profit organizations (NGOs) or persons, or foreign governmental organizations (FGOs) providing human rights assistance to North Koreans attempting to escape North Korea or its agents, or establishing or operating North Korean refugee camps or resettlement centers. Authorizes USAID grants to NGOs assisting North Korean orphans.

Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to: (1) NGOs or persons providing legal assistance to North Koreans applying for refugee status, parole, visas, or other means of admission to the United States; and (2) NGOs from the United States, South Korea, and Japan to promote dialogue regarding human rights in North Korea.

Directs the the Broadcasting Board of Governors to establish a program for the distribution of radios in North Korea.

Declares the sense of Congress regarding U.S. financial assistance designed to address conditions created by the economic and political system of North Korea, especially the activities of Division 39 of the North Korean Government.

Authorizes the USAID Director to make two-year grants to: (1) human rights NGOs or persons, or FGOs to promote and support programs for democracy, good governance, and the rule of law; and (2) other NGOs, persons, or FGOs that promote market economies modeled after programs in Vietnam.

Declares the sense of Congress regarding: (1) negotiations with North Korea; and (2) the lifting of trade sanctions against North Korea and provision of economic assistance to the North Korean people.

Prescribes conditions for humanitarian and nonhumanitarian U.S. aid and other assistance to North Korea.

Directs the President to establish an Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat North Korean Criminal Activities.</summary>
</bill>
