<bill session="117" type="s" number="882" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:37Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting American Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act to modify the authority for the National Labor Relations Board with respect to rulemaking, issuance of complaints, and authority over unfair labor practices.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting American Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2021-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2063" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-23T13:01:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting American Jobs Act

This bill limits the authority of the National Labor Relations Board.

Specifically, it repeals the authority of the General Counsel ofthe board to issue, and prosecute before the board, complaints of unfair labor practices. The bill also limits the board's rulemaking authority to rules concerning the internal functions of the board and prohibits the board from promulgating regulations affecting the substantive or procedural rights of any person, employer, employee, or labor organization, including rules concerning unfair labor practices and representation elections. Not later than six months after this bill is enacted, the board must review existing regulations and revise or rescind such regulations as necessary to implement these modifications to the board's rulemaking authority.

In addition, the bill repeals the board's authority to issue orders preventing unfair labor practices, replacing it with a more limited authority to investigate allegations of such practices. Finally, it repeals the board's authority to petition courts for enforcement of its orders, seek injunctions, or hold hearings on jurisdictional strikes.</summary>
</bill>
