<bill session="109" type="s" number="1557" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:21Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Respect for Life Pluripotent Stem Cell Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a program at the National Institutes of Health to conduct and support research in the derivation and use of human pluripotent stem cells by means that do not harm human embryos, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Respect for Life Pluripotent Stem Cell Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="popular">Stem Cell Research bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000560"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000595" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2005-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7366"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3144" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Cloning"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Human embryology"/>
    <term name="Laboratory animals"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-21T15:41:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Respect for Life Pluripotent Stem Cell Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to provide for the conduct and support of basic and applied research in isolating, deriving, and using pluripotent stems cells without creating or harming human embryos. Provides that such research may include: (1) research in animals to develop and test techniques for deriving cells from embryos without doing harm to embryos; (2) research to develop and test techniques for producing human pluripotent stems cells without creating or making use of embryos; and (3) research to isolate, develop, and test pluripotent stem cells from postnatal tissues, umbilical cord blood, and placenta.

Prohibits research under this Act that: (1) involves the use of human embryos; (2) involves the use of stem cells not otherwise eligible for NIH funds; (3) involves the use of any stem cell to create or to attempt to create a human embryo; or (4) poses a significant risk of creating a human embryo by any means.</summary>
</bill>
