<bill session="117" type="h" number="6141" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:07Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To make technical amendments to Public Law 93-531 relating to lands of the Navajo Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make technical amendments to Public Law 93-531 relating to lands of the Navajo Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-17T15:56:12Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill addresses the land settlement agreement between the Navajo Nation and the Hopi Tribe in Arizona. Among other things, the bill requires the Department of the Interior to study the impacts of relocation and federal development freezes (commonly known as the Bennett Freeze), allows the Navajo Nation to select an additional 757 acres of land, and expands the authority of the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation to carry out a rehabilitation program to redress the effects of the Bennett Freeze.

The Bennett Freeze was issued administratively in 1966 by former Bureau of Indian Affairs Commissioner Robert Bennett to restrict the Navajo Nation from constructing and repairing their dwellings on land subject to a land dispute with the Hopi Tribe.</summary>
</bill>
