<bill session="118" type="h" number="944" updated="2025-11-18T20:32:43Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Malign CCP Influence on Academic Institutions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Malign CCP Influence on Academic Institutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to disclose certain ties to organizations affiliated with the Government of the People's Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, and the People's Liberation Army, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2023-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000061" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001222" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2023-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="768" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-16T12:18:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Malign CCP Influence on Academic Institutions Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) to disclose information regarding gifts from and contracts with organizations affiliated with China's government, the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), or the People's Liberation Army (PLA), including certain educational institutes or programs, think tanks, and business entities.

Under current law, an IHE must disclose to the Department of Education (ED) a gift or contract from a foreign source that is valued at $250,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that foreign source. This bill establishes a special disclosure rule relating to organizations affiliated with China's government, the CCP, or the PLA. Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to disclose a gift from or contract with such an organization that is valued at $5,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that organization.

Additionally, the bill requires an IHE that receives federal grants to annually file a report with ED that identifies any activities conducted pursuant to a contract or other agreement between the IHE and such an organization, including any joint research or academic exchanges. Such contracts or agreements must be publicly available on the IHE's website.</summary>
</bill>
