<bill session="108" type="s" number="2820" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:31Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement To Improve Vital Emergency Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the availability of certain spectrum for public safety entities by amending the Communications Act of 1934 to establish January 1, 2009, as the date by which the transition to digital television shall be completed, and for other puropses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">SAVE LIVES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement To Improve Vital Emergency Services Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE LIVES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement To Improve Vital Emergency Services Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9445-9447"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="816">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 816.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>By Senator McCain from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 108-428.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television industry"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-10T22:12:11Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Spectrum Availability for Emergency-Response and Law-Enforcement to Improve Vital Emergency Services (SAVE LIVES) Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from granting any extension in the required reassignment of broadcasting stations between 764 and 776 and 794 and 806 megahertz for public safety services. Directs the FCC to complete the assignment of the electromagnetic spectrum between such stations, and to permit operations by public safety services on those frequencies commencing no later than January 1, 2008. Authorizes the FCC, beginning on such date, to modify or reassign the licenses of licensees as necessary to permit such new operations. Allows the FCC to waive such requirements in specified circumstances.

Requires the FCC to report to specified congressional committees on strategies for meeting public safety communications needs and the advisability of reallocating spectrum in the 700 megahertz band for unlicensed broadband uses.

Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security's Under Secretary for Science and Technology to establish the Wireless Public Safety Interoperability Communications Program (SAFECOM) and to complete a communications interoperability study. Authorizes appropriations.

Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a grant program to help first responders acquire and deploy interoperable communications equipment.

Establishes the Digital Transition Consumer Assistance Fund. Authorizes appropriations.

Requires the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program to assist households in transitioning from analog to digital television. Requires the program to: (1) become publicly available no later than January 1, 2008; and (2) give first priority to assisting lower income households.

Gives the FCC authority to require analog television sets sold or offered for sale after September 30, 2005, that will be incapable of broadcasting digital signals without an external device to be labeled as such.

Requires the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to recommend to specified congressional committees a program to educate consumers about the transition to digital broadcast signals.

Directs the FCC to issue final decisions in three pending proceedings. Requires the FCC, in one of the proceedings, to establish minimum guidelines for locally originated programming, local electoral and public affairs programming, and independently produced programming for television broadcast licensees.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-428</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
