<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="991" updated="2022-02-03T05:21:12Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2634" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-04-16T14:36:19-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000339"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-04-16"/>
  <description>Amendment made various technical corrections within the bill's "Findings" section, and added under the eligibility criteria the requirement that a country must be complying with minimum standards for eliminating human trafficking; cooperating with American efforts to stop illegal immigration to the United States and be committed to free and fair elections.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-586 to make various technical corrections within the bill's `Findings' section, and adds under the eligibility criteria the requirement that a country must also be complying with minimum standards for eliminating human trafficking; must be cooperating with American efforts to stop illegal immigration to the United States; and be committed to free and fair elections.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-04-16T14:36:19-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="196">
      <text>On agreeing to the Frank (MA) amendment (A001) as modified Agreed to by recorded vote: 424 - 0 (Roll no. 196).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2387" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16T13:50:33-04:00">
      <text>Frank (MA) amendment (A001) modified by unanimous consent. Modification made clarifying changes to the amendment as offered.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2387" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16T13:50:01-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Frank (MA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2387-2388, H2390" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16T13:50:01-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Frank (MA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2387-2388, H2390" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16T14:36:19-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16T14:36:19-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Frank (MA) amendment (A001) as modified Agreed to by recorded vote: 424 - 0 (Roll no. 196).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2387" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16T14:36:19-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
