<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="74" updated="2021-08-11T11:00:59Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3684" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-07-01T10:16:15-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000590"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-06-30"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 132 printed in House Report 117-75 to require that any wastewater infrastructure funded using the Clean Water State Revolving Fund or other Clean Water Act grant programs to first undergo a climate resiliency assessment, which would ensure that future wastewater infrastructure is designed and constructed to withstand potential impacts of climate change, including drought.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires that any wastewater infrastructure funded using the Clean Water State Revolving Fund or other Clean Water Act grant programs to first undergo a climate resiliency assessment, which would ensure that future wastewater infrastructure is designed and constructed to withstand potential impacts of climate change, including drought.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-07-01T10:16:15-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="206">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lee (NV) amendment (A009) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 200 (Roll no. 206).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3586" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30T22:58:36-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A009) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30T22:46:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A009) offered by Mrs. Lee (NV).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3574-3576" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3574-3575" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30"/>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30T22:46:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A009) offered by Mrs. Lee (NV).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3574-3576" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3574-3575" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01T10:16:15-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Lee (NV) amendment (A009) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 200 (Roll no. 206).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01T10:16:15-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lee (NV) amendment (A009) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 200 (Roll no. 206).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01T10:16:15-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
