<bill session="116" type="h" number="6991" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAUSE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit actions to terminate or withdraw the United States from international treaties without affirmative approval from both Houses of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAUSE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Actions Undermining Security without Endorsement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000613"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4304" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-06T17:38:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Actions Undermining Security without Endorsement Act or the PAUSE Act

This bill prohibits any action to terminate or withdraw the United States from an international treaty to which the Senate has given advice and consent to ratification unless specified conditions are met.

Specifically, such withdrawal may not occur unless the Department of Defense and the Department of State submit specific information to Congress and Congress enacts a joint resolution approving such action. The required submissions must include (1) a detailed justification for withdrawal from or termination of the treaty, (2) a certification that all other state parties to the treaty have been consulted with respect to such justification, and (3) a comprehensive strategy to mitigate against lost capacity of benefits from such treaty.

A decision by the President to not renew the treaty between the United States and Russia on measures for the reduction and limitation of strategic offensive arms (the New START Treaty) shall be subject to such requirements for up to an additional five years.</summary>
</bill>
