<bill session="119" type="h" number="2167" updated="2025-06-26T13:12:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To re-establish an advisory committee to provide independent advice and recommendations to the Secretary of Transportation regarding comprehensive, interdisciplinary issues related to transportation from a variety of stakeholders in transportation planning, design, research, policy, and advocacy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000808"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001229" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-26T13:08:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Transportation Equity Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to reestablish an advisory committee to provide independent advice and recommendations to DOT on transportation equity issues.

The bill designates the committee as the Transportation Equity Committee and requires the committee to also evaluate the work of DOT in connecting people to economic and related forms of opportunity and&#160;carrying out its strategic, research, technological, regulatory, community engagement, and economic policy activities related to transportation and opportunity.

In addition, DOT must appoint a full-time federal employee to serve as coordinator and act as the designated federal officer for the committee.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
