<bill session="118" type="s" number="297" updated="2025-08-30T10:56:24Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to authorize certain construction activities on public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to authorize certain construction activities on public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-311.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural equipment and machinery"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-06T22:19:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides for the construction of nurseries on public lands.

Using funds made available under the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to restore native vegetation and mitigate environmental hazards on mined land on federal and nonfederal lands, the Department of the Interior shall carry out a pilot program to establish and operate nurseries on lands under its jurisdiction.

Likewise, the Forest Service shall carry out a pilot program to establish and operate nurseries on National Forest System lands.

Interior shall carry out its pilot program in (1) four of the eleven contiguous Western states, and (2) one state that is not one of the eleven contiguous Western states.

The Forest Service shall carry out its pilot program in (1) four of the eleven contiguous Western states; and (2) one state, including Vermont, that is not one of the eleven contiguous Western states.</summary>
</bill>
