<bill session="118" type="s" number="2208" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Seafood Supply Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Seafood Supply Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to provide support for domestically harvested seafood, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2182" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-12T13:30:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Seafood Supply Act of 2023

This bill expands Department of Agriculture (USDA) support for domestically harvested seafood.

USDA must establish an Office of Seafood Policy and Program Integration to coordinate USDA's seafood policies and activities and to work in coordination with the Department of Commerce and the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative to support domestically harvested and processed wild and farmed seafood.

The bill&#160;establishes requirements that must be met to&#160;label fish&#160;as wild USA seafood&#160;or wild American seafood.&#160;

The bill also includes&#160;commercial fishing&#160;in the definition of farming for the purposes of certain USDA farm loans.

Further, the bill expands the Agricultural Marketing Service's Country of Origin Labeling (COOL) requirements to&#160;include cooked king crab and tanner crab and cooked and canned salmon. Under&#160;COOL,&#160;retailers must provide their customers with information regarding the source of certain foods (e.g., wild and farm-raised fish and shellfish).

In addition, the bill&#160;requires a school food authority to receive a waiver of Buy American requirements&#160;to purchase foreign seafood commodities and products under the&#160;National School Lunch Program unless the commodities or products are not produced domestically or available domestically. Further, the newly created Office of Seafood Policy and Program Integration&#160;must develop a plan to increase&#160;seafood in the school lunch program to levels commensurate with federal dietary guidelines.

Finally, USDA must conduct a&#160;study to identify barriers to local and regional food production, processing, and market delivery in locations facing food security challenges, including Alaska and Hawaii.</summary>
</bill>
