<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>791</number>
    <updateDate>2025-06-09T19:52:47Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2025-06-09T19:52:47Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2025-01-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>119</congress>
    <cdata>
      <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>&lt;pre&gt;[Congressional Record Volume 171, Number 18 (Tuesday, January 28, 2025)][House]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [&lt;a href="https://www.gpo.gov"&gt;www.gpo.gov&lt;/a&gt;]By Ms. LOFGREN:H.R. 791.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Pursuant to clause 7 of Rule XII of the Rules of the Houseof Representatives, the constitutional authority for enactingthe Foreign Anti-Digital Piracy Act is found in Article I,Section 8 of the United States Constitution, specifically.Clause 3 (Commerce Clause): Congress has the power ``Toregulate Commerce with foreign Nations, and among the severalStates, and with the Indian Tribes.'' This bill regulatesdigital piracy by targeting foreign websites engaged inlarge-scale copyright infringement, which impacts interstateand international commerce.Clause 8 (Copyright Clause): Congress has the power ``Topromote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, by securingfor limited Times to Authors and Inventors the exclusiveRight to their respective Writings and Discoveries.'' Thisbill protects copyright holders from foreign digital piracyoperations that threaten their exclusive rights.Clause 18 (Necessary and Proper Clause). Congress has thepower ``To make all Laws which shall be necessary and properfor carrying into Execution the foregoing Powers.'' This billestablishes enforcement mechanisms necessary to upholdCongress's authority under the Commerce and Copyright Clauses[Page H407]&lt;/pre&gt;</constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    </cdata>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2025-01-28T16:09:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-01-28</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-01-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2025-01-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000397</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Lofgren, Zoe [D-CA-18]</fullName>
        <firstName>Zoe</firstName>
        <lastName>Lofgren</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>18</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Commerce</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Commerce</name>
        <updateDate>2025-03-06T13:05:04Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2025-01-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2025-06-09T19:52:36Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreign Anti-Digital Piracy Act or FADPA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bill establishes a process for copyright owners and exclusive licensees to petition U.S. district courts to block access to foreign&amp;nbsp;websites or online services that engage in copyright infringement.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the bill allows a copyright owner or an exclusive licensee of a copyright owner to file a petition in a U.S. district court for the issuance of a preliminary order declaring that a foreign website or online service is engaging in copyright infringement. The petition must show that (1) the transmission through a foreign website or online service of a copyrighted work or live event likely infringes on the exclusive right of the owner or licensee to reproduce, distribute, publicly perform, or publicly display such work; and (2) the owner or licensee is likely to suffer irreparable harm as a result of the infringement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill outlines the process and the time frame for the court to issue a preliminary order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After obtaining a preliminary order, the copyright owner or licensee may request for the court to issue a blocking order that requires certain broadband service providers to take measures to prevent their users from accessing the foreign website or online service identified in the order. The bill outlines the terms and conditions of such an order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The court may require the copyright owner or licensee to pay the reasonable costs and expenses directly incurred by the service provider to comply with the order.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill includes liability protections for service providers.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Foreign Anti-Digital Piracy Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Foreign Anti-Digital Piracy Act</title>
        <updateDate>2025-03-04T12:53:20Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Foreign Anti-Digital Piracy Act</title>
        <updateDate>2025-03-04T12:53:18Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>To amend title 17, United States Code, to provide for blocking orders relating to specifically identified infringing foreign websites or online services, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2025-03-04T12:48:16Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2025-01-28T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-119hr791ih/xml/BILLS-119hr791ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2025-01-28</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
