<bill session="115" type="s" number="3019" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:11Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accurate Labels Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Packaging and Labeling Act to require that Federal and State mandated information declarations and labeling requirements applicable to the chemical composition of, and radiation emitted by, consumer products meet minimum scientific standards to deliver accurate and clear information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Labels Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6022" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-04T20:36:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accurate Labels Act

This bill&#160;restricts the authority of&#160;state and federal agencies&#160;to establish&#160;or enforce labeling&#160;requirements with respect to the chemical composition of,&#160;or radiation emitted by, consumer products. Specifically, such requirements&#160;(1) must exempt nonfunctional or naturally occurring substances; (2) must exempt the inclusion of trade secrets; (3)&#160;may not preclude the delivery of certain supplemental or clarifying information; (4)&#160;shall not apply to a&#160;substance if the concentration of the substance&#160;in the product is below a specified level; (5)&#160;shall not apply, with respect to the emission of radiation, if the level of emission is below a specified level; (6) must allow for certain information to be communicated to consumers electronically or digitally; and (7) must be risk-based and meet other specified standards.</summary>
</bill>
