<bill session="116" type="h" number="5842" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:44Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Voices for Environmental Justice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to award grants to entities to enable such entities to participate in decisions impacting the health and safety of their communities in connection with the release of certain hazardous air pollutants and the permitting of solid waste disposal facilities and hazardous waste facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voices for Environmental Justice Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2020-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2020-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2020-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-09T20:31:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Voices for Environmental Justice Act

This bill authorizes the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to award grants to eligible entities to participate in decisions impacting the health and safety of their communities in connection with an actual or potential release of a covered hazardous air pollutant. Additionally, the bill authorizes the EPA to award grants to eligible entities to participate in decisions impacting the health and safety of their communities relating to the permitting or permit renewal of a solid waste disposal facility or hazardous waste facility.

An eligible entity must be a group of individuals who reside in a community that (1) is a population or community of color, an indigenous community, or a low-income community; and (2) is in close proximity to the site of an actual or potential release of a covered hazardous air pollutant.

Covered hazardous air pollutants include those listed on the Toxics Release Inventory or those identified as carcinogenic by an assessment under the Integrated Risk Information System of the EPA.</summary>
</bill>
