<bill session="111" type="h" number="6272" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:32Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Servicemember Homeowner Assistance Program Extension Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeowners Assistance Program of the Department of Defense to eliminate the discretion of the Secretary of Defense to set an earlier termination date for the eligibility of a member of the Armed Forces for homeowner assistance when the member is permanently reassigned by order of the United States Government to a duty station or home port outside a 50-mile radius of the member's base or installation of residence.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemember Homeowner Assistance Program Extension Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000554"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-07T20:09:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Servicemember Homeowner Assistance Program Extension Act - Amends the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966 to provide a specific date of September 30, 2012, for the expiration of homeowners assistance provided through the Department of Defense (DOD) for members of the Armed Forces permanently reassigned to a duty station or home port outside a 50-mile radius of the member's home base or installation.</summary>
</bill>
