<bill session="117" type="h" number="6719" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 and the Water Resources Development Act of 1999 to provide assistance to non-Federal interests for water-related environmental infrastructure projects in northern and southern West Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Development Act of 1992 and the Water Resources Development Act of 1999 to provide assistance to non-Federal interests for water-related environmental infrastructure projects in northern and southern West Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001180"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-20T13:38:32Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides for furnishing assistance to nonfederal interests for water-related, environmental infrastructure and resource protection and development projects in northern and southern West Virginia.

The bill includes Gilmer, Mason, Putnam, Kanawha, Jackson, Roane, Clay, Wirt, Calhoun, Braxton, and Pendleton counties in central West Virginia as part of the Southern West Virginia Environmental Restoration Infrastructure and Resource Protection Development Pilot Program.

The bill redesignates the area of the pilot program to provide environmental assistance to nonfederal interests in central West Virginia to that of northern West Virginia.

The bill replaces the definition of the counties comprising central West Virginia with a definition of the counties comprising northern West Virginia.</summary>
</bill>
