<bill session="108" type="hr" number="611" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should immediately communicate to the members of the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) cartel and non-OPEC countries that participate in the cartel of crude oil producing countries the position of the United States that urgent action must be taken to increase world crude oil supplies so as to achieve stable crude oil prices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should immediately communicate to the members of the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) cartel and non-OPEC countries that participate in the cartel of crude oil producing countries the position of the United States that urgent action must be taken to increase world crude oil supplies so as to achieve stable crude oil prices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000716" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2004-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000392" joined="2004-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000712" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000008" joined="2004-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2004-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Deregulation"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy industries"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="OPEC countries"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-04T15:31:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the President and Congress should take both a short-term and a long-term approach to reducing and stabilizing crude oil prices as well as reducing dependence on foreign sources of energy.

Urges the President to communicate immediately to the members of the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) cartel and non-OPEC countries that participate in the cartel of crude oil producing countries that the United States: (1) seeks to maintain strong relations with crude oil producers around the world while promoting international efforts to remove barriers to energy trade and investment and increased access for U.S. energy firms around the world; (2) believes that restricting supply in a market that is in demand for additional crude oil does serious damage to OPEC member efforts to demonstrate that they represent a reliable source of crude oil supply; (3) believes that stable crude oil prices and supplies are essential for strong economic growth throughout the world; (4) seeks an immediate increase in the OPEC crude oil production quotas; and (5) will temporarily suspend further purchases of crude oil for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, thereby freeing up additional supply for the marketplace.

Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the actions and policies of the Administration with respect to energy should be transparent; and (2) the President should further review all administrative policies, programs, and regulations that put an undue burden on domestic energy producers, and consider new legislative policies aimed at increasing the ability of the domestic energy industries of the United States to supply a greater percentage of U.S. energy needs.

Urges the House of Representatives to appropriate sufficient funds for the development of domestic energy sources, including measures to increase the use of renewable energy resources and emerging technologies that could increase energy efficiency and reduce overall energy consumption.</summary>
</bill>
