<bill session="117" type="h" number="1649" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To make a technical correction to the ALS Disability Insurance Access Act of 2019.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make a technical correction to the ALS Disability Insurance Access Act of 2019.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2021-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="579" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-10T21:21:20Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill retroactively eliminates the waiting period for Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) benefits for certain individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). Commonly known as Lou Gehrig's Disease, ALS is a progressive neurodegenerative disease that affects nerve cells in the brain and spinal cord.

Under current law, most SSDI recipients must wait five months after becoming disabled before their benefit payments may begin. The ALS Disability Insurance Access Act of 2019 eliminated the waiting period for individuals with ALS but only covers individuals who apply for benefits after the date of enactment (December 20, 2020). As a result, individuals with ALS who applied for SSDI benefits in the five months before that date are still subject to the waiting period. This bill eliminates the waiting period for those individuals.</summary>
</bill>
