<bill session="118" type="s" number="3362" updated="2025-11-19T04:19:28Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional information in disclosures of foreign gifts and contracts from foreign sources, restrict contracts with certain foreign entities and foreign countries of concern, require certain staff and faculty to report foreign gifts and contracts, and require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2024-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2024-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2024-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2024-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5933" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6165" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-23T16:53:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act or the DETERRENT Act

This bill expands oversight and disclosure requirements related to foreign sources and institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to annually disclose to the Department of Education (ED) any year in which the IHE

receives a gift from a foreign country of concern (e.g., China or Russia) or foreign entity of concern of any dollar amount;receives a gift or contract from a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) that is valued at $50,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts or contracts within a calendar year (current disclosure threshold is $250,000 or more), or which has an undetermined monetary value;enters into a contract with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern after receiving a waiver for such contract; oris substantially controlled by a foreign source.Additionally, the bill

prohibits IHEs from entering into contracts with a foreign country of concern or with a foreign entity of concern without obtaining a waiver,requires certain IHEs to disclose gifts or contracts between covered individuals (e.g., researchers) and foreign sources, andrequires private IHEs with specified assets or investments to file annual investment disclosure reports.The bill requires ED to investigate possible violations of this bill and outlines the various penalties for each violation.</summary>
</bill>
