<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="115" updated="2024-03-18T20:24:23Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-03-23T18:13:21-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 5 printed in House Report 118-12 to include a findings section and sense of Congress regarding public education and rights that parents have access to in public schools. To include titles creating a parent coordinator position in public schools, increasing the authorization level for Full-Service Community Schools, increasing the authorization level for Statewide Family Engagement Centers, and to establish rules of construction prohibiting the banning of books or certain curricular materials.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to make tangible investments in parental involvement regarding public education and rights that parents have access to in public schools. The amendment includes titles creating a parent coordinator position in public schools, increasing the authorization level for Full-Service Community Schools, increasing the authorization level for Statewide Family Engagement Centers, and to establish rules of construction prohibiting the banning of books or certain curricular materials.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-03-23T18:13:21-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="150">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bonamici amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 203 - 223 (Roll no. 150).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23T16:56:17-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Bonamici.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1378-1381, H1386-1387" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1378-1380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23T16:56:17-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A005) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Bonamici.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1378-1381, H1386-1387" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1378-1380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23T18:13:21-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23T18:13:21-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23T18:13:21-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Bonamici amendment (A005) Failed by recorded vote: 203 - 223 (Roll no. 150).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
