<bill session="118" type="h" number="7888" updated="2025-11-19T03:35:59Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="short">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="display">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10T10:09:09-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1125 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7888, H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112 and H. Res. 1117. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 7888 under a structured rule and H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112, and H. Res. 1117 each under a closed rule. The rule provides for two hours of general debate on H.R. 7888 and one hour of general debate on H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112, and H. Res. 1117. Motion to recommit provided on H.R. 7888 and H.R. 529.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T07:08:52-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1137 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7888, H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112 and H. Res. 1117. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 7888 under a structured rule and H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112, and H. Res. 1117 each under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 7888, H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112, and H. Res. 1117. Motion to recommit allowed on H.R. 7888 and H.R. 529.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T09:39:53-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1137.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2328-2359" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2337-2345" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T09:39:58-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 7888, H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112 and H. Res. 1117. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 7888 under a structured rule and H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112, and H. Res. 1117 each under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 7888, H.R. 529, H. Res. 1112, and H. Res. 1117. Motion to recommit allowed on H.R. 7888 and H.R. 529.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T09:40:23-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1137 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T09:40:24-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Daniel Meuser to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T09:41:47-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 7888.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T10:51:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1137, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:03:27-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Turner demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:04:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1137, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:12:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Turner demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:12:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1137, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cline amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:22:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1137, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crenshaw amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:33:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crenshaw amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Crenshaw demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:34:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1137, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waltz amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:45:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waltz amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jayapal demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:46:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1137, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Turner amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T11:54:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Turner amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Turner demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T12:50:17-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 7888.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T12:51:15-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T12:51:27-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="119" datetime="2024-04-12T13:01:53-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 273 - 147 (Roll no. 119).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T13:01:55-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid upon the table. Objection heard.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T13:02:55-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Lee (FL) moved to reconsider.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T13:03:55-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Turner moved to table the motion to reconsider</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-12T13:03:56-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on the motion to table the motion to reconsider and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Luna demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15T18:31:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2382-2383" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15T18:32:16-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Turner moved to table the motion to reconsider</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15T19:03:38-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider Agreed to by recorded vote: 259 - 128 (Roll no. 120).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15T19:03:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time. (Legislative Day April 10, 2024).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-04-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="365">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 365.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2762"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2762"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2797"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-18">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2833"/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="141" datetime="2024-04-18" where="s" result="pass">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 67 - 32. Record Vote Number: 141.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2838"/>
    </vote-aux>
    <action datetime="2024-04-19">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2907"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-19">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 62 - 30. Record Vote Number: 143.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2921-2928" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="150" datetime="2024-04-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate, under the order of 4/19/2024, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 60 - 34. Record Vote Number: 150.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-04-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-04-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-04-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-49" type="public" datetime="2024-04-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-49.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7320" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6611" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4454" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1125" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1137" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7888" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h881"/>
    <amendment number="h880"/>
    <amendment number="h879"/>
    <amendment number="h878"/>
    <amendment number="h877"/>
    <amendment number="h876"/>
    <amendment number="s1841"/>
    <amendment number="s1840"/>
    <amendment number="s1839"/>
    <amendment number="s1838"/>
    <amendment number="s1837"/>
    <amendment number="s1836"/>
    <amendment number="s1834"/>
    <amendment number="s1833"/>
    <amendment number="s1832"/>
    <amendment number="s1831"/>
    <amendment number="s1830"/>
    <amendment number="s1829"/>
    <amendment number="s1828"/>
    <amendment number="s1827"/>
    <amendment number="s1826"/>
    <amendment number="s1825"/>
    <amendment number="s1824"/>
    <amendment number="s1823"/>
    <amendment number="s1822"/>
    <amendment number="s1821"/>
    <amendment number="s1820"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T18:29:58Z" status="Public Law">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act

This act reauthorizes Title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) for two years and makes changes to FISA, including expanding restrictions on surveillance under Section 702. (Section 702 concerns acquiring communications of non-U.S. persons believed to be outside the United States to obtain foreign intelligence information. Information about U.S. persons may incidentally be acquired by this type of surveillance and subsequently searched or queried under certain circumstances.)

Changes to FISA include

requiring applications for electronic surveillance or a physical search under&#160;FISA to be supported by sworn statements and limiting the use of information derived from political organizations or media sources&#160;in such applications;requiring any extension of an order for electronic surveillance under&#160;FISA targeting a U.S. person to be granted or denied by the same judge who issued the original order to the extent practicable and absent exigent circumstances;providing that specified congressional leaders are entitled to attend any proceeding of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (FISC) or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review (FISC-R) and that each such leader may also designate up to two staff members to attend on his or her behalf;repealing the authority to resume&#160;abouts collection (i.e., intentionally acquiring communications that contain a reference to, but are not to or from, a target of acquisition authorized under section 702(a) of FISA);increasing certain criminal and civil penalties related to&#160;FISA;requiring adverse consequences (e.g., suspension without pay or removal) for federal government officers and employees who engage in intentional misconduct with respect to proceedings before the&#160;FISC or FISC-R;expanding the definition of foreign intelligence information to include information related to the ability of the United States to protect against the international production, distribution, or financing of drugs driving overdose deaths (such as illicit synthetic drugs and&#160;opioids) or their precursors; andexpanding the definition of electronic communication service provider&#160;to include any service provider that has access to equipment that is being or may be used to transmit of store wire or electronic communications, but excluding entities that serve primarily as dwellings, food service establishments, community facilities, or public accommodation facilities.The act also makes various changes related to querying the contents of information collected under Section 702 of FISA. The statutory changes related to such querying include

prohibiting Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) personnel from making U.S. person queries without prior approval by certain FBI supervisors or attorneys unless the query might mitigate or eliminate a threat to life or serious bodily harm;requiring the FBI Deputy Director to approve certain politically sensitive query terms (such as those that identify certain elected and appointed officials);prohibiting the involvement of political appointees in the approval process for such politically sensitive query requests;requiring the FBI to establish consequences for&#160;noncompliant querying of U.S. person terms, including zero tolerance for willful misconduct and escalating consequences for unintentional noncompliance, as well as consequences for supervisors who oversee those that engage in noncompliant querying;requiring the FBI Director to notify congressional leaders and the affected Member of Congress of any query using the name or personally identifying information of a Member of Congress, except that the Director may waive such notification if it would impede an ongoing national security or law enforcement investigation;prohibiting the FBI from conducting a query using the name or personally identifying information of a Member of Congress to supplement a defensive briefing about a counterintelligence threat to that Member unless the Member consents or the FBI Deputy Director determines that exigent circumstances exist (however, the FBI Director must notify congressional leaders when the FBI seeks such consent or when it makes an exigent circumstance determination);prohibiting queries that are solely designed to find and extract evidence of a crime, with certain exceptions;allowing such querying to vet non-U.S. persons who are being processed for travel to the United States provided that no U.S. person terms are used;requiring the Department of Justice (DOJ) to audit all U.S. person queries within 180 days of such query; andrequiring the&#160;DOJ Inspector General to report to Congress on FBI querying practices, including an evaluation of compliance by FBI personnel with the procedures governing queries using U.S. person query terms.The act establishes a&#160;FISA Reform Commission to review the effectiveness of the current implementation of FISA and to develop recommendations for legislative reform of FISA that provide for the effective conduct of U.S. intelligence activities and the protection of privacy and civil liberties.

For&#160;additional information see

CRS In Focus 11451, Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA);CRS Legal Sidebar 11148, FISA Section 702 Sunset, Authorization, and Potential Extension; CRS Report R47477, Reauthorization of Title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act; andCRS Report R48592, FISA Section 702 and the 2024 Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</summary>
</bill>
