<bill session="118" type="h" number="7320" updated="2025-11-19T03:59:49Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6611" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7888" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-12T17:51:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Reforming Intelligence and Securing America Act 

This bill reauthorizes Title VII of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA) for five years and makes changes to FISA, including certain restrictions on surveillance under Section 702. (Sec. 702 concerns electronic surveillance of non-U.S. persons believed to be outside the United States to obtain foreign intelligence information. Information about U.S. persons may incidentally be acquired by this type of surveillance and subsequently searched or "queried" under certain circumstances.)

 The bill places statutory limits on querying the contents of information collected under Section 702, including

 prohibiting Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) personnel from making U.S. person queries without prior approval by certain FBI supervisors or attorneys unless the query might mitigate or eliminate a threat to life or serious bodily harm; requiring the FBI Deputy Director to approve certain politically sensitive query terms (such as those that identify certain elected and appointed officials); prohibiting the involvement of political appointees in the approval process for such politically sensitive query requests; and requiring the FBI Director to establish consequences for noncompliant querying of U.S. person terms, including zero tolerance for willful misconduct. Other provisions include

 requiring applications for a surveillance order under FISA to be supported by sworn statements and limiting the use of information in such applications derived from political organizations or media sources, increasing criminal penalties related to FISA, and requiring adverse consequences (e.g., suspension without pay or removal) for government officers and employees who engage in intentional misconduct with respect to proceedings before the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review.</summary>
</bill>
