<bill session="117" type="s" number="1369" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require United States educational institutions to include information regarding financial transactions with the Government of the People's Republic of China or its affiliates in any petition for certification or recertification with the Student and Exchange Visitor Program.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require United States educational institutions to include information regarding financial transactions with the Government of the People's Republic of China or its affiliates in any petition for certification or recertification with the Student and Exchange Visitor Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-13T20:06:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires educational institutions that participate in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program to report certain information regarding that institution's dealings with China's government.

Specifically, when an institution petitions for certification or recertification with the program, its petition must include (1) the final copies of any documentation of financial transactions between the institution (or any affiliated groups or entities) and an entity funded by China's government, and (2) a detailed description of any financial contribution from China's government to any student or faculty groups affiliated with the institution.

An institution that fails to provide such information shall lose its approval (or be denied approval) under the program, and visas for students attending the institution under the program shall be revoked or denied. Furthermore, the program shall conduct an out-of-cycle review of such an institution.</summary>
</bill>
