<bill session="117" type="h" number="7138" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:49Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Against Compromised Internet of Things Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Against Compromised Internet of Things Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish procedures to include certain foreign persons that pose a threat to the security of supply chains of Internet of Things devices on the Department of Commerce's Entity List, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2022-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-13T15:57:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Against Compromised Internet of Things Technology Act

This bill requires the Bureau of Industry and Security within the Department of Commerce to identify foreign persons that pose a threat to supply chain security for Internet of Things devices (i.e., any object or device that is connected to the internet and is not a laptop, cell phone, or other conventional technology device) for inclusion on the Entity List. This list identifies entities reasonably believed to be involved in, or to pose a significant risk of being or becoming involved in, activities contrary to the national security or foreign policy interests of the United States.

The bureau must periodically submit a list of any foreign persons identified as threats to Internet of Things device supply chains to the interagency committee that makes decisions regarding additions to, removals from, or other modifications to the Entity List. After receiving the bureau's list, the committee must vote on whether to add such foreign persons to the Entity List.

A company added to the Entity List through this process may not receive any federal financial assistance, and the federal government may not contract with such a company for Internet of Things devices.</summary>
</bill>
