<bill session="112" type="h" number="2403" updated="2019-11-15T20:51:49Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard Outreach Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Guard Outreach Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Defense to provide assistance to State National Guards to provide counseling and reintegration services for members of reserve components of the Armed Forces ordered to active duty in support of a contingency operation, members returning from such active duty, veterans of the Armed Forces, and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2011-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2011-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1820" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-08-24T15:41:09Z" status="Introduced in House">National Guard Outreach Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to assist a state National Guard in providing pre- and post-deployment outreach, reintegration, and readjustment program services to: (1) reserve component Armed Forces members residing in the state or National Guard members of the state regardless of place of residence who are ordered to active duty in support of a contingency operation and such members upon returning from such active duty, (2) veterans, and (3) dependents of such members and veterans.

Requires: (1) supported programs to use direct person-to-person outreach and other relevant activities ensuring that eligible persons receive all the available services and support; and (2) a decision to commit, obligate, or expend funds with or to a specific National Guard to be based on certain merit-based or competitive procedures.</summary>
</bill>
