<bill session="118" type="s" number="3611" updated="2025-09-03T02:26:41Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Let Pregnancy Centers Serve Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Let Pregnancy Centers Serve Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to clarify the longstanding authority of States to use funds made available under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program to fund life-affirming services to empower pregnant women to choose life for their babies instead of abortion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001079"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2024-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7427" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-19T19:30:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Let Pregnancy Centers Serve Act of 2024

This bill explicitly authorizes states to use Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) funding to carry out programs that encourage patients to carry their pregnancies to term rather than seek abortions. Under current law, states have broad authority to use TANF funds as they see fit to accomplish any of the program&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s four purposes, including to prevent and reduce out-of-wedlock pregnancies.&#160;

The bill also prohibits the federal government from subjecting entities receiving TANF funds to disparate treatment because they encourage patients to carry their pregnancies to term, or because they do not provide, assist, or counsel in favor of abortion. Similarly, the federal government may not subject states contracting with such entities to disparate treatment. Under the bill, disparate treatment includes presumed ineligibility for TANF funds or presumed failure to satisfy the purposes of the program. The Department of Justice, a state, or an entity adversely affected by a violation of these provisions may bring suit in civil court for appropriate relief, including money damages. Federal officials may not invoke sovereign immunity as a defense to such a suit. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
