<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3887</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:22Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:22Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-09-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
        <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-09-29T21:08:04Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001267</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bennet, Michael F. [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Bennet</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment and training programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Neurological disorders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-09T19:22:36Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Directs the Secretary of the Army to: (1) continue the Wounded Warrior Careers Demonstration (Careers) program being conducted in collaboration with the Army Wounded Warrior program at three locations pursuant to a memorandum of understanding between the Army and the National Organization on Disability; and (2) expand the Careers program to nine additional locations in FY2011. States that the purpose of the Careers program expansion shall be to identify and disseminate best practices related to employment counseling and job placement of severely wounded warriors into civilian communities and careers, and to assess various additional means to support the transition and reintegration of such warriors into such communities and careers. Requires: (1) all locations chosen under the expansion to have a large concentration of severely wounded warriors who are ready for career and employment counseling; and (2) the Careers program to be carried out at least until five years after the enactment of this Act.</p> <p>Allows Careers program services to be provided to severely wounded warriors of other branches of the Armed Forces pursuant to joint agreement. Directs the Secretary to continue to provide for the dissemination to other federal departments and agencies, state and local governments, and appropriate nonprofit organizations of lessons learned and best practices developed under the Careers program on the provision of benefits, services, and support to severely wounded warriors.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to report on the Careers program to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) and specified congressional committees.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>A bill to provide for a continuation and expansion of the Wounded Warrior Careers Demonstration program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for a continuation and expansion of the Wounded Warrior Careers Demonstration program, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for a continuation and expansion of the Wounded Warrior Careers Demonstration program, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3887is/xml/BILLS-111s3887is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
