<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="41" updated="2022-02-03T05:22:41Z">
  <amends type="h" number="985" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2007-03-14T16:59:09-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001045"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-03-14"/>
  <description>Amendment enhances whistleblower protection by including in the list of reportable actions any attempt to suppress the right of government scientists to publish or announce their findings in peer reviewed journals or public meetings with their fellow scientists.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-48 to clarifies that instances of political interference with science are to be considered `abuses of authority' and their disclosure therefore protected. The Stupak amendment adds an example of such interference, namely preventing a federal scientist or grantee from publishing or presenting their research.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2007-03-14T17:28:32-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="151">
      <text>On agreeing to the Stupak amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 173 (Roll no. 151).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T17:09:30-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Price (GA) demanded a separate vote on the Stupak amendment (A001).</text>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2007-03-14T16:59:09-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="149">
      <text>On agreeing to the Stupak amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 250 - 178 (Roll no. 149).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T15:46:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Stupak.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2530-2532, H2537-2538, H2539-2540" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2530" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T15:46:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Stupak.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2530-2532, H2537-2538, H2539-2540" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2530" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T17:28:32-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Stupak amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 173 (Roll no. 151).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T17:28:32-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Stupak amendment (A001) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 173 (Roll no. 151).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T17:28:32-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T16:59:09-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T16:59:09-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14T16:59:09-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Stupak amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 250 - 178 (Roll no. 149).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
