<bill session="109" type="h" number="3772" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:12Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Our Children from Sexual Predators Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that States do not issue driver's licenses or identification cards to sex offenders unless the offenders are in compliance with all applicable registration requirements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Our Children from Sexual Predators Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000152"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-28T21:35:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Our Children from Sexual Predators Act of 2005 - Requires a state actor (any state, the District of Columbia, or specified U.S. territories and possessions) or federally recognized Indian tribe (tribal actor) that issues driver's licenses or identification cards to have in effect throughout the jurisdiction laws and policies that ensure that: (1) the actor does not issue or renew a driver's license, commercial driver's license, or identification card to a sex offender (offender) without satisfactory evidence that the offender is in compliance with all applicable offender registration requirements; and (2) such license or card expires on the first anniversary date of the offender's birthday, measured from the birthday nearest the date of issuance.

Grants each actor two years to implement this Act. Directs the Attorney General to coordinate with the Secretary of the Interior to assist tribal actors in implementing this Act. Provides that for any fiscal year after the expiration of that period a state or tribal actor that fails to fully implement this Act shall not receive 10% of the funds that would otherwise be allocated under the Byrne, Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants program and any other program under which the Attorney General provides grants or financial assistance.</summary>
</bill>
