<bill session="117" type="h" number="1206" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restrict the authority of the Attorney General to enter into contracts for Federal correctional facilities and community confinement facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-16T19:23:59Z" status="Introduced in House">End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2021

This bill establishes a framework to phase out existing Bureau of Prisons (BOP) and U.S. Marshals Service contracts with private companies for correctional facilities and community confinement facilities (e.g., halfway houses).

The bill requires the Department of Justice to develop guidelines for community reintegration programs at community confinement facilities.

In carrying out prerelease and reentry planning procedures, the bill requires the BOP to ensure prisoners receive information and counseling about criminal record expungement; educational, employment, and treatment programs; and applications for public assistance programs. The BOP must also provide prisoners with postrelease information about fines, assessments, surcharges, restitution, and other penalties.</summary>
</bill>
