<bill session="108" type="h" number="4241" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Helping America Hear Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 89 of title 5, United States Code, and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Public Health Service Act to require coverage of hearing aids under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program and private group and individual insurance.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping America Hear Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service and Agency Organization.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO18" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Civil Service and Agency Organization" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hearing aids"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-17T21:09:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping America Hear Act of 2004 - Requires each Federal health benefits plan to include coverage for the provision of at least two hearing aids every three years, except that this provision shall not be construed as requiring the payment under such plan in any three-year period of more than $2,000 on hearing aids with respect to any individual.

Amends: (1) the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide that if a group health plan provides benefits with respect to hospital and surgical expenses, the plan (and any health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in connection with such a plan) shall provide coverage for the provision of at least two hearing aids every three years, except that this provision shall not be construed as requiring the payment under such plan in any three-year period of more than $2,000 on hearing aids with respect to any individual; and (2) the Public Health Service Act to make the above ERISA provision applicable to health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer in the individual market in the same manner as they apply to health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer in connection with a group health plan in the small or large group market.</summary>
</bill>
