<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="928" updated="2022-02-03T05:33:12Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5427" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-05-24T19:49:03-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000026"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-05-24"/>
  <description>Page 47, after line 2, insert the following new section: ?   SEC. 503. None of the funds made available by this Act shall be used by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to enforce any claim for a termination payment (as defined in any jurisdictional contract) asserted by any regulated entity the Commission has found to have violated the terms of its market-based rate authority by engaging in manipulation of market rules or exercise of market power in the Western Interconnection during the period January 1, 2000, to June 20, 2001.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds from being made available by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to enforce any claim for a termination payment asserted by any regulated entity the Commission has found to have violated the terms of its market-based rate authority by engaging in manipulation of market rules or exercise of market power in the Western Interconnection during the period January 1, 2000, to June 20, 2001.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-05-24T19:49:03-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Inslee amendment (A017) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24T19:45:19-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A017) offered by Mr. Inslee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3197-3198" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3198" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24T19:45:19-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A017) offered by Mr. Inslee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3197-3198" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3198" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24T19:49:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24T19:49:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Inslee amendment (A017) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
