<bill session="110" type="s" number="186" updated="2023-01-11T20:06:21Z">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide appropriate protection to attorney-client privileged communications and attorney work product.</title>
    <title type="display">Attorney-Client Privilege Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Attorney-Client Privilege Protection Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2008-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2008-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2008-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2008-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2008-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2008-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2008-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2008-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2008-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2008-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000803" joined="2008-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S181-183"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S183" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-18">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-280.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3013" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Attorney-client privilege"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-01-19T17:41:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Attorney-Client Privilege Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit any U.S. agent or attorney, in any federal investigation or criminal or civil enforcement matter, from demanding, requesting, or conditioning treatment on the disclosure by an organization (or affiliated person) of any communication protected by the attorney-client privilege or any attorney work product.

Prohibits a U.S. agent or attorney from conditioning a civil or criminal charging decision relating to an organization (or affiliated person) on one or more specified actions, or from using one or more such actions as a factor in determining whether an organization or affiliated person is cooperating with the government.

Numbers among the actions a U.S. agent or attorney may not use as a charging decision condition or a cooperation-determining factor: (1) any valid assertion of the attorney-client privilege or privilege for attorney work product; (2) the provision of counsel to, or contribution to the legal defense fees or expenses of, an employee of the organization; (3) entry into a joint-defense, information-sharing, or common-interest agreement with an employee of the organization if the organization determines it has a common interest in defending against the investigation or enforcement matter; (4) the sharing of relevant information with an employee; or (5) a failure to terminate an employee's employment, or otherwise sanction an employee, because of the employee's decision to exercise his or her constitutional rights or other legal protections in response to a government request.

Prohibits a U.S. agent or attorney from demanding or requesting that an organization or an affiliated person not take any such action.</summary>
</bill>
