<bill session="117" type="s" number="5221" updated="2023-01-17T20:02:37Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STEP Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEP Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the State Trade Expansion Program of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8844" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5220" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-22T19:16:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">STEP Improvement Act of 2022

This bill reauthorizes through FY2026 the Small Business Administration's (SBA) State Trade Expansion Program, which provides foreign trade assistance to small businesses, and it revises provisions related to the administration of the program.

Specifically, the SBA must establish a time frame for, and provide certain information related to, the application process, and it must conduct an annual survey to solicit feedback on the program. The SBA must collect data on certain performance metrics such as the (1) total number of small businesses assisted by the program, (2) total dollar amount of export sales by participating small businesses, and (3) number of small businesses that have created new jobs through their participation in the program.

The bill also requires applicants for participation to include a budget plan that outlines their intended use of funds awarded under the program.</summary>
</bill>
