<bill session="118" type="h" number="8708" updated="2025-08-01T15:39:43Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Eliminate DEI in Colleges Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eliminate DEI in Colleges Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Federal funding for institutions of higher education that carry out diversity, equity, and inclusion initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2024-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000597" joined="2024-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-01T15:39:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Eliminate DEI in Colleges Act

This bill prohibits an institution of higher education (IHE) from receiving federal funds or participating in federal student aid programs if the IHE carries out diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI) initiatives.

Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to certify to the Department of Education (ED) that the&#160;IHE (1) does not and will not carry out any program, project, initiative, or other activity that advocates, promotes, or otherwise supports DEI;&#160;and (2) does not and will not maintain any office or other entity within the IHE that advocates, promotes, or otherwise supports DEI.

Each IHE that provides the certification must, upon request, make available to ED any information necessary to verify the accuracy of the certification.&#160;

ED must publish regulations to implement and enforce the bill's provisions.&#160;

The bill establishes a process through which an IHE may appeal ED's decision to terminate the IHE's financial assistance for failure to comply with the bill's provisions.</summary>
</bill>
