<bill session="110" type="h" number="2545" updated="2023-01-11T16:17:52Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional Research Accessibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make available on the Internet, for purposes of access and retrieval by the public, certain information available through the Congressional Research Service web site.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Research Accessibility Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2007-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-07-02T17:39:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Research Accessibility Act - Requires the Director of the Congressional Research Service (CRS) to make available through a centralized electronic database, for purposes of access by the public through the websites maintained by Members and committees of the House of Representatives, the following information: (1) CRS issue briefs; (2) CRS reports that are available to Members of Congress through the CRS website; and (3) CRS authorization of appropriations products and appropriations products. Excludes any information that is either confidential or the product of an individual, office, or committee research request. Requires the information to be made accessible between 30 and 40 days after the first day it is available to Members of Congress through the CRS website. Allows the Director to make such information available without the prior approval of specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
