<bill session="117" type="s" number="2024" updated="2022-12-31T05:28:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that internet platforms give users the option to engage with a platform without being manipulated by algorithms driven by user-specific data.</title>
    <title type="display">Filter Bubble Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Filter Bubble Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2021-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5921" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-02T20:12:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Filter Bubble Transparency Act This bill establishes requirements for large online platforms that use algorithms applying artificial intelligence or machine learning to user-specific data to determine the manner in which content is displayed to users. Specifically, if an online platform applies such techniques to user-specific data that is not expressly provided by the user, the platform must (1) notify users that the platform uses such data, and (2) make a version of the platform available that uses only user-specific data that has been expressly provided by the user and which enables users to switch between the two platforms.

These requirements do not apply to search engines operated by downstream providers with fewer than 1,000 employees and that have an agreement to access an index of web pages from an upstream provider. However, the bill requires such upstream providers to make their algorithm available to downstream providers as part of such an agreement.</summary>
</bill>
