<bill session="112" type="h" number="4483" updated="2019-11-15T21:41:58Z">
  <state datetime="2012-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadening Participation in STEM Education Act</title>
    <title type="display">Broadening Participation in STEM Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Director of the National Science Foundation to provide grants to institutions of higher education for implementing or expanding reforms in undergraduate science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education in order to increase the number of students from underrepresented minority groups receiving degrees in these fields, and to recruit, retain, and advance STEM faculty members from underrepresented minority groups at institutions of higher education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000283" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000170" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2012-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E643"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY14" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-30T20:26:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadening Participation in STEM Education Act - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) to implement or expand research-based reforms in undergraduate science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) education to recruit and retain minority students who are underrepresented in STEM fields.

Authorizes the use of such grants on reforms that include: (1) bridge, cohort, tutoring, or mentoring programs; (2) outreach to minority elementary and secondary school students; (3) faculty development and recognition programs; (4) efforts to increase the participation of underrepresented minorities in the full gamut of STEM disciplines offered by IHEs; (5) efforts to increase and support their participation in research; and (6) support for the participation of minority graduate students and postdoctoral fellows in instructional or assessment activities at primarily undergraduate IHEs.

Requires each grant to include an education research component so that reform efforts can be evaluated and, if shown to be effective, replicated to improve the participation of minority students in STEM fields at other schools.

Requires the Director of the NSF to award competitive grants to IHEs to develop innovative reform efforts designed to increase the recruitment, retention, and advancement of individuals from underrepresented minority groups in academic STEM careers.</summary>
</bill>
