<bill session="118" type="s" number="933" updated="2025-11-19T02:45:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Data Center Enhancement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Data Center Enhancement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Data Center Enhancement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Carl Levin and Howard P. "Buck" McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to modify requirements relating to data centers of certain Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters without amendment. With written report No. 118-15.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-04-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="39">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2226" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5218" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-12T19:31:23Z" status="Reported to Senate">Federal Data Center Enhancement Act of 2023

This bill modifies requirements relating to federal agency data centers.

Specifically, the General Services Administration (GSA) must establish minimum requirements for new data centers, including regarding

 the availability and use of new data centers; the use of sustainable energy sources; uptime percentage; protections against power failures, including on-site energy generation and access to multiple transmission paths; protections against physical intrusions and natural disasters; and information security protections. The GSA must issue guidance to ensure that covered agencies incorporate the minimum requirements into current data centers.

During the development and planning of a new data center, an agency must report to the GSA and Congress upon determining it is likely to make a management or financial decision relating to such data center.

In determining whether to establish a new data center or continue to operate an existing data center, an agency must (1) ensure that each at-risk legacy application is updated, replaced, or modernized; and (2) prioritize and leverage commercial cloud environments.

The GSA must maintain a public-facing website that includes information related to agency compliance with data center requirements.

An agency must oversee and manage the data center portfolio and the information technology strategy of the agency in accordance with federal cybersecurity guidelines and directives.

The Government Accountability Office must review, verify, and audit compliance with the minimum requirements for new and existing data centers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-15</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
