<bill session="119" type="h" number="1069" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Responsible Oversight To Eliminate Communist Teachings for Our Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Our Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Promoting Responsible Oversight To Eliminate Communist Teachings for Our Kids Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">PROTECT Our Kids Act</title>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Our Kids Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the availability of Federal education funds for elementary and secondary schools that receive direct or indirect support from the Government of the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Workforce. H. Rept. 119-14.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-05" calendar="Union" number="8">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 8.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-24T20:32:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Responsible Oversight To Eliminate Communist Teachings for Our Kids Act or the PROTECT Our Kids Act

This bill prohibits federal education funding for any elementary or secondary school that directly or indirectly receives support from the Chinese government.

Specifically, the bill prohibits such funding for any school that (1) has a partnership in effect with a cultural or language institute funded by the Chinese government, including a Confucius Institute; (2) operates a learning center supported by the Chinese government (commonly referred to as a Confucius Classroom); or (3) receives support from an individual or entity acting on behalf of the Chinese government, including support in the form of teaching materials, personnel, funds, or other resources. However, the Department of Education (ED) may issue a waiver of the prohibition if a school has an existing contract with one of these entities and the school demonstrates that the contract is for the benefit of the school and promotes the security, stability, and economy of the United States.

The bill directs ED to provide notice of the bill's requirements to schools, as well as guidance for achieving compliance with the requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-14</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
