<bill session="112" type="s" number="3358" updated="2020-02-10T17:05:59Z">
  <state datetime="2012-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responding to Urgent needs of Survivors of the Holocaust Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RUSH Act</title>
    <title type="display">RUSH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to provide social services agencies with the resources to provide services to meet the unique needs of the Holocaust survivors to age in place with dignity, comfort, security, and quality of life.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2012-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2012-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4726"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2786" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-06-05T17:32:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Responding to Urgent Needs of Survivors of the Holocaust Act or RUSH Act - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to: (1) include specifically within its purview older Americans who are Holocaust survivors; (2) direct the Assistant Secretary for Aging of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants or contracts to nonprofit organizations to increase and improve transportation services to enable older individuals to remain in the community, with preference for Holocaust survivors; (3) authorize the Administrator for Community Living to designate, within the HHS Administration for Community Living, a person with specialized training, background, or experience with issues of Holocaust survivors to implement services for them; (3) require state nutrition projects to ensure that project meals meet the dietary needs of program participants based on religious, cultural, or ethnic requirements; and (4) require a state nutrition project to encourage individuals who distribute nutrition services to engage in conversation with homebound older individuals and to be aware of the warning signs of medical emergencies, injury, or abuse in order to reduce isolation and promote wellbeing.

Amends the Older Americans Act Amendments of 2006 to require the study of nutrition projects to analyze the abilities of service providers to obtain viable contracts for special foods necessary to meet a religious requirement, required dietary need, or ethnic consideration.</summary>
</bill>
