<bill session="109" type="s" number="3652" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:29Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the definition of a law enforcement officer under subchapter III of chapter 83 and chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, respectively, to ensure the inclusion of certain positions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000702"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2006-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7513-7514"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA03" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory retirement"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-11T19:27:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Law Enforcement Officers Retirement Equity Act - Redefines the term "law enforcement officer" under provisions of the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) and the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) to include: (1) Federal employees not otherwise covered by such term whose duties include the investigation or apprehension of suspected or convicted individuals and who are authorized to carry a firearm; and (2) such employees of the Internal Revenue Service whose duties are primarily the collection of delinquent taxes and the securing of delinquent returns. Requires that such service which is performed by an incumbent law enforcement officer be treated: (1) on or after the enactment date of this Act, for all purposes, as service performed as a law enforcement officer, irrespective of how such service is treated under the following; and (2) before, on, or after such date, for purposes of CSRS and FERS, as service performed as such an officer, but only if an appropriate written election is submitted to the Office of Personnel Management five years after such date or before separation from Government service, whichever is earlier.Provides that nothing under current law respecting mandatory separation from Government service under CSRS or FERS shall cause the involuntary separation of an officer before the end of the three-year period beginning on such date.</summary>
</bill>
