<bill session="108" type="s" number="1661" updated="2023-01-15T07:02:58Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Telemarketing Intrusive Practices Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Trade Commission to establish a list of consumers who request not to receive telephone sales calls.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telemarketing Intrusive Practices Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-30T21:08:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Telemarketing Intrusive Practices Act of 2003 - Directs the Federal Trade Commission to: (1) establish and maintain for each State a list of consumers who request not to receive telephone sales calls; (2) provide notice to consumers of the establishment of such list; (3) contract with a State to establish and maintain the lists; (4) contract with a private vendor to establish and maintain the lists, if the vendor has maintained a national listing of consumers who request not to receive such calls; and (5) and charge a reasonable fee for providing the list.

Requires a telephone solicitor to maintain a list of consumers who request not to receive telephone sales calls from that particular telephone solicitor.

Prohibits a telephone solicitor from knowingly using any method to block or otherwise circumvent the use of a caller identification service or device by a consumer.

States that a violation of this Act is an unfair or deceptive trade practice of the Federal Trade Commission Act.

Permits a private right of action in State court for an action to enjoin a violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
