<bill session="109" type="s" number="950" updated="2022-02-03T05:25:57Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elimination of Neglected Diseases Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">END Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">END Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance to combat tuberculosis, malaria, and other infectious diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000560" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2005-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4568-4569"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-05-27T15:16:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Elimination of Neglected Diseases Act of 2005 or the END Act of 2005 - Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish within the Department of State: (1) a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Malaria Globally; and (2) a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Tuberculosis Globally.

Directs: (1) the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a comprehensive five-year strategy to set U.S. assistance priorities for programs to combat malaria in foreign countries; and (2) the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Tuberculosis Globally to set similar priorities for tuberculosis.

Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit the President from providing assistance to combat tuberculosis and malaria (including assistance for mosquito nets and pharmaceuticals) except as set forth under this Act.

Establishes the Malaria Scientific Review Board.

Authorizes the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to implement infectious disease control programs in developing countries.

Directs the President to: (1) ensure that related clinical and epidemiological activities are carried out through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP); and (2) develop an infectious disease foreign assistance database.

Amends the the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the position of Assistant Secretary for Global Health, who shall: (1) direct the Office of Global Health Affairs within HHS; and (2) coordinate HHS international policies and activities, including international aspects of family and social policy.

States that two years after enactment of this Act, no Federal agency or department may donate or otherwise supply medicines or medical devices, including insecticide treated nets, insecticides, and other consumables required for disease control, to a foreign country which imposes tariffs or import duties on such medicines or medical devices.</summary>
</bill>
