<bill session="116" type="s" number="2022" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:49Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paul Benne Specially Adaptive Housing Improvement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paul Benne Specially Adaptive Housing Improvement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for improvements to the specially adapted housing program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2020-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3504" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-02T12:27:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Paul Benne Specially Adaptive Housing Improvement Act of 2019

This bill revises the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Specially Adapted Housing Program, which provides grants to veterans and service members with certain service-connected disabilities to assist with constructing, purchasing, or remodeling homes to fit their needs. The program is comprised of two grants: the Specially Adapted Housing grant (for acquisition of housing with special features), and the Special Housing Adaptation grant (for adaptations to a veteran's residence).

Specifically, the bill establishes grant priority for seriously ill veterans and directs the VA to define such term.

 The bill raises the cap on grants that may be issued per veteran from three to six and raises the number of applications that may be approved for the Specially Adapted Housing grant from 30 to 120. The bill increases the maximum amount of assistance available under the Special Housing Adaptation grant and also increases the aggregate amount of assistance available under both grant programs.

The bill also authorizes certain veterans to apply for additional assistance under both grants, subject to specified limitations.</summary>
</bill>
