<bill session="118" type="s" number="1919" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the United States Governor of, and the United States Executive Director at, the International Monetary Fund to oppose an increase in the weight of the Chinese renminbi in the Special Drawing Rights basket of the Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2023-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="510" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-08T16:34:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2023

This bill requires the United States to oppose, absent specified conditions, any increase in the weight of Chinese currency (i.e., the renminbi) in the basket of currencies (currently, a set of five currencies, each with different weightings) used to determine the value of Special Drawing Rights. Special Drawing Rights are a currency support tool available to members of the International Monetary Fund (IMF).

Specifically, the Department of the Treasury must instruct certain U.S. officials at the IMF to oppose any such increase unless Treasury has certified that (1) China is in compliance with all general obligations of members of the IMF, (2) China has not been found to have manipulated its currency in the preceding 12 months, and (3) China is implementing policies and practices necessary to ensure that the renminbi is freely usable.</summary>
</bill>
