<bill session="117" type="s" number="518" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:51Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FINISH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to support innovative, evidence-based approaches that improve the effectiveness and efficiency of postsecondary education for all students, to allow pay for success initiatives, to provide additional evaluation authority, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FINISH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fund for Innovation and Success in Higher Education Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2021-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1521" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-12T15:55:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fund for Innovation and Success in Higher Education Act or the FINISH Act

This bill establishes and revises programs to&#160;increase access to higher education for high-need students, increase their graduation rates, improve the efficiency of postsecondary education, and evaluate higher education programs.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of Education to

 award grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) and other entities to develop and implement evidence-based innovations, including pay-for-success initiatives, in order to improve postsecondary access and increase graduation rates of high-need students; approve up to five pay-for-success pilot initiatives each fiscal year to allow IHEs and private entities to use grants for improvement of student outcomes; and independently evaluate the effectiveness and efficiency of all higher education grant programs. The bill also encourages IHEs to make all forms of postsecondary instructional content, including open educational resources (e.g., textbooks), widely available. Open educational resources either reside in the public domain or have been released under a copyright license that permits their free use, reuse, modification, and sharing with others.</summary>
</bill>
