<bill session="111" type="h" number="715" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Saguaro National Park Boundary Expansion and Study Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Saguaro National Park Boundary Expansion and Study Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saguaro National Park Boundary Expansion and Study Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the boundary of Saguaro National Park, to study additional land for future adjustments to the boundary of the Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2009-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-310.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-10-21" calendar="Union" number="176">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 176.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-06T17:35:28Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Saguro National Park Boundary Expansion and Study Act of 2009 - Amends the Saguro National Park Establishment Act of 1994 to modify further the boundaries of Saguaro National Park to include specified land.

Allows the Secretary of the Interior, with the consent of the State of Arizona, to acquire from the state land or interests in land within the boundary of the Park. Authorizes the Secretary, if unable to acquire such state land, to enter into an agreement that would allow the National Park Service (NPS) to manage state land within such boundary.

Directs the Secretary to conduct and report on a study that identifies lands that would be a part of any future boundary adjustments for the Park and examines the natural, cultural, recreational, and scenic values and characters of the lands identified.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-310</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
