<bill session="117" type="h" number="6148" updated="2023-06-22T14:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alabama Underwater Forest National Marine Sanctuary and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alabama Underwater Forest National Marine Sanctuary and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of the Alabama Underwater Forest National Marine Sanctuary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001054"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2022-08-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2022-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2021-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-22T14:31:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Alabama Underwater Forest National Marine Sanctuary and Protection Act

This bill designates an ancient cypress forest in the Gulf of Mexico as the Alabama Underwater Forest National Marine Sanctuary under the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972.

In the sanctuary, the following activities are prohibited:

 cutting, removing, or any kind of subsurface salvage of the cypress trees; lowering certain devices (e.g., dredging) below the surface of the water; detonating explosives below the surface of the water; drilling or coring the seabed; and lowering, laying, positioning, or raising any type of seabed cable or cable-laying device. However, the prohibitions do not apply to

 fishing, diving, mooring, or similar recreational or commercial activities; necessary operations of public vessels; construction or placement of artificial reef structures for the purpose of enhancing fishery resources, fishing opportunities, or recreational diving opportunities; exploration, development, or production of oil or gas projects authorized before this bill's enactment; and certain other activities authorized by the Office of National Marine Sanctuaries. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must develop a comprehensive management plan for the sanctuary. NOAA must also establish an advisory council for the sanctuary.</summary>
</bill>
