<bill session="117" type="s" number="1547" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ivory Tower Tax Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to apply a 1 percent excise tax on large endowments of certain private colleges and universities, to require that such institutions distribute at least 5 percent of large endowments in each taxable year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ivory Tower Tax Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4897" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-15T14:22:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ivory Tower Tax Act of 2021

This bill imposes on each specified applicable educational institution an excise tax of 1% of the aggregate fair market value of its assets as of the end of the preceding taxable year. The bill defines specified applicable educational institution as any applicable educational institution, other than a religious institution, whose assets have an aggregate fair market of at least $2.5 billion at the end of the preceding taxable year.

The bill also imposes a 30% tax on undistributed excess endowment amounts of an educational institution, unless the failure to distribute such amounts is due to an incorrect valuation of assets that was not willful and was due to reasonable cause.

The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to transfer revenues generated by this bill to the Department of Labor to expand apprenticeship opportunities.</summary>
</bill>
