<bill session="118" type="s" number="2247" updated="2025-11-19T03:32:10Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Bureau of Reclamation to provide cost-shared funding to implement the endangered and threatened fish recovery programs for the Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-287.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with amendments. With written report No. 118-167.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-04-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="358">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 358.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5009" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3918" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4596" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4629" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-10T15:11:07Z" status="Reported to Senate">Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Reauthorization Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes through FY2031 and revises the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service's Upper Colorado River and San Juan River Basin recovery implementation programs to restore populations of certain endangered and threatened fish.

The goal of the Upper Colorado River Endangered Fish Recovery Program is to recover the humpback chub (Gila Cypha), bonytail (Gila elegans), Colorado pikeminnow (Ptychocheilus lucius), and razorback sucker (Xyrauchen texanus). The states of Colorado, Utah, and Wyoming are partners in the program.

The goal of the San Juan River Basin Recovery Implementation Program is to recover the Colorado pikeminnow (Ptychocheilus lucius) and razorback sucker (Xyrauchen texanus). The states of Colorado and New Mexico are partners in the program.

The bill expands the programs to include the recovery of threatened fish stock. Thus, the bill requires the Upper Colorado River program to continue efforts to restore populations of the humpback chub, which was reclassified from an endangered species to a threatened species in 2001.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-167</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
