<bill session="108" type="s" number="1939" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mercury Health Advisory Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that the public is provided adequate notice and education on the effects of exposure to mercury through the development of health advisories and by requiring that such appropriate advisories be posted, or made readily available, at all businesses that sell fresh, frozen, and canned fish and seafood where the potential for mercury exposure exists.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mercury Health Advisory Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4762" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Breast feeding"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fish inspection"/>
    <term name="Fishery products"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-11-03T16:10:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mercury Health Advisory Act of 2003 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs jointly to develop fish consumption advisories for methyl-mercury in fish.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) prepare and distribute to health professionals (and others upon request) a consumer's mercury advisory notice regarding the health risks of fish consumption; and (2) establish a toll-free number for individuals who desire additional information.

Requires the Administrator to prepare and distribute to specified State entities and applicants for fishing licenses (and others upon request) a consumer's guide to mercury, including a health advisory for the consumption of recreationally-caught fish.

Requires the Secretary to work with States and other entities to: (1) develop and distribute standardized advisories, including consumption advisories and health warnings, regarding the presence of methyl-mercury in seafood; and (2) design and implement a related national public education program.

Directs the Commissioner to resume the Food and Drug Administration's seafood methyl-mercury monitoring sampling program.

Requires the Secretary, within one year of enactment of this Act, to finalize the Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Point assessment to determine whether methyl-mercury exposure through fish consumption is a public health hazard.</summary>
</bill>
