<bill session="108" type="s" number="2544" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the certification of programs to provide uninsured employees of small businesses access to health coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2004-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2004-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/18/2004 S7014-7015"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7015-7016" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="906" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-15T19:04:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2004 - Amends the Social Security Act to create a new title XXII to address health insurance coverage for small businesses.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants for the startup and operation of 50 eligible three-share (three-way health insurance premium sharing between employer, employee, and the community) pilot programs for a five-year period.

Authorizes the use of grants to establish three-share programs, provide for contributions to premiums assessed for coverage under such programs, and establish risk pools.

Requires grant applicants to: (1) be either nonprofits or local governmental entities; (2) define the program's service region; (3) have the capacity to carry out administrative functions associated with managing health plans; and (4) have demonstrated community involvement.

Requires programs to pay for the costs of services through monthly premiums, divided according to specified percentages.

Sets forth minimal coverage requirements for three-share program eligibility.

Requires the Administrator to develop a formula to determine which businesses qualify as distressed businesses for purposes of this Act.

Directs the General Accounting Office to submit a report to the Secretary and appropriate congressional committees after the grant period has ended.</summary>
</bill>
