<bill session="117" type="s" number="5169" updated="2023-02-28T05:23:12Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Truck Parking Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truck Parking Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to establish a competitive grant program for projects for commercial motor vehicle parking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2022-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2022-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2187" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-23T15:39:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Truck Parking Safety Improvement Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to provide competitive grants to Indian tribes, states, metropolitan planning organizations, and local governments for projects that provide parking for commercial motor vehicles and improve the safety of commercial motor vehicle drivers on federal-aid highways or on a facility with reasonable access to such a highway or a freight facility.

In providing grants, DOT must prioritize applicants that demonstrate

 a shortage of commercial motor vehicle parking capacity in the corridor in which the project is located; consultation with motor carriers, commercial motor vehicle drivers, public safety officials, and private providers of commercial motor vehicle parking; the project will likely increase the availability or utilization of commercial motor vehicle parking, facilitate the efficient movement of freight, and improve highway safety, traffic congestion, and air quality; and the ability to provide for the maintenance and operation of the facility.</summary>
</bill>
