<bill session="108" type="s" number="1882" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:30Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Apprehension Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that certain notifications occur whenever a query to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System reveals that a person listed in the Violent Gang and Terrorist Organization File is attempting to purchase a firearm, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Apprehension Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2003-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2003-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2003-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15066-15067"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer matching"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-01T23:35:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Terrorist Apprehension Act - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to provide that if the national instant criminal background check system (NICS) determines that a prospective firearms transferee is listed in the Violent Gang and Terrorist Organization file or a similar terrorist watch list, regardless of the eligibility of such person to purchase a firearm, NICS shall provide this information to the employee at the Federal Bureau of Investigation's (FBI) Criminal Justice Information Services Division that is accessing it (NICS operator).

Directs the NICS operator, upon receiving this information, to immediately provide the FBI, the Department of Homeland Security, and the terrorist task force and State and local law enforcement in the jurisdiction in which the firearm purchase is being attempted with: (1) the name, date of birth, and any other identifying information reported by the prospective transferee; (2) the time and place of the attempted firearm purchase; and (3) the type of weapon, if known, that the prospective transferee attempted to purchase. Requires the NICS operator to also immediately provide that information to the agency that placed the name of the suspected terrorist on the terrorist watch list.</summary>
</bill>
