<bill session="119" type="s" number="616" updated="2025-11-25T16:15:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 36, United States Code, to revise the Federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2025-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-30">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2025-04-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2709-2710" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2709-2710: 2" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-05-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-05T14:08:46-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-05T14:28:35-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-25T16:15:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Foundation of the Federal Bar Association Charter Amendments Act of 2025

This bill revises the federal charter for the Foundation of the Federal Bar Association to shift authority from the charter to the bylaws.

Specifically, it makes the following changes:

removes the requirement for&#160;the foundation to be incorporated and domiciled in the District of Columbia;requires the board of directors to decide, and specify in the bylaws, the location of the principal office;specifies that the bylaws&#226;&#8364;&#8221;not the charter&#226;&#8364;&#8221;must provide for the terms of membership, the responsibilities of the board of directors, and the election of officers;prohibits a director or officer, in his or her corporate capacity, from contributing to, supporting, or participating in political activities;allows income and assets of the corporation to be used to reasonably compensate or reimburse expenses of an officer, director, or member; to award a grant to the Federal Bar Association chapter of an officer, director, or member; and to reasonably compensate employees;expands a prohibition on loans for directors and officers to include members and employees; andspecifies that on dissolution or final liquidation, any remaining assets must be distributed as provided by the board of directors instead of deposited in the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
