<bill session="118" type="h" number="6661" updated="2025-07-28T18:10:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Rural Cooperatives and Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Rural Cooperatives and Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to reauthorize rural cooperative development grants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2024-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2023-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-28T18:10:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Rural Cooperatives and Communities Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 and modifies the Rural Cooperative Development Grant (RCDG) Program. This Department of Agriculture (USDA) program provides grants to nonprofit institutions to help individuals and businesses start, expand, or improve rural cooperatives and other mutually-owned businesses through Rural Cooperative Development Centers.

USDA must give preference to grants that commit to providing technical assistance and other services to socially vulnerable,&#160;underserved, or distressed communities. Under current law,&#160;USDA must give preference to underserved and economically distressed areas in rural areas.

In addition, USDA may give an additional&#160;preference to applications that commit to providing a 25% matching contribution for the center with private funds and in-kind contributions.&#160;Specifically, USDA&#160;may&#160;award the maximum points in application scoring criteria to applicants that satisfy this requirement.

Under the bill, cooperative development includes activities (e.g., outreach, education, training, and technical assistance) to support the startup, expansion, or ongoing sustainability of new and existing cooperatives. Current law does not define cooperative development.

The bill directs the RCDG interagency working group to submit an annual report to Congress on its activities.

Finally, the program currently includes cooperative research program requirements to collect data on the effects of all types of cooperatives on the national economy. Under the bill, USDA must analyze the data resulting from the research and include the data and analysis in the annual report to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
