<bill session="117" type="s" number="4744" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish in the Department of Transportation a drone infrastructure inspection grant program and a drone education and training grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2022-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5315" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-13T14:15:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act

This bill establishes programs within the Department of Transportation (DOT) to support the use of drones and other small, unmanned aircraft systems when inspecting, repairing, or constructing road infrastructure, electric grid infrastructure, water infrastructure, or other critical infrastructure.

Specifically, DOT must award grants to state, tribal, and local governments; metropolitan planning organizations; or groups of those entities to purchase or otherwise use drones to increase efficiency, reduce costs, improve worker and community safety, reduce carbon emissions, or meet other priorities when carrying out inspections, repairs, and construction. Grant recipients must use domestically manufactured drones that are made by companies not subject to influence or control from certain foreign entities, including China and Russia.

DOT must also award grants to certain institutions of higher education for training students for careers using drones and related technologies.</summary>
</bill>
