<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="143" updated="2024-03-18T20:27:56Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-03-29T18:30:56-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 11 printed in Part B of House Report 118-30 to prohibit the Delaware River Basin Commission, Susquehanna River Basin Commission, and the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing any regulations relating to hydraulic fracturing other than those issued by the State in which the regulation is to be implemented or enforced.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to prohibit the Delaware River Basin Commission, Susquehanna River Basin Commission, and the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing any regulations relating to hydraulic fracturing other than those issued by the state in which the regulation is to be implemented or enforced.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-03-29T18:30:56-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="172">
      <text>On agreeing to the Perry amendment (A012) Failed by recorded vote: 210 - 223 (Roll no. 172).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T16:54:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A012) offered by Mr. Perry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1592-1593, H1600-1601" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1592" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T16:54:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A012) offered by Mr. Perry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1592-1593, H1600-1601" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1592" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T18:30:56-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Perry amendment (A012) Failed by recorded vote: 210 - 223 (Roll no. 172).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T18:30:56-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29T18:30:56-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
