<bill session="117" type="h" number="2844" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Election Protection Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish Election Security Enhancement Units in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, to direct the Election Assistance Commission to make a grant to each State which certifies that it has implemented certain steps to ensure the integrity of voter registration, the casting of ballots, and the tabulation of ballots in elections for Federal office in the State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Protection Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-05T17:20:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Election Protection Act of 2021

This bill establishes certain election security measures and provides grants to states for administering federal elections.

First, the bill establishes Election Security Enhancement Units within the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. These units must provide state and local election officials with access to risk management, resiliency, and technical support services provided by election administration and cybersecurity experts.

Next, the bill requires a federal entity to promptly share with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) any information it receives about a security threat to federal elections. DHS must, within 96 hours, review the information and determine whether a security incident occurred. If DHS determines that a security incident occurred, then DHS must notify state and local officials about the incident, with exceptions.

The Election Assistance Commission (EAC) must make a grant to each eligible state to administer federal elections. In order to receive such a grant, a state must submit to the EAC certain certifications, including that the state complies with voter registration list maintenance requirements and requires voters to present valid identification.

The bill also establishes within the legislative branch the Bipartisan Election Advisory Commission. The commission must study the effects of COVID-19 on the administration and security of elections and the extent of security shortfalls during the 2020 general elections. Further, the commission must report to Congress on recommendations for improving the administration of elections and enhancing the security of elections.</summary>
</bill>
