<bill session="112" type="h" number="6092" updated="2021-09-28T14:37:58Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildland Firefighters Health Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Wildland Firefighters Health Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement updated pay and personnel policies in order to improve the recruitment and retention of qualified Federal wildland firefighters and to reduce the Federal Government's reliance on the more costly services of non-Federal wildfire resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000021" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2012-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000465" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2012-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-08-22T22:22:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildland Firefighters Health Protection Act - Defines "wildland firefighter" as an employee of a federal land management agency who performs work directly related to the prevention, control, suppression, and management of wildfires, including an employee who is assigned to support wildland fire suppression activities and an employee who is transferred to a supervisory or administrative position.

Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), in cooperation with such agencies, to commence development of a separate wildland firefighter occupational series that will more accurately reflect the variety of duties performed.

Requires a wildland firefighter's hours of work officially ordered or approved in excess of 40 hours per week or 8 hours per day to be considered overtime work. Makes time the firefighter is away from his or her official duty station assigned to an emergency incident, in support of an emergency incident, or pre-positioned for emergency response compensable as work time. Includes hazardous duty differentials as basic pay for retirement purposes.

Prohibits OPM from excluding wildland firefighters from federal employees' group life insurance (FEGLI) and from federal health care benefits.</summary>
</bill>
