<bill session="111" type="h" number="5572" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:53Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the Minerals Management Service and offshore drilling for oil and gas, to repeal the limitation of liability of a responsible party for discharge of oil from an offshore facility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001228" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000299" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000366" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000107" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000822" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001045" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000031" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4784"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-25T21:39:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Oil Spill Prevention Act of 2010 - Establishes in the Department of the Interior the Minerals Management Service with the following components: (1) an Office of Leasing and Permitting, which shall perform functions relating to the leasing of areas of the outer Continental Shelf (OCS) and the issuance of activity permits under such leases that were vested in the Minerals Management Service (MMS) (or its Director) on May 19, 2010; (2) an Office of Inspection, which shall perform functions relating to vessel and facility inspection that were vested in the MMS (or its Director) on that date; and (3) an Office of Revenue, which shall perform functions relating to the collection of OCS lease revenue that were vested in the MMS (or its Director) on such date.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations that require each MMS employee to be subject to random testing for the use of a controlled substance at least twice a year.

Prohibits, during the two-year period beginning on an individual's departure from MMS employment, the employment of such individual by any person conducting any activity under a lease or permit issued by MMS or subject to MMS regulation.

Directs the Secretary, acting through MMS, to inspect monthly each vessel and facility used for OCS oil or gas drilling.

Prohibits the Secretary from exempting any category of vessel or facility activity in OCS oil or gas drilling in waters deeper than 1,000 feet from any applicable federal requirement or restriction.

Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to repeal the liability limits applicable to a responsible party for discharge of oil from an offshore facility.</summary>
</bill>
