<bill session="118" type="h" number="57" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Personal Data from Foreign Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Personal Data from Foreign Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To regulate or prohibit transactions using mobile applications or software programs that engage in the theft of user data on behalf of a communist country, foreign adversary, or state sponsor of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001301"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-19T11:43:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Personal Data from Foreign Adversaries Act

This bill authorizes sanctions and other prohibitions relating to software that engages in user data theft on behalf of certain foreign countries or entities.

The President may regulate or prohibit transactions using software that engages in the theft or unauthorized transmission of user data and provides access to such data to (1) a communist country, (2) the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), (3) a foreign adversary, or (4) a state sponsor of terrorism.

The President may also impose visa- and property-blocking sanctions on developers and owners of software that makes unauthorized transmissions of user data to servers located in China that are accessible by China's government or the CCP.

The Department of State shall report to Congress a determination regarding whether WeChat or TikTok fall within certain regulations and prohibitions, including those provided under this bill. (WeChat and TikTok are software programs developed by China-based companies.)</summary>
</bill>
