<bill session="118" type="h" number="2972" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Failed Bank Executives Clawback Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Failed Bank Executives Clawback Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to clarify that the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and appropriate Federal regulators have the authority to claw back certain compensation paid to executives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000929" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1045" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-08T16:18:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Failed Bank Executives Clawback Act

This bill requires the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to claw back compensation paid to certain responsible parties when an insured depository institution or financial company is placed into FDIC receivership.&#160;

Specifically, all or part of the compensation paid the previous five years to an institution-affiliated party substantially responsible for the condition of the institution must be paid to FDIC to prevent unjust enrichment and to assure that the party bears losses consistent with their responsibility. Compensation includes salary, bonuses, awards, and profits from buying or selling securities.



Finally, the bill establishes that an insured depository institution's holding company is liable to the FDIC for payments to insured depositors, the FDIC's receiver costs, and interest when the institution is under FDIC receivership.</summary>
</bill>
