<bill session="108" type="s" number="1474" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Head Start Centers of Excellence Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Head Start Act to designate up to 200 Head Start centers as Centers of Excellence in Early Childhood, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Head Start Centers of Excellence Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="popular">Head Start bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10062-10064"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10064-10065" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-15T22:30:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Head Start Centers of Excellence Act of 2003 - Amends the Head Start Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program for: (1) designating up to 200 exemplary Head Start agencies as Centers of Excellence in Early Childhood; and (2) making bonus grants to such centers to provide Head Start services to additional eligible children, and perform specified related activities.

Directs the Secretary to make grants to: (1) States to enable them to establish State Councils for Excellence in Early Childhood to work with the State Head Start Office of Collaboration; and (2) an independent organization to conduct research on the ability of the centers of excellence to improve the school readiness of children receiving Head Start services, and to positively impact school results in the earliest grades.</summary>
</bill>
