<bill session="118" type="hr" number="398" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:28Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-16T14:15:23-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-16T14:15:23-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2494) to make the assault of a law enforcement officer a deportable offense, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3091) to allow Federal law enforcement officers to purchase retired service weapons, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 40) expressing support for local law enforcement officers and condemning efforts to defund or dismantle local law enforcement agencies.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2494) to make the assault of a law enforcement officer a deportable offense, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3091) to allow Federal law enforcement officers to purchase retired service weapons, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the concurrent resolution (H. Con. Res. 40) expressing support for local law enforcement officers and condemning efforts to defund or dismantle local law enforcement agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000470"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-59, by Mrs. Fischbach.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15T20:58:40-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2494 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate; H.R. 3091 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate; and H.Con.Res. 40 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate. The resolution provides for a motion to recommit on H.R. 2494 and H.R. 3091.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-05-15" calendar="House" number="19">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16T12:10:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2360-2369" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16T12:15:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 398.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16T13:06:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 398, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16T13:33:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2370-2371" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16T14:05:42-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 209 (Roll no. 215).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="216" datetime="2023-05-16T14:15:23-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 222 - 203 (Roll no. 216).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2360" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16T14:15:25-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2494" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3091" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hc" number="40" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T16:54:22Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of

 H.R. 2494 (Protect Our Law enforcement with Immigration Control and Enforcement Act of 2023 or the POLICE Act of 2023, which makes assaulting a law enforcement officer a deportable offense), H.R. 3091 (Federal Law Enforcement Officer Service Weapon Purchase Act, which directs the General Services Administration to establish a program under which a federal law enforcement officer may purchase a retired handgun from the agency that issued the handgun to the officer), and H. Con. Res. 40 (which recognizes local law enforcement officers and condemns calls to defund or abolish the police).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-59</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
