<bill session="119" type="h" number="3475" updated="2025-11-01T08:05:53Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bipartisan American Homeownership Opportunity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bipartisan American Homeownership Opportunity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a new first-time homebuyer credit and to establish the starter home construction credit.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2025-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-02T18:36:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Bipartisan American Homeownership Opportunity Act of 2025

This bill provides a new refundable tax credit for first-time homebuyers and a new tax credit to home builders for the construction of starter homes, both subject to limitations.

First-time homebuyers may claim a tax credit equal to the amount of the down payment up to $50,000, subject to income limitations. The tax credit begins to&#160;phase out when a homebuyer&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s income exceeds $300,000 for joint filers or surviving spouses, $225,000 for head of household filers, and $150,000 for single filers. The amounts are adjusted annually for inflation after 2025.&#160;&#160;

The bill requires homebuyers to add the amount received as a tax credit to taxable income if, within five years from the purchase, the house is sold, leased, or is no longer used as the principal place of residence. (Some exceptions apply.)

The bill also provides a tax credit for home builders of up to 15% of construction costs (materials and labor) incurred to build a home that is no larger than 1,200 square feet and is sold for an amount that does not exceed 80% of the median home prices for the area. The amount of the tax credit increases to 30% if the home is sold to a first-time home buyer.

Finally, under the bill, each state receives an annual allocation for the tax credit for the construction of starter homes, for allocation by the state&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s housing finance agency to builders (similar to the administration of the low-income housing tax credit).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
