<bill session="116" type="s" number="1582" updated="2022-11-01T05:47:44Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish the White Sands National Park in the State of New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the White Sands National Park in the State of New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-308.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="871" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-06T17:17:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill establishes the White Sands National Park in New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System in order to protect, preserve, and restore the park's resources and recreational values and to enhance visitor experiences.

The bill abolishes the White Sands National Monument and incorporates the lands and interests that comprise the monument in and as a part of the park.

The Department of the Interior shall not nominate the park for inclusion on the World Heritage List of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) unless each county in which the park is located concurs in the nomination. Before submitting such a nomination, Interior must notify the Department of the Army of its intention to nominate the park for inclusion on the list.</summary>
</bill>
