<bill session="116" type="h" number="8753" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Election Integrity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Election Integrity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to provide for the establishment of election integrity measures by States and to prohibit ballot harvesting in Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2020-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4893" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-11T19:41:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Election Integrity Act of 2020

This bill requires states to establish certain election measures. It also prohibits ballot harvesting in federal elections.

Specifically, the bill requires each state, in order to receive certain election assistance funds, to

 prohibit the knowing collection and transmission of a ballot that was mailed to another person (commonly referred to as ballot harvesting), with exceptions; permit poll watching by at least two appointed campaign representatives per campaign; require absentee and mail-in ballots to be counted and recorded immediately upon receipt without disclosing any results until after the closure of polling places on election day; require continuous counting of ballots after the closure of polling places on election day; install video surveillance of ballot drop boxes; require each supervisor of elections to make publicly available a report outlining preparations for the upcoming general election; and require an audit of municipal voting systems. Finally, the bill generally prohibits ballot harvesting in federal elections, which is the process of collecting vote-by-mail ballots from voters and returning them to the polling place or election office. A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to five years, or both.</summary>
</bill>
