<bill session="117" type="s" number="3378" updated="2022-12-30T03:34:02Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional Review of Agency Legal Settlements Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Review of Agency Legal Settlements Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require agencies to submit certain settlement agreements to Congress, to allow Congress to disapprove of those settlement agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2021-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2021-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2021-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2021-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2021-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-04T20:10:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Congressional Review of Agency Legal Settlements Act of 2021

This bill requires federal agencies to submit certain settlement agreements to Congress and allows Congress to disapprove of such agreements.

The bill applies to proposed voluntary compromise settlements that include (1) a financial award paid by an agency that is more than $10 million aggregated across all similarly situated cases or legal claims against the agency, or (2) an agreement to modify or alter an agency rule.

Before an agency may enter into such an agreement, the agency must submit to Congress a report that includes specified information, such as the terms and class of claimants covered by the agreement.

The bill (1) specifies the effect of passage of a joint resolution of disapproval related to such an agreement, and (2) provides for an expedited procedure for such resolutions.</summary>
</bill>
