<bill session="118" type="s" number="365" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dream Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dream Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain individuals who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States as children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2023-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S319-323" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-23T21:09:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dream Act of 2023 

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to cancel removal and grant lawful permanent resident status on a conditional basis to certain non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law) who initially entered the United States as minors (younger than 18 years of age).

Specifically, DHS must do so for such an individual who (1) is inadmissible, is deportable, or has temporary protected status; (2) has been continuously physically present in the United States for four years preceding this bill's enactment; (3) is not inadmissible on various grounds such as those related to crime or security; and (4) has fulfilled specified educational requirements.

DHS must also do so for an individual who was granted Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) status unless the individual has engaged in conduct that would make the individual ineligible for DACA.

DHS shall remove the conditional basis of the lawful permanent resident status granted under this bill if the individual meets various requirements, such as (1) maintaining residence in the United States, and (2) acquiring a degree from an institution of higher education or serving in the uniformed services.

DHS may not disclose or use information provided in applications filed under this bill or in DACA requests for immigration enforcement purposes.

The bill also repeals a restriction barring states from providing higher education benefits to undocumented aliens unless those benefits are available to all U.S. citizens.</summary>
</bill>
