<bill session="119" type="h" number="177" updated="2025-03-19T15:00:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Yosemite National Park Equal Access and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Yosemite National Park Equal Access and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Act of December 19, 1913 (38 Stat. 242), to expand access to the Hetch Hetchy Reservoir and Lake Eleanor Basin areas for recreational purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2025-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-18T19:04:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Yosemite National Park Equal Access and Fairness Act

This bill modifies the Raker Act, which allowed San Francisco to dam&#160;the Hetch Hetchy&#160;Valley within Yosemite National Park, to (1) increase the annual&#160;rent San Francisco pays to the National Park Service (NPS), and (2) direct the&#160;NPS to expand public access to the reservoir and lake created by the dam.

Specifically, the bill increases rent paid by the San Francisco Public Utilities Commission for the use of the park from $30,000 to $2 million per year. That amount must be adjusted annually to reflect increases in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers. The commission may not recoup such sums from wholesale water or power customers. The bill allows collected rent to be used by the Department of the Interior for wildfire mitigation activities in the park and other national parks in California.

The bill also requires the NPS&#160;to administer the Hetch Hetchy Reservoir and Lake Eleanor Basin areas for public recreation, benefit, and use in a manner that will preserve scenic, historic, scientific, or otherwise important features.</summary>
</bill>
