<bill session="116" type="s" number="1578" updated="2022-11-01T05:47:44Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Do Not Track Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Not Track Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the privacy of internet users through the establishment of a national Do Not Track system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2019-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2019-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-14T17:08:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Do Not Track Act

This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to implement and enforce a do not track (DNT) system to protect consumers from unwanted online data harvesting and targeted advertising.

Specifically, the bill requires the FTC to designate a DNT signal (sent by a connected device) and make publicly available a program that (1) is available for download to any common connected device; and (2) sends the DNT signal to every website, online service, or online application to which a user does not want their data sent each time the device connects to it.

The bill further requires an operator of a website, service, or application to search for the DNT signal each time a device connects to it and, if it receives such signal, makes it unlawful for the operator to collect data (other than what is necessary for operation) from a user, use any data collected for targeted advertising, or share any data with a third party without consent. An operator shall not discriminate against a user based on DNT preference. If an operator collects more data than is necessary for operation and does not detect the signal, it must provide a user with notice of the user's rights under the DNT program.

Additionally, the bill prohibits a third-party operator of a program that receives the DNT signal through the connected device of a user of a covered website, service, or application from collecting user data other than data collected to analyze how or whether the user engaged with the program.</summary>
</bill>
