<bill session="111" type="h" number="4524" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:44Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Blue Ridge Parkway Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize funding to protect and conserve lands contiguous with the Blue Ridge Parkway to serve the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blue Ridge Parkway Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000369" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001154" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000600" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2010-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2951" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-13T12:34:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Blue Ridge Parkway Protection Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire lands and interests in land from willing sellers in order to protect up to 50,000 acres identified in the Blue Ridge Parkway Land Protection Plan.

Requires the lands and interests authorized to be acquired to be contiguous with the Blue Ridge Parkway and identified by the Superintendent of the Parkway as a priority for acquisition by the federal government.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants from funds under this Act to: (1) acquire lands and interests; and (2) provide technical expense assistance for costs associated with land acquisition by entering into cooperative agreements with qualified non-profit conservation organizations to acquire lands and interests.

Bars the Secretary from spending more than 10% of the funds made available under this Act in any fiscal year for site restoration and resource surveys.

Permits, from funds under this Act, the use of not more than $250,000 in FY2011-FY2015 to reimburse administrative expenses for qualified non-profit conservation organizations involved directly in land acquisition projects in which lands and interests are conveyed to the Parkway.

Requires the Secretary to submit a report to Congress which: (1) describes the condition of the Parkway, including threats and land preservation needs; (2) lists the land acquisitions that have been completed or are underway; and (3) lists priority land acquisitions that should be made.</summary>
</bill>
