<bill session="119" type="hj" number="4" updated="2025-11-08T09:05:59Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide that debate upon legislation pending before the Senate may not be brought to a close without the concurrence of a minimum of three-fifths of the Senators.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to provide that debate upon legislation pending before the Senate may not be brought to a close without the concurrence of a minimum of three-fifths of the Senators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000605" joined="2025-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2025-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-23T14:34:40Z" status="Introduced in House">This joint resolution proposes amending the Constitution to limit how the Senate may end debate on a measure or motion. Specifically, the proposed amendment provides that debate may only be brought to a close as provided under laws as in effect on January 3, 2025; by unanimous consent; or with the concurrence of at least three-fifths of all Senators.

The joint resolution provides that the amendment shall be valid when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the states.

Under Article V of the Constitution, both chambers of Congress may propose an amendment by a vote of two-thirds of all Members present for such vote. A proposed amendment must be ratified by the states as prescribed in Article V and as specified by Congress.</summary>
</bill>
