<bill session="112" type="h" number="6196" updated="2019-11-15T21:31:59Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Convicted Child Sex Offender DNA Index System Support Act</title>
    <title type="display">Convicted Child Sex Offender DNA Index System Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the backlog in performing DNA analyses of DNA samples collected from convicted child sex offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2012-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000471" joined="2012-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-11-02T18:50:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Convicted Child Sex Offender DNA Index System Support Act - Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to develop a plan to assist states in performing DNA analyses of samples collected from convicted child sex offenders, with the objective of eliminating the backlog of samples awaiting analysis in state or local forensic laboratory storage and providing for entry of those analyses into the combined DNA Indexing System (CODIS). Provides that the plan shall require that: (1) the Director establish requirements for the performance of DNA analyses by private forensic laboratories; (2) only laboratories determined to satisfy such requirements perform DNA analyses; (3) the Director provide assistance only pursuant to arrangements with those laboratories; and (4) each DNA sample collected and analyzed be accessible only under specified circumstances for criminal justice agencies, in judicial proceedings, for a criminal defendant, or for validation studies and protocol development purposes. Directs the Administrator of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to implement all of the recommendations made by the Office of Inspector General in its September 14, 2011, report regarding stopping improper payments from the Federal Government's Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund to deceased annuitants and survivors.</summary>
</bill>
