<bill session="116" type="h" number="8443" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cottage Homes to Improve Lives for Dependents (CHILD) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cottage Homes to Improve Lives for Dependents (CHILD) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to provide for the placement of a foster child in a cottage home, and to make a child so placed eligible for foster care maintenance payments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000628"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2020-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2020-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4839" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-21T17:04:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Cottages Homes and Improved Lives for Dependents (CHILD) Act

This bill requires states to consider foster family homes or cottage homes to be the least restrictive setting for children who have attained six years of age and have been removed from their homes, if suitable relatives or other designated caregivers are not available. A cottage home is a residential operation

 in which not more than 12 children reside; that implements a trauma-informed care plan for its residents; that involves family members of a child in the plan of service for the child, and maintains contact with the family of the child, if available and if the involvement supports the well-being of the child; and that is licensed by the state where it is located. The bill makes cottage homes eligible for foster care maintenance payments.</summary>
</bill>
