<bill session="112" type="h" number="2265" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:05Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">FEMA Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to forgo recoupment of liabilities relating to assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2011-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-07-22T11:31:17Z" status="Introduced in House">FEMA Recoupment Fairness Act of 2011 - Directs the President to forgo recoupment of liabilities to the United States relating to assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to individuals and households in relation to a major disaster declared by the President between August 28, 2005, and December 31, 2010, if: (1) such assistance was provided based on an error by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA); and (2) there was no fault on behalf of the recipient with respect to the error, including fraud, presentation of a false claim, or misrepresentation by the recipient or any party having an interest in the claim.

Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to submit to specified congressional committees a report assessing the cost-effectiveness of the efforts of FEMA to recoup erroneous assistance provided for such a major disaster or other catastrophic incident.</summary>
</bill>
