<bill session="116" type="s" number="4758" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">See Something, Say Something Online Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">See Something, Say Something Online Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require reporting of suspicious transmissions in order to assist in criminal investigations and counterintelligence activities relating to international terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="White-collar crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-19T18:53:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">See Something, Say Something Online Act of 2020

This bill requires an interactive computer service (e.g., a social media company) that detects a suspicious transmission to submit a suspicious transmission activity report (STAR) describing the suspicious transmission.

A suspicious transmission is any post, message, comment, tag, or other user-generated content or transmission that commits, facilitates, incites, promotes, or otherwise assists the commission of a major crime.

Each STAR must be submitted to the Department of Justice and contain (1) the name, location, and other identification information submitted by the user; (2) the date and nature of the user-generated content or transmission detected for suspicious activity; and (3) any relevant text, information, and metadata related to the suspicious transmission.

Any provider of an interactive computer service that fails to report a known suspicious transmission shall not be immune from liability for such transmission and may be held liable as a publisher for the related suspicious transmission.</summary>
</bill>
