<bill session="119" type="s" number="388" updated="2025-06-11T13:14:20Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act with respect to the implementation of building codes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2025-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-11T13:14:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Resilient Buildings Act

This bill increases flexibility for predisaster mitigation assistance for building code activities, prohibits using certain&#160;loan funds for building code activities, and establishes a pilot program to fund residential resilience retrofits.

Under current law,&#160;the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) may provide predisaster hazard mitigation assistance to government entities for implementing the latest published editions of relevant building codes and standards. Also,&#160;FEMA must consider a government entity&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s adoption of such building codes when determining whether to award it predisaster hazard mitigation assistance. The bill specifies that the building codes applicable in such instances are the two most recently published editions (i.e., either the current edition or the previous one).

Also, currently, under FEMA's Safeguarding Tomorrow Revolving Loan Fund (STRLF) program, states and Indian tribal governments may provide loans to local governments for establishing and carrying out building codes and standards. The bill removes this authority, so&#160;STRLF loans may not be used for such building code-related activities.

Additionally, the bill establishes a pilot program for FEMA to provide grants to government entities that then provide the funding to individuals for residential resilience retrofits. The retrofit projects must reduce risk to homes from local natural hazards and individuals must demonstrate financial need. To implement the pilot program,&#160;FEMA may use up to 10% of the funds FEMA provides annually for&#160;predisaster hazard mitigation assistance. The pilot program terminates at the end of FY2030.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
