<bill session="118" type="s" number="3266" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Focus on Learning Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Focus on Learning Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Education to conduct a study regarding the use of mobile devices in elementary and secondary schools, and to establish a pilot program of awarding grants to enable certain schools to create a school environment free of mobile devices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2023-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2024-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2024-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8993" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-16T17:34:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Focus on Learning Act

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to take certain actions related to mobile devices in elementary and secondary schools.

First, the bill directs ED, in consultation with the Department of Health and Human Services, to study and report on the use of mobile devices in elementary and secondary schools nationwide. Among other elements, this study must include the impact of mobile device use on student learning and academic achievement, student educational outcomes, and student mental health.

Second, ED must establish a pilot program to award grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to enable participating schools served by such LEAs to purchase secure containers and install lockers in order to create a school environment free of mobile devices.</summary>
</bill>
