<bill session="116" type="h" number="7001" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">World Press Freedom Protection and Reciprocity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect and promote the freedom of the press globally.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">World Press Freedom Protection and Reciprocity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2020-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3818" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-06T18:03:11Z" status="Introduced in House">World Press Freedom Protection and Reciprocity Act

This bill establishes requirements related to the protection and support of journalists and media personnel abroad.

Specifically, the President must establish a plan to (1) negotiate access for U.S. news and media organizations and their employees globally, and (2) work to enhance reciprocity for news and media organizations operating in the United States. The President must impose visa-blocking sanctions on any foreign person who is responsible for the jailing, killing, or torture of journalists or media personnel or significant efforts to harass or restrict the activities, terminate the visas, or threaten the safety of journalists or media personnel.

Identification statements required to be placed on informational materials distributed in the United States by an agent of a foreign principal on behalf of such principal must be labeled, marked, or stamped conspicuously at the top of the first page of such materials.

The annual country reports on human rights and development assistance and human rights and security assistance must include an assessment of freedom of expression with respect to electronic information in foreign countries.

Lastly, the bill establishes the Global Press Freedom Defense Fund to provide assistance to foreign journalists and media personnel who are victims of restrictions on the internationally recognized right to freedom of expression, including assistance to pay for legal and other related expenses.</summary>
</bill>
