<bill session="117" type="s" number="4742" updated="2022-12-29T19:18:38Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Housing Readiness Council Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Housing Readiness Council Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to create a Department of Defense Military Housing Readiness Council to enhance oversight and accountability for deficiencies in military housing, and accountability for deficiencies in military housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2022-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4543" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8642" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-05T10:43:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Housing Readiness Council Act

This bill establishes the Department of Defense Military Housing Readiness Council to review and make recommendations to the Department of Defense (DOD) regarding policies for privatized military housing.

The council must also monitor compliance by DOD with statutory improvements to policies for privatized military housing and make recommendations to improve collaboration, awareness, and promotion of accurate and timely information about privatized military housing, accommodations available through the Exceptional Family Member Program, and other support services among policymakers, service providers, and targeted beneficiaries.

The council must make all documents publicly available until the council ceases to exist.</summary>
</bill>
