<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="240" updated="2022-06-24T07:16:22Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4176" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-06-23T20:49:02-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part B of House Report 117-381 to require a report to Congress from the Comptroller General about the impact of the implementation of this Act on the provision of services to persons according to their gender identity, sexual orientation, and variations in sex characteristics.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires a report to Congress from the Comptroller General about the impact of the implementation of this Act on the provision of services to persons according to their gender identity, sexual orientation, and variations in sex characteristics.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-06-23T20:49:02-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="293">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A002) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 200 (Roll no. 293).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23T15:45:37-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A002) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23T15:37:36-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5862-5866" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5862" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23T15:37:36-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A002) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23T20:49:02-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A002) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 200 (Roll no. 293).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23T20:49:02-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23T20:49:02-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A002) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 200 (Roll no. 293).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
