<bill session="118" type="s" number="2105" updated="2025-11-19T04:17:02Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop the Spread of Invasive Mussels Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Spread of Invasive Mussels Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out activities to control the movement of aquatic invasive species into, across, and out of Federal land and waters, to provide for financial assistance from the Commissioner of Reclamation to Reclamation States for watercraft inspection and decontamination stations, to amend the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to make certain technical corrections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="10234" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="873" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-15T19:59:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop the Spread of Invasive Mussels Act of 2023

This bill provides for activities to control invasive species on federal lands and waters.

The Bureau of Land Management, Bureau of Reclamation, National Park Service, and Forest Service may inspect and decontaminate watercraft entering and leaving federal land and water located within a river basin that contains a Bureau of Reclamation water project.

The Bureau of Reclamation must establish a grant program to conduct inspections and decontamination of watercraft in reservoirs operated and maintained by Reclamation, including to purchase, establish, operate, or maintain a watercraft inspection and decontamination station. In carrying out the grant program, Reclamation shall coordinate with (1) states with Reclamation projects, (2) affected Indian tribes, and (3) the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force.</summary>
</bill>
