<bill session="112" type="h" number="2093" updated="2021-09-28T13:47:25Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Investigative Commission Act</title>
    <title type="display">Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Investigative Commission Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Investigative Commission to investigate the policies and practices engaged in by officers and directors at Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac responsible for making the decisions that led to the enterprises' financial instability and the subsequent Federal conservatorship of such enterprises.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2011-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2011-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-09-07T21:20:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Investigative Commission Act - Establishes the Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac Investigative Commission to investigate and make recommendations to Congress regarding certain decisions of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) (enterprises) that led to financial instability and federal conservatorship.

Requires the Commission to analyze specified topics, including: (1) the role of the enterprises in expanding homeownership and in helping housing market recovery; (2) enterprise involvement in the development of faulty risk standards, accounting practices, and the creation and proliferation of the securitized mortgage instrument, and how such instrument affected the solvency of such enterprises; (3) the role of the respective boards of directors in voting for the policies relating to risk assessments, subprime mortgages, and the international securitization of mortgages; and (4) compensation, stock options, and financial benefits that accrued to executive officers and members of the boards of directors.

Requires the enterprises and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to grant the Commission access to requested records and information.</summary>
</bill>
