<bill session="116" type="h" number="7369" updated="2022-04-22T14:30:18Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cable Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to amend provisions relating to franchise term and termination and provisions relating to the elimination or modification of requirements in franchises, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cable Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-22T14:21:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Cable Transparency Act

This bill modifies the term and termination of cable franchises.

Specifically, the bill provides that a cable franchise shall continue without any requirement for an operator to renew such franchise until the date the franchise is revoked or terminated. Under current law, a cable operator must submit a proposal for renewal of the franchise to the franchising authority.

The bill prohibits generally (1) a franchising authority from revoking a franchise, (2) a cable operator from terminating a franchise, or (3) the revocation or termination of a franchise by operation of law. However, a cable operator may terminate a franchise by submitting a written request to the franchising authority for the revocation of such franchise, and a franchise authority may revoke a franchise if it finds that the cable operator has knowingly and willfully failed to meet a material requirement of the franchise.

Further, during a franchise period, a cable operator may obtain the elimination or modification of a franchise requirement by submitting a request for such elimination or modification to the franchise authority.</summary>
</bill>
