<bill session="117" type="h" number="2032" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:09Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic Supplies Production Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to use authority under the Defense Production Act of 1950 to ensure an adequate supply equipment necessary for limiting the spread of COVID-19, to require the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency to establish a system for States and localities to access covered items during a covered emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic Supplies Production Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000557"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2021-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-16T13:13:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Pandemic Supplies Production Act

This bill requires certain actions to manage the supply and distribution of materials needed to respond to the COVID-19 emergency.

Specifically, the President must immediately exercise authorities under the Defense Production Act of 1950 to ensure the supply of necessary materials during the COVID-19 emergency. That act confers upon the President a broad set of authorities to influence domestic industry in order to provide essential materials and goods needed for the national defense.

In addition, the Defense Logistics Agency (DLA), which is responsible for supply activities common to all military departments, must manage requests for and distribution of materials to respond the COVID-19 emergency and future emergencies or disasters. The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must reimburse the DLA for costs incurred to undertake these activities. In addition, the DLA must report on the raw materials needed for the mass production of COVID-19 vaccines and related topics.</summary>
</bill>
