<bill session="111" type="h" number="5365" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:08Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sons and Daughters of America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the relief available to persons who have been unconstitutionally prohibited from protesting at military and other funerals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sons and Daughters of America Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2010-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-02T13:57:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Sons and Daughters of America Act - Limits the remedies of an injured party in a civil action for deprivation of rights to injunctive and declaratory relief where the deprivation is a deprivation of the right to freedom of speech secured by the Constitution and is under the authority of a statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage which prohibits or restricts picketing, protesting, or demonstrating at, or in proximity to, a funeral or any other ceremony, procession, or memorial service held in connection with the burial or cremation of the dead. Prohibits the award of attorney's fees to a prevailing party in any action that is brought against the United States or any federal agency or official acting in his or her official capacity and that alleges such an injury.</summary>
</bill>
