<bill session="117" type="h" number="8574" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:42Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Catastrophic Risk Management Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Catastrophic Risk Management Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an interagency committee on global catastrophic risk, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000465" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4521" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4488" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-23T17:23:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Global Catastrophic Risk Management Act of 2022

This bill directs the President to establish an interagency committee on global catastrophic risk. Global catastrophic risk is defined as the risk of events or incidents consequential enough to significantly harm, set back, or destroy human civilization at the global scale.

The President must (1) conduct and submit to Congress a detailed assessment of global catastrophic and existential risk; and (2) produce a report on the adequacy of continuity of operations and continuity of government plans based on the assessed risk.

The President, with support from the committee, shall develop and submit a strategy to

 provide for the basic needs of the civilian population that is impacted by catastrophic incidents in the United States; coordinate response efforts with state and local governments, the private sector, and nonprofit organizations; promote personal and local readiness and non-reliance on government relief during periods of heightened tension or after catastrophic incidents; and develop international partnerships with allied nations for the provision of relief services and goods. The President must issue a plan to implement and operationalize the strategy.

The Department of Homeland Security shall lead a national exercise to test and enhance the operationalization of the implementation plan.

The President must provide recommendations to Congress for (1) actions that should be taken to prepare the United States to implement the strategy, increase readiness, and address preparedness gaps; and (2) additional authorities that should be considered to more effectively implement the strategy.</summary>
</bill>
