<bill session="112" type="s" number="3526" updated="2019-02-20T23:43:26Z">
  <state datetime="2012-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Religious Freedom Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Military Religious Freedom Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to protect the rights of conscience of members of the Armed Forces and chaplains of members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2012-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2012-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2012-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2012-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3828" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4310" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-11-06T14:42:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Military Religious Freedom Act of 2012 - Requires the Armed Forces to accommodate the conscience and sincerely held moral principles and religious beliefs of its members concerning the appropriate and inappropriate expression of human sexuality, and prohibits the Armed Forces from using such conscience, principles, or beliefs (beliefs) as the basis of any adverse personnel action, discrimination, or denial of promotion, schooling, training, or assignment. Prohibits any member from: (1) directing, ordering, or requiring a chaplain to perform any duty, rite, service, or function that is contrary to his or her beliefs; or (2) discriminating or taking any adverse personnel action against a chaplain for refusing to comply with a direction, order, or requirement that is against his or her beliefs.

Prohibits a military installation or other property owned, rented, or under the jurisdiction or control of the Department of Defense (DOD) from being used to officiate, solemnize, or perform a marriage or marriage-like ceremony involving anything other than the union of one man with one woman.</summary>
</bill>
