<bill session="118" type="h" number="3939" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AUKUS Undersea Defense Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AUKUS Undersea Defense Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the transfer of not more than two Virginia class submarines from the inventory of the Navy to the Government of Australia on a sale basis under section 21 of the Arms Export Control Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2023-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-08T22:14:25Z" status="Introduced in House">AUKUS Undersea Defense Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD) to sell Australia up to two Virginia-class attack submarines under the Australia-United Kingdom-United States security partnership agreement (AUKUS). The bill authorizes DOD to transfer the submarines from existing Navy inventories. The bill also

 applies existing law to the transfer under this bill of special nuclear material related to submarine reactors, authorizes the Navy to determine the appropriate shipyard in any of the AUKUS countries for repair of U.S. Navy submarines, establishes a submarine security activities account to accept payments from Australia for non-nuclear related aspects of submarine security activities, and authorizes the President to transfer defense services to Australia to develop the Australian submarine industrial base for AUKUS activities.</summary>
</bill>
