<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="606" updated="2022-02-03T04:56:48Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4548" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-06-23T21:20:41-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000336"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  <description>At the end of title III (page 11, after line 8), insert the following new section: \   SEC. 304. INSPECTOR GENERAL REPORT ON EVIDENCE OF RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN SADDAM HUSSEIN AND AL-QAEDA. \   (a) AUDIT.--The Inspector General of the Central Intelligence Agency shall conduct an audit of the evidence of any relationship, existing before September 11, 2001, between the regime of Saddam Hussein and al-Qaeda, referenced in all intelligence reporting of the Central Intelligence Agency, including products, briefings and memoranda, distributed to the White House and Congress. \   (b) REPORT TO CONGRESS.--Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall submit to Congress a report on the audit conducted under subsection (a).</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 108-561 to direct the Inspector General of the Central Intelligence Agency to audit the evidence of the relationship, existing prior to September 11, 2001, between the regime of Saddam Hussein and al-Qaeda, referenced in all intelligence reporting, including products, briefings, and memoranda, distributed by the Central Intelligence Agency to the White House and Congress.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-06-23T21:20:41-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="295">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kucinich amendment (A008) Agreed to by recorded vote: 343 - 76 (Roll no. 295).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T19:31:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Kucinich.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4855, CR 6/24/2004 H4874" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4855" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T19:31:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Kucinich.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4855, CR 6/24/2004 H4874" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4855" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T21:20:41-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Kucinich amendment (A008) Agreed to by recorded vote: 343 - 76 (Roll no. 295).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T21:20:41-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23T21:20:41-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
