<bill session="118" type="h" number="3630" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Athlete Level Playing Field Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Athlete Level Playing Field Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain entities from barring a student athlete from participating in intercollegiate athletics as a result of such student athlete entering into an endorsement contract, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000601" joined="2023-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-19T19:16:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Athlete Level Playing Field Act

This bill generally prohibits an institution of higher education or a covered athletic organization (e.g., an athletic association, a conference, or an organization with authority over intercollegiate athletics) from restricting the ability of a student athlete to enter into an endorsement or agency contract or otherwise receive consideration for the athlete's name, image, or likeness.

 It also provides for enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), preempts state laws relating to endorsement or agency contracts, and establishes the Covered Athletic Organization Commission.

The FTC must

 establish a clearinghouse for endorsement contracts entered into by student athletes and athlete agents; require each student athlete and athlete agent to disclose to the clearinghouse each endorsement contract entered into with a value of more than $500; and establish a program to register athlete agents who represent student athletes, require such athlete agents to register, and treat a violation of such requirement as a violation regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices. The FTC may not charge a fee in relation to such registration.</summary>
</bill>
