<bill session="117" type="h" number="9534" updated="2023-08-25T22:47:52Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Space SSA Transition Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Space Safety and Situational Awareness Transition Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Space SSA Transition Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote space safety and provide for policy, planning, and agency roles and responsibilities for the transition to a civil space situational awareness capability of certain space situational awareness activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2022-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-25T20:05:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Space Safety and Situational Awareness Transition Act of 2022 or the Space SSA Transition Act of 2022

This bill sets out a process to transition responsibilities for space situational awareness capabilities (i.e., the knowledge and characterization of space objects and their operational environment to facilitate decisions that support safe, stable, and sustainable space activities) from the Department of Defense to the Department of Commerce by December 31, 2025. The bill requires the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to establish research and development programs related to space situational awareness.</summary>
</bill>
