<bill session="119" type="h" number="2554" updated="2025-11-18T20:58:09Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lower Drug Costs for Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lower Drug Costs for Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to apply prescription drug inflation rebates to drugs furnished in the commercial market and to change the base year for rebate calculations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1186" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-18T17:54:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Lower Drug Costs for Families Act

This bill applies certain Medicare prescription drug rebate requirements to prescription drugs that are available under private health insurance.

Current law requires drug manufacturers to issue rebates to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for brand-name drugs without generic equivalents under Medicare that (1) cost $100 or more per year per individual, and (2) for which prices increase faster than inflation. Manufacturers that fail to comply are subject to civil penalties.

The bill applies these requirements to prescription drugs that are available in the commercial market under private health insurance. It also indexes rebate calculations to drug prices in 2016 (as opposed to 2021).</summary>
</bill>
