<bill session="116" type="h" number="6593" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Territorial Judgeship Retirement Equity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend certain retirement provisions for judges serving in territorial district courts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Territorial Judgeship Retirement Equity Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2020-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2020-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-16T17:26:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Territorial Judgeship Retirement Equity Act of 2020

This bill lowers the age and service requirements for a district court judge in Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands to receive a retirement annuity and be eligible to serve as a senior judge.

Under the bill, such a judge may receive a retirement annuity after having served for at least 10 years and reaching 50 years of age, along with meeting other requirements. Such a retiring judge may serve as a senior judge if the judge (1) has served for at least 15 years, or (2) has served for at least 10 years and is at least 65 years old. Current law generally requires a greater combination of age and length of service before a district court judge in one of these territories may receive an annuity and obtain senior status.

The bill also lowers various requirements for such a district court judge to receive an annuity if the judge retired, or was removed, due to a disability.</summary>
</bill>
