<bill session="118" type="h" number="3807" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medical Device Shortage Reduction Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Device Shortage Reduction Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to device shortage notifications.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2023-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2023-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4697" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-06T16:17:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Medical Device Shortage Reduction Act of 2023

This bill expands the scope of required notifications about medical device&#160;shortages beyond public health emergencies.

Currently, manufacturers of medical devices that are critical during a public health emergency (e.g., devices that are life-supporting, life-sustaining, or intended for use in emergency medical care or during surgery), or for which the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) determines information about the supply chain is necessary during a public health emergency, must notify HHS of expected shortages of such devices. Manufacturers may voluntarily provide information on expected shortages of other critical medical devices, whether or not there is a public health emergency.

The bill expands these provisions so as to generally require manufacturers to notify HHS of expected shortages of critical medical devices, whether or not there is a public health emergency. It also requires manufacturers to develop risk management plans that identify potential risks to the supply chain of such devices.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
