<bill session="108" type="s" number="1528" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian Tribal Development Consolidated Funding Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a procedure to authorize the integration and coordination of Federal funding dedicated to the community, business, and economic development of Native American communities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Tribal Development Consolidated Funding Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2003-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2003-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10651"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10651-10653" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-09T23:04:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Tribal Development Consolidated Funding Act of 2003 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to select up to 24 Indian tribes, tribal organizations, or consortia of tribes or organizations per fiscal year to participate in projects to foster community, economic, and business development in Native American communities through grants or other financial assistance provided through Federal programs or projects.

Outlines procedures for processing requests for joint financing (financing by at least two Federal assistance programs). Authorizes the establishment of a joint assistance fund to ensure that amounts received from more than one Federal program or appropriation are more effectively administered.Provides for the financial management, accountability, and audits of the use of financial assistance provided.Authorizes the provision of technical assistance and personnel training under a project approved for joint financing. Authorizes the head of an executive agency to enter into an agreement with a State to extend the benefits of this Act to a project that involves assistance from at least one executive agency, the State, and at least one tribal agency or instrumentality.</summary>
</bill>
