<bill session="116" type="h" number="8398" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">University of Alaska Fiscal Foundation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">University of Alaska Fiscal Foundation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the continuation of higher education through the conveyance to the University of Alaska of certain public land in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4696" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-27T20:54:33Z" status="Introduced in House">University of Alaska Fiscal Foundation Act

This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to establish a program to identify and convey available federal land in Alaska to the University of Alaska for a land grant to support higher education.

No later than two years after enactment of the bill, Alaska and the university may jointly identify no more than 500,000 acres of land for inclusion in the program. Upon the request of Alaska and the university, the BLM shall provide technical assistance in the identification of land.

If Alaska and the university submit to the BLM one or more joint letters concurring with the conveyance of all or a portion of the land identified for conveyance, the BLM shall convey the land to the Board of Regents of the university, to be held in trust for the exclusive use and benefit of the university.

The BLM shall convey no more than 360,000 acres of land to the university.

The BLM shall notify Congress upon conveyance of the land.</summary>
</bill>
