<bill session="117" type="h" number="3300" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Get the Lead Out Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act with respect to replacement of lead service lines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Get the Lead Out Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2021-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-17T14:53:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Get the Lead Out Act

This bill requires community water systems (i.e., public water systems that provide drinking water) to identify and replace lead service lines (e.g., pipes) and allows the systems to use assistance from drinking water state revolving funds to replace those lines.

Specifically, the bill requires community water systems to submit to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) by specified deadlines (1) plans to inventory and replace lead service lines, and (2) certifications that lead service lines have been replaced except for any line that is not owned by the system and for which the owner declined replacement.

Community water systems must pay the full costs of all lead service line replacements and any filters required under their plans. Systems may incorporate into their base rates the costs of the line replacements and filters not fully covered by grants and other assistance.</summary>
</bill>
