<bill session="118" type="h" number="2586" updated="2024-08-27T16:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Noncontiguous Shipping Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Noncontiguous Shipping Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, to exempt certain noncontiguous trade from the coastwise laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2023-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-27T16:18:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Noncontiguous Shipping Competition Act 

This bill revises coastwise laws, commonly known as the Jones Act, that govern domestic transportation of merchandise or passengers by vessels.

The Jones&#160;Act generally requires that a vessel transporting merchandise or passengers&#160;from one U.S. point to another U.S. point be (1) built in the United States, (2)&#160;at least 75% owned by U.S. citizens, and (3) mostly crewed by U.S. citizens. The act also includes several exemptions and exceptions.

The bill exempts carriage on a route in noncontiguous trade from Jones Act requirements unless (1) at least three owners or operators of coastwise qualified vessels regularly operate such a vessel on the route, (2) each of such owners or operators transports at least 20% of the volume of goods on that route, and (3) none of such owners or operators are under common ownership.&#160;(Generally, noncontiguous trade is trade between two U.S. points where at least one of the points is in Alaska, Hawaii, Puerto Rico, or an insular territory or U.S. possession.)</summary>
</bill>
