<bill session="118" type="s" number="2409" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ROI of the Federal Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regular Order for Investments of the Federal Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROI of the Federal Reserve Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit purchases of the Federal reserve banks, to require Generally Accepted Accounting Principles standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-05T15:08:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Regular Order for Investments of the Federal Reserve Act or the ROI of the Federal Reserve Act

This bill establishes requirements for Federal Reserve System investments, accounting standards, and reports.

Under the bill, Federal Reserve banks are prohibited from purchasing Treasury bills with a term of maturity of more than three years and mortgage-backed securities. Federal Reserve banks are also prohibited from holding shares of common stock that are acquired on or after the date of enactment of this bill.

The Federal Reserve Board, Federal Reserve banks, and the Federal Open Market Committee must use generally accepted accounting principles and specified valuation methods in certain filings, reports, and audits.

Finally, the board and Federal Reserve banks must annually report to Congress on (1) the status of the middle class and the impact their policies and programs have had on the middle class, and (2) the impact their actions have had on small business lending and lines of credit since 2000.</summary>
</bill>
