<bill session="117" type="h" number="4775" updated="2022-12-31T05:04:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To counter malign influence, require transparency, and promote accountability within the United Nations system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">United Nations Transparency and Accountability Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United Nations Transparency and Accountability Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000317" joined="2021-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia, the Pacific, Central Asia and Nonproliferation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Indo-Pacific" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2494" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-30T17:54:55Z" status="Introduced in House">United Nations Transparency and Accountability Act of 2021

This bill requires various actions related to malign influence operations by other countries in the United Nations (UN), with such operations defined as coordinated actions by a UN member state to foster UN actions or attitudes that further that member state's interests in a manner inconsistent with the UN Charter.

The President shall direct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the UN to vote for and promote policies to (1) oppose malign influence operations and UN employees involved in such operations, and (2) support Taiwan's membership or meaningful participation in UN entities. (Taiwan was expelled from the UN in 1971.)

The Department of State shall designate a senior level official to assist in implementing such policies and fulfill other related responsibilities.

The State Department shall also establish an Office of Multilateral Strategy and Personnel within the Bureau of International Organization Affairs to promote the candidacy of U.S. citizens for roles in international organizations, including the UN, and to coordinate support for non-U.S. candidates when appropriate.

The State Department shall increase by at least 50% the number of U.S.-sponsored Junior Professional Officer positions in the UN.

The President shall periodically review evidence and determine if any countries have engaged in malign influence operations that have threatened U.S. interests. The President must designate any such country as a malign global actor and provide an explanation to Congress for why the designation was made.</summary>
</bill>
