<bill session="116" type="s" number="3346" updated="2022-02-08T23:22:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prevent BLEEDing Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent BLEEDing Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Blood Loss with Emergency Equipment Devices Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the use of Homeland Security Grant Program funds for anti-blood loss purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2020-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2550" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-17T14:33:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prevent Blood Loss with Emergency Equipment Devices Act of 2020 or the Prevent BLEEDing Act of 2020

This bill authorizes the use of Department of Homeland Security (DHS) grant funds for certain anti-blood loss purposes.

Specifically, a grant under the Urban Area Security Initiative or the State Homeland Grant Program may be used to

 purchase or distribute anti-blood loss supplies (tourniquets, gauze, dressings, or other appropriate materials) for use in medical emergencies in places where people gather; provide training on the proper use of anti-blood loss supplies to enhance public safety; or make grants to an eligible entity for such purposes. DHS shall (1) allocate such funds according to a formula that takes into consideration the relative populations of each geographic area for which a grant is made; and (2) conduct outreach to inform state, local, and tribal governments and high-risk urban areas that apply for grants of the availability of funds under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
