<bill session="119" type="s" number="59" updated="2025-09-11T14:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">One Subject at a Time Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">One Subject at a Time Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to end the practice of including more than one subject in a single bill by requiring that each bill enacted by Congress be limited to only one subject, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4324" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-11T19:12:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">One Subject at a Time Act

This bill requires each bill or joint resolution to include no more than one subject and the subject to be clearly and descriptively expressed in the measure's title.

Further, an appropriations bill may not contain any general legislation or change to existing law that is not germane to the subject of such bill.

The bill voids an entire law or joint resolution that has a title which addresses two or more unrelated subjects.&#160;For noncompliant provisions of a law or joint resolution, the bill voids the specific noncompliant provisions.&#160;For example, this includes appropriation provisions that are outside of&#160;the relevant subcommittee's jurisdiction.&#160;

Additionally, a person (individual or entity) who is aggrieved by the enforcement, or the attempted enforcement, of a law that passed without complying with this bill's requirements may sue the United States for appropriate relief.</summary>
</bill>
