<bill session="112" type="h" number="2974" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:23Z">
  <state datetime="2011-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require that not less than 10 percent of the amounts made available for certain high-speed rail projects be expended through small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require that not less than 10 percent of the amounts made available for certain high-speed rail projects be expended through small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2011-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-11-03T21:12:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Requires at least 10% of funds made available for high-speed rail corridor planning and development projects to be expended through small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals (disadvantaged business enterprises). Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), however, if this requirement will prevent the satisfactory completion of a project because of a lack of competitive bids by disadvantaged business enterprises, to reduce the percentage for the project to the extent necessary to ensure its satisfactory completion.

Requires the Secretary to establish minimum uniform criteria for recipients of high-speed rail corridor project funds to use in certifying small business concerns as disadvantaged business enterprises.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the federal government should continue to encourage participation by veteran-owned small businesses in federal contracting and procurement opportunities and federally-funded projects, including the small business programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT) and other federal agencies.</summary>
</bill>
