<bill session="119" type="s" number="1326" updated="2025-09-26T15:37:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food Security and Farm Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Security and Farm Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent States and local jurisdictions from interfering with the production and distribution of agricultural products in interstate commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2025-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2025-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2025-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-26T15:36:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Food Security and Farm Protection Act

This bill restricts state and local governments from imposing certain standards or conditions on the preharvest production of agricultural products in another state. Specifically, it prohibits the imposition of such standards or conditions on products sold or offered for sale in interstate commerce if (1) the production occurs in another state, and (2) the standard or condition adds to requirements applicable under federal law and the laws of the state and locality where the product is produced.

The bill also allows for a private right of action to challenge state or local regulations relating to agricultural goods sold in interstate commerce. A person may bring an action in (1) the U.S. district court for the judicial district in which the person is affected by a regulation or the person resides, operates, or does business; or (2) any other appropriate court with jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
