<bill session="109" type="s" number="1536" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:22Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Loan Manageability for Armed Forces in Higher Eucation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide certain members of the Armed Forces with a deferment of all loan payments under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965, and to provide such members with the option to reenroll in institutions of higher education after completion of their service.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Loan Manageability for Armed Forces in Higher Eucation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2005-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-02T19:38:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Loan Manageability for Armed Forces in Higher Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to provide certain members of the Armed Forces with a deferment of all student loan repayments under HEA title IV during the period of service and for six months after (with principal payments suspended, and accruing interest paid by the Secretary of Education).

Requires any institution of higher education that participates in a title IV program to offer an option to reenroll when such service is completed to any student who is enrolled at the time such service begins.

Makes eligible, for such deferment and option, members of: (1) the Armed Forces serving in a combat operation or combat zone; or (2) a reserve component of the Armed Forces serving pursuant to a call or order to active duty for a period of more than 30 days.</summary>
</bill>
