<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5832</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:53Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:53Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-07-22</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hssm00</systemCode>
        <name>Small Business Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-07-22T14:02:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Small Business Jobs Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>5297</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 111-240.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Small Business Export Enhancement and International Trade Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>2862</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 633.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-22</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hssm00</systemCode>
            <name>Small Business Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000608</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Dahlkemper, Kathleen A. [D-PA-3]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kathleen</firstName>
        <lastName>Dahlkemper</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <district>3</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see H.R.5297, which became Public Law 111-240 on 9/27/2010.]]></text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R.5297</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/111th-congress/house-bill/5297</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Commerce</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal officials</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Free trade and trade barriers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Manufacturing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Performance measurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rural conditions and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small Business Administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Trade agreements and negotiations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women in business</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Commerce</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-11-30T15:14:28Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Small Business Export Enhancement Act of 2010 - Amends the Small Business Act to: (1) require the Office of International Trade of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to implement small business export promotion programs that increase the number of small businesses that export as well as the volume of their exports; and (2) establish an Associate Administrator for International Trade as the head of the Office. Grants the SBA Administrator the authority to appoint additional Associate Administrators. </p> <p>Requires Export Assistance Centers (one-stop shops for U.S. exporters) to aid the Associate Administrator in: (1) maintaining a trade distribution network for trade promotion and trade assistance programs for small businesses; (2) aggressively marketing such programs and disseminate information to small businesses on exporting trends and international prospects for exports; (3) promoting export assistance programs through certain conduits; and (4) giving preference to the hiring of employees fluent in English to the Office. Requires the Associate Administrator to establish annual goals to enhance the export capabilities of small businesses and small manufacturers to compete against foreign entities.</p> <p>Directs the Associate Administrator, in order to provide small businesses access to certain export financing programs, to appoint at least one trade financial specialist within the SBA to oversee international loan programs and assist SBA employees with trade finance issues.</p> <p>Directs the SBA Administrator to establish an export and trade counseling certification program for employees of lead small business development centers and lead women's business centers in providing export assistance to small businesses. </p> <p>Requires the Associate Administrator to develop performance measures to support export growth goals for Office activities to promote exports by small businesses.</p> <p>Directs the SBA Administrator to carry out a comprehensive program to help small businesses to resolve international trade disputes.</p> <p>Directs the SBA Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, to ensure that the number of export finance specialists assigned to the Export Assistance Centers is at least the number that were assigned on January 1, 2003. Requires at least three specialists in each SBA region.</p> <p>Requires the SBA Administrator to: (1) study and report on small business exporters and high- and low-export volume areas in each state; and (2) report to Congress on rural export promotion programs for small businesses.</p> <p>Requires a small business development center that counsels a small business concern on international trade issues to: (1) consult with state trade agencies and Export Assistance Centers to provide appropriate services to the small business concern; and (2) refer the small business concern to a State trade agency or an Export Assistance Center, as necessary, for further counseling or assistance.<br> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Small Business Export Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Small Business Export Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Small Business Act to improve the Office of International Trade, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Small Business Export Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-07-22T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr5832ih/xml/BILLS-111hr5832ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-07-22</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
