<bill session="117" type="h" number="5782" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIRE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Improvement, Reform, and Efficiency Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve the provision of certain disaster assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2022-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2021-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2021-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2022-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2021-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3092" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-06T13:42:19Z" status="Introduced in House">FEMA Improvement, Reform, and Efficiency Act of 2021 or the FIRE Act

This bill addresses the federal government's approach to wildfires.

Specifically, the bill authorizes a public mitigation assistance applicant to relocate an eligible structure upon demonstrating that the structure is at risk from future damage and the relocation reduces the risk to the structure, is cost effective, and does not increase risk to adjacent structures.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), in coordination with the National Weather Service, must conduct a study on Red Flag Warnings and similar weather and notification methods to implement plans and actions prior to a wildfire that can limit the impact, duration, or severity of the fire.

The President must ensure that those providing counseling or case management services to victims of a major disaster are trained to address cultural competency.

FEMA must (1) conduct a study and develop a plan to address providing housing assistance to survivors of major disasters or emergencies when presented with challenges such as the lack of proof of ownership, and (2) seek to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study solutions to address the availability and affordability of insurance for wildfire perils and other related matters.

The bill allows Indian tribal governments to apply for grants for equipping, upgrading, and constructing state and local emergency operations centers.</summary>
</bill>
