<bill session="111" type="h" number="4250" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:58Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicaid DSH Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to revise regulations implementing the statutory reporting and auditing requirements for the Medicaid disproportionate share hospital ("DSH") payment program to be consistent with the scope of the statutory provisions and avoid substantive changes to preexisting DSH policy.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid DSH Integrity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001161"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000361" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001079" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000456" joined="2009-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2984" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-03T22:29:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicaid DSH Integrity Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to indicate, in appropriate guidance, that the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) do not intend to enforce any changes in policy related to calculating the limits on the adjustment in payment under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act for inpatient hospital services furnished by disproportionate share hospitals (DSH) that were contained in the Medicaid DSH auditing and reporting regulations the CMS issued pursuant to the Medicare Prescription Drug Improvement and Modernization Act of 2003.

Requires the Secretary to publish an interim final rule to revise such regulations as necessary to: (1) correct such policy changes; (2) provide appropriate guidance for otherwise implementing those auditing and reporting regulations; and (3) provide for specified regulatory changes to be included in the new interim rule.

Requires the CMS, in defining the costs of furnishing services to individuals with no health insurance (or other source of third-party coverage), to permit inclusion of all costs related to services provided to patients with no insurance for the service rendered, even if the patient has insurance that covers other services. Declares that the receipt by a hospital of nominal payments related to a service shall not constitute health insurance or a source of third-party coverage.</summary>
</bill>
