<bill session="116" type="s" number="3141" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food Donation Improvement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Donation Improvement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act to clarify and expand food donation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2020-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-16T20:34:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Food Donation Improvement Act of 2019

This bill expands liability protections for the donation of food and grocery products.

Specifically, the bill expands the liability protections to include donations of an apparently fit grocery product or apparently wholesome food:

 for which the recipient receives at zero cost or is charged a good Samaritan reduced price that is no greater than the cost of handling, administering, and distributing the product; or that is donated directly to a needy individual by a retail grocer, wholesaler, agricultural producer, restaurant, caterer, school food authority, or institution of higher education. The Department of Agriculture must issue regulations that clarify the quality and labeling standards that food products donated under the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act must meet to be eligible for liability protection.</summary>
</bill>
