<bill session="118" type="h" number="10448" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combating Loneliness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Loneliness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To combat loneliness and increase social connection, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001318"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2024-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-28T18:19:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Combating Loneliness Act

This bill creates and expands programs that promote mental health to address loneliness and that support the mental and community health workforce. &#160;

The bill creates grant programs that&#160;address loneliness by supporting community facilities (e.g., parks) and&#160;community outreach to at-risk individuals.&#160;It also expands grants promoting healthy lifestyles for older individuals&#160;to include&#160;services addressing loneliness.&#160;

In addition, the bill expands Medicare and Medicaid to include services provided by community health workers and increases the Medicaid federal matching rate for these services. It also&#160;expands Medicare to include certified community behavioral health clinic services.&#160;

The bill provides statutory authority for grants for developing school-based mental health programs and services. It also establishes grants for partnerships between certain entities, such as between hospitals and schools, to coordinate group therapy for mental health. The bill reauthorizes through FY2029 the 21st Century Community Learning Centers program and expands it to include mental health services and community service. It also reauthorizes for FY2026 grants for health care services in schools provided under Medicaid or the Children&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Health Insurance Program (CHIP).

The bill establishes a program for repaying student loans for individuals providing mental health services in designated shortage areas. It also makes community health workers eligible for the National Health Service Corps&#226;&#8364;&#8482; federal loan repayment program.&#160;

Additionally, the bill reauthorizes through FY2029 grant programs supporting full-service community schools, substance abuse recovery, and mental health for the health care workforce. It also requires a Government Accountability Office study on social isolation.</summary>
</bill>
