<bill session="116" type="s" number="2235" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Loan Debt Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Debt Relief Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to discharge the qualified loan amounts of each individual, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3887" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-26T16:32:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Student Loan Debt Relief Act of 2019

This bill establishes programs to cancel certain student loan debt and refinance student loans.

First, the bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to automatically discharge (i.e., repay or cancel) up to $50,000 of outstanding student loan debt for each qualified borrower. Borrowers with an adjusted gross income of $100,000 or less, based on the most recent tax year, may receive the maximum loan cancellation. Borrowers with an adjusted gross income above $100,000 may receive partial loan cancellation. Members of Congress are not eligible to receive loan cancellation.

Further, the bill outlines the method of loan discharge, and excludes loan cancellation from taxable income. It also requires ED to automatically place each federal student loan borrower in administrative forbearance for the one-year period in which ED carries out the cancellation of student loans. During this period, payments are not due, interest does not accrue, and ED may not pursue debt collection activities (e.g., wage garnishments).

Next, the bill requires ED to carry out student loan refinancing programs for those student loans that exist after the loan cancellation period. Specifically, it directs ED to automatically refinance federal student loans at the lower interest rates offered to new federal borrowers in the 2016-2017 school year. It also allows borrowers to convert their private student loans to federal student loans, thereby allowing such borrowers to qualify for loan cancellation.

It also makes student loans dischargeable in bankruptcy proceedings.

Finally, the bill specifies notification requirements.</summary>
</bill>
