<bill session="116" type="s" number="3920" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SECURE CAMPUS Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Educational Institutions, Colleges, Universities, and Research Entities from China's Attempts to Misappropriate Property of the United States Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SECURE CAMPUS Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to secure the research enterprise of the United States from the Chinese Communist Party, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2020-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7033" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Area studies and international education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-13T13:35:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safeguarding Educational Institutions, Colleges, Universities, and Research Entities from China's Attempts to Misappropriate Property of the United States Act of 2020 or the SECURE CAMPUS Act of 2020

This bill prohibits certain Chinese citizens from receiving visas to participate in graduate or post-graduate studies in science, technology, engineering, or math (STEM) and contains other related provisions.

This prohibition applies to F (academic student) and J (exchange visitor) visas and does not apply to citizens or permanent residents of Taiwan or Hong Kong. (China considers Taiwan a Chinese province. Hong Kong is a special administrative region within China, and most of its permanent inhabitants are Chinese citizens.)

The Department of State may waive this prohibition on a case-by-case basis for national security purposes or if the applicant is a member of a religious or ethnic group that is systematically oppressed by the Chinese Communist Party.

A recipient of a federal STEM research grant must certify that the recipient (1) is not a Chinese citizen or a participant in a Chinese government foreign researcher recruitment program (a program that compensates individuals to conduct STEM-related research and development), and (2) will not knowingly use grant funds to employ such an individual.

Entities that receive certain federal research or education assistance shall not knowingly employ any individual participating in a Chinese government foreign researcher recruitment program. An individual who&#160;recruits or performs research for such a program must register as an agent of a foreign principal.</summary>
</bill>
