<bill session="117" type="s" number="2548" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for fiscal gap and generational accounting analysis in the legislative process, the President's budget, and annual long-term fiscal outlook reports.</title>
    <title type="display">Intergenerational Financial Obligations Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intergenerational Financial Obligations Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5340" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-22T18:29:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Intergenerational Financial Obligations Reform Act

This bill requires the Congressional Budget Office, the Office of Management and Budget, and the Government Accountability Office to provide various reports that include a fiscal gap analysis and a generational accounting analysis.

Under the bill, the fiscal gap generally refers to the sum of (1) the total amount of Treasury liabilities outstanding on the last day of the budget year, and (2) the discounted present value of the projected difference between federal spending and revenues during the period of the budget year and at least the next 75 fiscal years (excluding spending for net interest and principal payments on Treasury liabilities).

A generational accounting analysis addresses the fiscal impact that projected federal spending and tax burdens will have on various generations of individuals.</summary>
</bill>
