<bill session="118" type="s" number="1535" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildfire Response Aviation Modernization and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Response Aviation Modernization and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to promulgate regulations to allow the transport of firefighters on board a covered aircraft operated on a mission to suppress a wildfire, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000377"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-24T16:29:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wildfire Response Aviation Modernization and Safety Act

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to promulgate rules to specify that the FAA must allow for the transport of firefighters on board certain aircraft operated on a mission to suppress a wildfire. The FAA must also issue a rule to specify that certain FAA noise standards do not apply to such an operation.

Current regulations allow a type certificate for a restricted category aircraft to be used for the aerial dispensing of liquids (e.g., liquids for aerial fire suppression) and exclude from noise requirements certain aircraft that are dispensing fire fighting materials. Restricted category aircraft are prohibited from carrying passengers.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
