<bill session="119" type="h" number="122" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Original LAW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Original LAW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Original Living American Wage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act to provide for the calculation of the minimum wage based on the Federal supplemental poverty threshold for a renter family of 4, with 2 children under the age of 18, as determined by the Bureau of the Census, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-03T12:06:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Original Living American Wage Act or the Original LAW Act

This bill increases the federal minimum wage according to a formula specified in the bill.

First, the bill increases the minimum hourly wage to $10.59&#160;beginning on January 1, 2026, and increases the minimum hourly wage by $4 annually from January 1, 2027,&#160;through January 1, 2030.

Next, beginning on January 1, 2031, the Department of Labor shall increase the minimum hourly wage every seven years&#160;according to a specified formula.

The formula establishes the minimum hourly wage as the wage sufficient for a person working 1,799 hours per year (approximately 35 hours per week) to earn an annual income that is 40%&#160;higher than the federal supplemental poverty threshold for a renter family of four, with two children under the age of 18, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics for the preceding year. However, if this formula results in a reduction, the minimum&#160;hourly wage may not be lowered.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
