<bill session="111" type="h" number="5738" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:56Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Enhancement of Talented Students Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to carry out a pilot program to reduce the amount of processed food served each day under the school breakfast program or school lunch program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School EATS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Enhancement of Talented Students Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000844" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2010-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1322-1323"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-23T20:32:31Z" status="Introduced in House">School Enhancement of Talented Students Act or School EATS Act - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to award competitive grants to states, local educational agencies, or school food authorities to reduce the amount of processed food served each day under the school lunch and breakfast programs.

Gives grant priority to applicants: (1) in which at least 50% of the students enrolled in schools under their jurisdictions are eligible for free or reduced price meals; and (2) located in states where the adult obesity rate is not less that 30% and the child obesity rate is more than 30%, as determined by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).

Requires grant funds to be used to: (1) procure unprocessed foods; (2) train food service staff to prepare such foods; and (3) purchase the equipment needed to prepare such foods.

Requires the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees on the procurement of healthy, unprocessed foods.

Makes food weight and quantity requirements under the school lunch and breakfast programs inapplicable to food served under this Act's grant program.</summary>
</bill>
