<bill session="116" type="h" number="4054" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stand By Every Ad Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require the sponsors of certain general public political advertisements to include in the advertisements information on the persons who provided the funding for such advertisements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stand By Every Ad Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="949" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-24T15:40:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Stand By Every Ad Act 

This bill generally revises requirements related to disclosures provided with political advertisements. The bill applies political advertising disclosure requirements currently applicable to candidates (also known as stand by your ad requirements) to entities such as corporations and nonprofit organizations. Political advertisements made by these organizations must generally disclose the top funders of the entity, with specified exceptions.

The bill revises the classification of certain media, including audio and visual media, for purposes of disclaimer requirements. The bill also expands the definition of public communication to include digital communication, creates additional disclaimer readability requirements, and expands disclosure requirements for public communications consisting of campaign-related disbursements.</summary>
</bill>
