<bill session="117" type="h" number="4208" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify the obligations of licensees under section 331 of that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Section 331 Obligation Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Section 331 Obligation Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2021-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2021-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2220" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-30T17:41:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Section 331 Obligation Clarification Act

This bill specifies that certain service obligations owed by the licensee of a commercial television broadcast station apply regardless of the broadcast frequency used by the licensee.

Specifically, the bill provides that a licensee making a change from a very high frequency (VHF) broadcast station to an ultrahigh frequency (UHF) broadcast station must ensure the change does not affect its obligation to provide service to its customers. The bill also requires such a licensee to (1) broadcast at least 14 hours of common local programming per week, (2) include a substantial amount of particularized local content, and (3) maintain a studio in the station's community.

 The bill further provides for the reallocation of a station to a community where there is no VHF or UHF station.

The Government Accountability Office must examine and report on the process used by the Federal Communications Commission for renewing broadcast television licenses to determine if that process meets specified obligations. In particular, the GAO must review how the process relates to television broadcast stations with specific obligations to serve the needs of their local communities.</summary>
</bill>
