<bill session="118" type="s" number="1339" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pharmacy Benefit Manager Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Pharmacy Benefit Manager Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Safe Step Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pharmacy Benefit Manager Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for increased oversight of entities that provide pharmacy benefit management services on behalf of group health plans and health insurance coverage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Sanders with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="113">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 113.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2630" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="652" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4005" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4712" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-12T14:17:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pharmacy Benefit Manager Reform Act

This bill establishes various requirements for pharmacy benefit managers (PBMs) with respect to services provided to health insurance plans.

First, PBMs must report annually to the plan sponsor certain information about the PBM's services, including the amount of prescription drug copayment assistance funded by drug manufacturers, a list of covered drugs billed under the plan during the reporting period, and the total net spending by the health plan on prescription drugs. PBMs also must provide plan sponsors with a supplementary report every six months with specified information about drugs that were dispensed under the plan by pharmacies that are wholly or partially owned by the PBM.

Second, the bill prohibits spread pricing. Under the bill, spread pricing occurs when a PBM charges an insurance plan (or an insurance plan charges plan participants) a price for a prescription drug that exceeds the price paid to the pharmacy for the drug.

Finally, PBMs must remit to the plan sponsor all rebates, fees, alternative discounts, and other remuneration received from a drug manufacturer.

The bill establishes civil penalties for violations of these requirements and provides funding for the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Department of Labor to implement the provisions of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
