<bill session="116" type="s" number="955" updated="2022-11-01T18:47:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Polling Place Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Polling Place Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to reduce waiting times for voters in Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-31T17:00:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Polling Place Protection Act of 2019 

This bill requires states and jurisdictions responsible for administering elections to provide sufficient resources to ensure

 a reasonably uniform ratio of staff and voting systems to registered voters, a reasonably uniform geographic distribution of polling places, a fair and equitable waiting time for voters, and a wait of no longer than 30 minutes to cast a ballot at a polling place. These states and jurisdictions must develop an election administration plan that includes a contingency plan for additional resources to be deployed if there are wait times of over 30 minutes at any polling place on an election day. Contingency plans must be approved by the Federal Election Commission.

 This bill provides a private right of action for an individual aggrieved by a state or jurisdiction's violation of the voting wait time limit.

A U.S. district court may extend polling hours to enforce these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
