<bill session="116" type="h" number="7493" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Granny Pods Study Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to conduct a study on temporary family health care structures.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Granny Pods Study Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-20T14:03:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Granny Pods Study Act of 2020

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to study the provision of certain long-term care services for physically or mentally impaired individuals through temporary family health care structures (also known as granny pods).

Specifically, the CMS must (1) identify services that are already covered by Medicare or Medicaid that could be provided in temporary family health care structures by caregivers, (2) determine reasonable reimbursement rates for such services, and (3) provide the cost differential between such rates and the rates for services provided in nursing facilities.

The bill defines temporary family health care structure as a transportable residential structure that helps a caregiver (i.e., adult relative) of an individual who is mentally or physically impaired to care for the individual. The structure must have been primarily assembled at a different location from&#160;where it is installed, may be no larger than 300 gross square feet, and must be limited to only one occupant (the individual in need of care).</summary>
</bill>
