<bill session="118" type="s" number="3467" updated="2025-11-19T03:12:47Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energizing American Shipbuilding Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a certain percentage of natural gas and crude oil exports be transported on United States-built and United States-flag vessels, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energizing American Shipbuilding Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2024-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6724" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-25T14:32:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energizing American Shipbuilding Act of 2023

This bill requires an increasing percentage of liquefied natural gas&#160;(LNG) and crude oil exports to be transported on U.S. vessels with American crews by certain deadlines. Specifically, the bill directs (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to require specified percentages of LNG exports to be transported on vessels built or retrofitted in the United States and documented under its laws, and (2) the President to require specified percentages of crude oil exports to be transported on vessels built or retrofitted in the United States and documented under its laws.

The vessels that are subject to these requirements must also have certain components that are built in the United States.&#160;If the vessels are retrofitted, the work must be done in a shipyard in the United States. FERC and the President may waive the component requirements under specified circumstances.&#160;

The Energy Information Administration must collect and publish information on exports of natural gas and crude oil by vessels, including forecasts and data on those exports.</summary>
</bill>
