<bill session="108" type="s" number="1390" updated="2023-01-15T06:02:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Medication Safety Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect children and their parents from being coerced into administering a controlled substance in order to attend school, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Medication Safety Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2003-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2003-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2003-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2003-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1170" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-04T20:55:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Child Medication Safety Act of 2003 - Requires States, as a condition of receiving funds under any program or activity administered by the Secretary of Education, to develop and implement policies and procedures prohibiting school personnel from requiring a child, as a condition of attending school or receiving services, to obtain a prescription for a controlled substance in schedule II under the Controlled Substances Act. (Thus prohibits school personnel from coercing children to receive, or their parents to administer, psychotropic medication.) Provides that nothing in such requirement shall be construed to create a Federal prohibition against teachers and other school personnel consulting or sharing classroom-based observations with parents or guardians regarding a student's academic performance or behavior in the classroom or school, or regarding the need for evaluation for special education or related services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA). Directs the Comptroller General to review and report on: (1) the variation among States in definitions of psychotropic medication as used in regard to State jurisdiction over public education; (2) the prescription rates of medications used in public schools to treat children diagnosed with attention deficit disorder, attention deficit hyperactivity disorder, and other disorders or illnesses; (3) which such medications are listed under the Controlled Substances Act (CSA); and (4) which such medications are not listed under CSA, including their properties and effects and whether they have been considered for CSA listing.</summary>
</bill>
