<bill session="108" type="s" number="1158" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:17Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Library and Bookseller Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to exempt bookstores and libraries from orders requiring the production of tangible things for foreign intelligence investigations, and to exempt libraries from counterintelligence access to certain records, ensuring that libraries and bookstores are subjected to the regular system of court-ordered warrants.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Library and Bookseller Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Library and Bookseller Protection Act - Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (the Act) to provide that no application by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to a U.S. court for an order requiring the production of tangible things for an investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information from a U.S. person or to protect against international terrorism may be made for the sole purpose of searching for, or seizing from, a bookseller or library documentary materials that contain personally identifiable information concerning a patron. Provides that nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude a physical search for documentary materials (including books, records, papers, documents, and other items) under other provisions of law.Amends Federal criminal law to exclude libraries from provisions requiring wire or electronic communication service providers to comply with requests by the FBI Director in foreign counterintelligence investigations for subscriber information and toll billing records information, or electronic communication transactional records in their custody.</summary>
</bill>
