<bill session="119" type="h" number="575" updated="2025-11-19T04:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Increased TSP Access Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increased TSP Access Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to modify the delivery of technical assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000474" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001094" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000590" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2025-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001232" joined="2025-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001225" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001213" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000490" joined="2025-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2025-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="156" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-17T18:31:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Increased TSP Access Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to modify the&#160;certification process for Technical Service Providers (TSPs) at the Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) by establishing an approval process for nonfederal certifying entities and a streamlined certification process for TSPs that hold certain specialty certifications.

As background, TSPs are third-party service providers, such as private businesses, Indian tribes, and nonprofit organizations, that work on behalf of customers to offer planning, design, and implementation services that meet NRCS criteria.

The bill specifies that USDA must ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, third-party providers with expertise in the technical aspects of conservation practice design, implementation, and evaluation are eligible to become approved TSPs.

USDA must provide a streamlined certification process for TSPs who hold appropriate specialty certifications (e.g., certified crop advisors).

In determining the eligibility of a nonfederal certifying entity, USDA must consider the ability, experience, expertise, and history of the entity. USDA must decide whether to approve an application submitted by a nonfederal certifying entity to certify&#160;TSPs&#160;within a specified time period. &#160;

USDA must also review a TSP's certification by a nonfederal certifying entity within a specified time period. If the certification is satisfactory, USDA must include the&#160;TSP on a USDA-maintained registry of certified TSPs.

The bill also specifies that TSPs must be paid at rates equivalent to technical assistance provided by USDA.

Further, USDA must provide accessible public information on TSPs, including information on funding, certification results, and utilization rates.</summary>
</bill>
