<bill session="118" type="h" number="7151" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:27Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-09T19:25:33-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-09T19:25:33-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short">Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to provide for expedited consideration of proposals for additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to entities on the Entity List, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000812"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2024-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T19:15:52-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Wagner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T19:16:19-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5083-5084" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T19:16:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7151.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-09-09T19:25:33-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5083" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T19:25:34-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-10T16:07:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Export Control Enforcement and Enhancement Act

This bill allows federal agencies to expedite consideration of modifications to the Entity List. (The Entity List provides the names of foreign entities that are subject to export license requirements because they are threats to U.S. national security and foreign policy.)

Specifically, the bill allows the Departments of State, Defense, or Energy (or other appropriate federal agencies) to submit proposals to the Department of Commerce for additions to, removals from, or other modifications with respect to entities on the Entity List. Commerce must submit each proposal to the End-User Review Committee (which is responsible for creating and maintaining the Entity List). Generally, within 30 days of receiving a proposal, the committee must vote to approve or disapprove the proposal. (Commerce administers licensing and civil enforcement functions for dual-use exports through its Bureau of Industry and&#160;Security.)

The bill creates a presumption of denial of licenses for the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of any item (including software and technology) included on the Commerce Control List that is controlled for national security reasons to or in a country subject to an embargo, including an arms embargo, imposed by the United States or to any foreign person included on the Entity List. Commerce must notify Congress within 15 days of (1) determining not to apply a presumption of denial (in accordance with the bill), or (2) removing national security as the reason for a control on any item on the Commerce Control List.</summary>
</bill>
