<bill session="108" type="hc" number="97" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:38Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to pulmonary hypertension.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to pulmonary hypertension.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000755"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Lung diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Special months"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the role played by national and community organizations and health care providers in promoting awareness of the importance of early diagnosis, testing, and ongoing screening for pulmonary hypertension should be recognized and applauded; (2) the Federal Government should raise awareness about the importance of the early detection of and proper treatment for pulmonary hypertension, increase funding for research, and improve access to quality health care services for early detection and treatment; (3) the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute should continue to take a leadership role through the expansion of basic, clinical, and genetic research; (4) the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention should give priority consideration to the establishment of a pulmonary hypertension awareness program aimed at the general public and health care providers; and (5) National Pulmonary Hypertension Awareness Month should be established.</summary>
</bill>
