<bill session="117" type="s" number="3922" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unlocking Capital for Small Businesses Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlocking Capital for Small Businesses Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to create a safe harbor for finders and private placement brokers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8998" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-27T14:50:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Unlocking Capital for Small Businesses Act of 2022

This bill revises the regulatory treatment of private-placement brokers (brokers who receive transaction-based compensation for the sale of securities to preselected individuals or institutions) and finders (private-placement brokers who do not exceed a specified amount of compensation, transaction value, or number of transactions in a year).

Specifically, the bill (1) requires the Securities and Exchange Commission to establish registration requirements for&#160;private-placement brokers that are no more stringent&#160;than those imposed on crowdfunding portals, (2) allows for membership in any national securities association for private-placement brokers, (3) exempts private-placement brokers from broker regulations, and (4) otherwise modifies provisions related to private-placement brokers and finders.</summary>
</bill>
