<bill session="116" type="s" number="2073" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:43Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to address fees erroneously collected by Department of Veterans Affairs for housing loans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address fees erroneously collected by Department of Veterans Affairs for housing loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2019-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-24T15:01:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to submit a plan to identify individuals who were erroneously charged a fee between January 1, 2012, and December 31, 2017, in relation to VA-backed home loans. Specifically, the bill focuses on veterans who are rated as eligible for disability compensation and are supposed to have such home loan fees waived by the VA. The VA must also submit a plan to identify individuals who were erroneously charged a fee prior to January 1, 2012. Both plans must include the number of individuals who may be due a refund and a time line for refunding the fees.

The bill also requires the VA to

 develop an automated process for refunding fees, update policies to ensure certificates of eligibility are accurate for determining eligibility under the VA home loan guaranty program and the exemption from the collection of fees, develop a process for determining whether a fee has been collected from an individual with a waiver (due to service-connected death or disability), and develop a plan for annual audits to determine the rate at which fees are erroneously collected from individuals with waivers.</summary>
</bill>
