<bill session="117" type="h" number="5480" updated="2023-01-01T23:51:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the applicability of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 to rules issued under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 and to amend such Act to prohibit emergency temporary standards with respect to vaccines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To clarify the applicability of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 to rules issued under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 and to amend such Act to prohibit emergency temporary standards with respect to vaccines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000298"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-04T14:32:42Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill places certain restrictions on employer-based vaccination requirements.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the Department of Labor from issuing an emergency temporary occupational safety or health standard that requires employers to ensure their employees receive a vaccine.

In addition, the bill expressly applies the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993 (RFRA) to occupational health and safety rules issued by Labor. Currently, RFRA prohibits the government from substantially burdening a person's exercise of religion even if the burden results from a rule of general applicability, except in furtherance of a compelling governmental interest when using the least restrictive means.</summary>
</bill>
