<bill session="116" type="h" number="6267" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:30Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">State- and Science-based Gray Wolf Reintroduction Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a process for State determinations with respect to Canis lupus reintroduction, to protect ungulate, stock animal, and dog populations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State- and Science-based Gray Wolf Reintroduction Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000470"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-27T16:17:38Z" status="Introduced in House">State- and Science-based Gray Wolf Reintroduction Act of 2020

This bill requires a state to obtain approval from the Department of the Interior before reintroducing the gray wolf (Canis lupus) and allows a person to take (e.g., kill or harm) a gray wolf under certain circumstances.

Specifically, the bill prohibits a state from reintroducing the gray wolf unless Interior approves a state petition that meets the requirements of this bill. If an affected county makes a recommendation to deny the petition, then Interior may not approve the petition.

A person in a state with an approved petition may take a gray wolf that is attacking a stock animal or dog if the person (1) is not trespassing or on land administered by the National Park Service; and (2) did not intentionally bait, feed, or otherwise attract the wolf.</summary>
</bill>
