<bill session="111" type="h" number="6230" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:33Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 37, United States Code, to exclude bonus payments made by a State or political subdivision thereof to a member of the Armed Forces, including a reserve component member, on account of the service of the member in the Armed Forces from consideration in determining the eligibility of the member (or the member's spouse or family) for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 37, United States Code, to exclude bonus payments made by a State or political subdivision thereof to a member of the Armed Forces, including a reserve component member, on account of the service of the member in the Armed Forces from consideration in determining the eligibility of the member (or the member's spouse or family) for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000609"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-06T22:36:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Excludes bonus payments made by a state or political subdivision thereof to a member of the Armed Forces, including a reserve member, on account of military service from consideration as income in determining the member's eligibility (or the member's spouse or family) for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any federal, state, or local program financed in whole or in part with federal funds.

Provides that if a bonus payment is paid to another person on behalf of a deceased member, such exclusion shall apply to that recipient.

Applies such exclusion retroactively to any bonus paid: (1) during the period beginning on August 2, 1990, and ending on March 3, 1991; and (2) since September 11, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
