<bill session="111" type="s" number="238" updated="2022-02-03T06:06:14Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Build America Bonds Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Build America Bonds Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide $50,000,000,000 in new transportation infrastructure funding through bonding to empower States and local governments to complete significant infrastructure projects across all modes of transportation, including roads, bridges, rail and transit systems, ports, and inland waterways, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2009-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2009-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2009-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S390"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-25T22:39:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Build America Bonds Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax credit for any Build America bond issued by the Transportation Finance Corporation as part of an issue, if 100% of the available project proceeds from such issue are to be used for expenditures incurred for one or more qualified projects. Requires proceeds from the sale of bonds issued under this Act to be held in a Build America Bonds Trust Account.

Defines "qualified project" as the capital improvements to any transportation infrastructure project (including roads, bridges, rail and transit systems, ports, and inland waterways) proposed by one or more states and approved by the Transportation Finance Corporation.

Grants Congress' consent and recognition to the establishment by two or more state infrastructure banks of the Transportation Finance Corporation. Authorizes the Transportation Finance Corporation to: (1) issue Build America bonds for the financing of qualified projects; (2) establish and operate the Build America Bonds Trust Account; (3) leverage resources and stimulate public and private investment in transportation infrastructure; and (4) perform any other function the sole purpose of which is to carry out the financing of qualified projects through Build America bonds.

Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to extend certain customs fees for the processing of merchandise entered into the United States through specified dates in 2046.</summary>
</bill>
