<bill session="108" type="h" number="4022" updated="2023-01-15T10:32:58Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Private Security Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the Nation's ability to protect its key assets and the life, health, and property of its populace by granting providers of private security services access to the criminal history records available through the National Crime Information Center in connection with their employees and prospective employees, requiring such providers to employ only those employees who pass criminal history records checks, to protect against unauthorized use of such records, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Private Security Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000443" joined="2004-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000392" joined="2004-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2004-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001033" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000097" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000268" joined="2004-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-26T14:51:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Private Security Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, upon request by a covered employer (certain non-governmental companies that provide security guard services or that have more than 50 employees of which at least three are internal security employees), to provide for a National Crime Information Center (NCIC) criminal history records check on a current or prosepective security employee. Requires such request to include fingerprints of the employee.

Prohibits such an employer from employing such an employee to provide any security service or function unless: (1) the employer first obtains the results of an NCIC criminal history records check; and (2) neither the results of that check nor any other information made available to the employer indicate that the employee has any unpardoned conviction under Federal or State law of any felony or of specified offenses.

Prohibits such an employer from making such a request without the employee's consent. Requires an employer to ensure that information received under this Act is maintained confidentially, not misused, and destroyed within a specified time. Directs the Secretary to establish procedures to ensure that the Department of Homeland Security properly uses the results.

Sets penalties for knowingly and intentionally using any information obtained pursuant to this Act for a purpose other than that of determining suitability for employment.</summary>
</bill>
