<bill session="119" type="h" number="1457" updated="2025-08-12T20:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IDs for an Inclusive Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IDs for an Inclusive Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration to produce and make available at no cost to certain individuals in the United States an identification for the purpose of allowing such individuals to meet certain identification requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001117"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2025-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-12T20:44:32Z" status="Introduced in House">IDs for an Inclusive Democracy Act

This bill directs the Social Security Administration (SSA) to produce and make available at no cost to individuals over the age of 14 a&#160;means of&#160;identification (ID) sufficient to satisfy certain identification requirements (i.e., requirements otherwise satisfied by a driver's license or state ID).

The ID must include a photograph, specified information, and certain security features, and must generally be valid for 10 years.

SSA must develop and implement a campaign to educate the public about the ID, including how an individual can obtain and use one.

The U.S. Postal Service (USPS)&#160;must develop and implement a process that enables individuals to apply for and renew an ID through USPS, modeled after the process for passport applications.

The bill also establishes a task force to set forth requirements for the production and distribution of the new IDs. The task force must (1) issue a report outlining such requirements, including procedures to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of any information obtained from applicants seeking assistance with the ID process; and (2) develop and publish voluntary best practices for nonprofit organizations and entities that serve vulnerable populations on assisting individuals with the application process.</summary>
</bill>
