<bill session="115" type="s" number="2717" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:40Z">
  <state datetime="2018-04-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maritime Authorization and Enhancement Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize provisions relating to the Maritime Administration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Authorization and Enhancement Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Maritime Authorization and Enhancement Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2018-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-292.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="505">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 505.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-22T17:24:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maritime Authorization and Enhancement Act for Fiscal Year 2019

This bill reauthorizes for FY2019 programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT) associated with maintaining the United States merchant marine, including the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy (USMMA), state maritime academies, the National Security Multi-Mission Vessel Program, U.S. Maritime Administration operations and programs, the ship disposal program, and the maritime guaranteed loan program.

The bill addresses (1) DOT jurisdiction over the USMMA; (2) the USMMA policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; (3) implementation of recommendations for the USMMA Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Program; (4) electronic records on mariner availability to meet national security needs; (5) small shipyard grants; (6) domestic ship recycling facilities; (7)&#160;USMMA cadet Sea Year training needs; (8) the national maritime strategy; (9) the DOT Office of Inspector General report on the financial controls and protections included in its policies and procedures for approving loan applications under the Federal Ship Financing Program; (10) multi-year contracts for the procurement of vessels within the National Security Multi-Mission Vessel Program; (11) the use of state academy training vessels; (12) DOT authority to issue war risk insurance; and (13) the comprehensive study of the Great Lakes-Saint Lawrence Seaway navigation system.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-292</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
