<bill session="108" type="s" number="995" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Nutrition Initiatives Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to improve certain child nutritional programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Nutrition Initiatives Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5736-5737"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5737-5738" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fruit"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="Vegetables"/>
    <term name="WIC program"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Child Nutrition Initiatives Act of 2003 - Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (NSLA) and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) to revise, reauthorize, establish, and provide funding for certain nutritional and educational programs.Amends NSLA to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) to establish a program of incentives for healthier schools, under which a school or institution receiving funds for meals under NSLA or CNA may receive an increase in the reimbursement rate if it implements a plan for improving the nutritional value of meals consumed there by increasing the consumption of fluid milk, fruits, and vegetables, under criteria established by the Secretary. Requires such increased reimbursements to be not less than two and not more than ten cents per meal, to reflect additional costs incurred.Amends NSLA to direct the Secretary to make competitive grants to nonprofit entities and educational institutions to establish and carry out Farm-to-Cafeteria projects that may include the purchase of equipment, the procurement of foods, and the provision of training and education activities, in order to improve access to local foods in schools and institutions receiving funds under NSLA and CNA (except the special supplemental program for women, infants, and children (WIC) which already has a WIC Farmers Market Nutrition program). Makes appropriations for Farm-to-Cafeteria projects (through transfers of specified amounts by the Secretary of Treasury).Amends CNA to revise requirements for school breakfast and related programs to increase the required minimum amount payable for State administrative expenses, and to adjust such amount for inflation. Reauthorizes appropriations for State administrative expenses.Expresses the sense of the Congress that the WIC program should be fully funded. Reauthorizes appropriations for the WIC program, including funds for nutrition services and administration.Makes appropriations for the WIC Farmers Market Nutrition program (through transfers of specified amounts by the Secretary of Treasury).Makes appropriations for the Nutrition Education and Training (NET) program (through transfers of specified amounts by the Secretary of Treasury). Increases the required minimum amount for an NET grant to a State.</summary>
</bill>
