<bill session="112" type="h" number="2730" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:33Z">
  <state datetime="2011-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening the Child Welfare Response to Human Trafficking Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to better enable State child welfare agencies to prevent human trafficking of children and serve the needs of children who are victims of human trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening the Child Welfare Response to Human Trafficking Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2012-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2012-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2012-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000517" joined="2012-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2012-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2012-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2012-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2012-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2012-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-10-26T16:20:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening the Child Welfare Response to Human Trafficking Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop guidelines for use by state child welfare agencies in training appropriate child welfare employees and court employees in identifying, documenting, educating, and counseling children at risk of becoming victims of trafficking or who are human trafficking victims who may need to be in the care of the child welfare system.

Requires the Secretary to develop guidelines that contain recommendations on how state child welfare agencies may prevent children from becoming victims of trafficking, including advice on how state and local law enforcement agencies may collaborate proactively with nonprofit organizations on how to manage cases involving a child who is such a victim.

Requires the Secretary to draft recommendations for state child welfare agencies on how to best update licensing requirements for childcare institutions so that specialized, long-term residential facilities or safe havens serving children who are human trafficking victims can quality as childcare institutions under part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act.

Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require state part E plans to include components that provides that: (1) the records of the agency classify each child to whom the agency is providing child welfare services and whom the agency has identified as being a victim of trafficking, and specify the reasons why the child is so classified; (2) each report submitted by the agency to the data collection system includes information on each child so classified; and (3) the agency shall report immediately to the appropriate law enforcement agencies for entry into the National Crime Information Center database the identity of each missing or abducted child to whom the agency is providing child welfare services.

Includes as part of the case plan for a child classified as a victim of trafficking documentation of the measures taken to ensure the child's safety and of specifically designed services the child is receiving.

Extends to age 21 any services for trafficked youth under the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program.

Requires state part E plans to describe the practices and future plans of the state child welfare agency regarding the human trafficking and commercial sexual exploitation of foreign, U.S. citizen, and legal resident children.</summary>
</bill>
