<bill session="110" type="s" number="2800" updated="2019-11-15T21:57:47Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EARN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Employment Access for Recidivism Reduction Nationwide</title>
    <title type="display">Employment Access for Recidivism Reduction Nationwide</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the incentives for employers to hire qualified ex-felons by enhancing the effectiveness of the work opportunity tax credit, to reduce the backlog of applications pending certification under the work opportunity tax credit program, to enhance the effectiveness of the Federal bonding program, to enhance the effectiveness of the Federal bonding program, and to authorize a pilot program for employment-focused re-entry projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2008-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-30T15:21:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Employment Access for Recidivism Reduction Nationwide or the EARN Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) promote the work opportunity tax credit program by reducing backlogs of employer applications for certifications under such program and by increasing awareness of the availability of such credit; and (2) increase the number of fidelity bonds purchased and issued by states through the Federal Bonding Program.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the work opportunity tax credit for employers who employ ex-felons hired under certain federal programs.</summary>
</bill>
