<bill session="118" type="h" number="7245" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:29Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide supplemental appropriations for fiscal year 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide supplemental appropriations for fiscal year 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000148" joined="2024-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2024-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000601" joined="2024-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2024-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="815" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-07T15:26:03Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides FY2024 supplemental appropriations to several federal agencies for assistance to Ukraine, Israel, and Taiwan.

Specifically, the bill provides additional funding for

 the Department of Defense (DOD), the National Nuclear Security Administration, the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), the Administration for Children and Families, the Department of State, and the U.S. Agency for International Development. The bill provides the funding for purposes such as

 assistance for Ukraine, Israel, and Taiwan; improvements to the submarine industrial base; the FEMA Nonprofit Security Grant Program; refugee assistance; and humanitarian assistance. In addition, the bill includes provisions that (1) expand the authorities of the President to transfer defense articles and services from DOD to foreign countries or international organizations; and (2) prohibit funds from being used for payments to the U.N. Relief and Works Agency.</summary>
</bill>
