<bill session="108" type="s" number="2069" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">International Weapons of Mass Destruction Informant Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the S visa classification to include aliens who are in possession of critical reliable information with respect to weapons of mass destruction, to establish a Weapons of Mass Destruction Informant Center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Weapons of Mass Destruction Informant Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2004-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-09T20:33:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">International Weapons of Mass Destruction Informant Act - Expands the S nonimmigrant visa classification of the Immigration and Nationality Act to include aliens who possess and are willing to share with the U.S. Government critical reliable information concerning the activities of governments or organizations with respect to weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and related delivery systems, where those weapons or systems are at risk of being developed, sold, or transferred. Provides for S nonimmigrant status for specified family members of such aliens in appropriate circumstances.

Increases the numerical limitation on S nonimmigrant visas to 3,500 per fiscal year.

Establishes a Weapons of Mass Destruction Informant Center within the Directorate for Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection of the Department of Homeland Security, which shall : (1) receive and report to specified Federal agencies all information provided by aliens granted S nonimmigrant status under this Act; (2) ensure that aliens who have provided WMD-related information are given the highest consideration for S nonimmigrant visas; (3) educate consular officers and immigration inspectors and examiners regarding the expanded visa classification; (4) facilitate, receive, and evaluate visa requests submitted pursuant to this Act and facilitate the issuance of visas when requests are approved; (5) facilitate the cooperation with the U.S. Government of aliens receiving WMD-related S nonimmigrant visas; (6) ensure that aliens who receive such visas comply with visa terms; and (7) ensure that such visas are not used to gain entry into the U.S. for purposes other than those outlined in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
