<bill session="117" type="s" number="3498" updated="2022-12-30T04:04:47Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FORWARD Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Finding Orphan-disease Remedies With Antifungal Research and Development Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FORWARD Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support endemic fungal disease research, incentivize fungal vaccine development, discover new antifungal therapies and diagnostics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000377"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2022-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5566" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-10T16:27:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Finding Orphan-disease Remedies With Antifungal Research and Development Act of 2022 or the FORWARD Act of 2022

This bill establishes programs to support research on endemic fungal diseases and the development of antifungal drugs, with a particular focus on Valley Fever. Endemic fungal diseases are fungal infections that tend to occur in specific geographic areas and affect older adults and other at-risk populations.

Specifically, the bill establishes the Endemic Fungal Disease Working Group to review, coordinate, and make recommendations about the Department of Health and Human Services' efforts to address endemic fungal diseases. The working group is comprised of experts from both relevant federal agencies and the private sector.

In addition, the National Institutes of Health must continue its support for research on endemic fungal diseases.

Furthermore, the Food and Drug Administration must issue guidance for entities seeking approval for therapies, diagnostics, and vaccines to prevent and treat Valley Fever. Additionally, the bill provides for the use of priority reviews and other fast-track procedures to incentivize and expedite development and approval of these medical products.

The bill also requires the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority to implement the Combating Antimicrobial Resistance Biopharmaceutical Accelerator Program to reduce and prevent antimicrobial resistance.</summary>
</bill>
