<bill session="110" type="h" number="2171" updated="2023-01-11T15:47:58Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Knowledge Is Power Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to provide for disclosure to consumers of the fuels and sources of electric energy purchased from electric utilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Knowledge Is Power Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="2196" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Ocean currents"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-06-20T20:10:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Knowledge Is Power Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to require electric utilities to disclose prominently on consumers' periodic billing statements the percentage mix of energy technologies and fuels used to generate the electricity sold within the distribution utility's distribution area.

 Requires such disclosure to specify the percentage of electricity generated from coal, from gas, from nuclear, from any other fuel, and from any particular type of renewable energy (including solar, wind, biomass, landfill gas, ocean tidal, ocean wave, ocean current, ocean thermal, geothermal, municipal solid waste, or hydroelectric).

 Declares compliance requirements inapplicable if before enactment of this Act: (1) the state has implemented for such utility the standard concerned, or a comparable one; (2) the state regulatory authority or relevant nonregulated electric utility has conducted a proceeding to consider the standard's implementation; or (3) the state legislature has voted on its implementation.</summary>
</bill>
