<bill session="112" type="h" number="1050" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:22Z">
  <state datetime="2011-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to improve access and choice for entrepreneurs with small businesses with respect to medical care for their employees.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001082" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000451" joined="2011-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000549" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000564" joined="2012-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2012-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2011-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2011-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="105" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="299" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="397" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3682" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="6299" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-05-09T18:55:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2011 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans (AHPs), which are group health plans whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations, and which meet certain ERISA certification requirements.

Prescribes rules governing AHPs, including requirements relating to certification, sponsors and boards of trustees, participation and coverage, nondiscrimination, contribution rates, notice of voluntary termination, correction actions, and mandatory termination.

Establishes the Association Health Plan Fund to be used by the Secretary of Labor to make payments to an insurer to maintain coverage for a plan if there is a reasonable expectation that, without such payments, claims would not be satisfied by reason of termination of coverage.

Requires the Secretary to establish a Solvency Standards Working Group.

Allows a state to impose a contribution tax on an association health plan that commenced operations in such state after the enactment of this Act.

Preempts any state law that may preclude a health insurance issuer from: (1) offering health insurance coverage in connection with a certified AHP; or (2) offering health insurance coverage of the same policy type to other employers operating in the state that are eligible for coverage under such AHPs, whether or not such other employers are participating employers in such plan.

Subjects to criminal penalties a person who willfully makes false representations with respect to an AHP.</summary>
</bill>
