<bill session="119" type="s" number="341" updated="2025-11-19T03:43:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Smoke and Heat Ready Communities Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smoke and Heat Ready Communities Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to establish a grant program for supporting local communities in detecting, preparing for, communicating about, or mitigating the environmental and public health impacts of wildfire smoke and extreme heat, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="903" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-18T16:21:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Smoke and Heat Ready Communities Act of 2025

This bill authorizes the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to make grants to air pollution control agencies to support the development and implementation of programs that support local communities in detecting, preparing for, communicating with the public about, or mitigating the environmental and public health aspects of wildfire smoke and extreme heat. The EPA must establish a formula to distribute the grants among air pollution control agencies.

The bill requires the EPA to establish four Centers of Excellence for Wildfire Smoke and Extreme Heat at institutions of higher education to research (1) the effects of smoke emissions from wildland fires and extreme heat on public health, and (2) the means by which communities can better respond to impacts from such conditions.

Additionally, the EPA must begin to carry out research to

study the health effects of smoke emissions from wildland fires and extreme heat;develop and disseminate personal and community-based interventions to reduce exposure to, and health effects of, wildland fire smoke emissions and extreme heat;increase the quality of smoke and extreme heat monitoring and prediction tools and techniques; anddevelop implementation and communication strategies.The EPA must also establish a competitive grant program to assist certain entities (e.g., a state) in developing and implementing collaborative community plans for mitigating the impacts of smoke emissions from wildland fires and extreme heat.</summary>
</bill>
