<bill session="116" type="h" number="5667" updated="2022-02-09T01:42:35Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance stakeholder outreach to and operational engagement with owners and operators of critical infrastructure and other relevant stakeholders by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency to bolster security against acts of terrorism and other homeland security threats, including by maintaining a clearinghouse of security guidance, best practices, and other voluntary content developed by the Agency or aggregated from trusted sources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2020-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5780" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-06T16:36:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Communities Act

This bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to increase outreach and engagement with owners and operators of critical infrastructure.

Specifically, the bill directs CISA to maintain a clearinghouse where owners and operators of critical infrastructure and other stakeholders may access security guidance, best practices, and other voluntary content developed by CISA. CISA must also issue a strategy to foster stakeholder outreach and operational engagement and establish a pilot program whereby law enforcement agencies and government officials may be trained by protective security advisors on carrying out vulnerability and risk assessments of facilities.</summary>
</bill>
