<bill session="118" type="h" number="1295" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Early Voting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Early Voting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to allow individuals to vote in an election for Federal office during an early voting period which occurs prior to the date of the election, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2023-08-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="11" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2344" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-13T17:15:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Early Voting Act

This bill expands early in-person voting.

The bill generally requires each state to allow individuals to vote in federal elections during an early voting period of at least 15 days. This requirement does not apply to jurisdictions that send a mail-in ballot to every registered voter.

Further, states and jurisdictions must ensure that polling places are accessible by public transportation, located in rural areas, and located on each branch campus of an institution of higher education.

The Election Assistance Commission must issue certain voluntary standards for early voting, including the nondiscriminatory geographic placement of polling places.

Finally, states and jurisdictions must begin processing and scanning ballots cast during the early voting period at least 14 days prior to election day. However, states and jurisdictions cannot tabulate ballots before the polls close on election day unless the tabulation is necessary and performed in accordance with existing state law.</summary>
</bill>
