<bill session="118" type="s" number="3733" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a national, evidence-based education campaign to increase public and health care provider awareness regarding the potential risks and benefits of human cell and tissue products transplants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2024-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2024-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7188" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-11T20:26:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to educate the public and health care providers about the benefits and risks of transplants that use human cell or tissue products, including the risk of infections.

HHS must develop the educational campaign after taking into consideration information about products that carry the highest risk of transmitting infections to transplant recipients. HHS may award grants to other entities to conduct public awareness initiatives and media campaigns about the risk of infections.&#160;

The bill also establishes specific civil penalties for violations of laws regarding the spread of communicable diseases and regulations regarding procedures for human cell or tissue products.</summary>
</bill>
