<bill session="108" type="h" number="254" updated="2023-01-15T21:49:01Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To authorize the President of the United States to agree to certain amendments to the Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the United Mexican States concerning the establishment of a Border Environment Cooperation Commission and a North American Development Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the President of the United States to agree to certain amendments to the Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the United Mexican States concerning the establishment of a Border Environment Cooperation Commission and a North American Development Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000617" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000306" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000107" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000164" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000170" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000568" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2003-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 108-17.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-02-25" calendar="Union" number="11">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 11.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26T13:42:07-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Biggert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26T13:42:25-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1343-1351" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26T13:42:27-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 254.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2003-02-26T14:27:57-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1343-1344" label="text of measure as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26T14:27:59-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2755-2756" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-03-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T11:37:57-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bereuter moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1388-1393" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T11:38:25-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 254.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T12:04:48-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="87" datetime="2004-03-25T11:41:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 377 - 48 (Roll no. 87).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1494-1495" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 3/24/2004 H1388-1389" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25T11:46:40-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-04-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-215" type="public" datetime="2004-04-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-215.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="449" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2856"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced to the House on January 8, 2003. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)(Sec. 1) Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act to authorize the President to agree to amendments to the Border Environment Cooperation Agreement (the November 1993 Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the United Mexican States Concerning the Establishment of a Border Environment Cooperation Commission and a North American Development Bank) that: (1) enable the North American Development Bank to make grants and non-market rate loans out of its paid-in capital resources with the approval of its Board of Directors for qualified water conservation projects; and (2) amend the definition of "border region" as it relates to such projects to include specified areas in the United States and Mexico that are within 300 kilometers of the international boundary between the two countries.(Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report annually to certain congressional committees on the North American Development Bank, addressing specified issues.(Sec. 3) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) water conservation projects are eligible for funding from the Bank under the Cooperation Agreement; and (2) the Board of Directors of the Bank should support qualified water conservation projects which can assist Texas irrigators and agricultural producers in the lower Rio Grande River Valley.(Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress that the Bank should support: (1) the development of qualified water conservation projects in southern California and other eligible areas in the four U.S. border States (California, Arizona, New Mexico, and Texas), including the conjunctive use and storage of surface and ground water, delivery system conservation, the re-regulation of reservoirs, improved irrigation practices, wastewater reclamation, regional water management modeling, operational and optimization studies to improve water conservation, and cross-border water exchanges consistent with treaties; and (2) new water supply research and projects along the Mexico border in southern California and other eligible areas in the four U.S. border States to desalinate ocean seawater and brackish surface and groundwater, and dispose of or manage the brines resulting from desalination.(Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Bank Board should: (1) take into consideration the needs of all of the border states before approving funding for water conservation projects; and (2) strive to fund such projects in each of such states.(Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Bank Board should support the financing of projects, on both sides of the international boundary between the United States and Mexico, which address: (1) coastal issues and the problem of pollution in both countries having an environmental impact along their Pacific Ocean and Gulf of Mexico shores; and (2) air pollution.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-17</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
