<bill session="116" type="s" number="3561" updated="2022-02-08T23:23:06Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Telework Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Telework Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal agencies to permit employees to telework full-time during the public health emergency relating to COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2020-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-13T14:48:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency Telework Act of 2020

This bill requires each federal agency (executive, legislative, and judicial) to allow eligible employees to telework full-time during the public health emergency declared on January 31, 2020, relating to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019). An employee is considered eligible if the employee has not received specified disciplinary action and is otherwise determined eligible by the agency.

In the event the public health emergency is renewed, the bill's requirements continue to apply if the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), in coordination with the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), determines the requirements would reduce the spread of COVID-19. If the requirements no longer apply, agencies may still allow high-risk employees or employees at certain work sites to telework full-time during the renewal period.

Additionally, OPM must, in coordination with HHS, develop an expansive telework policy for use in future outbreaks of infectious diseases.</summary>
</bill>
