<bill session="119" type="h" number="3665" updated="2025-11-11T09:05:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Economic Security Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Economic Security Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to limit the penalty for late enrollment under part B of the Medicare Program to 15 percent and twice the period of no enrollment, and to exclude periods of COBRA, retiree, and VA coverage from such late enrollment penalty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000788"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2025-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2025-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000399" joined="2025-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2025-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2025-08-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T15:39:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Economic Security Solutions Act

This bill modifies provisions relating to enrollment periods for Medicare medical services.

Among other things, the bill establishes a late enrollment penalty of 15% of monthly premiums and applies the penalty for a period equal to twice the number of months in each 12-month period during which the individual was not enrolled. Currently, the late enrollment penalty is 10% of monthly premiums for each 12-month period during which the individual was not enrolled, and the penalty continues to apply for as long as the individual is enrolled in Medicare medical services.

The bill also expands the special enrollment periods to individuals who have health insurance coverage other than through their employer.</summary>
</bill>
