<bill session="109" type="s" number="1638" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:03Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Health Workforce Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of programs and activities to assist in mobilizing an appropriate healthcare workforce in the event of a health emergency or natural disaster.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Health Workforce Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000167"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2005-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9844-9845"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-08T15:53:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hurricane Katrina Emergency Health Workforce Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the National Emergency Health Professionals Volunteer Corps to provide for an adequate supply of health professionals in the event of an emergency.

Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to establish a national database of health professionals to increase health preparedness for federal emergencies.

Includes service by physicians and other health professionals who are providing treatment or services related to a declared major disaster as "service in the uniformed services" for purposes of employment and reemployment benefits.

Amends the Public Health Service Act and title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require hospitals that receive federal payments for graduate medical education costs to provide disaster preparedness training as part of any approved graduate medical residency training program provided by the hospital.

Deems volunteer health professionals providing a qualifying health service related to a declared major disaster to be employees of the Public Health Service for purposes of liability protection.

Authorizes the Secretary to suspend state health professional licensing and certification requirements for health professionals that are operating in such state during a declared major disaster.

Authorizes the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive any federal requirements applicable to health professions that would limit the ability of health professionals to provide volunteer medical services related to a declared major disaster.</summary>
</bill>
