<bill session="118" type="h" number="1743" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">People Over Petroleum Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">People Over Petroleum Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal fossil fuel subsidies for oil companies, to establish gas price rebates to individuals for 2022, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001117"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2023-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1483" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-22T14:35:16Z" status="Introduced in House">People Over Petroleum Act

This bill limits or repeals certain fossil fuel oil and gas subsidies for oil companies and establishes a gas prices rebate for individual taxpayers.

Among other elements, the bill

 repeals the tax credits for producing oil and gas from marginal wells and for enhanced oil recovery; repeals various tax deductions, including the deduction for the intangible drilling and development costs of oil and gas wells; repeals the passive loss exception for working interests in oil and gas property; denies the tax deduction for income attributable to domestic production activities for oil and gas activities; prohibits the use of the last-in, first-out (LIFO) accounting method by major integrated oil companies; limits the foreign tax credit for dual capacity taxpayers (i.e., taxpayers who are subject to a levy of a foreign country or U.S. possession and receive specific economic benefits from such country or possession); and expands the definition of crude oil for purposes of the excise tax on petroleum and petroleum products to include any oil derived from a bitumen or bituminous mixture (tar sands), and any oil derived from kerogen-bearing sources (oil shale). The bill also allows individual taxpayers a 2022 gas prices rebate for the first taxable year beginning in 2022. The bill defines 2022 gas prices rebate amount as the sum of $500 ($1,000 for joint returns), plus $500 times the number of taxpayer dependents who had attained the age of 16 as of the end of the taxable year.</summary>
</bill>
