<bill session="110" type="s" number="1486" updated="2023-01-11T16:47:39Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural America Preservation Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to restore integrity to and strengthen payment limitation rules for commodity payments and benefits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural America Preservation Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2007-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-06-26T17:04:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural America Preservation Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to reduce maximum annual direct and counter-cyclical commodity payments to $20,000 and $30,000, respectively. Revises limitation provisions for marketing loan gains, loan deficiency payments, and commodity certificate transactions, and establishes an annual combined limitation of $75,000 for such payments. Doubles payment limitations for single farming operations. Limits an individual to a combined annual payment of $250,000.

Makes a person who commits fraud in connection with a scheme or device to evade certain program limitations (multiple entities, citizenship) ineligible for farm benefits for six years.

Revises provisions respecting limitation of benefits to active farmers.

Makes foreign entities ineligible for agricultural program benefits.

Expresses the sense of the Senate that any savings achieved by this Act should be used to establish a permanent agricultural disaster relief program.</summary>
</bill>
