<bill session="117" type="s" number="1638" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness for Immigrant Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect immigrant families, combat fraud, promote citizenship, and build community trust, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Immigrant Families Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-08T21:18:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness for Immigrant Families Act

This bill modifies provisions barring certain aliens from admission and addresses other immigration-related issues.

The bill repeals various admissions bars against aliens who were unlawfully present in the United States for certain amounts of time.

The bill also modifies a provision that generally makes inadmissible aliens who had been ordered removed and who attempt to reenter the United States without being admitted. Specifically, the bill exempts from that provision minors, asylum seekers, aliens who received a stay of removal under a family unity program, victims of severe trafficking, and certain aliens who entered the United States as children.

An alien who entered the United States without inspection may apply for lawful permanent residence during the five-year period starting from this bill's enactment if the alien is the beneficiary of a family-based petition or labor certification.

The bill also prohibits removing an alien with certain pending immigration-related applications, such as an application for a family-based immigrant visa, if the application is not obviously deficient.

Before removing a parent or legal guardian of an individual who is less than 21 years old and a U.S. citizen or permanent resident, the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement must review and approve the removal.

Furthermore, the bill makes it a crime to fraudulently provide immigration services. The Department of Justice must make grants to support enforcement of such laws and to assist victims.

The bill establishes the National Office of New Americans to support the integration of immigrants and refugees.</summary>
</bill>
