<bill session="115" type="h" number="5971" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:25Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To include nonprofit and volunteer ground and air ambulance crew members and first responders for certain benefits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000017"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T22:09:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act

This bill amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to modify the requirements for a member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew to qualify as a public safety officer for purposes of death benefits under the Public Safety Officers' Benefits program.

Specifically, it removes the requirement that an individual member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew be part of a public agency or nonprofit entity that actually engages in rescue activity or provides emergency medical services to qualify as public safety officers. Instead, the bill requires an individual member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew be part of a public agency or nonprofit entity that is officially designated as a pre-hospital emergency medical response agency.

The bill permanently rescinds specified unobligated amounts in the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund.</summary>
</bill>
