<bill session="118" type="h" number="4145" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding American Education From Foreign Control Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding American Education From Foreign Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional disclosures relating to gifts and contracts from foreign sources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000375" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2023-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000828" joined="2023-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2856" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-29T13:48:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding American Education From Foreign Control Act

This bill establishes a special disclosure rule requiring institutions of higher education (IHEs) to disclose any gift from or contract with a foreign source that is associated with a covered nation (i.e., North Korea, China, Russia, or Iran).

Under current law, an IHE must disclose to the Department of Education (ED) a gift from or contract with a foreign source that is valued at $250,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that foreign source. This bill establishes a special disclosure rule relating to foreign sources associated with covered nations. Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to disclose any gift from or contract with a foreign source that is associated with a covered nation, regardless of the amount of the gift or contract.

The bill also directs ED to transmit disclosure reports and related records to the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</summary>
</bill>
