<bill session="116" type="s" number="3410" updated="2022-02-09T01:10:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AIM-HIGH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Instructional Materials in Higher Education Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIM-HIGH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve access to postsecondary instructional materials for students with print disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2020-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-27T18:07:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Access to Instructional Materials in Higher Education Act of 2020 or the AIM-HIGH Act

This bill revises model demonstration programs requiring the Department of Education (ED) to award certain grants or contracts to eligible partnerships to develop systems for the timely delivery and quality of instructional materials to postsecondary students with print disabilities.

Specifically, the bill (1) revises the definition of student with a print disability, and (2) requires such instructional materials to be commercially produced or open source and in accessible formats.

Additionally, the bill requires eligible partnerships to include (1) one or more institutions of higher education with demonstrated expertise in meeting the needs of students with print disabilities, and (2) a public or private entity with demonstrated expertise in developing such materials in accessible formats. Such public or private entity must also have a demonstrated capability to partner with national consumer organizations with the capacity to engage postsecondary students with print disabilities in the development and implementation of such materials.

 It also authorizes ED to complete a national expansion of such model programs.</summary>
</bill>
