<bill session="116" type="s" number="3358" updated="2022-03-08T04:47:30Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Part-Time Worker Bill of Rights Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Part-Time Worker Bill of Rights Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend protections to part-time workers in the areas of family and medical leave and pension plans, and to ensure equitable treatment in the workplace.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2020-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5991" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-07T20:38:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Part-Time Worker Bill of Rights Act of 2020 This bill modifies various employment, leave, and pension rules with respect to part-time workers. Specifically, the bill removes the requirement that employees work a minimum number of hours during the preceding 12-month period before becoming eligible for family and medical leave. The bill also sets the maximum length of service on which employers may condition the eligibility of part-time employees for a qualified pension plan (e.g., 401(k) retirement plan). Except as required by an applicable collective bargaining agreement, such service requirement may be no longer than two consecutive 12-month periods of at least 500 hours of service for part-time employees who have reached the age of 21 by the end of such period. The bill further prohibits employers from setting disparate terms of employment or working conditions for part-time employees, including with respect to compensation, notice of work hours, and promotion opportunities, among others. Additionally, the bill requires large employers to offer available, qualified part-time employees additional work hours before hiring new employees for such hours. Among other enforcement methods, employers must maintain three years of certain records related to the requirements of this bill. The bill also provides a private right of action for employees to enforce the nondiscrimination requirements of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
