<bill session="116" type="s" number="2967" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restore the Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Restore the Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore the Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Commission on Intergovernmental Relations of the United States to facilitate the fullest cooperation, coordination, and mutual accountability among all levels of government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-314.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="617">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 617.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3883" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-07T19:50:39Z" status="Reported to Senate">Restore the Partnership Act

This bill establishes in the executive branch the Commission on Intergovernmental Relations of the United States.

The commission shall, among other things, provide a forum for discussing ways to improve the administration and coordination of federal grant-in-aid, regulatory, tax, and other programs requiring intergovernmental cooperation, and identify the intergovernmental impacts of rulings by the U.S. Supreme Court on federal, state, tribal, and local governments.

The commission shall (1) report to Congress, one year after its initial meeting and annually thereafter, detailing the programs, initiatives, departments, offices, and any other efforts carried out under the authority of a state, local, or tribal government for which at least 50% of the funding is derived from federal sources; and (2) terminate eight years after this bill's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-314</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
