<bill session="109" type="h" number="1055" updated="2022-02-03T05:26:17Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Methamphetamine Response Act</title>
    <title type="display">Comprehensive Methamphetamine Response Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the designation and funding of high intensity methamphetamine abuse and trafficking areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000762"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2005-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000119" joined="2005-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug addiction"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-22T15:44:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Comprehensive Methamphetamine Response Act - Authorizes the Director of National Drug Control Policy to designate a State, or any portion of a State, as a high intensity methamphetamine abuse and trafficking area (HIMATA) and provide funding for such areas after: (1) receiving a Governor's petition for such designation; and (2) making a determination for the area on the basis of the methamphetamine epidemic severity index developed under this Act. Requires the Director to give priority consideration to areas that are already so designated if methamphetamine is a primary reason for that designation.

Requires the Director to develop a methamphetamine epidemic severity index to be used in making HIMATA determinations based on specified factors, including per capita rates of methamphetamine possession or production, lab seizures, and addiction in an area.

Authorizes the Director to provide funding to a State to implement a HIMATA after receipt of a comprehensive methamphetamine response plan (CMRP). Requires the Director to determine funding levels based on the population and the severity index of the area, with an exception.

Requires the Director to require the State in which the HIMATA is located to develop a CMRP that: (1) describes the manner in which the State plans to use funding provided to address any existing inadequacies in enforcement, treatment, prevention, and precursor controls; and (2) in the case of a HIMATA that overlaps with a high intensity drug trafficking area, addresses how the two programs will coordinate.</summary>
</bill>
