<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6628</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:32:34Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:32:34Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-12-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. POE of Texas:H.R. 6628.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8 Clause 1, which reads: The Congressshall have Power To lay and collect Taxes, Duties, Impostsand Excises, to pay the Debts and provide for the commonDefence and general Welfare of the United States; but allDuties, Imposts and Excise shall be uniform throughout theUnited States;Article 1, Section 8, Clause 18, which reads: The Congressshall have Power To make all Laws which shall be necessaryand proper for carrying into Execution the foregoing Powers,and all other Powers vested by the Constitution in theGovernment of the United States, or in any Department orOfficer thereof.[Page H6623]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
            <name>Crime and Federal Government Surveillance Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2012-12-07T18:35:32Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-12-04T15:01:25Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>SAFER Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1523</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-07-11</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>2338</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-04-24</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Ordered Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 364.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To amend the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to provide for Debbie Smith grants for auditing sexual assault evidence backlogs, and for other purposes.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3250</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-01-02</actionDate>
          <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendments to Senate bill.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-12-07</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju08</systemCode>
            <name>Crime and Federal Government Surveillance Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-12-04</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-12-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-12-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000592</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Poe, Ted [R-TX-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ted</firstName>
        <lastName>Poe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000087</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Maloney, Carolyn B. [D-NY-14]</fullName>
        <firstName>CAROLYN</firstName>
        <lastName>MALONEY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>B.</middleName>
        <district>14</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2012-12-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001149</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Michaud, Michael H. [D-ME-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Michaud</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <district>2</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2012-12-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001059</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Costa, Jim [D-CA-20]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Costa</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>20</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2012-12-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000375</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Keating, William R. [D-MA-10]</fullName>
        <firstName>William</firstName>
        <lastName>Keating</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <district>10</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2012-12-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Crime victims</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crimes against women</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Genetics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sex offenses</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-12-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-02-07T20:07:18Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry Act of 2012 or the SAFER Act of 2012 - Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to authorize the Attorney General to make Debbie Smith grants under such Act to states or local governments to conduct audits of samples of sexual assault evidence that are awaiting testing, provided such government submits an audit plan that includes a good-faith estimate of the number of such samples. Requires between 5% and 10% of Debbie Smith grant funds distributed in FY2014-FY2018 to be awarded for such purpose if sufficient applications to justify such amounts are received by the Attorney General, provided such award doesn't decrease funds for other distribution requirements. </p> <p>Requires the Attorney General to establish a Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry that: (1) allows state and local governments to enter specified information about samples of sexual assault evidence in their possession that are awaiting testing, and (2) tracks the testing and processing of such samples. Requires such a government: (1) to complete a funded audit and enter such information about the sample into the Registry within one year after receiving a grant under this Act; (2) within 21 days after receiving a sample that was not in such government's possession at the time of the initiation of such audit, to enter information about such sample into the Registry; (3) to update the status of a sample within 30 days after any change; (4) to provide that the chief law enforcement officer of such government is the individual responsible for such government's compliance with registry requirements; and (5) to assign each sample a unique numeric or alphanumeric identifier. Exempts from such Registry-requirements samples that are not considered criminal evidence or that relate to a sexual assault for which the prosecution of each perpetrator is barred by a statute of limitations. </p> <p>Requires the Attorney General to make publicly available on a website aggregate non-individualized and non-personally identifying data compiled from information required to be entered into the Registry, to allow for comparison of backlog data by state and local governments. </p> <p>Requires, for each fiscal year through FY2018, not less than: (1) 40% of Debbie Smith grant amounts to be awarded to carry out DNA analyses of samples from crime scenes for inclusion in the Combined DNA Index System, and (2) 75% of grant amounts to be awarded for a combination of that purpose and to increase the capacity of state or local government laboratories to carry out DNA analyses.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>SAFER Act of 2012</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>SAFER Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>SAFER Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to provide for Debbie Smith grants for auditing sexual assault evidence backlogs and to establish a Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2012-12-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr6628ih/xml/BILLS-112hr6628ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-12-07</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
