<bill session="112" type="h" number="4087" updated="2019-11-15T21:15:50Z">
  <state datetime="2012-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prescription Drug Labeling Promotion Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Prescription Drug Labeling Promotion Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development and dissemination of best practices to ensure that visually-impaired and blind individuals in the United States have safe, consistent, reliable, and independent access to the information in prescription drug labeling.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2012-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2012-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2012-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2012-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2516" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3187" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-06-21T14:31:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Prescription Drug Labeling Promotion Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a working group to develop best practices on access to prescription drug labeling for the visually impaired.

Requires the working group to: (1) include equal representation of consumer and industry advocates; (2) promulgate guidance on best practices for pharmacies to ensure that blind and visually impaired individuals have safe, consistent, reliable, and independent access to the information in the labeling of prescription drugs; (3) consider the use of Braille, specified auditory means, and enhanced visual means to provide such access; and (4) consider whether there are technical, financial, manpower, or other factors that may fundamentally impact the ability of pharmacies with 20 or fewer retail locations to implement the best practices.

Directs the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (FDA) to conduct an informational and educational program to inform the public and pharmacists about such guidance and practices.

Directs the Comptroller General: (1) 18 months after such guidance and practices are published, to review pharmacy compliance and the extent to which access barriers continue; and (2) by September 30, 2016, to report on such review, including recommendations for reducing such barriers.</summary>
</bill>
