<bill session="117" type="h" number="8140" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enable high research activity status historically Black colleges or universities to increase capacity toward achieving very high research activity status, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2022-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2022-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001159" joined="2022-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2022-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2022-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4018" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-01T18:18:07Z" status="Introduced in House">HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish a pilot program to increase capacity for historically Black colleges and universities (HBCUs) that are designated as high research activity status to achieve and maintain very high research activity status. High research activity status (known as R2 status) and very high research activity status (known as R1 status) are classifications by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education.

DOD must award grants to support research activities in the areas of science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) and critical technologies. DOD may expand the program to other HBCUs beyond those that are classified as high research activity status if DOD determines that the program can support such an expansion.

DOD must annually establish a list of research areas for STEM and critical technologies for which grant applicants may seek funding.</summary>
</bill>
