<bill session="119" type="h" number="402" updated="2025-03-06T16:49:19Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEBT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEBT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debt Explanation Before Taxwriters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to require the Secretary of the Treasury to appear before Congress before the debt limit is reached or extraordinary measures are taken to prevent default.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    <term name="Senate Committee on Finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-27T14:43:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Debt Explanation Before Taxwriters Act or the DEBT Act

This bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to appear before the House Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee before the federal debt limit is reached or extraordinary measures are taken to prevent the United States from defaulting on its obligations.

The term extraordinary measures generally refers to a series of actions that the Department of the Treasury may implement to allow the United States to borrow additional funds without exceeding the debt limit. The measures generally include suspensions or delays of debt sales and suspensions or redemptions of investments in certain government funds.

The bill requires the Secretary of the Treasury to appear before the committees to provide a detailed explanation of (1) the extraordinary measures that Treasury will take and the administrative costs of taking the measures, and (2) any reversal of such measures and any other changes in the funding of federal government obligations.</summary>
</bill>
