<bill session="118" type="h" number="4058" updated="2025-11-18T18:56:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy SNAP Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy SNAP Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require the Secretary to designate food and food products to be made available under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000597" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1485" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-23T16:51:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy SNAP Act of 2023

This bill amends the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) to redefine the foods eligible for purchase with SNAP benefits.

SNAP benefits may not be used for soft drinks, candy, ice cream, or prepared desserts, such as cakes, pies, cookies, or similar products.

Further, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must designate by regulation foods and food products to include in the SNAP definition of the term food. USDA must consider food and products that (1) based on nutrition research, contain nutrients lacking in the diets of people in the United States; and (2) promote the health of the population served by SNAP, based on relevant nutrition science, public health concerns, and cultural eating patterns. USDA must also, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that the fat, sugar, and salt content of the food and food products are appropriate. At least every five years, USDA must review and amend the list.

Prepared meals purchased with SNAP benefits must have nutritional values consistent with standards developed by USDA for the list of food and food products.&#160;

A state agency may substitute different foods for food USDA designated under this bill, with USDA approval, so long as the foods are nutritionally equivalent; this is permitted to allow for different cultural eating patterns.</summary>
</bill>
