<bill session="118" type="s" number="5292" updated="2025-08-28T16:33:34Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-25">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022 to modify a provision relating to the acquisition of a Coast Guard icebreaker.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Don Young Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2022 to modify a provision relating to the acquisition of a Coast Guard icebreaker.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2024-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-09-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6467" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6467" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-27T10:02:44-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-27T10:04:20-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-28T16:33:19Z" status="Passed Senate">This bill allows the Coast Guard to pursue the acquisition of an icebreaker without having to meet certain early-stage acquisition steps typically required for Coast Guard major acquisition programs.

The bill exempts acquisition or procurement projects from meeting specific requirements to produce information until the first phase of the initial acquisition or procurement is complete and initial operating capacity is achieved. Specifically, the project is exempt from requirements that the Coast Guard

clearly define the operational requirements for the project or program;develop an acquisition project or program baseline; andsubmit to Congress materials on the project, including an acquisition program baseline showing costs and schedule information.If the Coast Guard provides a briefing to Congress within 30 days of the bill's enactment that includes a detailed cost estimate for an icebreaker, then the project is also exempt from additional requirements until the first phase of the initial acquisition or procurement is complete and initial operating capacity is achieved. Specifically, the project is exempt from requirements that the Coast Guard produce documents that include (1)&#160;an approved test and evaluation master plan, and (2) a life cycle cost estimate.</summary>
</bill>
