<bill session="117" type="h" number="9580" updated="2023-01-19T19:33:38Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RISE from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resilience Investment, Support, and Expansion from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RISE from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the identification and support of children and families who experience trauma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2086" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-19T19:26:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Resilience Investment, Support, and Expansion from Trauma Act or the RISE from Trauma Act

This bill establishes and extends various programs to support infants, children, youth, and families who have experienced, or may experience, trauma.

Specifically, the bill allows federal agencies to use specified discretionary funds to implement pilot projects to improve outcomes for children experiencing trauma.

It also requires the Department of Health and Human Services to provide tool kits and other guidance to train frontline service providers and certain community members about trauma, toxic stress, and resilience. In addition, the Department of Justice (DOJ) must establish a national center to disseminate to law enforcement agencies best practices and other assistance to enhance interactions with infants, children, youth, and families who are exposed to violence and trauma.

Furthermore, the bill establishes grants for

 multi-sector demonstration projects to prevent and mitigate trauma and toxic stress; interventions to improve outcomes for hospital patients who experience drug overdoses, suicide attempts, or violent injury; and clinical training in infant and early childhood mental health. The bill also authorizes DOJ grants to reduce violence and substance use by preventing children's trauma from exposure to violence and substance use. Additionally, it incorporates trauma-informed practices and otherwise addresses trauma in programs for health care professional education, increasing access to health services, and training for educators.</summary>
</bill>
