<bill session="117" type="s" number="1673" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">30 &#195;&#8212; 30 Termination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve access to Federal land, control fires, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">30 &#195;&#8212; 30 Termination Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2022-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3014" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-13T23:35:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">30 x 30 Termination Act

This bill prohibits federal acquisition of land or declaration of a national monument in certain areas and nullifies a provision of an executive order related to conservation.

In a state or county where 15% or more of the land is managed by a federal agency (1) federal funds may not be used to acquire nonfederal land unless the agency proposing the acquisition disposes of an equal amount of federal land within the state or county, and (2) a declaration of a national monument shall not apply.

The bill prohibits from having the force and effect of law a provision of Executive Order 14008 (86 Fed. Reg. 7619), titled Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad, that requires the Department of the Interior to recommend steps to achieve the goal of conserving at least 30% of U.S. lands and waters by 2030. No federal funds may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out any report or program substantially similar to the report or program of such provision.

No federal funds may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out any action on federal land that results in a net-loss of multiple use or any principal or major use, unless such action has been authorized by an act of Congress.

No federal funds may be used by a federal agency to acquire more than 160 acres of nonfederal land unless

 the federal agency has received written notice from the state in which the nonfederal land is located that the state has enacted legislation approving the proposed acquisition, and the proposed acquisition has been authorized by an act of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
