<bill session="117" type="h" number="4240" updated="2022-12-31T04:58:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit digital platforms from using information about a user unless the user consents to such use, to ensure personal information is considered a property right, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">User Data Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">User Data Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-24T14:27:04Z" status="Introduced in House">User Data Protection Act

This bill establishes requirements for websites and other digital platforms that collect and store information about their users, including information saved to a web browser to track a user over time (i.e., cookies).

Specifically, a website may not (1) use cookies or otherwise collect information about a user without the user's consent, (2) restrict access to the website if a user declines such consent, (3) use pixel-sized images that are hidden or embedded in a web page that collect data about a user (i.e., tracking pixels), or (4) share a user's information with other websites or online businesses.

Further, if a user consents to the collection of information, the website must (1) disclose to the user what the information will be used for, and (2) treat any such information as an exclusive property right owned by the user.

The bill provides for enforcement of these provisions by the Federal Trade Commission, state attorneys general, and private right of action.</summary>
</bill>
