<bill session="116" type="h" number="7510" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AHEAD Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a study by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine on the potential benefits on population health outcomes of incorporating into the Federal legislative process tools that measure the impacts of proposed legislation (including in areas outside of health care) on health and health disparities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AHEAD Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assimilating Health and Equity Assessments into Decision-making of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001124"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2020-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4919" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-14T15:59:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Assimilating Health and Equity Assessments into Decision-making of 2020 or AHEAD Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (National Academies) to study, and make certain recommendations concerning, the use of health impact assessments or other tools to evaluate the effect of proposed federal legislation on health and health disparities.

When developing recommendations to incorporate these tools into the federal legislative process, the National Academies must consult with the Government Accountability Office, the Congressional Budget Office, and the Congressional Research Service.</summary>
</bill>
