<bill session="116" type="h" number="7857" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connect America Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude gain from the sale or exchange of the entire interest in a wholly-owned rural incumbent local exchange carrier, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000465"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Revenue Measures.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM05" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Tax" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-08T16:43:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Connect America Now Act or the CAN Act

This bill allows an exclusion from gross income, for income tax purposes, of gain from the sale or exchange of the entire interest in a wholly-owned rural incumbent local exchange carrier. A rural incumbent local exchange carrier is a carrier that serves an area where it is required to provide communications services to any customer regardless of cost, and an area other than an urbanized area with not fewer than 50,000 periople, and a core where there are not fewer than 1,000 people per square mile. The bill requires recapture of tax for income from the sale or exchange of stock in a carrier not held for at least one year.

The bill allows an investment tax credit for 30% of expenditures to purchase, maintain, or improve property to provide voice telephone service or broadband internet access in rural empowerment zones.

The bill increases the volume cap for private activity bonds and allows the use of bond proceeds for infrastructure for broadband internet access service.</summary>
</bill>
