<bill session="109" type="s" number="3956" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:04Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Crime Victims with Disabilities Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a grant program for collaboration programs that ensure coordination among criminal justice agencies, adult protective service agencies, victim assistance programs, and other agencies or organizations providing services to individuals with disabilities in the investigation and response to abuse of or crimes committed against such individuals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crime Victims with Disabilities Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000294"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10303-10304"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-25T12:58:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Crime Victims with Disabilities Act of 2006 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General to make grants to states, local governments, Indian tribes, or tribal organizations to plan and implement programs for collaboration among criminal justice agencies, adult protective services agencies, crime victim assistance organizations, and/or other agencies or organizations that provide services to individuals with disabilities to investigate and remediate abuse of or crimes against such individuals and to provide services to such individuals. Authorizes the Attorney General to establish a national center to evaluate such programs.</summary>
</bill>
