<bill session="118" type="s" number="605" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Biking on Long-Distance Trails Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biking on Long-Distance Trails Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to develop long-distance bike trails on Federal recreational lands and waters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2023-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="873" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-03T22:47:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Biking on Long-Distance Trails Act

This bill establishes requirements related to long-distance bike trails.

The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall identify

 not fewer than 10 long-distance bike trails that make use of existing trails and roads, and not fewer than 10 areas in which there is an opportunity to develop or complete such trails. Interior and USDA shall

 coordinate with stakeholders on the feasibility of, and identifying any resources necessary for, completing the development of the trails so identified; before identifying a trail or road as a long-distance bike trail, ensure that identifying a trail or road as a long-distance bike trail would not conflict with an existing use of the trail or road; and seek geographically equitable identification, development, and completion of long-distance bike trails.</summary>
</bill>
