<bill session="116" type="h" number="5967" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Library Innovation Space Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Museum and Library Services Act to authorize grants to support the use of public libraries for community economic development.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Library Innovation Space Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2020-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-11T20:25:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Library Innovation Space Act

This bill requires the Institute of Museum and Library Services to carry out a program for making competitive grants to eligible partnerships (composed of a public library and an economic development corporation, a local government, a tribal government, a state government, an elementary or secondary school, a museum, an institution of higher education, a nonprofit organization, a corporation, and/or other entities) to establish makerspaces at public libraries.

A makerspace is a facility (which may be at a fixed location or a mobile unit) that is open to the public and provides individuals with access to (1) tools, technology, and educational resources designed to enable such individuals to create physical goods, including prototypes; and (2) educational opportunities, including vocational training and assistance with early-stage business ventures.

A partnership must contribute, for the activities for which the grant was awarded, nonfederal matching funds in an amount determined appropriate by the institute.

Each eligible partnership that receives a grant may not use its grant funds, or the matching funds contributed by it, for construction activities at a public library that would provide extra square footage to house a makerspace.</summary>
</bill>
