<bill session="116" type="s" number="4799" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHAME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sanctioning and Highlighting Authoritarian Medicine and Eugenics Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHAME Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the imposition of sanctions with respect to forced abortions by the Government of the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000594" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2020-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-16T22:11:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sanctioning and Highlighting Authoritarian Medicine and Eugenics Act of 2020 or the SHAME Act

This bill imposes sanctions on individuals and entities responsible for carrying out coercive policies to limit births in China's Xinjiang province.

Specifically, the Department of State shall annually report to Congress the identities of any Chinese government official or agency or any member of the Chinese Communist Party that knowingly orders, controls, or routinely carries out such coercive policies in Xinjiang, such as requiring involuntary abortions or mandatory contraception use. The State Department shall also publish a list of the named entities and individuals on its website in English and Mandarin Chinese.

The President shall impose property-blocking sanctions on the individuals and entities named in the report, as well as visa-blocking sanctions on the named individuals. An individual or entity that violates, attempts to violate, or conspires to violate the sanctions provided under this bill may be subject to civil and criminal penalties.</summary>
</bill>
