<bill session="119" type="h" number="1219" updated="2025-09-16T08:05:36Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oral Health Products Inclusion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oral Health Products Inclusion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to include over-the-counter oral healthcare products as qualified medical expenses which can be purchased with HSA and FSA funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000317" joined="2025-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2025-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-27T16:31:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Oral Health Products Inclusion Act

This bill allows individuals to use funds in a flexible spending arrangement (FSA), health reimbursement arrangement (HRA), health savings account (HSA), or Archer medical savings account (Archer MSA) to pay for toothbrushes (manual or electric), water flossers, and oral health products.

Under current law, reimbursements from an FSA or HRA and tax-free distributions from an HSA or Archer MSA may be used to pay for the qualified medical expenses. Reimbursements from an FSA or HRA for nonmedical expenses generally are not allowed and distributions from an HSA or Archer MSA for nonmedical expenses generally are taxed as income and may be subject to an additional penalty.

Under the bill, the definition of qualified medical expenses is expanded to include toothbrushes (manual or electric), water flossers, and oral health products.

The bill defines an oral health product as an over-the-counter product that is (1) used for preventing or treating dental cavities, plaque, or gingivitis;&#160;(2) suitable for topical administration to the teeth or gums; and (3) generally recognized as safe and effective.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
