<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="666" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4437" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-12-16T20:34:52-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001246"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  <description>At the end of title VII, insert the following: \   SEC. 709. REPORT ON EMPLOYMENT ELIGIBILITY VERIFICATION SYSTEM. \   Not later than one year after the implementation of the employment eligibility verification system and one year thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report on the progress and problems associated with implementation of the system, including information relating to the most efficient use of the system by small businesses.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 17 printed in House Report 109-350 to require the Department of Homeland Security to provide a report both one and two years after implementation of the Employment Eligibility Verification System to Congress. Reports would contain information relating to problems reported by businesses during implementation as well as progress made up to the report's date. Report would contain information relating to the most efficient use of the system by small businesses.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-12-16T20:34:52-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bradley (NH) amendment (A031) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T20:24:47-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A031) offered by Mr. Bradley (NH).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11979-11980" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11979" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T20:24:47-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A031) offered by Mr. Bradley (NH).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11979-11980" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11979" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T20:34:52-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T20:34:52-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Bradley (NH) amendment (A031) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
