<bill session="119" type="s" number="737" updated="2025-11-20T12:03:20Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SCREEN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SCREEN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shielding Children's Retinas from Egregious Exposure on the Net Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain interactive computer services to adopt and operate technology verification measures to ensure that users of the platform are not minors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1623" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-12T19:52:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shielding Children's Retinas from Egregious Exposure on the Net Act or the SCREEN ActThis bill establishes age-verification requirements for commercial interactive computer services (e.g., websites) that make available content that is harmful to minors (e.g., content that appeals to the prurient interest in nudity or sex, is obscene, or is child pornography).Specifically, the bill requires such services to adopt and utilize technology verification measures to ensure that (1) users of the service are not minors, and (2) minors are prevented from accessing any content on the service that is harmful to minors.Additionally, such services must (1) use the technology to verify a user's age; (2) publish the verification process that the service uses; and (3) subject users'&#160;Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, including known virtual proxy network (VPN) IP addresses, to the technology verification measures, unless the service determines a user is not located within the United States.Covered services also must implement data security measures to protect information about individuals collected through the verification process.The Federal Trade Commission must conduct regular audits of such services, issue guidance, and otherwise enforce the requirements of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
