<bill session="119" type="h" number="705" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a compensation fund for military firefighters exposed to PFAS.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a compensation fund for military firefighters exposed to PFAS.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2025-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-17T21:12:42Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish the Military Firefighters Compensation Fund to provide compensation to current and former military firefighters, or survivors of such firefighters, for illnesses incurred in the line of duty due to exposure to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly known as PFAS. PFAS are man-made and may have adverse human health effects.

Under the bill, current and former military firefighters are presumed to have been exposed to PFAS (in the absence of substantial evidence to the contrary) if the firefighter was employed at a military installation, facility of the National Guard, or formerly used defense site during a period when PFAS would have been present at such facility.

The bill provides that in cases where a military firefighter is deceased at the time of payment of compensation, the surviving spouse must receive the payment. If there is no surviving spouse, the bill provides for the order of distribution to other surviving parties (e.g., a child or parent of the firefighter). The bill also provides that a survivor of a firefighter may file a claim for compensation if the firefighter dies before filing a claim.

DOD must furnish the services, appliances, and supplies prescribed or recommended to a military firefighter who is receiving medical benefits for an illness related to PFAS exposure. Additionally, such firefighter&#160;may be furnished necessary and reasonable transportation and expenses incident to securing care for such illness.</summary>
</bill>
