<bill session="118" type="h" number="5643" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SNP Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNP Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Nutrition Paperwork Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to permit States to record in writing that applicants for supplemental nutrition assistance benefits have signed an application through a recorded verbal assent over the telephone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2885" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-26T19:16:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Streamlining Nutrition Paperwork Act of 2023 or the SNP Act of 2023

This bill allows state agencies to receive&#160;Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) applications by video phone or a simplified telephonic system.&#160;

Specifically, a state agency may establish a system to allow applicants who are deaf or hard of hearing (referred to as hearing-impaired under the bill) to sign a submitted SNAP application by gesture over a video phone. (Currently, a state agency may allow for a telephonic signature through a recorded verbal assent.)

The bill also specifies that, for a video phone or telephonic signature, the current recording system requirement may be satisfied through an audio recording or in writing. (During 2020 and 2021, the Food and Nutrition Service provided waivers to certain state agencies which allowed the state agency to document in writing that an applicant verbally signed the application, instead of requiring an audio recording.)</summary>
</bill>
