<bill session="118" type="h" number="6305" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Terminate CDC Overreach Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terminate CDC Overreach Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title III of the Public Health Service Act to impose a limitation on regulations relating to the control of communicable diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001132" joined="2023-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001096" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-06T20:52:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Terminate CDC Overreach Act

This bill narrows the authority of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to create regulations on controlling the spread of disease.&#160;

Under current law, the&#160;CDC is authorized to create regulations generally relating to quarantine and isolation to prevent the spread of disease between people. This includes regulations applicable to individuals traveling interstate that are reasonably believed to have a disease in a qualifying stage, meaning the disease is contagious or would likely cause a public health emergency if transmitted. The bill specifies that there must be&#160;a positive clinical test, rigorous contact tracing, or clinical presentation of the disease in order for individuals to be considered as having a disease in a qualifying stage for purposes of regulation. The bill also&#160;specifies that&#160;CDC&#160;regulations must relate to preventing the spread of disease between states through the identification, isolation, or destruction of the disease itself. The bill establishes procedures for Congress to expedite consideration of joint resolutions of disapproval for&#160;CDC regulations on this topic.&#160;

In addition, the bill prohibits the CDC from creating a new regulation or policy on controlling the spread of disease that is intended to influence the general public unless the CDC publishes with it evidence supporting the measure, including updated science briefs.</summary>
</bill>
