<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>425</number>
    <updateDate>2025-07-21T19:32:26Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2025-07-21T19:32:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2023-02-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>118</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2023-02-14T23:50:06Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-02-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-02-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000359</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Graham, Lindsey [R-SC]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lindsey</firstName>
        <lastName>Graham</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>SC</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000476</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tillis, Thomas [R-NC]</fullName>
        <firstName>Thomas</firstName>
        <lastName>Tillis</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName>Roland</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2023-02-16</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Immigration</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Immigration</name>
        <updateDate>2023-03-17T01:15:19Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2023-02-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2023-04-24T22:37:55Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Secure and Protect Act of 2023 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This bill makes changes to the handling of unaccompanied alien children and asylum applications. (&lt;i&gt;Aliens &lt;/i&gt;is the term in federal law used to describe non-U.S. nationals.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;Flores&lt;/i&gt; settlement (a court settlement imposing conditions on the treatment of detained alien minors) shall not restrict any activities. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall have sole discretion as to the conditions of detention for such minors. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Statutory provisions governing the handling of unaccompanied alien children from U.S.-bordering countries shall now govern all unaccompanied alien children. The bill provides for requirements relating to the handling of such children. Certain immigration officer determinations relating to unaccompanied alien children shall be unreviewable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;DHS may detain accompanied alien children while removal proceedings are pending (some courts have ruled that &lt;i&gt;Flores&lt;/i&gt; limits the detention of certain children to 20 days). States may not impose licensing requirements for family detention facilities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An unaccompanied alien child may not be released from custody while immigration or removal proceedings are pending, with some exceptions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The bill limits asylum eligibility to individuals entering the United States at a designated port of entry and provides for additional grounds for asylum ineligibility. A &lt;i&gt;credible fear of persecution&lt;/i&gt; is redefined to mean that it is more likely than not that the individual would be able to establish eligibility for asylum.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Department of State must establish refugee application and processing centers in Mexico and Central America. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The bill also requires the hiring of additional immigration judges, support staff, and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement attorneys.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Secure and Protect Act of 2023</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Secure and Protect Act of 2023</title>
        <updateDate>2024-07-24T15:23:44Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Secure and Protect Act of 2023</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:42:25Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to protect alien minors and to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to end abuse of the asylum system and establish refugee application and processing centers outside the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-03-07T03:43:44Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2023-02-14T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-118s425is/xml/BILLS-118s425is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2023-02-14</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
