<bill session="118" type="hj" number="78" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to set limits on Federal campaign contributions and spending, prohibit corporate spending in the political process, require Congress to develop a system of public campaign financing for all Federal candidates who qualify for the ballot, and allow the States to set reasonable limits on campaign contributions and spending in State and local elections, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to set limits on Federal campaign contributions and spending, prohibit corporate spending in the political process, require Congress to develop a system of public campaign financing for all Federal candidates who qualify for the ballot, and allow the States to set reasonable limits on campaign contributions and spending in State and local elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2023-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-18T17:31:29Z" status="Introduced in House">This joint resolution proposes a constitutional amendment regarding federal campaign contributions and spending.

Specifically, the amendment

 declares that the right of U.S. citizens to vote in elections in which campaign contributions and spending are subject to enforceable limits (as set forth in the amendment) shall not be abridged, sets forth limits on federal campaign contributions and spending, and prohibits corporations (or other entities created by law) from contributing or spending money for the purpose of influencing federal elections. Not later than 60 days after ratification of the amendment, Congress shall enact legislation to

 limit the amounts that candidates, their campaigns for federal office, and political parties may spend on such candidacies; provide public funding for all federal candidates who qualify for the ballot; require disposition to the Treasury of any unspent campaign funds after each election, without compensation; and enforce, with civil and criminal penalties, the limits and prohibitions of the amendment. States shall have the power to implement and enforce reasonable regulations on the raising and spending of money by candidates and others to influence state or local elections.</summary>
</bill>
