<bill session="109" type="h" number="3726" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:14Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Pornography Prevention Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance prosecution of child pornography and obscenity by strengthening section 2257 of title 18, United States Code, to ensure that children are not exploited in the production of pornography, prohibiting distribution of child pornography used as evidence in prosecutions, authorizing assets forfeiture in child pornography and obscenity cases, expanding administrative subpoena power to cover obscenity cases, and prohibiting the production of obscenity, as well as its transportation, distribution, and sale, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Pornography Prevention Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H849"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7823"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Copying processes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-25T19:10:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Child Pornography Prevention Act of 2005 - Amends federal criminal code provisions regarding the sexual exploitation of children to: (1) prohibit producers of visual depictions of sexually explicit conduct from refusing to permit the Attorney General to inspect records at business premises; and (2) modify the definition of "produces" to include actually filming, videotaping, photographing, or digitally manipulating an image of an actual human being that contains a visual depiction of sexually explicit conduct.

Requires, in any criminal proceeding: (1) any material that constitutes child pornography to remain in the care, custody, and control of either the government or the court; and (2) a court to deny any request by the defendant to reproduce material that constitutes child pornography, provided the government makes the material reasonably available to the defendant.

Makes specified provisions of the Controlled Substances Act applicable to the criminal forfeiture of obscene property. Authorizes criminal and civil asset forfeiture in specified child exploitation and obscenity cases, such as cases involving: (1) the use of interstate facilities to transmit information about a minor with intent to solicit sexual activity; and (2) the use of misleading domain names on the Internet with intent to deceive a person into viewing obscene material. Makes the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) Act applicable to activities relating to material involving the sexual exploitation of minors.

Authorizes administrative subpoenas for investigations of federal offenses involving the distribution of obscenity.

Prohibits the production of obscene matter.</summary>
</bill>
