<bill session="117" type="h" number="7629" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Satellite Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Satellite Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a report on Federal support to the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, establish a commercial satellite system cybersecurity clearinghouse in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000597" joined="2022-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3511" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1254" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-04T19:07:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Satellite Cybersecurity Act

This bill addresses cybersecurity matters related to commercial satellite systems.

Specifically, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) must maintain a publicly available clearinghouse of resources concerning the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems. CISA must also consolidate voluntary recommendations for the development, maintenance, and operation of such systems. The recommendations must include measures to protect systems against cyber-related vulnerabilities, risks, and attacks.

The bill also requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to study and report on federal actions to support the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, including with respect to critical infrastructure sectors. In carrying out its study and report, the GAO must coordinate with designated federal agencies.</summary>
</bill>
