<bill session="117" type="h" number="3970" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accelerating Rural Broadband Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Federal agencies to timely respond to right-of-way requests for the build out of broadband service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Rural Broadband Deployment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2021-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1113" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-23T14:46:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Accelerating Rural Broadband Deployment Act

This bill authorizes the granting of an occupancy license to any person who requests access to a right-of-way that is owned by the federal government in order to place, construct, modify, or operate facilities for the provision of broadband service.

Specifically, an executive agency with control over such a right-of-way may grant an occupancy license for the expansion of broadband service. An occupancy license may not have a duration of more than 30 years and may be automatically renewed. The granting agency must establish an annual license fee and make a decision regarding the issuance of the occupancy license within 60 days of receiving an application for a license. If the agency does not act on a request within 60 days, the application shall be considered granted.</summary>
</bill>
