<bill session="117" type="h" number="4293" updated="2022-12-30T15:47:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Young Entrepreneurs Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide loan deferment and loan cancellation for certain founders and employees of small business start-ups, to amend the Small Business Act to establish a young entrepreneurs business center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Young Entrepreneurs Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2021-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2021-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2021-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2021-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-06T20:14:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting America's Young Entrepreneurs Act of 2021

This bill provides deferment and cancellation of federal student loans for certain founders and employees of small business start-ups. The bill also establishes a young entrepreneurs business center.

First, the bill allows a founder of a small business start-up to defer student loan payments for up to three years.

Next, the bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to cancel up to $20,000 in federal student loan debt for a borrower who (1) has made 24 monthly payments on the loan while employed as a founder of a small business start-up in a distressed area, (2) is approved for loan cancellation by the young entrepreneurs business center established by the bill, and (3) is not currently in default on the loan.

Further, ED must cancel up to $3,000 in federal student loan debt for a borrower who (1) has made 12 monthly payments on the loan while employed full-time by a small business start-up, and (2) is not currently in default on the loan.

The bill also excludes from an individual's gross income, for income tax purposes, the amount of such canceled student loan debt.

Finally, the bill establishes a young entrepreneurs business center within the Small Business Administration to certify small business start-ups, identify distressed areas, and approve loan cancellations. To be certified by the center, a start-up must have a founder who is a recent graduate of an institution of higher education.</summary>
</bill>
