<bill session="117" type="s" number="2980" updated="2023-01-01T23:49:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the voluntary donation of grazing permits and leases in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Wildlife-Livestock Conflict Resolution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildlife-Livestock Conflict Resolution Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2021-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Failed to report favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-04T21:57:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wildlife-Livestock Conflict Resolution Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior, for public land, and the Department of Agriculture, for National Forest System land, to accept the donation of any valid existing leases or permits authorizing grazing on such lands in New Mexico beginning in FY2022.

For each permit or lease donated, the department concerned shall (1) terminate the grazing permit or lease; and (2) except as provided below, ensure a permanent end to grazing on the land covered by the permit or lease.

If the land covered by a permit or lease that is donated also is covered by another valid grazing permit or lease that is not donated, the department concerned shall not allow the total grazing use on the land to exceed the average actual grazing use under the other valid grazing permit or lease for the five-year period preceding the date of the donation.</summary>
</bill>
