<bill session="118" type="s" number="2167" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">INSPIRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INSPIRES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspiring New STEM Professionals by Investing in Renovation of Education Spaces Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable schools serving grades 6 through 12 that are located in rural areas or that serve Native American students to remodel or build new facilities to provide STEM classrooms and laboratories and support high-speed internet, to establish a program to support the modernization, renovation, or repair of career and technical education facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-17T15:54:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inspiring New STEM Professionals by Investing in Renovation of Education Spaces Act or the INSPIRES Act

This bill directs the Department of Education to establish grant programs (1) for the modernization, renovation, or repair of career- and technical-education facilities; and (2) to enable secondary schools that are located in rural areas or that serve Native American students to improve facilities that provide science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM)&#160;education and to&#160;support high-speed internet in STEM facilities.</summary>
</bill>
