<bill session="119" type="h" number="292" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GRAPE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GRAPE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grape Research And Protection Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation to carry out research and development regarding a policy to insure table, wine, and juice grapes against losses due to a freeze event, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-25T15:44:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Grape Research And Protection Expansion Act or the GRAPE Act

This bill requires the federal crop insurance program (FCIP) to provide for the research and development of a policy to insure table, wine, and juice grapes against losses due to a freeze event. (Under current law, the term policy means an insurance policy, plan of insurance, provision of a policy or plan of insurance, and related materials.) The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the agency that finances FCIP operations, must make any resulting policy available that meets specified FCIP requirements.

The FCIP must also submit a report to Congress on the research and any resulting policy.</summary>
</bill>
