<bill session="116" type="h" number="5796" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">E&#226;&#8364;&#8220;Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance consumer access to electric energy and natural gas information, to allow for the adoption of innovative products and services to help consumers manage their energy usage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Consumer Energy Information Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">E&#226;&#8364;&#8220;Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2020-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-17T20:44:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Access to Consumer Energy Information Act or the E-Access Act

This bill revises federal guidelines for state energy conservation plans.

The bill authorizes state energy conservation plans to include programs that (1) enhance consumer access to, and understanding of, electric energy and natural gas usage and cost information, including consumers' own residential and commercial retail electric energy and natural gas information; and (2) facilitate the development and adoption of innovative products and services to assist consumers in managing energy consumption and expenditures.

The Department of Energy (DOE) must issue guidelines that establish model data sharing standards and policies for states to provide electric and gas consumers with access to retail electric energy information and retail natural gas information. States may submit to DOE a description of their data sharing standards and policies for certification that they meet such guidelines.

DOE must periodically review and revise the guidelines to reflect changes in technology, privacy needs, and the market for electric energy and natural gas and related services.</summary>
</bill>
