<bill session="108" type="s" number="1456" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:49Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Positive Aging Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to mental health services for elderly individuals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Positive Aging Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000780"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9963-9964" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2241" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Community centers"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug utilization"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Life care communities"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-08-29T20:35:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Positive Aging Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services, to make grants for evidence-based demonstration projects to integrate mental health services for older patients into primary care settings. Requires the inclusion of collaborative care, screening services, referrals, and protocols for prevalent mental health disorders, such as depression, anxiety, dementia, and substance abuse.

Requires the Director to make grants to community-based providers of geriatric mental health services for multi-disciplinary health outreach teams. Authorizes cooperative agreements with senior centers, adult day care programs, assisted living facilities, and other places providing services to senior citizens under the Older Americans Act.Requires the Director to designate a Deputy Director for Geriatric Mental Health Services to develop and implement research programs, demonstration projects, models, and model training programs.Revises the membership of the Advisory Council for the Center for Mental Health Services to include representatives of older Americans, their families, and geriatric mental health specialists.Revises the criteria for State plans under Community Mental Health Services Block Grants to include goals and initiatives for improving access to services for older adult patients.</summary>
</bill>
