<bill session="117" type="s" number="3845" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Empowering the U.S. Fire Administration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering the U.S. Fire Administration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the United States Fire Administration to conduct on-site investigations of major fires, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2022-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2022-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7077" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5118" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-31T18:50:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Empowering the U.S. Fire Administration Act

This bill authorizes the U.S. Fire Administration (USFA) to conduct on-site investigations of major fires and other fires under other specified circumstances.

In the case of a major fire, the USFA may send incident investigators (e.g., safety specialists, fire protection engineers, codes and standards experts, researchers, and fire training specialists) to the site. Any such investigation shall (1) be conducted in coordination with appropriate federal, state, and local authorities; and (2) examine the determined cause and origin of the fire and assess broader systematic matters.

Upon concluding any such investigation, the USFA must issue a public report to local, state, and federal authorities on the findings of such investigation or collaborate with another investigating federal agency on that agency's report.

Additionally, the USFA may send fire investigators to conduct investigations at the site of any fire with unusual or remarkable context that results in losses less severe than those occurring as a result of a major fire.</summary>
</bill>
