<bill session="118" type="s" number="2034" updated="2025-01-14T19:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CONSULT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Obstructive National Security Underreporting of Legitimate Threats Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CONSULT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to develop procurement policy and guidance to mitigate consulting company conflict of interests related to national security and foreign policy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-07T19:26:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Obstructive National Security Underreporting of Legitimate Threats Act of 2023 or the CONSULT Act of 2023

This bill prohibits the Department of Defense (DOD) from contracting with consultancies who, for one year prior, entered into contracts with the government of China, the Chinese Communist Party, the Chinese People's Liberation Army, or other entities related to the Chinese or Russian governments.

Any individual or entity submitting an offer or bid for a contract for consulting services with DOD must disclose any contracts or grant awards from such Chinese or Russian entities during the past five years. If a contractor fails to disclose such contracts or awards, DOD must terminate the contract for cause and initiate a suspension and debarment proceeding on the contractor.</summary>
</bill>
