<bill session="111" type="h" number="1336" updated="2022-02-03T06:10:19Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Education Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the basic educational assistance program administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001037"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2009-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-05">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-23T19:32:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Education Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Montgomery GI Bill educational assistance program for veterans to: (1) authorize the use of such assistance for business courses and seminars, courses taken to prepare for licensing or certification tests, and the repayment of federal student loans; (2) allow for withdrawal of the election not to enroll in the program; (3) extend the increase in benefits for certain individuals pursuing apprenticeships or on-job training; (4) provide educational assistance benefits for veterans discharged under a general discharge; (5) increase the reporting fee payable to educational institutions that enroll veterans receiving assistance; (6) provide additional areas of work-study for veterans; (6) require a five-year pilot program for on-campus work-study positions; (7) modify the advance payment of initial educational assistance or subsistence allowance; and (8) authorize, for certain individuals, the accelerated payment of educational assistance.</summary>
</bill>
