<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1900</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T06:03:05Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T06:03:05Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Ms. JACKSON LEE of Texas:H.R. 1900.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18This bill in enacted pursuant to the power granted toCongress under Article 1, Section 8, Clause 18 of the UnitedStates Constitution.``The Congress shall have Power . . . to make all Law whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States or in andDepartment or Officer thereof.[Page H3302]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hshm07</systemCode>
            <name>Transportation and Maritime Security Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2011-06-02T17:36:00Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-13T13:03:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hshm07</systemCode>
            <name>Transportation and Maritime Security Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-13</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>J000032</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Jackson Lee, Sheila [D-TX-18]</fullName>
        <firstName>SHEILA</firstName>
        <lastName>JACKSON LEE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>18</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000193</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Thompson, Bennie G. [D-MS-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>BENNIE</firstName>
        <lastName>THOMPSON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MS</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-05-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000096</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Davis, Danny K. [D-IL-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANNY</firstName>
        <lastName>DAVIS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>K.</middleName>
        <district>7</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-05-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001067</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Clarke, Yvette D. [D-NY-11]</fullName>
        <firstName>Yvette</firstName>
        <lastName>Clarke</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>D.</middleName>
        <district>11</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-05-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Animal protection and human-animal relationships</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Firearms and explosives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor carriers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Performance measurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public transit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Railroads</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Roads and highways</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-09-02T14:46:47Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Surface Transportation and Mass Transit Security Act of 2011 - Amends the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 to replace the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) with the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for purposes of TSA's surface transportation security program.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish: (1) within the TSA a Surface Transportation Security Inspection Office, headed by a Director, to train, employ, and utilize surface transportation security inspectors to assist surface transportation carriers to enhance their security against terrorist attacks and other security threats; and (2) primary and secondary U.S. field offices for such inspectors.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to maintain at least 100 more surface transportation security inspectors than were employed at the end of FY2010. Requires the Director to provide training to each inspector.</p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary to submit to Congress a plan for expanding the duties and training of inspectors to enhance TSA's surface transportation security mission.</p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary to: (1) develop qualitative performance measures and objectives for assessing the effectiveness of Visible Intermodal Prevention and Response (VIPR) teams in providing transportation security, (2) establish risk-based criteria to evaluate all proposals for VIPR deployments in the United States, and (3) implement an interoperability of communications plan for VIPR team operations.</p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary to establish: (1) within the TSA a Surface Transportation Security Advisory Committee, and (2) within the Committee passenger carrier security and freight rail security security working groups.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to submit to Congress a human capital plan for TSA's hiring and training of surface transportation security personnel, including surface transportation security inspectors.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the status of DHS implementation of the 9/11 Commission's recommendations for development and issuance of transportation security training regulations.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that the DHS Transportation Security Grant Program should be restored from the FY2011 reductions to ensure that transit agencies in high-risk areas can protect their systems and passengers from terrorist attacks.</p> <p>Authorizes the Assistant Secretary to conduct a passenger rail security demonstration project to assess the feasibility of technologies to strengthen the security of passenger rail systems against terrorist attacks involving the use of improvised explosive devices (IEDs).</p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary, by the end of FY2011, to increase to at least 200 the number of canine teams for passenger rail and public transportation security activities.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to carry out a First Observer Program under which mass transit and other surface transportation professionals and related stakeholders may report to the Assistant Secretary suspicious activities or security threats that may be related to a potential transportation security incident or act of terrorism.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Surface Transportation and Mass Transit Security Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Surface Transportation and Mass Transit Security Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Surface Transportation and Mass Transit Security Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To authorize programs and activities within the Transportation Security Administration to enhance the security of surface transportation, including mass transit, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2011-05-13T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr1900ih/xml/BILLS-112hr1900ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-06-02</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
