<bill session="108" type="s" number="889" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:09Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Victim Citizenship Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to accord honorary citizenship to the alien victims of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States and to provide for the granting of citizenship to the alien spouses and children of certain victims of such attacks.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Victim Citizenship Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2003-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5350" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1801" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Terrorist Victim Citizenship Relief Act - Deems aliens who died as a result of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States to be honorary U.S. citizens if they held lawful immigration status. Entitles the spouses and children of such victims to naturalization as U.S. citizens upon being administered the oath of renunciation and allegiance in an appropriate ceremony pursuant to the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA), without regard to their current status, if they apply to the Secretary of Homeland Security for naturalization within two years. Directs the Secretary to record the date of naturalization of any such person as being September 10, 2001. Prohibits naturalization of, or affording honorary citizenship to, any alien (or family member) who is inadmissible or deportable under the INA, including any perpetrator of such attacks.</summary>
</bill>
