<bill session="111" type="h" number="2177" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:29Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency and Accountability in Security Contracting Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require accountability for personnel performing private security functions under Federal contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency and Accountability in Security Contracting Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001154" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000749" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="963" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-23T18:53:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency and Accountability in Security Contracting Act of 2009 - Requires each contract, subcontract, or task order awarded or issued by a federal agency that includes private security functions (covered contract) to require the contractor to provide to the agency contracting officer specified information, including the number of persons to perform the security functions and the hiring and training process for such persons. Requires agency oversight in the performance of the covered contract.

Requires the Secretary of Defense to establish and maintain a comprehensive security contracting database.

Prohibits any agency from awarding a covered contract for performance of activities that require or involve: (1) direct participation by contractor personnel in hostilities with an enemy combatant or force; or (2) interrogation by contractor personnel of an individual who is a detainee or prisoner in the custody or under the effective control of the U.S. government.

Directs the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (JCS) to issue rules regarding the circumstances under which force may be used by contractor personnel performing private security functions within the area covered by a contingency operation and the types of force authorized. Requires each agency awarding a covered contract: (1) for a contingency operation, to prescribe minimum standards for contract personnel, including hiring, training, and equipment standards; and (2) to issue guidance on equipment used for private security functions. Requires the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to designate a Theater Security Contract Coordinating Officer for each contingency operation with respect to which covered contracts are awarded.

Requires the Secretary of State to work through appropriate existing or new international fora to achieve agreement on an international framework regulating the use of private contractors for security functions and facilitating cooperation on measures to ensure the transparency and legal accountability of security contractors.</summary>
</bill>
