<bill session="116" type="h" number="5817" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair and Honest Advance Cost Estimate for Patients Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act, the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require health plans to provide to participants, beneficiaries, and enrollees an advanced explanation of benefits with respect to items and services scheduled to be received from providers and facilities and to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require health care providers and health care facilities to provide good faith estimates of the expected charges for furnishing such items and services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Honest Advance Cost Estimate for Patients Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2020-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5826" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-08T21:48:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair and Honest Advance Cost Estimate for Patients Act of 2020 This bill requires health care providers and private health insurance plans to provide certain estimates for the costs of services that are scheduled three or more business days in advance. Specifically, providers must inquire whether an individual scheduling such service is enrolled in a health plan, including a government health care program, and intends to seek benefits for the service under the plan. Within a specified time period prior to administering such service, the provider must submit to the individual&#8217;s plan, or to the individual if the individual is not enrolled in a plan, an estimate of expected charges for the service. Providers are subject to a maximum fine of $10,000 for each failure to provide such an estimate. Within a specified time period after receiving an estimate from a provider for a service, private health insurance plans must provide the plan holder with specified benefits information that includes but is not limited to

 the provider's estimated charge, whether the provider is in-network, the plan's estimated share of the amount, the plan holder's estimated cost-sharing amount, and the estimated amount remaining to meet the plan holder's deductible or out-of-pocket maximum.</summary>
</bill>
