<bill session="118" type="s" number="262" updated="2025-11-19T02:54:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Spying Bosses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit, or require disclosure of, the surveillance, monitoring, and collection of certain worker data by employers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Spying Bosses Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2024-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7690" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-25T13:11:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Spying Bosses Act This bill establishes requirements for employers with respect to the collection and disclosure of certain worker data. The requirements apply to employers with more than 10 workers, including government employers. For example, employers must disclose to their workers (including job applicants) any workplace surveillance by the employer, including (1) what data is collected, (2) how the data is used, and (3) how such surveillance affects workers' performance assessments. Further, employers may not use workplace surveillance for certain purposes, such as to (1) monitor a worker's activities related to a labor organization, (2) collect a worker's health information that is unrelated to the worker's job duties, (3) monitor a worker who is off duty or in a sensitive area, or (4) use an automated decision system (e.g., machine learning or artificial intelligence techniques) to predict the behavior of a worker that is unrelated to the worker's job . Employers must disclose to a worker any work-related decision that relies on workplace surveillance data and allow the worker to review the data. Employers also must meet certain requirements before transferring surveillance data to a third party. Additionally, the bill establishes the Privacy and Technology Division within the Department of Labor to implement and enforce the workforce surveillance requirements. The bill also provides for enforcement by private right of action, states, and other specified agencies.</summary>
</bill>
