<bill session="117" type="h" number="8064" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:47Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advanced Manufacturing Jobs in America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Manufacturing Jobs in America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to establish demonstration and pilot projects to facilitate education and training programs in the field of advanced manufacturing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2022-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="121" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-25T22:47:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Advanced Manufacturing Jobs in America Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to establish demonstration and pilot projects, through the awarding of grants or contracts, to facilitate training and education in advanced manufacturing.

A local educational entity (e.g., a technical college, a community college, or an entity that assists educationally underserved communities) in partnership with a manufacturer that employs individuals who have advanced manufacturing skills is eligible to receive such grants or contracts. The corresponding project must (1) develop skills and competencies in communities with expected growth in advanced manufacturing; (2) provide education and training for available and anticipated jobs in advanced manufacturing; (3) educate individuals about career advancement opportunities within advanced manufacturing; and (4) give priority to incumbent workers, dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals.</summary>
</bill>
