<bill session="109" type="h" number="177" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:57Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-18T13:22:18-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-18T13:22:18-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Prado Basin Natural Treatment System Project, to authorize the Secretary to carry out a program to assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines in California, to authorize the Secretary to participate in the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001139"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000830" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000492" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2005-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2005-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18T13:16:06-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Musgrave moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18T13:16:21-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8868-8869" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18T13:16:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 177.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2005-10-18T13:22:18-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8868" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-18T13:22:23-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2106" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water purification"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-23T15:17:30Z" status="Passed House amended">Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2005 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) participate, in cooperation with the Orange County Water District, in the design, planning, and construction of natural treatment systems and wetlands for the flows of the Santa Ana River, California, and its tributaries into the Prado Basin; (2) carry out, in cooperation with local governments, a program to assist agencies in projects to construct regional brine lines to export the salinity imported from the Colorado River to the Pacific Ocean; and (3) participate, in cooperation with the Chino Basin Watermaster, the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, and the Santa Ana Watershed Project Authority, in the design, planning, and construction of the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project. Authorizes appropriations. Specifies limits on the federal share of project costs and prohibits the use of funds provided by the Secretary for operation and maintenance.

Specifies limits on the federal share of the costs of phase 1 of the Orange County Regional for FY2007-FY2016.

Directs the Secretary to establish at the District a center to provide: (1) assistance in the development and advancement of membrane technologies; and (2) educational support in the advancement of public understanding and acceptance of membrane produced water supplies. Requires the Secretary: (1) to enter into contracts with the District to manage the center; and (2) in consultation with the District, to jointly prepare a plan identifying the center's goals and objectives and to report to Congress within one year on the center's status and accomplishments. Authorizes appropriations. .

 Terminates provisions of this Act after 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
