<bill session="117" type="s" number="140" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BLUE GLOBE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve data collection and monitoring of the Great Lakes, oceans, bays, estuaries, and coasts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">BLUE GLOBE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Bolstering Long-term Understanding and Exploration of the Great Lakes, Oceans, Bays, and Estuaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BLUE GLOBE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bolstering Long-term Understanding and Exploration of the Great Lakes, Oceans, Bays, and Estuaries Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2021-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="206">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 206.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15">
      <text>By Senator Cantwell from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 117-74.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3748" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-12T14:46:54Z" status="Reported to Senate">Bolstering Long-term Understanding and Exploration of the Great Lakes, Oceans, Bays, and Estuaries Act or the BLUE GLOBE Act

This bill addresses data collection and monitoring of the Great Lakes, oceans, bays, estuaries, and coasts.

Specifically, it expands requirements related to a study of the scientific workforce in areas of oceanic and atmospheric research and development. For example, the bill requires the study to include an investigation on whether there is a workforce shortage in the number of individuals with technical or trade-based skillsets or credentials suited to a career in oceanic and atmospheric data collection, processing, satellite production, or satellite operations. The study must also investigate actions the federal government can take to increase diversity in the scientific workforce and shorten the hiring backlog for such workforce.

The bill also directs the National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to create an Electronic Monitoring Innovation Prize, which may be awarded for the development of advanced electronic fisheries monitoring equipment and data analysis tools.

NOAA must also seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to evaluate whether there is a need for an Advanced Research Projects Agency-Oceans within NOAA.

Additionally, NOAA must establish a program to improve the collection, aggregation, and analysis of data to measure the value and impact of industries related to the Great Lakes, oceans, bays, estuaries, and coasts on the U.S. economy.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-74</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
