<bill session="117" type="h" number="5321" updated="2023-08-03T20:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to address the inappropriate or unlawful denial by the Department of Veterans Affairs of benefits and services for former members of the Armed Forces who were discharged or released from the active military, naval, or air service under conditions characterized as neither dishonorable nor honorable, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Unlawful Turn-Aways Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlawful Turn-Aways Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2021-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2786" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-03T20:04:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Unlawful Turn-Aways Act of 2021

This bill addresses training for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) employees regarding discharge eligibility standards for VA benefits and services, requires notification of eligibility for VA benefits and services for individuals who were discharged or released from active service under conditions characterized as neither honorable nor dishonorable, and modifies the requirements of eligibility for certain mental and behavioral health care related to military sexual trauma, readjustment counseling, and related mental health services.</summary>
</bill>
