<bill session="108" type="s" number="1955" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Technical Corrections Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make technical corrections to laws relating to Native Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Technical Corrections Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Cowlitz Indian Tribe Distribution of Judgment Funds Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15978"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15978-15981" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-273.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="529">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 529.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cultural policy"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tribes and tribal system"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3256"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-04-06T20:52:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native American Technical Corrections Act of 2004 - Makes technical amendments to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, the Indian Financing Act of 1974, the Indian Tribal Justice Technical and Legal Assistance Act, the Crow Boundary Settlement Act of 1994, the Fallon Paiute Shoshone Indian Tribes Water Rights Settlement Act of 1990, the California Indian Land Transfer Act, and other specified Federal law with regard to: (1) replacing "American Indian Education Foundation" with "National Fund for Excellence in American Indian Education"; (2) loan guaranties and insurance with respect to eligible borrowers and loan approval; (3) Indian trust land; (4) Indian tribal justice technical and legal assistance; (5) tribal justice systems; (6) authorization of 99-year leases for the Prairie Band of Potawatomi; (7) certain Navajo Healthcare contracting; (8) distribution of capital gains and any other noninterest income received on funds in the Crow Tribal Trust Fund; (9) use of the Fallon Paiute-Shoshone Tribe Settlement Fund; (10) deeming of specified lands in Alaska under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to a Native Corporation; and (11) certain lands to be held in trust for the Utu Utu Gwaitu Paiute Tribe, Benton Paiute Reservation.

Cowlitz Indian Tribe Distribution of Judgment Funds Act - Specifies the required distribution and use of funds awarded in Indian Claims Commission Docket No. 218 to the Cowlitz Indian Tribe of Washington.

Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation Judgment Fund Distribution Act of 2003 - Specifies the required distribution and use of funds awarded to the Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation in the case of Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation v. United States of America, Docket No. 773-87-L.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-273</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
