<bill session="111" type="h" number="3671" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:28Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-19T10:49:21-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-19T10:49:21-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote Department of the Interior efforts to provide a scientific basis for the management of sediment and nutrient loss in the Upper Mississippi River Basin, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000420" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000652" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2010-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000283" joined="2009-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2009-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:35:43-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:35:44-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1611-1613" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:35:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3671.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T14:43:35-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T10:38:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1668" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="137" datetime="2010-03-19T10:49:21-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 289 - 121 (Roll no. 137).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/18/2010 H1611-1612" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T10:49:22-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2779" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Missouri River"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-18T18:36:41Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Upper Mississippi River Basin Protection Act - (Sec. 3) Declares that it is the policy of Congress that federal investments in the Upper Mississippi River Basin must be guided by sound science.

Title I: Sediment and Nutrient Monitoring Network - (Sec. 101) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey (USGS), to establish a nutrient and sediment monitoring network for the Upper Mississippi River Basin as part of the Upper Mississippi River Stewardship Initiative.

(Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish guidelines for the effective design of data collection and storage activities regarding sediment and nutrient monitoring, for the use of suitable and consistent methods for data collection, and for consistent reporting, data storage, and archiving practices; (2) inventory the sediment and monitoring efforts of governmental and nongovernmental entities for the purpose of creating a baseline understanding of overlap, data gaps, and redundancies and, on the basis of the inventory, integrate the monitoring efforts into the sediment and nutrient monitoring network; (3) collaborate with other public and private monitoring programs in establishing the network; and (4) report to Congress on the development of the network. (Sec. 106) Directs the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a water resources assessment of the Basin. Title II: Computer Modeling and Research - (Sec. 201) Requires the Director of the USGS, as part of the Initiative, to establish a computer modeling program to identify significant sources of nutrient and sediment in the Basin. (Sec. 202) Requires the Director to establish an Internet-based system to provide information regarding: (1) programs designed to reduce sediment and nutrient loss in the Basin; (2) nutrient and sediment levels in the Upper Mississippi River and its tributaries; and (3) successful sediment and nutrient reduction projects. (Sec. 203) Requires the Director to provide to Congress and make available to the public: (1) an annual report regarding monitoring activities conducted in the Basin; and (2) a progress report every three years regarding modeling activities. Title III: Authorization of Appropriations and Related Matters - (Sec. 301) Authorizes appropriations to: (1) USGS to carry out this Act, with one-third to be made available for the Cooperative Water Program and the remainder for the Hydrologic Networks and Analysis Program; and (2) National Research Council for the water resources assessment of the Basin.</summary>
</bill>
