<bill session="118" type="hr" number="996" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:00Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-06T14:11:22-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-02-06T14:11:22-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H.Res. 863) impeaching Alejandro Nicholas Mayorkas, Secretary of Homeland Security, for high crimes and misdemeanors, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 485) to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to prohibit the use of quality-adjusted life years and similar measures in coverage and payment determinations under Federal health care programs.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H.Res. 863) impeaching Alejandro Nicholas Mayorkas, Secretary of Homeland Security, for high crimes and misdemeanors, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 485) to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to prohibit the use of quality-adjusted life years and similar measures in coverage and payment determinations under Federal health care programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-374, by Mr. Burgess.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05T21:38:03-05:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H. Res. 863 under a closed rule and H.R. 485 under a structured rule. The rule provides for two hours of general debate on H. Res. 863 and one hour of general debate on H.R. 485. One motion to recommit allowed on H.R. 485. The resolution further provides that upon adoption H. Res. 863, H. Res. 995 is hereby adopted; and further, that no other resolution incidental to impeachment relating to H. Res. 863 shall be privileged during the remainder of the 118th Congress.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-02-05" calendar="House" number="62">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 62.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06T12:21:14-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H437-447" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06T12:24:51-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 996.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06T13:26:06-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 996, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06T13:31:46-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H447-449" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06T14:02:36-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 207 (Roll no. 34).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H447-448" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="35" datetime="2024-02-06T14:11:22-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 216 - 209 (Roll no. 35).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H437" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06T14:11:24-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="863" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="995" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="485" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-29T18:15:21Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of the resolution (H.Res. 863) impeaching Alejandro Nicholas Mayorkas, Secretary of Homeland Security, for high crimes and misdemeanors.

Further, it provides for consideration of the bill (H.R. 485) to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to prohibit the use of quality-adjusted life years and similar measures in coverage and payment determinations under federal health care programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-374</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
