<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4040</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:17:19Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:17:19Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-11-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2009-11-09T22:27:10Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-11-06T14:00:47Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-09</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-06</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000030</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Farr, Sam [D-CA-17]</fullName>
        <firstName>SAM</firstName>
        <lastName>FARR</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>17</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-11-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-02-22T21:32:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Big Sur Forest Service Management Unit Act of 2009 - Establishes the Big Sur Management Unit of Los Padres National Forest in California to replace the Monterey Ranger District in the Forest. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to transfer to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) all Bureau of Land Management (BLM) administered public lands within the boundaries of the Unit for inclusion in the Unit. </p> <p>Authorizes the lease or issuance of permits for the use of all or a part of Brazil Ranch. </p> <p>Designates the Unit as a Wildland Urban Interface Special Study Area. Requires the Secretary to: (1) make use of existing authority and resources to pioneer innovative fire pre-suppression methods consistent with public safety and wilderness values; (2) create and annually update a fire management plan applicable to the Unit; and (3) establish agency approval procedures for responding to fire emergencies in the Unit. </p> <p>Adjusts the boundaries of the Ventana Wilderness Area. Designates the Horse Canyon and Horse Pasture proposed wilderness additions as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Adjusts the boundaries of the Silver Peak Wilderness Area. Designates the Alder Creek proposed wilderness addition as wilderness and a component of such System. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to take measures in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by this Act necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases. </p> <p>Designates: (1) specified segments of the Arroyo Seco River, Big Creek, Carmel River, San Antonio River, and San Carpoforo Creek and their tributaries in Big Sur, California, as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; (2) Forest Service Road 19S09, to be known as the Arroyo Seco-Indians Trail, as a National Recreation Trail; and (3) the Jeff Norman Botanical Area.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Big Sur Forest Service Management Unit Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Big Sur Forest Service Management Unit Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To redesignate the Monterey Ranger District of Los Padres National Forest in the State of California as the Big Sur Management Unit, to transfer certain Bureau of Land Management land for inclusion in the management unit, to adjust the boundaries of the Ventana and Silver Peak Wilderness Areas, to designate segments of Arroyo Seco River, Big Creek, Carmel River, San Antonio River, San Carpoforo Creek, and their tributaries as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Big Sur Forest Service Management Unit Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2009-11-06T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr4040ih/xml/BILLS-111hr4040ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-11-09</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
