<bill session="117" type="h" number="5268" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to implement certain recommendations of the Comptroller General of the United States with respect to the mitigation and prevention of training accidents, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preventing Future Tragedies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Future Tragedies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001260"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-13T17:38:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Future Tragedies Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to implement various recommendations relating to the mitigation and prevention of training accidents.

Specifically, the bill requires DOD to

 develop clearly defined roles for vehicle commanders, establish mechanisms and procedures for tactical vehicle risk management to be used by first-line supervisors (including vehicle commanders), evaluate the number of personnel responsible for tactical vehicle safety and determine if their units are appropriately staffed or if any adjustments are needed to implement operational unit ground-safety programs, ensure that tactical vehicle driver training programs include a well-defined process with specific performance criteria and measurable standards to identify driver skills and experience under diverse conditions, and evaluate the extent to which ranges and training areas are identifying and communicating hazards to units. Additionally, the Department of the Army and the Department of the Navy must jointly establish a formal collaboration forum amongst range officials through which such officials must share methods for identifying and communicating hazards to units.</summary>
</bill>
