<bill session="118" type="h" number="4660" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HALT Our Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALT Our Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Halting Academic Liaisons To Our Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Federal funding for institutions of higher education that have agreements with certain academic institutions in the People's Republic of China and the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001095" joined="2024-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-11T14:20:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Halting Academic Liaisons To Our Adversaries Act or the HALT Our Adversaries Act

This bill&#160;prohibits federal funding for institutions of higher education (IHEs) that have certain agreements with China or Russia.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to identify academic institutions of China, Russia, and other countries that are known to provide support to China's People's Liberation Army or Russia's armed forces. Further, the bill prohibits an IHE&#160;from receiving federal funds if it maintains a contract or other agreement with such an academic institution identified by DOD.

Additionally, the bill prohibits an IHE from receiving funds made available for an element of the intelligence community for research, development, testing, and evaluation if it maintains a contract or other agreement with (1) any entity identified as a Chinese military company operating in the United States, or (2) an academic institution of China that maintains a relationship with such an entity.

The bill also prohibits an IHE or other postsecondary educational institution from receiving federal funds (with exceptions for certain federal education funds) if it&#160;has a contractual partnership in effect with an entity that is (1) owned or controlled by the Chinese government, or (2) organized under the laws of China.&#160;The IHE or other postsecondary educational&#160;institution may regain eligibility for these funds upon termination of the partnership.</summary>
</bill>
