<bill session="117" type="h" number="6151" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Highway Accident Fairness Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highway Accident Fairness Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to prohibit staged collisions with commercial motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2022-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-22T12:17:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Highway Accident Fairness Act of 2021

This bill makes staging a collision with a commercial motor vehicle a federal crime and modifies legal procedures for suits arising from commercial motor vehicle accidents.

A person who operates a motor vehicle and intentionally collides with a commercial motor vehicle (or arranges for another person to cause such a collision) is subject to a fine, a prison term of up to 20 years, or both. If the collision results in serious bodily injury or death, the prison term may not be less than 20 years.

With respect to legal procedures, the bill (1) requires a plaintiff in a suit concerning a bodily injury or death that involves one or more commercial motor vehicles to disclose the identity of any third party who is financing the litigation in exchange for a portion of the plaintiff's recovery, and (2) grants federal courts jurisdiction over such actions in cases where damages exceed $5 million.</summary>
</bill>
