<bill session="111" type="h" number="848" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:11Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Performance Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Performance Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Performance Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide parity in radio performance rights under title 17, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000364" joined="2009-03-03" withdrawn="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2009-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000213" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001043" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2009-03-10" withdrawn="2009-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000113" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2009-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2009-03-10" withdrawn="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2009-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2009-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2009-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000266" joined="2009-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2009-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000119" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000794" joined="2009-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2009-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2010-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E202-203"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 111-680.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-14" calendar="Union" number="405">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 405.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="379" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Sound recording"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-20T20:14:08Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Performance Rights Act - (Sec. 2) Amends federal copyright law to: (1) grant performers of sound recordings equal rights to compensation from terrestrial broadcasters (AM and FM radio); and (2) modify the circumstances under which the public performance of a sound recording is subject to statutory licensing.

(Sec. 3) Establishes separate annual flat fees in lieu of royalty payments for certain minority, female, religious, rural, small, noncommercial, public, educational, and community terrestrial broadcast stations that have annual revenues falling within corresponding separate specified ranges.

Prohibits such annual fees from being taken into account in any Copyright Royalty Board rate-setting proceeding or in any other federal government proceeding.

Includes broadcasts of religious services and incidental uses of musical sound recordings publicly by digital audio transmission among performances of a sound recording that are not copyright infringements.

(Sec. 4) Provides a per program license option for terrestrial broadcast stations that make limited feature uses of sound recordings.

(Sec. 5) Prohibits: (1) license fees payable for the public performance of sound recordings from being used in any governmental proceeding to set the license fees payable to copyright owners of musical works for the public performance of their works to adversely affect such license fees; (2) a licensee of a sound recording from publicly performing such sound recording unless a license has been granted for the public performance of any copyrighted musical work contained in the sound recording; (3) anything in this Act from adversely affecting the public performance rights or royalties payable to songwriters or copyright owners of musical works; and (4) rates established by the Copyright Royalty Judges for the public performance of sound recordings from being used in any governmental proceeding to adversely affect license fees payable to copyright owners of musical works for the public performance of their works by terrestrial broadcast stations.

(Sec. 6) Entitles a featured recording artist who performs on a sound recording that has been licensed for public performance by means of an audio transmission to payments from the sound recording's copyright owner in accordance with the terms of the artist's contract.

Requires: (1) sound recording copyright owners to deposit 1% of the receipts from their licensing of public performance rights by means of an audio transmission into the American Federation of Musicians and American Federation of Television and Radio Artists Intellectual Property Rights Distribution Fund for distribution to nonfeatured performers who have performed on sound recordings; and (2) the Fund to pay 50% to nonfeatured musicians and 50% to nonfeatured vocalists.

(Sec. 7) Prohibits a broadcaster's payment of royalties on underlying works publicly performed by terrestrial broadcast stations from affecting that broadcaster's public interest obligations to its local community under the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) regulations related to radio broadcast services.

(Sec. 8) Directs copyright royalty judges making determinations or adjustments of rates and terms of copyright royalty payments for public performances of sound recordings, to consider the effect of such rates and terms on: (1) religious, minority-owned, female-owned, small, and noncommercial broadcasters; (2) non-music programming, including local news and information programming for stations that are part of station groups located in one designated market area; and (3) religious, minority or minority-owned, and female or female-owned royalty recipients.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-680</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
