<bill session="109" type="h" number="5492" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:25Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Constitution Center Operations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Constitution Heritage Act of 1988 to provide for the operation of the National Constitution Center.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Constitution Center Operations Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001227"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1686" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civics education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-08-24T18:48:09Z" status="Introduced in House">National Constitution Center Operations Act - Amends the Constitution Heritage Act of 1988 to set forth requirements for cooperative agreements between the Secretary of the Interior and the National Constitution Center (NCC) for the operation of the NCC, including: (1) that revenues from the operation of the NCC be made available to the NCC (without further appropriation) to offset its operating expenses; and (2) that the NCC maintain appropriate risk insurance, maintain its tax-exempt status, and report annually to the Secretary or Congress on its activities, goals and plans. Authorizes the Secretary to terminate a cooperative agreement in the public interest.

Exempts agreements, leases, contracts or other arrangements entered into under this Act from certain requirements for leases of buildings by the federal government and for the award of concession contracts in units of the National Park System.</summary>
</bill>
