<bill session="118" type="s" number="255" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Asylum Seeker Work Authorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asylum Seeker Work Authorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain aliens seeking asylum to be employed in the United States while their applications are being adjudicated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2023-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S235-236" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-16T13:43:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Asylum Seeker Work Authorization Act of 2023

This bill provides expedited work authorization to certain asylum applicants, specifically those who (1) entered the United States at a designated port of entry, or (2) have been continuously physically present in the United States since this bill's enactment.

Such individuals, if they meet other requirements (e.g., are not in detention and have filed an application for work authorization), shall be eligible to receive work authorization 30 days after filing an asylum application. By contrast, other asylum applicants (e.g., an individual who entered the United States after this bill's enactment at a place other than a designated port of entry) must wait 180 days after filing an asylum application to be eligible for work authorization, as required under current law for all asylum applicants.

Furthermore, asylum applicants who meet all the requirements to receive expedited authorization shall be entitled to work authorization. By contrast, other asylum applicants may, but are not entitled to, receive work authorization, as specified under current law for all asylum applicants.</summary>
</bill>
