<bill session="119" type="s" number="3001" updated="2025-10-24T17:42:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shutdown Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shutdown Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to appropriate funds for pay and allowances of excepted Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2025-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5801" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3012" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-24T17:41:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shutdown Fairness Act

This bill provides appropriations to pay federal employees who work during a government shutdown.

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations for federal agencies to provide pay and allowances to excepted employees who are required to work during any period in which interim or full-year appropriations are not in effect for a fiscal year (i.e., a government shutdown).&#160;

Under current law, excepted employees are required to work during a government&#160;shutdown and are&#160;not paid until the government shutdown is over. This bill provides appropriations to pay excepted employees during a government shutdown. The bill also specifies that the term excepted employee includes certain contractors who support federal employees during a government shutdown.&#160;

A federal agency may not use the funds provided by this bill during any period in which continuing appropriations are in effect for the purpose of paying excepted employees of the agency.</summary>
</bill>
