<bill session="118" type="h" number="2617" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Choices for Stranded Passengers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Choices for Stranded Passengers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require air carriers to provide passengers experiencing a delay or cancellation with alternative transportation on another air carrier.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-09T18:59:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Choices for Stranded Passengers Act of 2023

This bill requires air carriers (including foreign air carriers) that cause a significant flight delay or cancellation to provide, in certain circumstances, passengers with alternative transportation.

For the purposes of this bill, a domestic flight is considered significantly delayed when the departure or arrival has changed by three or more hours; an international flight to or from the United States is significantly delayed at six or more hours. Further, a qualifying flight is a scheduled flight in an aircraft designed for 31 passenger seats or more.

Under the bill, an air carrier that has caused a significant delay or cancellation to a qualifying flight must provide a passenger with an alternative flight on another air carrier at no additional charge if that alternative flight would arrive at the destination before the original flight or before another flight by the original air carrier.

This requirement does not apply if the passenger voluntarily chooses (1) to accept alternative ground transportation, provided at no additional charge by the air carrier; or (2) not to travel to the original destination and the air carrier promptly provides a full cash refund for the ticket cost and fees.

Passengers must be informed of their rights under this bill when booking a ticket and at the time such a delay or cancellation occurs.</summary>
</bill>
