<bill session="118" type="h" number="4116" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:09Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Systemic Risk Authority Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Systemic Risk Authority Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="display">Systemic Risk Authority Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require reports on the use of the systemic risk authority applicable to winding up a failed insured depository institution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2023-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 50 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-614.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-07-30" calendar="Union" number="512">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 512.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-28T18:04:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Systemic Risk Authority Transparency Act 

This bill requires banking regulators to submit a report to Congress in the event of the failure of an insured depository institution that leads to a systemic risk determination by the Department of the Treasury.

Regulators must report confidential supervisory information relating to the institution, any institutional mismanagement by the executives and the board, any shortcomings by the regulator, and recommendations to improve the safety and soundness of similarly situated institutions. This report must be made no later than 60 days after such a determination and again 180 days afterwards.

The Governmental Accountability Office (GAO) must report on additional factors in its report regarding such a determination. Specifically, GAO must report on any mismanagement by the executives and board of the institution, a review of the institution's compensation practices, supervisory or regulatory shortcomings, actions taken by regulators, and other relevant information. The bill also requires this report to be made no later than 60 days after such a determination and again 180 days afterwards.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-614</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
