<bill session="117" type="h" number="5671" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-15T17:41:15-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-11-15T17:41:15-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish seasonal influenza vaccines to certain individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish seasonal influenza vaccines to certain individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15T17:35:42-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15T17:36:37-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6257" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15T17:36:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5671.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-11-15T17:41:15-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6257" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15T17:41:20-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-25T18:08:29Z" status="Passed House">This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to furnish a seasonal influenza vaccine through April 29, 2022, to covered individuals during the COVID-19 public health emergency.

Under the bill, covered individuals are

 veterans who are not eligible to enroll in the VA health care system; specified veterans who are eligible for hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care abroad; beneficiaries who are eligible for care due to a specified disability or death of a veteran; family caregivers of veterans who are participating in the VA's Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers; caregivers of veterans participating in the VA's Program of General Caregiver Support Services; caregivers of veterans participating in the VA's Medical Foster Home Program, Bowel and Bladder Program, Home Based Primary Care Program, or Veteran Directed Care Program; and the spouses of veterans. The VA must prioritize the vaccination of (1) veterans who are enrolled in the VA health care system, (2) veterans who fail to enroll but receive hospital care and medical services for specified disabilities in their first 12 months of separation from service, and (3) caregivers accompanying such prioritized veterans.

Under the bill, the VA is authorized to determine the timing for offering a vaccine to the spouse of a veteran.</summary>
</bill>
