<bill session="117" type="h" number="3624" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Learning and Life Saving Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a National Disaster Safety Board.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Learning and Life Saving Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1952" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5532" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5118" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-12T18:44:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Learning and Life Saving Act of 2021

This bill establishes within the executive branch a National Disaster Safety Board to study the underlying causes of disaster-related fatalities and property damage nationwide and make policy recommendations, and authorizes appropriations for the board through FY2025.

Specifically, the board shall review and establish the facts, circumstances, and cause or probable cause of the loss of life, human injury, and economic injury due to a natural hazard with 10 or more fatalities.

The board shall

 initiate a review of an incident by monitoring the situation and assessing available facts to determine the appropriate review response without interfering in any ongoing lifesaving and life sustaining efforts underway by other entities; disseminate best practices to develop disaster investigation and review capacity within state, tribal, and local governments; and establish an office to review and make recommendations to mitigate and prevent the loss of life, or human or economic injury, for vulnerable populations. The Government Accountability Office shall audit the programs and expenditures of the board at least once every two years.

The bill defines natural hazard to mean a major disaster that is naturally occurring, to include any naturally occurring heat wave, storms, or wildfires, and to exclude a technological disaster.</summary>
</bill>
