<bill session="118" type="h" number="3522" updated="2025-01-24T18:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIRESHEDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRESHEDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Improvements through Research and Emergency Stewardship for Healthy Ecosystem Development and Sustainability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to establish emergency fireshed management areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-09-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1719" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T20:41:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Forest Improvements through Research and Emergency Stewardship for Healthy Ecosystem Development and Sustainability Act or the FIRESHEDS Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA), with respect to National Forest System lands, and the Department of the Interior, with respect to public lands, no later than 90 days after receiving a request from a state, to enter into an agreement with such state to jointly

 designate one or more fireshed management areas within such state, and conduct fireshed management projects in such fireshed management areas. Not later than 90 days after entering into an agreement, the USDA or Interior, as appropriate, and such state shall jointly conduct a stewardship and fireshed assessment.

The USDA and Interior shall carry out fireshed management projects in accordance with the timeline and project size limitations included in the stewardship and fireshed assessment.

Fireshed management projects shall be categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement and exempt from the special administrative review process.

The bill makes permanent the authority for a state to use revenue from timber sales under a good neighbor agreement for forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services.</summary>
</bill>
