<bill session="116" type="h" number="7528" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Get America Back to Work Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the civil liability of persons for the spread or possible transmission of SARS-COV-2 caused by an act or omission while acting in good faith during the COVID-19 emergency period, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Get America Back to Work Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2020-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2020-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2020-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-16T22:57:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Get America Back to Work Act

This bill limits civil liability of persons for the spread or transmission of coronavirus (i.e., the virus that causes COVID-19) and exempts employers from certain federal occupational safety and health laws and regulations in relation to the virus.

The bill shall be in effect from January 1, 2020, until 18 months after the end of the COVID-19 public health emergency.

Generally, a person shall be exempt from liability for the spread or transmission of the virus if the person made reasonable efforts to comply with applicable guidance regarding COVID-19. Further, a health care provider acting in good faith shall be exempt from liability for the spread or transmission of the virus caused by the provider's act or omission if (1) the provider was providing health care services significantly impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic, (2) the act or omission occurred while a health professional was performing services within the scope of the professional's license or certification to provide such services, and (3) the act or omission does not exceed the scope of the license or certification of a substantially similar health professional.

However, a person (including a health care provider) may still be liable in certain instances, such as if the act or omission in question constitutes willful or criminal misconduct, reckless misconduct, or gross negligence.

Additionally, the bill exempts employers from citation and civil and criminal penalties for violating occupational safety and health standards related to the spread or transmission of the virus, if the employer made reasonable efforts to comply with applicable guidance related to the virus.</summary>
</bill>
