<bill session="109" type="s" number="1265" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:04Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Diesel Emissions Reduction Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Diesel Emissions Reduction Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Diesel Emissions Reduction Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make grants and loans available to States and other organizations to strengthen the economy, public health, and environment of the United States by reducing emissions from diesel engines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2005-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2005-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000595" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2005-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2005-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2005-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2005-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2005-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2005-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2005-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001163" joined="2005-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000888" joined="2005-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6761-6762"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6762-6763" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Clean Air and Nuclear Safety. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-960.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-133.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-09-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="202">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 202.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEV10" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Clean Air and Nuclear Safety" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Automobile engines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction equipment"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine engines"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Railroad equipment"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-31T19:57:45Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Diesel Emissions Reduction Act of 2005 - (Sec. 3) Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) use 70% of the funding provided by this Act to provide grants and low-cost revolving loans, on a competitive basis, to a regional, state, local, or tribal agency or port authority with jurisdiction over transportation or air quality and to certain nonprofit organizations (eligible entities) to reduce diesel emissions; (2) provide not less than 50% of such funding to eligible entities for the benefit of public fleets of diesel vehicles; and (3) provide not less than 90% of such funding to eligible entities for projects using a certified engine configuration (new, rebuilt, or remanufactured engine configuration with a more stringent set of emission standards) or a verified technology. Defines "verified technology" as a pollution control technology (including a retrofit technology), advanced truckstop electrification system, or auxiliary power unit that has been verified by the Administrator or the California Air Resources Board.

 Limits to 10% the amount of funding available to eligible entities for the development and commercialization of emerging technologies. Defines "emerging technology" as an uncertified technology for which an approvable application and test plan has been submitted for verification to the Administrator or the California Air Resources Board).

Sets forth grant and loan application requirements for eligible entities, priorities for awarding such grants or loans, and criteria for use of funds provided by this Act.

(Sec. 4) Requires the Administrator to: (1) use 30% of the funding provided by this Act to support state grant and loan programs to reduce diesel emissions; (2) provide certain guidance to states for such programs; (3) make funding allocations; and (4) award additional funding (50%) to states that match allocations.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Administrator, not later than one year after funds are first available under this Act and biennially thereafter, to submit to Congress reports evaluating the implementation of programs under this Act.

(Sec. 6) Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish a program to inform industry stakeholders (equipment owners and operators, emission and pollution control technology manufacturers, engine and equipment manufacturers, state and local air quality managers, community organizations, and public health, educational, and environmental organizations) of the benefits of eligible technologies (defined as verified or emerging technologies); (2) develop nonfinancial incentives to promote the use of such technologies; (3) develop appropriate guidance to provide credit to a state for emission reductions created by eligible technologies though a Clean Air Act state implementation plan; and (4) in coordination with the Department of Commerce and industry stakeholders, inform foreign countries with air quality problems of the potential of U.S. technology to reduce emissions in those countries.

(Sec. 7) Affirms that nothing in this Act affects any authority under the Clean Air Act in existence prior to the enactment of this Act.

(Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations for FY2007-FY2011.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-133</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
