<bill session="118" type="hr" number="458" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Requiring foreign state media outlets with credentialed members in the House news media galleries to comply with the Foreign Agents Registration Act by prohibiting the admission into such galleries of reporters and correspondents who are representatives of such outlets who are not in compliance with the requirements of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Requiring foreign state media outlets with credentialed members in the House news media galleries to comply with the Foreign Agents Registration Act by prohibiting the admission into such galleries of reporters and correspondents who are representatives of such outlets who are not in compliance with the requirements of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001301"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2023-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA06" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="Oversight" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="189" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-08T20:26:59Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution restricts access to the news media galleries in the House Chamber by representatives of media outlets that are affiliated with a foreign government, the family of the ruling monarch of a foreign country, or a foreign political party.

Specifically, the resolution bars access to the news media galleries by representatives of a foreign state media outlet if that outlet is not registered as a foreign agent or it otherwise fails to comply with applicable requirements for foreign agents.

In addition, before being admitted to the news media galleries, representatives of foreign state media outlets must (1) certify that they have, within the prior six months, undergone a background check conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); and (2) that the FBI determined they do not pose a threat to U.S. security.

The resolution also caps at 10 the number of reporters and correspondents from the same foreign state media outlet who may be admitted to the news media galleries.

The bill also requires a report on the most effective methods for implementing these restrictions.</summary>
</bill>
