<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1361" updated="2022-02-03T05:12:18Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:54-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:54-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should lead a high-level diplomatic effort to ensure that the Durban Review Conference serves as a forum to review implementation of commitments made at the 2001 Durban Conference to combat all forms of racism by defeating the campaign by some members of the Organization of the Islamic Conference to divert the United Nation's Durban Review Conference from a review of problems in their own and other countries by attacking Israel, promoting anti-Semitism, and undermining the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should lead a high-level diplomatic effort to ensure that the Durban Review Conference serves as a forum to review implementation of commitments made at the 2001 Durban Conference to combat all forms of racism by defeating the campaign by some members of the Organization of the Islamic Conference to divert the United Nation's Durban Review Conference from a review of problems in their own and other countries by attacking Israel, promoting anti-Semitism, and undermining the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should lead a high-level diplomatic effort to defeat the campaign by some members of the Organization of the Islamic Conference to divert the United Nation's Durban Review Conference from a review of problems in their own and other countries by attacking Israel, promoting anti-Semitism, and undermining the Universal Charter of Human Rights and to ensure that the Durban Review Conference serves as a forum to review commitments to combat all forms of racism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000410"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000022" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2008-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000021" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2008-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000366" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2008-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2008-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2008-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2008-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2008-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2008-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2008-07-22" withdrawn="2008-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2008-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2008-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T17:23:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T17:23:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8647-8652" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T17:23:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1361.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:54-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8647-8648" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:56-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:57-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-14T22:32:34Z" status="Passed House amended">Acknowledges that the 2001 World Conference Against Racism marked an important recognition of the historic wounds caused by racism, slavery, and colonialism.

Calls on the President and the Secretary of State to lead a diplomatic effort to ensure that the Durban Review Conference focuses on the implementation of state commitments to combat racism, xenophobia and related intolerance, and to defeat any effort by states to use the forum to promote anti-Semitism or hatred against members of any group or to call into question the legitimacy of any state.

Commends all governments that have declared their intentions not to participate in any United Nations Durban Review Conference that sidesteps such commitments and promotes hate, undermines human rights standards, and damages U.N. credibility.

Urges all member states not to support such a Conference.

Commends civil society organizations that have joined together to learn from the shortcomings of the 2001 World Conference Against Racism and to work toward a 2009 Durban Review Conference that rejects hatred.

Recognizes the attempts of some countries to prevent a focus on ongoing racism by utilizing inflammatory language, employing divisive tactics and strategies, fostering an atmosphere of anti-Semitism and otherwise deviating from the commitments made at the 2001 World Conference Against Racism in order to divert the 2009 Durban Review Conference from the important goal of eradicating global racism.

Calls on U.N. Secretary General Ban Ki-Moon to urge the Human Rights Council to adhere to its mandate and asks him to refocus the 2009 Durban Review Conference efforts on the review of what U.N. member states have done to fulfill their commitments to combat racism, racial discrimination, xenophobia and related intolerance, and on concrete action to fight racism, anti-Semitism, and all forms of hatred and violence.

Calls on the High Commissioner for Human Rights to urge U.N. member states to adhere to the agreed framework of the 2009 Durban Review Conference.</summary>
</bill>
