<bill session="119" type="h" number="316" updated="2025-03-12T16:30:05Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Natural Disaster Recovery Program Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Disaster Recovery Program Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the President to provide disaster assistance to States and Indian Tribes under a major disaster recovery program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-12T16:29:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Natural Disaster Recovery Program Act of 2025

This bill establishes Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) funding sources for unmet needs caused by major disasters, expands FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s assistance for housing and home repair, and requires certain considerations in FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s recommendations on presidential emergency/disaster declarations.

The bill establishes the National Disaster Recovery Reserve Fund for FEMA to provide grants to states and Indian tribal governments for unmet need. The bill defines unmet need as any necessary expense for activities related to a declared major disaster, including disaster relief or resilience activities. In addition, the bill authorizes FEMA to set aside funding from the Disaster Relief Fund to provide grants to states and Indian tribal governments for unmet needs resulting from a declared disaster, including home repair, economic recovery measures, and other services assisting disaster victims.&#160;

Also, the bill makes the following changes regarding housing assistance:

authorizes FEMA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Individuals and Households Program (IHP) to provide home repair assistance directly to homeowners when there is a lack of available housing resources,&#160;expands IHP home repair assistance for persons with disabilities,&#160;extends the maximum duration of&#160;IHP&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s direct housing assistance from 18 to 24 months,authorizes&#160;IHP permanent housing construction where FEMA considers it a cost-effective alternative, and&#160;authorizes minor home repairs in the essential assistance federal agencies may provide following a disaster.&#160;Additionally, the bill requires FEMA to give greater weight to local impacts, and events over the past five years, when making recommendations to the President regarding emergency or major disaster declarations.</summary>
</bill>
