<bill session="116" type="h" number="8225" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:37Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-01T14:27:41-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-10-01T14:27:41-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fight Notario Fraud Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit certain types of fraud in the provision of immigration services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fight Notario Fraud Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fight Notario Fraud Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fight Notario Fraud Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fight Notario Fraud Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001207"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001110" joined="2020-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2020-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-533.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-09-24" calendar="Union" number="433">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 433.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01T14:17:01-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bass moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01T14:17:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5149-5151" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01T14:17:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8225.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2020-10-01T14:27:41-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5149-5150" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01T14:27:43-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-16T22:09:25Z" status="Passed House">Fight Notario Fraud Act of 2020

This bill prohibits certain types of fraud or misrepresentations related to immigration matters, provides for criminal penalties for such actions, and contains related provisions.

Specifically, a person shall be subject to fines, imprisonment, or both, if that person knowingly executes a scheme related to immigration laws to (1) defraud another, or (2) receive anything of value from another based on false pretenses or representations. Such a person shall be subject to additional criminal penalties if that person (1) threatens to report another to federal or state authorities, (2) takes actions or makes attempts to adversely impact another's immigration status, or (3) demands or retains anything of value for services fraudulently performed or not performed.

Similarly, a person shall be subject to fines, imprisonment, or both, if the person knowingly and falsely claims to be an attorney or an accredited representative in any matter arising under the immigration laws. (An accredited representative is an individual authorized by the Executive Office of Immigration Review to represent clients in certain immigration matters.)

The bill provides for longer terms of imprisonment for a person who causes a cumulative loss of more than $10,000 through actions prohibited under this bill.

The Department of Justice shall establish at least 15 Special U.S. Attorney positions to enforce these provisions and take other actions related to enforcement and protecting consumers from fraudulent immigration schemes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-533</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
