<bill session="108" type="h" number="1014" updated="2023-01-15T21:49:02Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:26-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:26-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require Federal land managers to support, and to communicate, coordinate, and cooperate with, designated gateway communities, to improve the ability of gateway communities to participate in Federal land management planning conducted by the Forest Service and agencies of the Department of the Interior, and to respond to the impacts of the public use of the Federal lands administered by these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000116" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2003-02-27" withdrawn="2003-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000962" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000549" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000477" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000166" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2003-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-508, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than May 20, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20" calendar="Union" number="291">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 291.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:33:47-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hayworth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:34:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5931-5932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:34:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1014.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:26-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5931" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act - Requires the National Park Service, the United States Forest Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Bureau of Land Management to: (1) provide for public involvement by government officials of local gateway communities (communities, including recognized Indian tribes or Alaska Native villages, adjacent to or near public lands) in the development of land use plans, programs, regulations, and decisions, transportation plans, general management plans, and any other public land plans, decisions, projects, or policies that will have a significant impact; (2) provide such communities with early public notice of such proposed decisions; (3) offer training sessions for officials for understanding and participating in agency planning processes; (4) assign an employee or contractor to work with such a community to develop data and analysis relevant in the preparation of agency plans, decisions, and policies; and (5) assist in conducting a review of plans likely to affect such community.Allows a Federal land manager to enter into a cooperative agreement with gateway communities to provide for coordination between Federal, State, local, and tribal governments in land use inventory, planning, and management activities.Requires the consolidation and coordination of the plans and planning processes of two or more Federal agencies to facilitate an affected gateway community's participation.Directs Federal land agencies to solicit the participation of gateway communities as cooperating agencies under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 when a proposed action is determined to require the preparation of an environmental impact statement.Allows a Federal land manager to make grants to enable an eligible gateway community (population under 10,000) to: (1) participate in Federal land planning or management processes; (2) obtain professional land use or transportation planning assistance necessary as a result of Federal action; (3) address and resolve public infrastructure impacts that are a likely result of the Federal land management decisions and for which sufficient funds are not otherwise available; and (4) provide information and interpretive services.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-508</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
