<bill session="116" type="s" number="4170" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:41Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Enhancing Oversight to End Discrimination in Policing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Oversight to End Discrimination in Policing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform pattern or practice investigations conducted by the Department of Justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7488" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-16T16:02:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Enhancing Oversight to End Discrimination in Policing Act

This bill contains provisions related to federal investigations of state and local law enforcement activities, including an authorization of additional appropriations for the Department of Justice (DOJ) Civil Rights Division for FY2020-FY2029.

Certain DOJ-imposed limitations on civil settlement agreements between DOJ and a local or state entity shall have no effect. (Typically, such an agreement involves the entity agreeing to take certain actions, such as a law enforcement agency agreeing to require certain officer training or stop certain policing practices. In November 2018, DOJ announced that it would adopt certain procedures and requirements to limit such agreements, such as requiring approval by a senior DOJ official if an agreement would create long-term structural obligations for the entity.)

A certain portion of the increased funding for the Civil Rights Division authorized by the bill shall be available for investigations into law enforcement agencies or related entities that engage in a pattern or practice of depriving persons of their civil rights.

The bill also authorizes a state attorney general's office to file a lawsuit under federal law against a law enforcement agency or related entity that engages in a pattern or practice of depriving persons of their civil rights, where currently only DOJ has such authority. DOJ may provide grants to state and tribal governments to investigate and pursue such cases.</summary>
</bill>
