<bill session="116" type="h" number="6527" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:12Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alerting Localities of Environmental Risks and Threats Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 to require an emergency notification meeting in the event of the release of an extremely hazardous substance from a facility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alerting Localities of Environmental Risks and Threats Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001303"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-30T20:52:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Alerting Localities of Environmental Risks and Threats Act of 2020

This bill requires the owner or operator of a facility where hazardous chemicals are produced, used, or stored to hold a public meeting within 72 hours of the release of an extremely hazardous substance. The owner or operator must publish a notice in a local newspaper, giving at least 24 hours of notice before the public meeting. Such notice must be posted at a local library, other local government buildings, and on the facility's public website.

The bill also requires the owner or operator of a facility to hold an annual public meeting, where specified information regarding the extremely hazardous substances at the facility must be disclosed. Notice for such meeting must be published in a local newspaper at least a week in advance of the meeting. The bill provides for a civil penalty if such public meeting and notice requirements are not met.</summary>
</bill>
