<bill session="117" type="s" number="2852" updated="2022-12-30T07:04:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into contracts and agreements for the payment of care in non-Department of Veterans Affairs medical foster homes for certain veterans who are unable to live independently, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7158" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-27T12:00:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to enter into contracts to pay for specified veterans (i.e., certain veterans who have service-connected disabilities and require nursing home care) to be placed in medical foster homes at their request. A medical foster home is a home designed to provide non-institutional, long-term, supportive care for veterans who are unable to live independently and prefer a family setting.

Veterans receiving such care must agree, as a condition of payment for their care, to accept home health services furnished by the VA.

Under the bill, no more than a daily average of 900 veterans may have their care in a medical foster home covered by the VA.

The VA must create a monitoring system to assess its workload in carrying out the medical foster home payments. Additionally, the Government Accountability Office must submit to Congress reports that assess the implementation of this program and provide recommendations for improvements.</summary>
</bill>
