<bill session="111" type="s" number="1187" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:39Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Homeland Event Response Operations Grant Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize grants for use in response to homeland security events of national and international significance.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Homeland Event Response Operations Grant Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-10-16T16:51:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Local Homeland Event Response Operations Grant Act of 2009 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to make grants to a law enforcement agency or fire department for overtime expenses relating to preparation for, and activities during or directly following, a special event.

Authorizes the President or the Secretary to designate an event as a special event if it is an event of significant national importance that may require consultation, technical advice, and support to specific functional areas in which the state or local government agencies may lack expertise or key resources, designation of a Federal Coordinator, and development of an integrated Federal Support Plan and either: (1) extensive federal interagency security and incident management preparedness and predeployment of federal assets; or (2) direct national-level federal support and situational awareness and limited predeployment of federal assets.</summary>
</bill>
