<bill session="119" type="h" number="837" updated="2025-11-19T04:14:07Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-05T13:47:49-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-02-05T13:47:49-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to convey the Pleasant Valley Ranger District Administrative Site to Gila County, Arizona.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to convey the Pleasant Valley Ranger District Administrative Site to Gila County, Arizona.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001132"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05T13:37:02-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05T13:37:10-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H480-481" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05T13:37:12-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 837.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-02-05T13:47:49-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H480" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05T13:47:53-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="700" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-05T21:16:51Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Forest Service to convey specified property to Gila County, Arizona, upon the county's submission of a written request for such conveyance. The property, identified as the Gila County Area, consists of approximately 232.9 acres of National Forest System land located in the Tonto National Forest in Arizona.

The county must use the land for the purposes of serving and supporting veterans.&#160;If any land conveyed under this bill ceases to be used for such purpose, all right, title, and interest in and to the land shall revert to the United States, at the discretion of the Forest Service.

The conveyance&#160;must be made with a&#160;quitclaim deed and without consideration (value, such as payment, provided in exchange for the property).

The Forest Service&#160;must not be required to provide any covenant or warranty for the land and improvements conveyed to the county under such conveyance.

As a condition of the conveyance, the county must pay all the costs associated with the conveyance, including any (1) surveys, (2)&#160;environmental analysis or resource survey required under federal law, and (3) analysis required to comply with certain provisions of the National Historic Preservation Act.</summary>
</bill>
