<bill session="116" type="h" number="6199" updated="2022-08-10T23:27:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Unemployment Insurance Stabilization and Access Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for emergency transfers for unemployment compensation administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Unemployment Insurance Stabilization and Access Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001066"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6201" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-26T13:30:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Unemployment Insurance Stabilization and Access Act of 2020

This bill responds to the coronavirus outbreak by expanding unemployment benefits and providing grants to states for processing and paying claims.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Labor to transfer FY2020 emergency grants to a state's Unemployment Trust Fund to administer unemployment insurance. Grant recipients must (1) require employers to notify employees at the time they lose their jobs of the availability of unemployment compensation (UC), (2) ensure that UC applications and assistance with them are accessible, and (3) take certain steps to ensure the successful processing of applications.

A state may receive an additional grant if its UC claims increased by 10% over the previous calendar year and it

 expresses its commitment to maintain and strengthen access to the UC system; and demonstrates steps to ease eligibility requirements and access to UC for claimants (e.g., waiving work search requirements and the waiting week, and relieving benefit charges for claimants and employers directly impacted by COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) due to an illness in the workplace or direction from a public health official to isolate or quarantine workers). The bill (1) allows states to temporarily modify their UC laws and policies to respond to the spread of COVID-19; (2) waives interest on state loans for UC programs through December 31, 2020; (3) requires Labor to provide technical assistance and guidance to states for short-term UC programs; and (4) temporarily provides full federal financing of extended UC benefits, rather than requiring 50% state financing.</summary>
</bill>
