<bill session="108" type="h" number="2144" updated="2023-01-15T15:33:25Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Aviation Security Technical Corrections and Improvements Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to make technical corrections and improvements relating to aviation security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Security Technical Corrections and Improvements Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000006" joined="2003-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Aviation Consideration and Markup Held Prior to Introduction and Referral (May 14, 2003).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-03T19:15:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Aviation Security Technical Corrections and Improvements Act of 2003 - Restates and recodifies provisions of Federal transportation law relating to the administrative and aviation security functions of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) that were transferred from the Department of Transportation to the Directorate of Border and Transportation Security in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Creates an Office of Small Business Ombudsman within the TSA.

Directs the Under Secretary of Border and Transportation Security in DHS to give priority to developing, testing, improving, and deploying technology at passenger screening checkpoints that will detect non-metallic weapons and explosives on passengers or in their carry-on luggage.

Prohibits aircraft from flying within a certain distance of sport stadiums unless specified conditions are met.

Authorizes the Under Secretary to establish a program to certify explosives detection canine and handler teams.

Directs the Under Secretary to: (1) make grants to airport sponsors for airport security improvement projects; and (2) complete a security review and audit of foreign aircraft repair stations.

Directs the Administrator of Federal Aviation Administration to issue an order amending, modifying, suspending, or revoking an air carrier certificate if notified by the Under Secretary that the certificate holder poses, or is suspected of posing, a risk of air piracy or terrorism or a threat to airline or passenger safety.

Increases certain civil penalties for violations of aviation security laws.

Exempts certain charter airline operations that provide transportation for the armed forces from provisions of this Act and the Aviation and Transportation Security Act .

Directs the Under Secretary to: (1) allow non-scheduled air carriers to operate at Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport under an approved security plan; (2) conduct a pilot program for cargo security; (3) implement a trusted traveler program; (4) report to Congress on security threats faced by U.S. airports and on blast-resistant cargo container technology; and (5) reimburse air carriers and airports for the cost of certain screening activities.</summary>
</bill>
