<bill session="117" type="s" number="1062" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keep China Out of Solar Energy Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the procurement of solar panels manufactured or assembled in the People's Republic of China.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep China Out of Solar Energy Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-17T02:30:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keep China Out of Solar Energy Act of 2021

This bill prohibits federal procurement of solar panels manufactured or assembled in China.

Specifically, the bill directs the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to develop standards and guidelines for executive agencies to prohibit (1) federal funds from being awarded for the procurement of solar panels that are manufactured or assembled by any entity domiciled in China or subject to influence or control by the government of China or the Chinese Communist Party, and (2) the use of government-issued purchase cards to purchase solar panels that are manufactured or assembled by any such entity.

The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation to implement the prohibition with respect to federal contracts and subcontracts.

The bill sets forth provisions regarding waivers, quarterly reports by the OMB to Congress, and a report by the Government Accountability Office.

The OMB shall seek to enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center under which the center will study (1) the current and future domestic market of solar panel production, (2) the ability of the solar panel domestic market to keep pace with technological advancements across the industry, and (3) the current global supply chain and workforce involved with solar panel production.</summary>
</bill>
