<bill session="108" type="h" number="4640" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Fairness in Representation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the District of Columbia as a Congressional district for purposes of representation in the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Fairness in Representation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000116" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000180" joined="2004-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2004-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political representation"/>
    <term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-21T21:13:55Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia Fairness in Representation Act - Considers the District of Columbia as a congressional district for purposes of representation in the House of Representatives.



Provides, until the taking effect of the first reapportionment occurring after the regular decennial census conducted for 2010, that: (1) the membership of the House shall be increased by two Members; and (2) each such Representative shall be in addition to such current membership; and (3) the State identified by the Clerk of the House in a specified report by the President to Congress shall be entitled to one additional Representative.

Prohibits the temporary increase from: (1) increasing or decreasing the permanent membership of the House; (2) affecting the basis of reappointment established by Federal law; or (3) being taken into account in determining the number of electors with respect to the 2004 Presidential election.

Amends the District of Columbia Delegate Act to repeal the office of District of Columbia Delegate.

Amends the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Initiative of 1979 to repeal the office of Statehood Representative.</summary>
</bill>
