<bill session="108" type="s" number="2003" updated="2023-01-15T09:17:37Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Information for Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to promote higher quality health care and better health by strengthening health information, information infrastructure, and the use of health information by providers and patients.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Information for Quality Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16138-16140"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Human engineering"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Life sciences"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-16T19:09:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Health Information for Quality Improvement Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish: (1) an Office of National Healthcare Information Infrastructure to develop a strategic plan to create such an infrastructure; and (2) a Medical Systems Safety Initiative to conduct research on improving and advancing medical care. Requires efforts to increase information technology usage and efficiency in health care to improve the quality of patient care and safety, while protecting privacy and security of information.

Prohibits health insurers from denying and preventing individuals with serious illnesses participation in approved clinical trials. Supports research on: (1) how best to care for older patients with multiple chronic conditions; and (2) the effectiveness and safety of prescription drugs with a high level of use in federally funded health programs.

Requires the development and use of standardized indicators of health care quality. Supports data collection and analysis to assess health care quality in communities and among people of different backgrounds.

Requires a study on approaches to developing and disseminating practice guidelines that synthesize the scientific evidence to support clinical practice.

Requires an evaluation of options to align health care performance with payment, including Medicare payments.

Supports projects to assess the feasibility of using different organizations to disseminate information about health care quality to consumers.

Awards grants for research on patient experiences. Requires the development of standardized materials to assist non-English speaking or functionally illiterate patients in the safe and appropriate use of prescription drugs.</summary>
</bill>
