<bill session="112" type="h" number="2704" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:41Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">JUSTICE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the spread of sexually transmitted infections in correctional facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JUSTICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for the Unprotected Against Sexually Transmitted Infections among the Confined and Exposed Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001085" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2012-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2474" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-11-17T23:33:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for the Unprotected Against Sexually Transmitted Infections among the Confined and Exposed Act or the JUSTICE Act - Requires the Attorney General to direct the Bureau of Prisons to allow community organizations to distribute sexual barrier protection devices (e.g., condoms) and to engage in sexually transmitted infection (STI) counseling and prevention education in federal correctional facilities. Prohibits a federal correctional facility from taking adverse action against a prisoner who possesses or uses a sexual barrier protection device.

Expresses the sense of Congress that states should allow for the legal distribution of sexual barrier protection devices in their correctional facilities.

Amends the Social Security Act to provide for automatic reinstatement of Medicaid benefits for ex-offenders upon their release from a public institution if such an offender: (1) was enrolled under the state plan immediately before becoming an inmate of such institution, or (2) is diagnosed with human immunodeficiency virus. Increases the federal matching payments made to a state by five percentage points for a one-year period to provide for such benefits.

Directs the Attorney General to: (1) conduct a survey of all educational, testing, and other programs in federal and state correctional facilities for reducing the spread of STIs; and (2) develop and implement a five-year strategy to reduce the prevalence and spread of STIs in such facilities.</summary>
</bill>
