<bill session="117" type="h" number="5058" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish a competitive grant program to assist local governments in providing efficient review and approval of zoning and permitting applications that facilitate the deployment of broadband infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Broadband Incentives for Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadband Incentives for Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2021-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-07T14:05:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadband Incentives for Communities Act

This bill requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to establish a grant program to assist local governments and Indian tribes with efficient review and approval of zoning or permitting applications that facilitate the deployment of broadband infrastructure.

Grant recipients must use awarded funds to build application processing capacity or to purchase technology, software, and equipment to facilitate the processing of applications.

The NTIA must also establish the Local Broadband Advisory Council to develop solutions to challenges faced by local governments, Indian tribes, and infrastructure providers in facilitating wireless and broadband deployment, including in unserved and underserved communities.</summary>
</bill>
