<bill session="117" type="hr" number="663" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require that a Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House who accepts an offer of free attendance with respect to a charity event to notify the Committee on Ethics if the value of such free attendance exceeds $1,000, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GALA Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GALA Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Greater Accountability from Lawmakers for Americans Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2021-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2021-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-21T16:01:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Greater Accountability from Lawmakers for Americans Resolution or the GALA Resolution

This resolution amends the House Rules to prohibit a Member of Congress, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House from accepting free attendance at a charity event if the value of free attendance exceeds $1,000 unless attendance is appropriate to the performance of the official duties or representative function of the person attending. A Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House who accepts free attendance that is appropriate to the performance of official duties must submit a statement to the House Ethics Committee prior to attending that explains why attendance is appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
