<bill session="117" type="h" number="7545" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Kimberly Vaughan Firearm Safe Storage Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kimberly Vaughan Firearm Safe Storage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make unlawful the sale of any firearm by a licensed manufacturer, licensed importer, or licensed dealer without a written notice promoting safe storage and a safe storage device, to create and disseminate best practices regarding safe firearm storage, to create a grant program for the distribution of safe storage devices, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow for a credit against tax for sales at retail of safe firearm storage devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2022-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E393-394"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7910" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9060" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-25T11:47:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Kimberly Vaughan Firearm Safe Storage Act

This bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish voluntary best practices for safe firearm storage solely for the purpose of public education. DOJ must give at least 90 days public notice and afford an opportunity for a hearing before establishing such best practices.

The bill authorizes DOJ to award grants for the development, implementation, and evaluation of Safe Firearm Storage Assistance Programs.

The bill also provides for a new tax credit through 2030 for 10% of amounts received from the retail sale of a safe firearm storage device for use in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
