<bill session="118" type="s" number="2675" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Backcountry Aviation Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Backcountry Aviation Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify minimum altitudes for go-arounds, inspection passes, practice approaches, and qualified instrument approaches, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2024-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2024-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7660" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-20T10:44:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Backcountry Aviation Protection Act

This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to revise regulations to&#160;allow a properly qualified pilot operating an aircraft to conduct a go-around, an inspection pass, a practice approach, or a qualified instrument approach without regard to minimum safe altitude standards. Under current&#160;regulations, a person may not operate an aircraft below certain minimum safe altitudes except when necessary for takeoff or landing. The regulation does not include exceptions for situations such as a go-around (i.e., an aborted landing) or a practice approach.

Beginning one year after the bill's enactment, if the FAA has not published final regulations as required by the bill, the FAA may not take an enforcement action against a person related to&#160;a go-around, inspection pass, or practice approach.

Under the bill, the FAA has the burden of proof with respect to enforcement actions to prove each element of the offense and the inapplicability of each exception to the offense.</summary>
</bill>
