<bill session="116" type="h" number="3950" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Remedial Education Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a grant program for the improvement of remedial education programs at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Remedial Education Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001124" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2019-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4674" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-13T19:07:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Remedial Education Improvement Act

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to award grants to improve remedial education programs at institutions of higher education (IHEs).

ED must contract with an independent evaluator, who shall (1) consult with ED regarding which eligible entities should receive such grants, and (2) evaluate the impact of remedial education programs funded with such grants. A recipient must use grant funds to develop or improve a remedial education program through specified models, such as (1) aligning coursework between high school coursework and postsecondary education, (2) accelerating course work (e.g., by allowing multiple sequential remedial course enrollments in a semester), or (3) specifically targeting skills that students need to move forward in courses at the postsecondary level. ED must give preference to recipients that primarily serve low-income students, and it must ensure that (1) at least 30 eligible entities are awarded grants in a 5-year period, (2) grants are geographically distributed in an equitable manner, and (3) grants are used to develop or improve remedial education programs under specified models and for a range of types and sizes of IHEs.</summary>
</bill>
