<bill session="118" type="s" number="510" updated="2025-11-19T02:45:57Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expediting Israeli Aerial Refueling Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expediting Israeli Aerial Refueling Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Air Force to provide training to members of the air force of Israel on the operation of KC-46 aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1218" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2226" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T14:24:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expediting Israeli Aerial Refueling Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD), particularly the Department of the Air Force, to provide certain training and support to the air force of Israel.

Specifically, the bill requires the U.S. Air Force to train members of the air force of Israel on (1) the operation of the KC-46 aircraft, and (2) maintenance and sustainment requirements of the KC-46 aircraft.

Before completing the training required by this bill, DOD must authorize members of the air force of Israel who are associated with the operation of KC-46 aircraft to participate in the U.S. Air Force Military Personnel Exchange Program. DOD must make the program available to such members of the air force of Israel and ensure that they may participate immediately after completing training.

DOD must rotationally deploy one or more KC-46 aircraft to Israel until the earlier of five years after the enactment of this bill or the date on which a KC-46 aircraft procured by the military forces of Israel is commissioned into such military forces and achieves full combat capability.</summary>
</bill>
