<bill session="117" type="h" number="3597" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:31Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">William Becker Promoting Careers in Aviation for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that for taxable years beginning before 1980 the Federal income tax deductibility of flight training expenses shall be determined without regard to whether such expenses were reimbursed through certain veterans educational assistance allowances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">William Becker Promoting Careers in Aviation for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-05T18:14:02Z" status="Introduced in House">William Becker Promoting Careers in Aviation for America's Veterans Act

This bill modifies the treatment of reimbursed flight training expenses for tax deduction purposes and in relation to educational assistance benefits for veterans.

In taxable years before January 1, 1980, the determination of whether a deduction for flight training expenses is authorized as a trade or business expense must be made without regard to whether the taxpayer was reimbursed for any portion of such expenses by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

The bill removes the requirement that an individual must possess a valid private pilot certificate and meet certain medical requirements to utilize VA educational assistance for flight training purposes.

The VA, the Department of Defense, and the Department of Labor must develop a national strategy for providing assistance to veterans in pursuing careers in aviation.</summary>
</bill>
