<bill session="119" type="s" number="743" updated="2025-07-24T18:00:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ag Disputes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ag Disputes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prioritizing Offensive Agricultural Disputes and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the establishment of a joint task force to identify and eliminate barriers to agriculture exports of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2025-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="India"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-08T16:31:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prioritizing Offensive Agricultural Disputes and Enforcement Act or the Ag Disputes Act

This bill establishes a joint task force to identify and address trade barriers to U.S.&#160;agricultural exports.

Specifically, the bill directs the President to establish the Agricultural Trade Enforcement Task Force. Members of this task force include employees of the Department of Agriculture's Foreign Agricultural Service and the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative.

The bill requires the task force to (1) identify trade barriers to U.S. agricultural exports that are vulnerable to dispute settlement under the World Trade Organization (WTO) or other trade agreements to which the United States is a party, (2) develop and implement a strategy for enforcing violations of trade agreements related to those trade barriers, (3) identify like-minded trading partners that could act as complainants on disputes relating to specific trade barriers that are systemically or economically important to the United States, and (4) submit periodic reports to Congress.

In its first report, the task force must include a plan for filing a request for consultations under the WTO with respect to agricultural price supports implemented by the Indian government.</summary>
</bill>
