<bill session="108" type="s" number="147" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:11Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">General Attempt Provision Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18 of the United States Code to add a general provision for criminal attempt.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">General Attempt Provision Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000294"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S234" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">General Attempt Provision Act - Amends the Federal criminal code to establish a general attempt offense providing that whoever, acting with the state of mind otherwise required for the commission of a criminal offense, intentionally engages in conduct that constitutes a substantial step toward the commission of the offense, is guilty of an attempt and is subject to the same penalties as those prescribed for the offense, except the death penalty. Specifies that inability to commit the offense and failure to complete the offense are not defenses to a prosecution under this Act. Makes it an affirmative defense that the defendant prevented the commission of the offense under circumstances manifesting a voluntary and complete renunciation of criminal intent.Specifies that if two or more persons conspire to commit any offense against the United States, and one or more of such persons commit any act to effect the object of the conspiracy, each shall be subject to the same penalties (except the death penalty) as those prescribed for the most serious offense the commission of which was the object of the conspiracy.</summary>
</bill>
