<bill session="109" type="hr" number="598" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16T22:41:28-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-16T22:41:28-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Condemning actions by the Government of Syria that have hindered the investigation of the assassination of former Prime Minister of Lebanon Rafik Hariri conducted by the United Nations International Independent Investigation Commission (UNIIIC), expressing support for extending the UNIIIC's investigative mandate, and stating concern about similar assassination attempts apparently aimed at destabilizing Lebanon's security and undermining Lebanon's sovereignty.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning actions by the Government of Syria that have hindered the investigation of the assassination of former Prime Minister of Lebanon Rafik Hariri conducted by the United Nations International Independent Investigation Commission (UNIIIC), expressing support for extending the UNIIIC's investigative mandate, and stating concern about similar assassination attempts apparently aimed at destabilizing Lebanon's security and undermining Lebanon's sovereignty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000022" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2005-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2005-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T23:37:55-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T23:38:09-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11644-11649" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T23:38:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 598.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-14T23:58:28-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T22:36:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12014-12015" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="662" datetime="2005-12-16T22:41:28-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 404 - 5, 1 Present (Roll no. 662).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 12/14/2005 S11644-11645" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16T22:41:29-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Assassination"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-01-26T22:28:00Z" status="Passed House amended">Condemns the government of Syria for hindering and failing to cooperate with the United Nations International Independent Investigation Commission's (UNIIIC) investigation of former Prime Minister of Lebanon Rafik Hariri's assassination.

Supports extending UNIIIC's investigative mandate for at least six months.

 States that insecurity in Lebanon could have a destabilizing effect on the region and harm Lebanon's strengthening of democracy and economic prosperity.

Expresses gratitude to: (1) chief investigator Detlev Mehlis and UNIIIC for their continuing efforts to uncover evidence about Rafik Hariri's assassination; and (2) those who have freely assisted the UNIIIC investigation.

 Demands that Syria commit itself to fulfill all obligations with UNIIIC and with U.N. Security Council Resolutions 1559, 1595, and 1636.

Encourages the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use U.S. influence in the U.N. Security Council to advocate for the application of punitive measures and sanctions against Syria that target its leadership if Syria fails to cooperate fully with the UNIIIC investigation and continues to violate Resolutions 1559, 1595, and 1636.

Urges the U.S. government to support UNIIIC's extension of jurisdiction to include assassinations and assassination attempts in Lebanon since October 1, 2004.

 Urges the President to implement further measures against the Syrian leadership in accordance with the Syria Accountability and Lebanese Sovereignty Restoration Act of 2003 (Public Law 108-175), particularly if Syria fails to cooperate fully with the ongoing UNIIIC investigation and continues to violate Resolutions 1559, 1595, and 1636.</summary>
</bill>
