<bill session="112" type="s" number="3415" updated="2023-01-11T13:23:08Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Government Transparency and Recordkeeping Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the disclosure of all payments made under the Equal Access to Justice Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Transparency and Recordkeeping Act of 2012</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2012-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5218"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-17T18:32:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Government Transparency and Recordkeeping Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to make available to Congress and the public all records of individual payments made since January 1, 2003, from a permanent appropriation of funds (commonly referred to as the Judgment Fund) available to the federal government to pay certain final judgments, awards, and compromise settlements (including appropriate attorney's fees, interest, and costs under the Equal Access to Justice Act [EAJA]) resulting from claims against the United States.

Requires the publicly available records to be updated annually to include payments made during the previous year.

Requires such records, including a payment breakdowns showing the specific amount of the damages, interest, and attorneys' fees, to be maintained on a publicly accessible Internet website.

Prohibits records from being made available under this Act if: (1) the payment was not the result of any executive branch, federal agency, or instrumentality statutory or regulatory approval or permit related case, court order, consent decree, or settlement; or (2) the disclosure of the information is otherwise prohibited by law or court order, or is not in the best interest of national security.</summary>
</bill>
