<bill session="119" type="h" number="1152" updated="2025-10-09T00:06:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-31T17:44:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-31T17:44:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Filing and Payment Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Electronic Filing and Payment Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Electronic Filing and Payment Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short">Electronic Filing and Payment Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="display">Electronic Filing and Payment Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the application of the mailbox rule to documents and payments electronically submitted to the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2025-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 41 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 119-45.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-27" calendar="Union" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:36:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (MO) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:36:26-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1354-1356: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:36:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1152.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-03-31T17:44:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1355" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:44:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1075" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-28T15:12:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Electronic Filing and Payment Fairness Act 

This bill provides that a federal tax document or payment that is electronically submitted to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) shall be considered delivered to the IRS on the date such document or payment is sent. Further, the bill requires the IRS to issue guidance on electronically submitted federal tax documents and payments no later than December 31, 2025.

Under current law, a federal tax document or payment that is sent by mail is considered delivered to the IRS on the date that such document or payment is postmarked and is considered timely if the postmark date is on or before the due date of such document or payment. (This is known as the mailbox rule.)

Further, under current law, the IRS is authorized to provide guidance on electronically submitted federal tax documents but not payments. In accordance with such authority, IRS guidance provides that the date that an authorized electronic return transmitter receives the transmission of an electronically filed document on its host system is the electronic postmark date.

The bill expands the mailbox rule to include all electronically submitted federal tax documents and payments and specifically requires the IRS to provide guidance on electronically submitted payments.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-45</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
