<bill session="109" type="h" number="3558" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:31Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to provide compensation to members of the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for damage resulting from the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1685"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1535" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-13T21:04:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Amendments Act of 2005 - Amends the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe Equitable Compensation Act to make member landowners eligible for the additional financial compensation provided to the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribe for the acquisition by the federal government of 104,492 acres of land of the Tribe and member landowners for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir project. Defines member landowner as a member of the Tribe (or an heir of such a member) that owned land on the Cheyenne River Sioux Reservation that was acquired by the United States for the Oahe Dam and Reservoir Project.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to deposit into the Cheyenne River Sioux Tribal Recovery Trust Fund an amount equal to 25% of the amount deposited into the Treasury from the power program during the preceding fiscal year for the period between October 1, 2004, and the last date of the fiscal year during which the total amount deposited into the Treasury from the power program equals a specified amount.

Authorizes the plan prepared for the use of payments to the Tribe to provide for payment of additional compensation to member landowners.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to assist the Tribe in claims processing by providing any record requested to identify the heirs of member landowners within 60 days after receiving a request.</summary>
</bill>
