<bill session="111" type="s" number="750" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:40Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Caring for an Aging America Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to attract and retain trained health care professionals and direct care workers dedicated to providing quality care to the growing population of older Americans.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Caring for an Aging America Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4073"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3098" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-21T18:34:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Caring for an Aging America Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish a Geriatric and Gerontology Loan Repayment Program to enter into contracts with qualified physicians, nurse practitioners, clinical nurse specialists, pharmacists, social workers, physician assistants, and psychologists to pay educational loans in exchange for providing full-time clinical practice and service to older adults; and (2) establish the National Advisory Council on the Geriatric and Gerontology Loan Repayment Program.

Requires the Secretary to ensure that individuals eligible for the nurse loan repayment program include registered nurses who complete specialty training in geriatrics or gerontology and who elect to provide nursing services to older adults in home and long-term care settings.

Authorizes the Secretary to award nursing education grants and enter into contracts for programs that focus on specialty training in providing long-term care services for nursing personnel who provide services in home and long-term care settings.

Requires the Secretary to establish a Health and Long-Term Care Workforce Advisory Panel to: (1) examine, and provide advice on, workforce issues related to health and long-term care for the aging population; and (2) conduct a research project to identify incentives for recruitment and retention of clinicians and providers who agree to serve vulnerable older adults in geriatric and long-term care settings.</summary>
</bill>
