<bill session="109" type="s" number="1634" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:03Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-08">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow United States courts to conduct business during emergency conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2005-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2005-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2005-09-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9774-9776" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9775-9776" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T13:08:59-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08T15:27:37-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3650" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-13T18:35:38Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Federal Judiciary Emergency Special Sessions Act of 2005 - Allows federal circuit courts of appeals, district courts, bankruptcy courts, and magistrate judges to hold special sessions outside their circuits or districts upon a finding by a chief judge or judicial council that, because of emergency conditions, no location within the courts' regular circuits or districts is reasonably available. Authorizes such courts to transact any business, except certain district court criminal proceedings, at a special session outside their circuits or districts which they might transact at a regular session.

Requires special session courts, through the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts, to notify the Judiciary Committees of Congress of any order issued in a special session. Requires the Administrative Office to report to such congressional committees describing the reasons for the issuance of a special session order, the duration of such order, the impact of such order on litigants, and the costs to the judiciary resulting from such order. Requires special session courts to provide reasonable notice to the U.S. Marshals Service before the commencement of any special session.

Prohibits a criminal trial from being conducted at a special session outside the state in which the crime was committed unless the defendant consents. Restricts criminal jury pools to the district in which a crime was committed unless the defendant consents to be tried by jurors from the district in which the trial court is holding a special session.</summary>
</bill>
