<bill session="116" type="s" number="4242" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:38Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Addiction Prevention and Responsible Opioid Practices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Addiction Prevention and Responsible Opioid Practices Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish programs related to prevention of prescription opioid misuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4351-4354" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7701" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-23T16:20:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Addiction Prevention and Responsible Opioid Practices Act

This bill addresses substance use and mental health related to opiods, including by imposing an excise tax on opioids; modifying controlled substances regulations, prescription drug monitoring programs (PDMPs), and health insurance coverage; and requiring other activities.

Specifically, the bill (1) establishes federal licensure requirements for pharmaceutical representatives who market opioids, (2) requires certain training and PDMP participation as conditions for controlled substance registration, and (3) withdraws regulatory approval for opioids with ultra-high doses.

In addition, as a condition for receiving certain grants, recipients must, for example, mandate the use of PDMPs in specified ways and increase data-sharing. Additionally, to meet certain certification standards, health information technology must be interoperable with PDMPs.

Additionally, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must reimburse mental health services provided through telehealth under Medicare and develop a web-based tool to compare opioid prescribing in state Medicaid programs. The bill also creates grants to support compliance with requirements to provide parity in insurance coverage for mental health and substance use disorder services. The Government Accountability Office must study health care coverage and reimbursements for substance use disorder treatments.

Furthermore, the Department of Health and Human Services and the CMS must develop quality measures and guidelines for treatment of non-fatal overdoses, and the Department of Justice must operate a drug take-back program. The National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine and medical and dental schools must also report on Medicare coverage of non-opioid treatment for back pain and educational courses on pain management and opioid prescribing practices, respectively.</summary>
</bill>
