<bill session="115" type="s" number="3457" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:21Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SWIFT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to increase survivors benefits for disabled widows, widowers, and surviving divorced spouses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surviving Widow(er) Income Fair Treatment Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWIFT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2018-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2018-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2018-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2018-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-07T20:56:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Surviving Widow(er) Income Fair Treatment Act of 2018 or the SWIFT Act 

This bill modifies eligibility requirements and increases benefits for widows, widowers, and surviving divorced spouses under the Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) benefits program.

The bill makes widow and widower's benefits available to disabled individuals at any age, whereas currently the benefits are limited to such individuals between ages 50 to 60. Provisions reducing benefits in various instances, such as when a beneficiary is entitled to multiple types of benefits, shall not apply to widow and widower's benefits for individuals with disabilities.

For determining whether a beneficiary has a child in his or her care, the bill raises the upper age limit for the child from 16 to 18 years (or 19, if the child is a full-time elementary or secondary school student). An individual with a child in care&#160;may receive increased benefits in&#160;specified instances.

The bill also increases various limits on&#160;widow and widower's benefits in certain instances and modifies the calculation for increased benefits for individuals who choose to delay receiving such benefits.

For current beneficiaries, increases in OASDI benefits under this bill shall not affect the beneficiary's eligibility for any federal assistance program or the benefit amount to be received under such an assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
