<bill session="116" type="h" number="8819" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Solid Start Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solid Start Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve and expand the Solid Start program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2020-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2020-11-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4724" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-10T19:36:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Solid Start Act of 2020

This bill permanently authorizes and expands the Solid Start program, which is an outreach program for veterans in their first year of separation from the military.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to coordinate with the Department of Defense to

 collect updated contact information during transition classes or separation counseling for members of the Armed Forces who are separating from service, explain the existence and purpose of the program, call veterans at least twice within the first year of separation, publish information about the program in booklets and on the VA website, provide information about veterans' eligibility for VA programs and benefits, and prioritize outreach to veterans who have accessed mental health resources prior to separation from the Armed Forces. Under the bill, the VA is authorized to (1) encourage members of the Armed Forces to provide additional contact information if they are unreachable following their separation, (2) follow up on missed phone calls, and (3) reach out to veterans who separated prior to the initiation of the Solid Start program.

The Government Accountability Office must assess and report on the Solid Start program.</summary>
</bill>
