<bill session="112" type="s" number="1816" updated="2019-02-20T23:20:35Z">
  <state datetime="2011-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to modify a provision relating to minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to modify a provision relating to minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2012-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2011-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3810" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1813" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-07T16:29:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the federal-aid highway program to modify the minimum penalties states are required to impose on motorists convicted multiple times for driving while intoxicated or under the influence of alcohol.

Requires repeat offenders to have: (1) all their driving privileges suspended (currently, a driver's license suspension) for at least one year; or (2) a combination of suspension of unlimited driving privileges for one year, allowing for reinstatement of limited driving privileges, subject to restrictions and limited exemptions as established under state law, if an ignition interlock device is installed for at least one year on each of the motor vehicles they own or operate.

Eliminates the current alternative of a combination of suspension of all driving privileges for the first 45 days of the suspension period followed by a reinstatement of limited driving privileges for the purpose of getting to and from work, school, or an alcohol treatment program if an ignition interlock device is installed on each of the motor vehicles owned or operated, or both, by the individual.</summary>
</bill>
