<bill session="118" type="s" number="3696" updated="2025-11-18T21:26:59Z">
  <state datetime="2024-07-23">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEFIANCE Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEFIANCE Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disrupt Explicit Forged Images And Non-Consensual Edits Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DEFIANCE Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Disrupt Explicit Forged Images and Non-Consensual Edits Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve rights to relief for individuals affected by non-consensual activities involving intimate digital forgeries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2024-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2024-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2024-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2024-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5318-5319" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-07-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5317-5318" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-07-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-24T15:55:44-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-24T16:02:58-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7569" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3049"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-08-22T17:04:20Z" status="Passed Senate">Disrupt Explicit Forged Images and Non-Consensual Edits Act of 2024 or the DEFIANCE Act of 2024

This bill establishes a civil cause of action for individuals who are the subject of nonconsensual digital forgeries (commonly known as deepfakes) depicting intimate activity or nudity.

Under the bill, digital forgery is any intimate visual depiction of an identifiable individual created through the use of software, machine learning, artificial intelligence, or any other computer-generated or technological means that is indistinguishable from an authentic visual depiction of the individual.

Specifically, an identifiable individual who is the subject of a digital forgery may bring a civil action against any person who knowingly produces, distributes, solicits, or possesses with the intent to distribute a digital forgery without the individual's consent.

Current law provides civil remedies, including damages and injunctive relief,&#160;for the nonconsensual disclosure of intimate images. This bill makes all relief available for the new cause of action for nonconsensual digital forgeries&#160;and expands the relief available for both causes of action. For example, an identifiable individual may recover profits of the defendant that are attributable to the conduct at issue in&#160;the claim as part of&#160;actual damages.

The bill also establishes a 10-year statute of limitations, but tolls the running of the statute of limitations until the individual learns about the violation or the individual turns 18, whichever occurs later. This applies to both current law related to nonconsensual disclosure of intimate images and the new cause of action for nonconsensual digital forgeries.</summary>
</bill>
