<bill session="118" type="s" number="437" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bicycles for Rural African Transport Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bicycles for Rural African Transport Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish within the Office of Gender Equality and Women's Empowerment of the United States Agency for International Development a rural mobility program to promote mobility in rural communities through access to affordable, fit-for-purpose bicycles, provide support to sustainably increase access to rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S427-428" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="992" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-29T20:27:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bicycles for Rural African Transport Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the U.S. Agency for International Development to administer a bicycle mobility program in rural areas of sub-Saharan Africa.

The purpose of the program is to (1) promote rural communities' access to critical services and opportunities by means of affordable bicycles; and (2) provide support to sustainably increase access to critical services in rural areas, including through support for rural-based mechanics, access to spare parts, and reduction of social and gender-based stigma. To the greatest extent practicable, the program must partner with overseas entities that have successful models for providing access to affordable bicycles.</summary>
</bill>
