<bill session="118" type="s" number="1655" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare for All Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Medicare-for-all national health insurance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-20T15:20:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare for All Act

This bill establishes a national health insurance program that is administered by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).

Among other requirements, the program must (1) cover all U.S. residents; (2) provide for automatic enrollment of individuals upon birth or residency in the United States; and (3) cover items and services that are medically necessary or appropriate to maintain health or to diagnose, treat, or rehabilitate a health condition, including hospital services, prescription drugs, mental health and substance abuse treatment, dental and vision services, home- and community-based long-term care, gender affirming care, and reproductive care, including contraception and abortions.

The bill prohibits cost-sharing (e.g., deductibles, coinsurance, and copayments) and&#160;other charges for covered services, with the exception of prescription drugs. Additionally, private health insurers and employers may only offer coverage that is supplemental to, and not duplicative of, benefits provided under the program.

Health insurance exchanges and specified federal health programs terminate upon program implementation. However, the program does not affect coverage provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs, TRICARE, or the Indian Health Service. Additionally, state Medicaid programs must cover certain institutional long-term care services.

The bill also establishes a series of implementing provisions relating to (1) health care provider participation; (2) HHS administration; and (3) payments and costs, including the requirement that HHS negotiate prices for prescription drugs and establish a formulary.

Individuals who are age 18 or younger may enroll in the program starting one year after enactment of this bill; other individuals may buy into a transitional plan or an expanded Medicare program at this time, depending on age. The bill's program must be fully implemented four years after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
