<bill session="118" type="h" number="9825" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Head Start Eligibility Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Head Start Eligibility Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Head Start Act to include TANF, SSI, SNAP, WIC, and federal housing assistance as eligible public assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-09T16:00:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Head Start Eligibility Act of 2024

This bill expands eligibility for Head Start programs to include the children of families eligible for specified public assistance programs.&#160;

Specifically, the bill expands Head Start eligibility to include the children of families that qualify for the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC), the Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations (FDPIR), and federal housing assistance (commonly known as Section 8). The bill also provides statutory authority for the eligibility of families that qualify for Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF), Supplemental Security Income (SSI), and the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP). Families that qualify for state-funded food assistance programs with eligibility standards identical or substantially similar to the standards for SNAP shall also be eligible for Head Start.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
