<bill session="108" type="h" number="4788" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:15Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Guard and Reservists Education Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to States for tuition assistance for undergraduate studies for members of the Selected Reserve at public institutions of higher learning.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard and Reservists Education Benefits Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000793"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-30T19:44:06Z" status="Introduced in House">National Guard and Reservists Education Benefits Act - Requires the Secretary of Education to carry out a program of block grants to States (defined to include U.S. territories and the District of Columbia) to pay tuition and fees for undergraduate studies at public institutions for members of the Selected Reserve.

Excludes from the block grant program those members of the Selected Reserve who participate in other specified educational assistance programs.

Requires the chief executive officer of each State wishing to receive block grant funds to submit an annual certification that the State will: (1) use such funds to defray the cost of undergraduate tuition and fees for members of the Selected Reserve; (2) return any unused funds to the Secretary according to the reconciliation process set forth in this Act; and (3) comply with the reporting requirements of this Act.

Sets forth an allotment scheme for block grant funds that requires allotments to reflect the ratio of Selected Reserve members in the receiving State to Selected Reserve members in all States. Establishes minimum allotments.</summary>
</bill>
