<bill session="116" type="h" number="7831" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Farm to School Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Farm to School Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a pilot program to provide selected States with an increased reimbursement for school lunches that are comprised of locally-grown and unprocessed foods, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000630"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2020-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-25T19:52:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Farm to School Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to award three-year grants to eight states or tribal organizations to provide school food authorities with an increased reimbursement for free and reduced price lunches that are comprised of locally-grown and unprocessed foods procured directly from certain agricultural producers.

USDA must select at least one state or tribal organization located in each of the following regions: (1) the Mid-Atlantic Region, (2) the Midwest Region, (3) the Mountain Plains Region, (4) the Northeast Region, (5) the Southern Region, (6) the Southwest Region, and (7) the Western Region.

USDA must give the highest priority to applications that propose to carry out certain projects, including projects that (1) serve a high proportion of children from socially disadvantaged backgrounds, and (2) increase the availability of locally-produced and unprocessed foods to children. Additionally, priority must be given to states or tribal organizations with a high quantity and variety of growers of local fruits and vegetables on a per capita basis, and with a demonstrated commitment to farm-to-school activities.

Each state or tribal organization that receives a grant must provide, from non-federal sources, an amount equal to 100% of the awarded grant amount.</summary>
</bill>
