<bill session="116" type="s" number="4194" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Institute of Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Institute of Manufacturing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Institute of Manufacturing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-24T19:43:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Institute of Manufacturing Act

This bill establishes the National Institute of Manufacturing to serve as the central hub for federal manufacturing programs, and it directs the institute to coordinate such programs across agencies through a national strategic plan for manufacturing.

The institute shall, among other things, (1) convene key stakeholders to develop a national strategic plan for manufacturing in the United States that identifies the needs and priorities of the U.S. manufacturing sector; (2) support and incentivize manufacturing-focused research, collaboration, and education; and (3) be the primary federal entity for all decisions related to manufacturing.

Overseen by a Chief Manufacturing Officer, the institute shall be composed of various directorates (e.g., a Directorate for Technology Development and a Directorate for Trade), and the functions of specified federal manufacturing programs and offices shall be transferred to the institute and its directorates.

The bill also permanently reauthorizes the U.S. Manufacturing Council of the International Trade Administration as the National Manufacturing Council, and it tasks the council with (1) ensuring regular communication between the federal government and the U.S. manufacturing sector, (2) advising the institute's Chief Manufacturing Officer on government policies and programs that affect U.S. manufacturing, and (3) ensuring the U.S. remains the leading destination for investment in manufacturing throughout the world.

Lastly, the bill requires the Chief Manufacturing Officer to establish the manufacturing.gov hub, a section of the Department of Commerce's website that shall serve as the primary point for information relating to every federal manufacturing program.</summary>
</bill>
