<bill session="108" type="h" number="5340" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:39Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer Abuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide additional protections for recipients of the earned income tax credit.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Abuse Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2947" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Electronic benefits transfers"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Garnishment"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-11-29T19:41:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Taxpayer Abuse Prevention Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide that advance payments of the earned income tax credit are not transferable or assignable or subject to the claims of any creditors, except outstanding claims of the Federal Government.

Prohibits: (1) the collection of a debt from a debtor's Federal tax refund by means of a refund anticipation loan; and (2) mandatory arbitration as a condition of providing a refund anticipation loan.

Terminates the Department of Treasury Debt Indicator Program.

Excludes tax returns that have been filed subject to a refund anticipation loan from any determination of whether goals for electronic filing of tax returns have been met.

Allows earned income tax credit benefits to be paid through electronic transfer accounts.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) develop and implement a program to encourage the greater use of the advance earned income tax credit; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with federally insured depository institutions to provide low- and moderate-income taxpayers with the option of establishing low-cost direct deposit accounts using appropriate tax forms.</summary>
</bill>
