<bill session="119" type="h" number="1398" updated="2025-06-02T13:38:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing Strictly Needy Americans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Pivotal (SNAP) Benefits Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Strictly Needy Americans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Pivotal (SNAP) Benefits Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023, to limit the conditions applicable to the use of electronic benefit transfer (EBT) cards to purchase food, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000379" joined="2025-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2025-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-02T13:37:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Strictly Needy Americans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Pivotal (SNAP) Benefits Act of 2025

This bill establishes additional limitations on the use of&#160;Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits.

The bill requires that a state agency suspend a SNAP household account when the Electronic Benefits Transfer (EBT) card transactions are made exclusively out-of-state for a period longer than 60 days. The state agency must maintain the suspension until (1) the household affirmatively provides substantiating evidence that the participating household members still reside in the state from which they receive benefits, or (2) an investigation conclusively determines that the participating&#160;household members still reside in the state from which they receive benefits.

In addition, a SNAP household may not redeem SNAP benefits at a SNAP-approved retail food store or wholesale food concern that is owned by a household member. This does not apply to a retail food store or a wholesale food concern that is owned by a publicly owned corporation or a government.</summary>
</bill>
