<bill session="119" type="h" number="5836" updated="2025-11-05T09:05:47Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keep WIC Working Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep WIC Working Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make continuing appropriations for the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children in the event of a Government shutdown.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000598" joined="2025-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001230" joined="2025-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2025-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001228" joined="2025-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-30T14:11:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep WIC Working Act

This bill provides appropriations for the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to carry out the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) during any lapse in FY2026 discretionary appropriations for USDA. WIC provides nutrition-rich foods, nutrition education, and health care and social services referrals to eligible low-income women, infants, and children.

The bill also provides appropriations for USDA to reimburse state agencies for any state funds used to carry out operations necessary to maintain participation in WIC during the period that began on September 30, 2025, and ends on the date that this bill is enacted.

The appropriations provided by this bill are available until legislation is enacted that provides FY2026 appropriations for USDA (including continuing appropriations for USDA).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
