<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1256</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:22:52Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:22:52Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-06-22</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
        <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported original measure</name>
            <date>2011-06-22T20:01:47Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1253</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-07-13</actionDate>
          <text>Senate Committee on Armed Services. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-80, pt. 2.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1867</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-12-01</actionDate>
          <text>See also H.R. 1540.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 83.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Levin. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Levin. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000261</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Levin, Carl [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>CARL</firstName>
        <lastName>LEVIN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <middleName>MILTON</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Arms control and nonproliferation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computers and information technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Defense spending</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Idaho</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Illinois</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Kentucky</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement officers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and inland water transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military facilities and property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military procurement, research, weapons development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Missouri</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nevada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New York State</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear weapons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Russia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>South Carolina</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Strategic materials and reserves</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tennessee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Texas</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-07-05T19:56:25Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Department of Energy National Security Act of 2012 - Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY2012 for: (1) activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration in carrying out programs necessary for national security, and (2) environmental management activities in carrying out national security programs, with specified allocations for defense environmental cleanup and other defense activities.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Energy to annually review and report on computer security vulnerabilities at each DOE national laboratory.</p> <p>Recognizes the museum operated by the Nevada Test Site Historical Foundation and located in Las Vegas, Nevada, as the official atomic testing museum of the United States.</p> <p>Requires: (1) a report on the feasibility of federalizing the security protective forces contract guard workforce at specified DOE facilities, and (2) a study on oversight of DOE defense nuclear facilities.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2012 for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.</p> <p>Sets forth Maritime Administration organization provisions.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>80</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-09-26T19:32:01Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Department of Energy National Security Act of 2012 - <b>Division C: Department of Energy National Security Authorizations and Other Authorizations - Title XXXI [<i>sic</i>]: Department of Energy National Security Programs - Subtitle A: National Security Programs Authorizations </b>- (Sec. 3101) Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY2012 for: (1) activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA) in carrying out programs necessary for national security, and (2) environmental restoration and waste management activities and plant projects in carrying out national security programs, with specified allocations for defense environmental cleanup and other defense activities.</p> <p><b>Subtitle B: Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations</b> - (Sec. 3111) Amends the Atomic Energy Defense Act to terminate the requirement of an annual independent &quot;red team&quot; review of the security and vulnerabilities of computers at DOE national laboratories, as well as a National Counterintelligence Policy Board annual report on review results. Requires instead the Secretary of Energy to conduct such annual review and report review results to the congressional defense and appropriations committees only when a significant vulnerability is discovered.</p> <p>(Sec. 3112) Amends the National Nuclear Security Administration Act to direct the Secretary to: (1) review an assessment by the Comptroller General ( CG) of budget requests with respect to the modernization and refurbishment of the DOE nuclear security complex, and (2) report review results to the defense and appropriations committees.</p> <p>(Sec. 3113) Allows the Secretary to procure no more than one aircraft using DOE weapons activities funds for any fiscal year before FY2013.</p> <p>(Sec. 3114) Limits to $500,000 the amount of DOE nuclear nonproliferation funds that may be used to establish a center of excellence in a country not a state of the former Soviet Union until 15 days after the NNSA Administrator identifies the country involved and describes the center's purpose.</p> <p>(Sec. 3115) Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1992 and 1993 to recognize the museum operated by the Nevada Test Site Historical Foundation in Las Vegas, Nevada, as the official atomic testing museum of the United States.</p> <p><b>Subtitle C: Reports </b>- (Sec. 3121) Directs the Secretary and the NNSA Administrator to jointly submit to the defense and appropriations committees: (1) a report on the feasibility of federalizing some or all of the security protective forces contract guard workforce at specified DOE national laboratories and facilities, and (2) the CG's comments on such report.</p> <p>(Sec. 3122) Requires the CG to: (1) study the value of and need for external regulation or oversight of the safety of nuclear operations and the design and construction of DOE nuclear facilities to protect the public health and safety, and (2) submit to the defense and appropriations committees an interim and final report on study results. Requires comments on such reports by the Secretary, the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board, and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC).</p> <p>(Sec. 3123) Directs the NNSA Administrator to submit to Congress a plan to complete the Global Initiatives for Proliferation Prevention program in the Russian Federation by the end of 2013.</p> <p><b>Title XXXII: Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board </b>- (Sec. 3201) Authorizes appropriations for FY2012 for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board (Board).</p> <p>(Sec. 3202) Directs the Board to exercise its authority to review the design of, and review and monitor construction with respect to, NNSA Project 10-D-904.</p> <p><b>Title XXXIII: Maritime Administration </b>- (Sec. 3301) Revises generally provisions concerning the establishment and authorization of appropriations for the Maritime Administration. </p><p><br> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Department of Energy National Security Act of 2012</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Department of Energy National Security Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Department of Energy National Security Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Department of Energy National Security Act of 2012</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2012 for defense activities of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2011-06-22T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1256rs/xml/BILLS-112s1256rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-06-22</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 83.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
