<bill session="108" type="s" number="1279" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Area Health and Environmental Monitoring Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to carry out a program for the protection of the health and safety of residents, workers, volunteers, and others in a disaster area.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Disaster Area Health and Environmental Monitoring Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Disaster Area Health and Environmental Monitoring Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Area Health and Environmental Monitoring Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2003-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8131-8133" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-03">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-183.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="360">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 360.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="S15503-15507" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S15503-15505" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15503-15507" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25T12:02:35-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="5329" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child care workers"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Post-traumatic stress disorder"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2210"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2003-12-01T21:37:41Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Disaster Area Health and Environmental Monitoring Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President, if one or more chemicals or substances associated with potential acute or chronic human health effects (substances of concern) are being or have been released in a disaster area, to carry out a program for the protection, assessment, monitoring, and study of the health and safety of individuals.

Requires such a program to ensure that: (1) the individuals are adequately informed about and protected against potential health impacts of the substance of concern and potential mental health impacts in a timely manner; (2) they are monitored and studied over time for any such impacts, both short- and long-term; (3) they receive needed health care referrals; and (4) information from any such monitoring and studies is used to prevent or protect against similar health impacts from future disasters.

Allows the program to include such activities as: (1) collecting and analyzing environmental exposure data; (2) developing and disseminating information and educational materials; (3) performing baseline and followup clinical health and mental health examinations and taking biological samples; (4) establishing and maintaining an exposure registry; (5) studying the short- and long-term human health impacts of any exposures through epidemiological and other health studies; and (6) providing assistance to individuals in determining eligibility for health coverage and identifying appropriate health services.

Requires activities under any such program (including baseline health examinations), to the maximum extent practicable, to be commenced in a timely manner that will ensure the highest level of public health protection and effective monitoring.

Makes participation in any registry or study voluntary. Requires the President to take appropriate measures to protect the privacy of any registry or study participant.

Authorizes the President to carry out such a program through a cooperative agreement with a medical institution (including a local health department) or a consortium of medical institutions, especially those located near the disaster area and any other area in which there reside groups of individuals that worked or volunteered in response to the disaster. Requires such an institution to have appropriate experience in the areas of environmental or occupational health, toxicology, and safety.

Requires the President, in establishing and maintaining such a program, to involve interested and affected Federal, State,and local parties, including in advisory or oversight committees or boards.

Requires the President to carry out such a program in accordance with certain regulations promulgated under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 with respect to privacy of individually identifiable health information exchanged in electronic transmissions.

(Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to enter jointly into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study and report on disaster area health and environmental protection and monitoring, including: (1) establishment of monitoring and response protocols; (2) Federal, State, and local agency responsibilities; and (3) capabilities and capacity within the Federal Government to conduct appropriate environmental monitoring and response in the event of a disaster, including a terrorist attack.

Authorizes appropriations.

(Sec. 4) Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to extend from December 31, 2003, through September 30, 2006, the President's authority to establish a program to provide technical and financial assistance to State and local governments to assist in the implementation of cost-effective predisaster hazard mitigation measures designed to reduce injuries, loss of life, and damage and destruction of property.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-183</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
