<bill session="108" type="s" number="49" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:06Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Deficit Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the deficit of the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deficit Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Irrigation Subsidy Reform Act of 2001</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S51-53"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S53-54" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Farm corporations"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Submarines"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Water allocation (Policy)"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deficit Reduction Act of 2003 - Irrigation Subsidy Reduction Act of 2001 (sic) - Amends the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 to direct the Secretary of the Interior, for each parcel of land to which irrigation water is delivered or proposed to be delivered, to identify a single individual or legal entity as the owner, lessee, or operator.Allows irrigation water to be delivered at less than the normal per-acre cost to either: (1) a qualified recipient that reports gross farm income from a single farm operation in excess of $500,000 per taxable year; or (2) a limited recipient that received such water on or before October 1, 1981, and that reports gross farm income in excess of such amount.Requires lessees (currently, only owners and operators) of an irrigation district to furnish such district a certification of compliance with the Act. Allows the Secretary to require a lessee or operator to submit for examination a copy of a tax return for any taxable year in which the single farm operation of the lessee or operator received irrigation water at less than full cost.Repeals a provision exempting from Federal reclamation ownership and cost pricing limitations district lands held in trust for a beneficiary or beneficiaries whose interests in the lands served do not exceed such limitations.Directs the Secretaries of the Interior, the Treasury, and Agriculture to enter into a memorandum of understanding to permit the Secretary of the Interior to have access to and use available information collected or maintained by either the Department of the Treasury or Agriculture that would aid in enforcement of the ownership and pricing limitations of Federal reclamation law.Terminates the Uniformed Services University of Health Science.Requires the Secretary of Defense to terminate production of D5 submarine-launched ballistic missiles under the D5 submarine-launched ballistic missile program.</summary>
</bill>
