<bill session="108" type="s" number="1609" updated="2023-01-15T07:02:59Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROMISE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make aliens ineligible to receive visas and exclude aliens from admission into the United States for nonpayment of child support.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Parental Responsibility Obligations Met through Immigration System Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">PROMISE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parental Responsibility Obligations Met through Immigration System Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROMISE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2004-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11417-11418"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11418" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="511">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 511.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4644" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Paternity"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-17T20:13:14Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Parental Responsibility Obligations Met through Immigration System Enforcement Act or PROMISE Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to render aliens inadmissible for nonpayment of child support if arrearages exceed a specified amount unless payments are satisfied or the alien is in compliance with an approved payment agreement.

Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to parole such inadmissible aliens into the United States if parole is essential to the fulfillment of child support and the alien is placed in removal proceedings, has authorized employment, and is otherwise admissible. Prohibits entry of a final removal order against such aliens during the pendency of State court child support proceedings.

Adds nonpayment of child support to the INA's list of conduct barring a finding that an alien is a person of good moral character unless support payments are satisfied or the alien is in compliance with an approved payment agreement.

Authorizes immigration officers to serve process in child support or paternity cases on aliens seeking admission.

Amends the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, upon request by the Attorney General, Secretary of Homeland Security, or Secretary of State, to provide authorized persons with information that may aid alien child support delinquency determinations. Prohibits the further disclosure of such information other than for Federal law enforcement purposes. Authorizes disciplinary action and civil penalties for unauthorized disclosures.</summary>
</bill>
