<bill session="119" type="s" number="318" updated="2025-10-11T08:05:25Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-08">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="display">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a plan to improve the cybersecurity and telecommunications of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-29">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cruz with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 119-64.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-09-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="169">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 169.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2025-10-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-10-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-10T12:33:04-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-10T12:33:05-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-01T16:56:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act or the ANCHOR Act&#160;

This bill requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) to develop a plan to improve the cybersecurity and telecommunications capabilities of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet (ARF).

ARF is comprised of U.S.-flagged vessels that provide at-sea laboratories where oceanographic scientists, educators, and students research and learn about marine science.&#160;

The bill requires the plan to include assessments of

telecommunications and networking needs of ARF, consistent with typical scientific missions;cybersecurity needs appropriate for the ownership of ARF vessels and their typical research functions;the costs necessary to meet these needs; andthe time required to implement necessary upgrades.The plan must also include (1) a spending plan for the NSF, the Office of Naval Research, nonfederal&#160;owners of ARF vessels,&#160;and users of the vessels to cover identified costs; and (2) a proposal regarding the adoption of common solutions or&#160;consortial licensing agreements, or the centralization of cybersecurity, telecommunications, or data management at a single facility.&#160;

Among other factors specified in the bill, the&#160;NSF must consider the network capabilities necessary to meet mission needs (e.g., to upload data to shoreside servers), international standards and guidance for information security, and requirements for controlled unclassified or classified information.&#160;

The plan must be provided to Congress within one year of the bill's enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-64</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
