<bill session="116" type="h" number="5996" updated="2022-02-09T00:41:26Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SUN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require that return information from tax-exempt organizations be made available in a searchable format and to provide the disclosure of the identity of contributors to certain tax-exempt organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sunlight for Unaccountable Non-profits Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2020-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2020-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="735" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-11T18:33:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Sunlight for Unaccountable Non-profits Act or the SUN Act

 This bill expands the disclosure requirements for certain tax-exempt organizations. It requires (1) the annual tax return information for tax-exempt organizations and deferred compensation plans to be made available to the public at no charge and in an open structured data format that is processable by computers, with the information easy to find, access, reuse, and download in bulk; and (2) the disclosure of the names and addresses of contributors of $5,000 or more to tax-exempt organizations that participate or intervene in political campaigns on behalf of, or in opposition to, any candidate for public office.

The Internal Revenue Service may withhold from public inspection any Social Security account number included on Form 990 (information returns for tax-exempt organizations).</summary>
</bill>
