<bill session="110" type="h" number="6230" updated="2019-11-15T20:55:44Z">
  <state datetime="2008-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Rating Agency Transparency and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="display">Credit Rating Agency Transparency and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require nationally registered statistical rating organizations to provide additional disclosures with respect to the rating of certain structured securities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000243" joined="2008-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-09-03T14:57:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Credit Rating Agency Transparency and Disclosure Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to instruct the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to promulgate rules that: (1) require nationally recognized statistical rating organizations (NRSROs), with respect to their determination of credit ratings for structured securities, to disclose the information they require from originators, issuers, and underwriters regarding the collateral underlying such securities; (2) establish procedures to disseminate information about processes used by such originators, issuers, and underwriters to assess the accuracy and integrity of their data and fraud detection; and (3) require each NRSRO to maintain on a publicly accessible Internet site the historical default rates of all classes of financial products it has rated.</summary>
</bill>
