<bill session="116" type="s" number="4077" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unfunded Mandates Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unfunded Mandates Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Unfunded Mandates Accountability and Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 to provide for regulatory impact analyses for certain rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2020-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment. With written report No. 116-333.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="643">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 643.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="870" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7332" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-22T16:45:52Z" status="Reported to Senate">Unfunded Mandates Accountability and Transparency Act

This bill revises rulemaking requirements with respect to unfunded mandates.

Specifically, the bill requires federal agencies to prepare and publish in the Federal Register an initial and final regulatory impact analysis prior to promulgating any proposed or final major rule. The analysis must include regulatory alternatives to the rule.

Major rule means a rule that the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs determines is likely to cause

 an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, federal, state, local, or tribal government agencies, or geographic regions; or significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, public health and safety, or the ability of U.S.-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets. Before promulgating any proposed or final major rule, an agency shall select the regulatory alternative that maximizes net benefits, taking into consideration only the costs and benefits that arise within the scope of the statutory provision that authorizes the rulemaking, with exceptions.

The bill prohibits Congress from considering a bill that increases private sector costs more than a certain amount unless certain conditions are met.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-333</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
