<bill session="117" type="h" number="4169" updated="2022-12-31T04:58:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase market access for Black farmers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers, to ensure civil rights accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Black Farmers and Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Increased Market Share Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Black Farmers and Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Increased Market Share Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-02T20:01:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Black Farmers and Socially Disadvantaged Farmers Increased Market Share Act

This bill addresses ways to increase market access for socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers and to ensure civil rights accountability for Department of Agriculture (USDA) employees. (Socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers are those who have been subjected to racial or ethnic prejudice because of their identity as members of a group without regard to individual qualities.)

Specifically, USDA must establish a program to make grants to support new or expanding food hubs designed to increase market access for socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers.

USDA shall establish a process to prioritize the purchase of agricultural food products from socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers. That process must account for barriers to market entry faced by socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers while maintaining the integrity of the purchasing process.

The bill also establishes an agriculture hub income tax credit, which shall be an amount equal to 25% of the qualified food hub expenses for the taxable year.

USDA must (1) ensure that its officials and employees are held accountable for engaging in discriminatory or retaliatory actions, harassment, civil rights violations, or related misconduct; and (2) bear the burden of proving by substantial evidence that an adverse decision was valid.</summary>
</bill>
