<bill session="116" type="s" number="1440" updated="2022-02-08T23:21:48Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Immigration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Immigration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Rights Of Towns against federal Enforcement contrary to Constitutional Tenets for Immigration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to discontinue a Federal program that authorizes State and local law enforcement officers to investigate, apprehend, and detain aliens in accordance with a written agreement with the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and to clarify that immigration enforcement is solely a function of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2019-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2729" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-06T18:32:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting the Rights Of Towns against federal Enforcement contrary to Constitutional Tenets for Immigration Act or the PROTECT Immigration Act

This bill establishes that the authority to investigate, apprehend, or detain aliens for the purposes of immigration enforcement is limited to immigration officers and authorized Department of Homeland Security employees, except when such authority is provided to other individuals under specified statutes. Specifically, this restriction does not apply in certain instances involving (1) an actual or imminent mass influx of aliens, (2) persons bringing in and harboring aliens in violation of immigration laws, and (3) an alien illegally present in the United States who had previously left or was deported after being convicted of a felony.

The bill repeals the authority allowing the Department of Justice to enter into agreements authorizing state or local government employees to perform immigration enforcement functions.</summary>
</bill>
