<bill session="115" type="s" number="3616" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:56Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pregnant Women in Custody Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of restraints and restrictive housing on inmates during the period of pregnancy, labor and postpartum recovery, to collect data on incarcerated pregnant women in the United States and the results of such pregnancies, to address the health needs of incarcerated women related to pregnancy and childbirth, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pregnant Women in Custody Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women in Custody Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2018-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6805" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-26T12:56:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women in Custody Act or the Pregnant Women in Custody Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to limit the use of restraints and restrictive housing for prisoners who are pregnant or in postpartum recovery.

Additionally, it requires the Bureau of Justice Statistics to include, in the National Prison Statistics Program and Annual Survey of Jails, statistics on the health needs of incarcerated pregnant women.

A Bureau of Prisons facility must provide appropriate services and programs to address the health and safety needs of women inmates related to pregnancy and childbirth.

The Government Accountability Office must study the services and protections for pregnant incarcerated women in state and local correctional settings.</summary>
</bill>
