<bill session="118" type="hr" number="1175" updated="2025-01-15T18:51:50Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that hydropower is a vital component to an all-of-the-above approach to energy development which is critical to United States national security.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that hydropower is a vital component to an all-of-the-above approach to energy development which is critical to United States national security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000668" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2024-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy, Climate and Grid Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-06T21:43:17Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution urges the Department of Energy (DOE) to create a hydropower independence plan which articulates a clear and comprehensive proposal for how DOE intends to create, maintain, improve, and expand a vigorous domestic hydropower industry. It also expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that (1) hydropower is a necessary part of an all-of-the-above approach to energy development; (2) protecting the existing hydropower resources and establishing new ones are critical to national security; (3) increased hydropower production will lower energy prices for consumers, decrease the national carbon footprint, and enhance the resiliency of the U.S. power grid; and (4) hydro-hegemony will provide the United States with an edge over global competitors and foreign bad actors.</summary>
</bill>
