<bill session="112" type="h" number="2550" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:45Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Spouses of Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the transfer of entitlement to educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs by deceased members of the Armed Forces.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spouses of Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001254"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2011-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-09-26T19:34:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Spouses of Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act - Requires an Armed Forces member's entitlement to educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to be transferred to the member's surviving spouse, unless another eligible dependent is designated, upon the death of a member who is entitled to such assistance while serving on active duty.

Limits the maximum amount of assistance transferrable to a spouse under this Act to the amount the deceased member was actually entitled on the date of the member's death.

Directs a surviving spouse who is also entitled to other specified VA educational assistance for survivors and dependents to make an irrevocable election to receive assistance either under this Act or such other provisions. Prohibits a surviving spouse from receiving assistance under both provisions.

Requires this Act to take effect retroactively from August 1, 2009.</summary>
</bill>
