<bill session="117" type="s" number="3452" updated="2022-02-08T07:09:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-10">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Dangerous Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Dangerous Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that State and local law enforcement may cooperate with Federal officials to protect our communities from violent criminals and suspected terrorists who are illegally present in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-01-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="232">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 232.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="42" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-03T18:46:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Dangerous Sanctuary Cities Act

This bill prohibits a sanctuary jurisdiction from receiving grants under certain Economic Development Assistance Programs and the Community Development Block Grant Program. Under the bill, a sanctuary jurisdiction is a state or local government that has in effect a statute, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts (1) information sharing with another government entity about an individual's immigration status, or (2) compliance with a lawfully issued Department of Homeland Security (DHS) detainer request or notification of release request.

 When complying with a DHS-issued detainer, a state or local government shall be deemed to be acting as an agent of DHS with all authority available to DHS officers and employees. The bill also limits the legal liability of a state or local government for complying with a detainer.</summary>
</bill>
