<bill session="119" type="h" number="205" updated="2025-06-28T08:06:21Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Congressional Funds for Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Congressional Funds for Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of Federal funds for congressional earmarks targeted to a State or unit of local government that is a sanctuary jurisdiction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2025-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000619" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2025-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000829" joined="2025-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-12T22:22:20Z" status="Introduced in House">No Congressional Funds for Sanctuary Cities Act

This bill prohibits federal funds from being used as congressionally directed spending (i.e., an&#160;earmark) for jurisdictions that withhold information about citizenship or immigration status or do not cooperate with immigration detainers.

Specifically, such funds are denied to any jurisdiction that has a law, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts any government entity from

maintaining, sending, or receiving information regarding the citizenship or immigration status of any individual;exchanging information regarding an individual's citizenship or immigration status with a federal, state, or local government entity;complying with a valid immigration detainer from the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); ornotifying DHS about an individual's release from custody.The funding restriction does not apply to a law, policy, or practice that only applies to an individual who comes forward as a victim of or a witness to a criminal offense.

This prohibition begins in FY2026.</summary>
</bill>
