<bill session="117" type="s" number="4663" updated="2023-03-09T17:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8236" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2617" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-01T15:38:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2023

This bill provides FY2023 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military activities.

(The bill excludes military construction, military family housing, civil works projects of the Army Corps of Engineers, and nuclear warheads, which are all considered in other appropriations bills.)

Within the DOD budget, the bill provides appropriations for

 Military Personnel; Operation and Maintenance; Procurement; Research, Development, Test and Evaluation; and Revolving and Management Funds. The bill provides appropriations for other DOD programs and activities, including

 the Defense Health Program, Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, the Office of the Inspector General, and Support for International Sporting Competitions. In addition, the bill provides appropriations for related agencies, including (1) the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund, and (2) the Intelligence Community Management Account.

The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
</bill>
