<bill session="112" type="h" number="6353" updated="2019-11-15T21:47:03Z">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacturing American Innovation Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Manufacturing American Innovation Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction for patent box profit from the use of United States patents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001255" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="6544" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-10-02T18:40:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Manufacturing American Innovation Act of 2012 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a taxpayer to elect a tax deduction for an amount equal to 71% of the lesser of: (1) the taxpayer's patent box profit, or (2 the taxpayer's taxable income for the taxable year. Defines "patent box profit" to include gross receipts derived from the sale, lease, license, or or other disposition of qualified patent property in the course of a U.S. trade or business over the sum of the taxpayer's cost of goods sold allocable to patent gross receipts, other expenses, losses, or deductions, including research and development expenditures, allocable to such receipts, plus routine profit. Defines "qualified patent" to include a patent issued or extended by, or for which an application is pending before, the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO).

Sets forth rules for the application of the patent box profit deduction to pass-thru entities, including partnerships and S corporations, trusts and estates, and agricultural and horticultural cooperatives.</summary>
</bill>
