<bill session="112" type="h" number="5649" updated="2019-11-15T20:50:53Z">
  <state datetime="2012-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacturing Certainty and Captive Finance Affiliate Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="display">Manufacturing Certainty and Captive Finance Affiliate Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Commodity Exchange Act to clarify the exemptions for captive finance companies from the definition of major swap participant and from the swap clearing requirement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001182"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000169" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3336" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-07-18T19:34:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Manufacturing Certainty and Captive Finance Affiliate Clarification Act - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to redefine an exclusion from "major swap participant" (and as a result from the swap clearing requirement) an entity (captive finance company) whose primary business is providing financing that facilitates the sale or lease of products by or on behalf of the parent company or its subsidiary, and uses derivatives only for the purpose of hedging underlying commercial risks in a consolidated financing and leasing portfolio at least 90% of which, as of the end of its preceding fiscal year, is qualifying financing (including loans, notes, installment sales contracts, receivables, and operating and financing leases).

 Declares amendments made by this Act effective as of the enactment of the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010 (title VII of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act).</summary>
</bill>
