<bill session="112" type="h" number="1660" updated="2019-11-15T20:54:57Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Faster Access and Shorter Transaction Time for Checks Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FASTT Checks Act</title>
    <title type="display">Faster Access and Shorter Transaction Time for Checks Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Expedited Funds Availability Act, to adjust dollar limits on check hold policies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000465"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2011-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-16T19:00:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Faster Access and Shorter Transaction Time for Checks Act of 2011 or FASTT Checks Act - Amends the Expedited Funds Availability Act to provide for faster access to funds deposited in a receiving depository institution by doubling the amounts available for withdrawal at specified earliest times after deposit.

Revises the next business day availability requirement for cash deposited in a new depositor account. Eliminates the exception from this rule (thus requiring next business day availability) for large deposits in large depository banks if a check: (1) has been truncated and cleared in accordance with the Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act, and (2) is received for payment or deposit at a depositary bank with total assets of $10 billion or more.

Treats Saturday as a business day in the calculation of any period within which funds deposited in an account at a receiving depository institution are required to be available.</summary>
</bill>
