<bill session="116" type="h" number="7192" updated="2022-02-09T02:43:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TRAIN Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 53 of title 49, United States Code, to establish a program to provide public transportation agencies with grants to be used during a disaster declaration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRAIN Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transit Reliability, Acknowledgment, Investment and Need Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-06T19:18:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Transit Reliability, Acknowledgment, Investment and Need Act of 2020 or the TRAIN Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish a program to provide public transportation agencies with grants for use during a state disaster declaration such as the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) public health emergency.

Grants may be expended for

 providing continued services during the pandemic or disaster declaration, stabilization of fare prices for passengers during the period of such disaster declaration, no-cost public transportation services during such disaster declaration; provision of new or supplemental public transportation service bus routes, or bus rapid systems; and procurement of personal protective gear and equipment needed to protect employees from hazards generated or originating from the disaster declaration. Additionally, grant awards may not exceed $5 billion.

Public transportation agencies receiving funds must (1) provide assistance to the general public during the disaster declaration period and, subsequently, for a period of six months after the termination of such disaster declaration; (2) certify with DOT every seven days that any use of funds meet applicable health and safety standards and guidance by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention issued during the disaster declaration for passengers and employees of the public transportation agency that includes a description of the compliance mechanisms employed by such agency; and (3) submit to DOT an annual report regarding the progress its grant projects have made to make transportation access points accessible to persons with limited mobility.</summary>
</bill>
