<bill session="119" type="s" number="155" updated="2025-11-19T04:06:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MAILS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAILS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mandating Advisable and Informed Locations and Solutions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve communication between the United States Postal Service and local communities relating to the relocation and establishment of Postal Service retail service facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2025-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="765" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-16T20:35:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mandating Advisable and Informed Locations and Solutions Act or the MAILS Act

This bill requires the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) to&#160;(1) establish a formal process for a local government official to request a new post office, and (2) modify how it communicates with local officials and the public about certain topics.

Specifically, USPS must modify existing regulations with respect to temporary relocations of postal retail services for holidays, special events, overflow business, and commemorative events. USPS may not implement any such temporary relocation for more than two days unless it first collects and considers community input. USPS must also provide specified notifications to local officials and the public, periodic updates to local officials, and a public presentation about such a relocation.</summary>
</bill>
