<bill session="118" type="h" number="5006" updated="2024-08-02T16:40:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of State to take certain actions for the declassification and publication of materials relating to the Afghanistan withdrawal, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of State to take certain actions for the declassification and publication of materials relating to the Afghanistan withdrawal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2023-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001216" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2023-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2023-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2023-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2023-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-02T16:40:38Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of State to make certain information regarding the 2021 withdrawal of U.S. personnel from Afghanistan available to Congress and to the public.

Specifically, the State Department must provide Congress with the July 13, 2021, dissent channel cable regarding the likely consequences of a U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan and the official State Department response to the cable. (The dissent channel is a tool that foreign service officers may use to communicate alternative or dissenting views about foreign policy matters with senior State Department officials. )

The&#160;unredacted cable and official response must be provided to Congress within five days of the bill's enactment, except that the names of the cable signatories may be redacted.

The bill also requires the State Department to complete a declassification review of (1) the dissent channel cable and official response, and (2) the after-action review developed with respect to the Afghanistan withdrawal. After determining what information may be declassified, the State Department must publish such information online within 60 days of the bill's enactment.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
