<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="296" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:56Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="23" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-03-21">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-03-19"/>
  <description>To express the sense of the Senate that the Attorney General should conduct a study on the need and cost to establish radio interoperability between law enforcement agencies, fire departments, and emergency medical services, and that Congress should authorize and appropriate $20,000,000 for grants to local governments to assist fire departments and emergency medical services agencies to establish radio interoperability.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-03-21" how="Voice Vote" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 296 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4260" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-21">
      <text>Amendment SA 296 proposed by Senator Conrad for Senator Rockefeller. (consideration: CR S4259-4260) To express the sense of the Senate that the Attorney General should conduct a study on the need and cost to establish radio interoperability between law enforcement agencies, fire departments, and emergency medical services, and that Congress should authorize and appropriate $20,000,000 for grants to local governments to assist fire departments and emergency medical services agencies to establish radio interoperability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-21">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 296 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4260" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-21">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 296 proposed by Senator Conrad for Senator Rockefeller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4259-4260" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
