<bill session="118" type="s" number="2278" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:29Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Enforcement, Security, and Trade (BEST) Facilitation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Border Enforcement, Security, and Trade (BEST) Facilitation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="display">Border Enforcement, Security, and Trade (BEST) Facilitation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish Image Adjudicator and Supervisory Image Adjudicator positions in the U.S. Customs and Border Protection Office of Field Operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2024-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2024-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-02">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 118-251.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="652">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 652.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5990" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-12T22:03:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Border Enforcement, Security, and Trade (BEST) Facilitation Act of 2023

This bill establishes positions within U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to review inspection images of vehicles and cargo entering or exiting the United States.

Specifically, the bill establishes the position of image adjudicator within the CBP Office of Field Operations. An image adjudicator must (1) review nonintrusive inspection images of vehicles and cargo entering or exiting the United States; (2) assess whether such vehicles and cargo contain contraband, illicit drugs, weapons, or persons seeking to unlawfully enter the United States; and (3) refer suspicious vehicles and cargo for further inspection by a CBP officer.

The bill also establishes the position of supervisory image adjudicator with additional responsibilities, including receiving and reporting intelligence to the National Targeting Center about techniques used by malign actors to transport contraband, illicit drugs, weapons, and persons seeking to unlawfully enter the United States.

The bill establishes annual training requirements for both image adjudicator and supervisory image adjudicator positions, including training on privacy and civil liberties and how to analyze inspection images.

Within a year of this bill's enactment, CBP must develop a workforce staffing model for these positions. The Government Accountability Office must validate the model within six months of the model's completion.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-251</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
