<bill session="111" type="h" number="3068" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TARP for Main Street Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To use amounts made available under the Troubled Assets Relief Program of the Secretary of the Treasury for relief for homeowners and neighborhoods.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TARP for Main Street Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000339"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001050" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2009-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2009-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-09">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-15T19:27:31Z" status="Introduced in House">TARP for Main Street Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer specified funds, from dividends paid by financial institution recipients of financial assistance under the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP) of the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA), to the Housing Trust Fund and to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).

Requires the use of such funds for assistance to: (1) states and local governmental units to redevelop abandoned and foreclosed homes; (2) the Emergency Homeowners' Relief Fund (which the Secretary shall establish under the Emergency Housing Act of 1975) for emergency mortgage assistance; and (3) the Multifamily Mortgage Resolution Program to stabilize multifamily properties that are in default or foreclosure, or have recently been foreclosed.

Amends the Emergency Housing Act of 1975 to: (1) increase the maximum aggregate amount of insured emergency mortgage loans and advances; and (2) extend through FY2011 the program for insured loans and emergency mortgage relief payments made under the Act.

Directs the HUD Secretary to develop a program to ensure the protection of current and future tenants of at-risk multifamily properties.

Amends EESA to reduce the TARP authorization limit in order to offset the costs of loans, advances, insurance, and appropriations authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
