<bill session="116" type="h" number="8708" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:27Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Families United Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Families United Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to promote family unity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2020-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2020-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-07T12:06:11Z" status="Introduced in House">American Families United Act

This bill limits what constitutes a conviction for immigration purposes and contains other related provisions. (A conviction can in certain instances be grounds for denying an individual immigration benefits.)

Under this bill, certain judgments of guilt, such as one that has been deferred, expunged, or invalidated, shall not be considered a conviction for immigration purposes. An order of probation without an entry of judgment shall also not count as a conviction. Similarly, a pardon shall render the underlying conviction null for immigration purposes.

Furthermore, for immigration purposes, a term of imprisonment shall only include the actual period of incarceration ordered by a court. If a term of imprisonment is suspended for any length, the suspended time shall not be considered as part of the term of imprisonment. (An individual may be denied certain immigration benefits if the individual has been convicted for a crime with a certain term of imprisonment.)

The bill also provides statutory authority for the Department of Justice and Department of Homeland Security to, in certain instances, exercise discretion when enforcing immigration laws, such as waiving one or more grounds of inadmissibility or declining to order an alien removed. Such discretion may only be exercised on a case-by-case basis for humanitarian purposes or to preserve family unity and is subject to other limitations.</summary>
</bill>
