<bill session="118" type="s" number="1341" updated="2025-11-19T02:24:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EDUCATORS for America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EDUCATORS for America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize title II of the Higher Education Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1421" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1757" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="963" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2992" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-25T13:23:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">EDUCATORS for America Act

This bill provides resources to support the recruitment, retention, and preparation of educators.

Specifically, the bill expands the Teacher Quality Partnership program to include training and professional development opportunities for principals and other school leaders.

Additionally, the bill updates the Augustus F. Hawkins Centers of Excellence program to support underrepresented candidates in educator preparation programs.

The bill establishes an education careers opportunity program to provide individuals from underrepresented backgrounds with education and training to become educators.

Further, the bill revises the Teacher Education Assistance for College and Higher Education (TEACH) grant program to raise the maximum amount for TEACH grants.

The bill also expands loan forgiveness for educators by revising the Teacher Loan Forgiveness Program, including by

 renaming the program as the Educator Loan Forgiveness Programs, making additional loan types eligible for benefits under the program (e.g., parent PLUS loans), and expanding program eligibility to early childhood educators and program directors serving in early childhood education programs and school leaders serving in public high-need schools. Next, the bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to (1) make monthly student loan payments on behalf of the educator during qualifying service (i.e., employment as a full-time qualifying educator in a high-need school or an early childhood education program), and (2) provide complete loan forgiveness after five years of qualifying service.

ED must also carry out a program to provide loan credits to eligible educator borrowers enrolled in income-contingent or income-based repayment plans.</summary>
</bill>
