<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="2028" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:35Z">
  <amends type="s" number="139" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-10-30">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000304"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-10-29"/>
  <description>To provide for a program of scientific research on abrupt climate change, to accelerate the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions in the United States by establishing a market-driven system of greenhouse gas tradeable allowances, to limit greenhouse gas emissions in the United States and reduce dependence upon foreign oil, and ensure benefits to consumers from the trading in such allowances.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-10-30" how="roll" result="fail" roll="420">
      <text>Amendment SA 2028 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 43 - 55. Record Vote Number: 420.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13572, S13598" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Amendment SA 2028 proposed by Senator Lieberman. (consideration: CR S13485-13509) To provide for a program of scientific research on abrupt climate change, to accelerate the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions in the United States by establishing a market-driven system of greenhouse gas tradeable allowances, to limit greenhouse gas emissions in the United States and reduce dependence upon foreign oil, and ensure benefits to consumers from the trading in such allowances.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 2028 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 43 - 55. Record Vote Number: 420.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 2028 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 43 - 55. Record Vote Number: 420.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2028 proposed by Senator Lieberman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13485-13509" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
