<bill session="117" type="h" number="6335" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:58Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HUBS for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Unleash Benefits and Services for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HUBS for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Labor to award grants to organizations for the provision of transition assistance to members and former members of the Armed Forces who are separated, retired, or discharged from the Armed Forces, and spouses of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2021-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="711" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-09T21:57:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Unleash Benefits and Services for Veterans Act of 2021 or the HUBS for Veterans Act of 2021

This bill establishes a grant program to assist the transition of military personnel to civilian life. It directs the Department of Labor to carry out a five-year program of grants to nonprofit organizations that assist the transition of the following persons from Armed Forces service to civilian life:

 members eligible for preseparation counseling, former members who are transitioning to civilian life, and spouses of such members or former members. Funds must be used for a broad range of supportive programs, such as job recruitment training.</summary>
</bill>
