<bill session="111" type="sr" number="346" updated="2017-12-13T21:29:30Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-09">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that, at the 21st Regular Meeting of the International Commission on the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas, the United States should seek to ensure management of the eastern Atlantic and Mediterranean bluefin tuna fishery adheres to the scientific advice provided by the Standing Committee on Research and Statistics and has a high probability of achieving the established rebuilding target, pursue strengthened protections for spawning bluefin populations in the Mediterranean Sea to facilitate the recovery of the Atlantic bluefin tuna, pursue imposition  of more stringent measures to ensure compliance by all Members with the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas' conservation and management recommendations for Atlantic bluefin tuna and other species, and ensure that United States' quotas of tuna and swordfish are not reallocated to other nations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that, at the 21st Regular Meeting of the International Commission on the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas, the United States should seek to ensure management of the eastern Atlantic and Mediterranean bluefin tuna fishery adheres to the scientific advice provided by the Standing Committee on Research and Statistics and has a high probability of achieving the established rebuilding target, pursue strengthened protections for spawning bluefin populations in the Mediterranean Sea to facilitate the recovery of the Atlantic bluefin tuna, pursue imposition  of more stringent measures to ensure compliance by all Members with the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas' conservation and management recommendations for Atlantic bluefin tuna and other species, and ensure that United States' quotas of tuna and swordfish are not reallocated to other nations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000374" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2009-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2009-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2009-11-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11301-11302" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11301-11302" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11293-11294" label="text as introduced in Senate"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-23T17:32:55Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses the sense of the Senate that the U.S. delegation to the 21st Regular Meeting of the International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas should: (1) seek the adoption of all revisions to the multi-annual recovery plan for bluefin tuna in the eastern Atlantic and Mediterranean that will conform the plan to the scientific advice provided by the Standing Committee on Research and Statistics; (2) seek to expand time and area closures of spawning areas in the Mediterranean in conformity with the scientific advice provided by the Standing Committee; (3) pursue the continued review and assessment of compliance; (4) seek to address noncompliance; (5) pursue the commitment by the Commission and its parties to fund additional research on the western Atlantic and eastern Atlantic and Mediterranean bluefin tuna stocks including, but not limited to, the extent to which they mix; and (6) defend U.S. interests with regard to Atlantic bluefin tuna, Atlantic swordfish, and other species managed by the Commission, including the protection of U.S. quota shares.</summary>
</bill>
