<bill session="117" type="s" number="218" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to approve certain advanced biofuel registrations, to require the consideration of certain advanced biofuel pathways, and to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to approve certain advanced biofuel registrations, to require the consideration of certain advanced biofuel pathways, and to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S476-477" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1637" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-14T18:50:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill expedites the approval process for renewable fuels under the renewable fuel standard (RFS) program. The existing RFS program requires transportation fuel to contain a minimum volume of renewable fuel. Producers must register renewable fuels under the program.

The bill considers an application to register a renewable fuel under the RFS program to be approved by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) if the fuel has been approved under any state renewable fuel program. It also establishes a deadline for the EPA to make a decision on any pending application for a renewable fuel that has not yet been approved under any state program.

In addition, the bill establishes deadlines for the EPA to make decisions on pending pathway petitions by producers to register biofuels. If the EPA does not make decisions on the petitions by the deadlines, then petitions are automatically approved.</summary>
</bill>
