<bill session="115" type="h" number="6686" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:43Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 41, United States Code, to require the head of each executive agency to consider the existence of qualified training programs of contractors in the award of certain contracts.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 41, United States Code, to require the head of each executive agency to consider the existence of qualified training programs of contractors in the award of certain contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2018-08-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2018-08-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-30T13:15:26Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires each executive agency to take into account the existence of qualified training programs of contractors. Specifically, a contracting officer, in evaluating offers for any contract in an amount greater than $25 million, must consider:

 the existence of a qualified training program of an offeror as a factor in the evaluation; an offeror that provides comprehensive training and education programs to develop its workforce, consistent with the agency's needs; and in assessing past performance, the manner in which an incumbent contractor is educating, investing, and retaining the contractor's workforce. "Qualified training program" is defined as:

 a program eligible to receive funds under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, a program eligible to receive funds under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006, a program registered under the National Apprenticeship Act, or any other federal program determined by the agency to be a qualified training program. Each agency shall develop workforce development investment incentives for contractors.</summary>
</bill>
