<bill session="117" type="s" number="1411" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lander County Land Management and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land to Lander County, Nevada, to designate certain wilderness areas in Lander County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lander County Land Management and Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2021-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-16T16:54:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lander County Land Management and Conservation Act

This bill conveys all interest in certain federal land to Lander County, Nevada, and designates wilderness areas in the county.

After Lander County selects certain parcels for conveyance, the Department of the Interior and Forest Service must convey the parcels to the county, for no consideration, for use by the county for watershed protection, recreation, and parks.

Interior shall convey to Lander County parcels of federal land identified as Kingston Airport to improve the airport facility and related infrastructure. The only costs to the county of the conveyance shall be surveying costs.

Land conveyed by this bill reverts to federal land if it is not managed in accordance with the purpose of its conveyance.

The bill designates the Cain Mountain and Desatoya Mountains Wildernesses in Nevada as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill releases the Augusta Mountain and Desatoya Wilderness Study Areas within Lander County from further study for designation as wilderness.</summary>
</bill>
