<bill session="118" type="s" number="622" updated="2025-01-14T17:02:09Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Helping Heroes Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Heroes Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs for veteran families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2023-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-10T13:07:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping Heroes Act of 2023

This bill implements programs and procedures related to the provision of support services for veterans and their families.

First, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must place at least one Family Coordinator at each of its medical centers and ensure adequate staffing and resources at each such medical center so the coordinators are able to carry out their duties. Family Coordinators must, among other duties, assess the needs of the families of veterans using evidence-based strategies and refer veterans to support resources.

The VA must also establish the Family Support Program to provide and coordinate the provision of supportive services to veterans who have a service-connected disability rated at 70% or more and eligible children (i.e., individuals who are under 18 years of age and are wards, children, stepchildren, grandchildren, or siblings of the eligible veteran).

Next, the VA must conduct an outreach program to ensure eligible veterans who enrolled in the VA health care system, employees of the VA, and other entities are informed of the Family Support Program and the availability of Family Coordinators.

The VA must include information regarding supportive services available in the transition assistance curriculum for members of the Armed Forces who are being separated from active duty (and their families).

Finally, the VA must conduct an annual survey of disabled veterans and their families to identify and better understand the needs of such persons.</summary>
</bill>
