<bill session="117" type="h" number="8065" updated="2023-08-01T15:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National R &amp; D Strategy for Distributed Ledger Technology Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National R &amp; D Strategy for Distributed Ledger Technology Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the development of a national strategy for the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, to authorize awards to support research on distributed ledger technologies and their applications, and to authorize an applied research project on distributed ledger technologies in commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000823"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2022-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2022-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2022-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2022-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4109" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-01T15:37:14Z" status="Introduced in House">National R &amp; D Strategy for Distributed Ledger Technology Act of 2022

This bill provides for a national strategy and research and development regarding technologies related to distributed ledgers (e.g., blockchain or Bitcoin). A distributed ledger is a ledger that is shared across and synchronized between a set of distributed nodes (i.e., devices or processes) in a network that store a complete or partial replica of the ledger and meet other requirements.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy must develop a national strategy for the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, including applications of public and permissionless distributed ledgers. The office must coordinate with the National Science and Technology Council and other relevant federal agencies, as appropriate, on the strategy. The national strategy shall include

 plans to support public and private sector investment and partnerships in research and technology development for societally beneficial applications of distributed ledger technologies, and an identification of additional resources, administrative action, or legislative action recommended to assist with the implementation of such strategy. The National Science Foundation shall make competitive awards to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations (or their consortia) to support research, including interdisciplinary research, on distributed ledger technologies and their applications.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology may carry out an applied research project to study and demonstrate the potential benefits and unique capabilities of distributed ledger technologies.</summary>
</bill>
