<bill session="118" type="h" number="1791" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Classified Documents Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Classified Documents Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide civil penalties for unauthorized removal and retention of classified documents or material, to amend chapter 22 of title 44, to include a certification process for Presidential records, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Q000023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2023-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-13T18:01:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Classified Documents Accountability Act

This bill provides for civil penalties for the unauthorized removal and retention of classified documents or material and establishes a certification process for presidential records.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of Justice to bring a civil action in U.S. district court and provides for a civil penalty of up to $500,000 per violation for the unauthorized removal and retention of classified documents or material.

An officer or employee from the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) must be present in the Executive Office of the President and the Office of the Vice President to ensure proper logging and handling of presidential and vice-presidential records.

Any record of the President and Vice President shall be screened for classified material by NARA during the presidential transition and shall be retained by NARA.

The outgoing President and Vice President or designee must certify whether they have retained any classified records. The bill establishes penalties for noncompliance, including a limitation on funds for travel and a reduction in pension.</summary>
</bill>
