<bill session="118" type="h" number="56" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RAISE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RAISE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming Alternatives to Incarceration and Sentencing to Establish a Better Path for Youth Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide alternatives to incarceration for youth, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-10T10:56:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Reforming Alternatives to Incarceration and Sentencing to Establish a Better Path for Youth Act of 2023 or the RAISE Act of 2023

This bill modifies requirements and procedures related to the sentencing, confinement, and release of youth who are involved in the federal criminal justice system. The term youth means an individual who is prosecuted or sentenced for a criminal offense committed at age 21 or younger.

The bill modifies federal sentencing options for youth, including by allowing courts

 to depart from the statutory mandatory minimum for certain nonviolent offenses, to reduce the prison term of a youth who has completed 20 years of the sentence, and to treat as discretionary a sentence of imprisonment for life. Additionally, it requires the Bureau of Prisons to separately designate youth correctional facilities, minimize contact between youth and other offenders, and establish programs regarding youth education, skills training, reentry, and mental and emotional health.

Finally, the bill promotes reentry and reintegration into the community, including by

 providing an early release option for youth offenders who complete one half or more of their prison term and meet certain criteria; authorizing home confinement for a longer period of time; limiting the maximum prison term for technical violations of probation; establishing pilot programs for mentorship, government service, and animal service; and establishing pilot programs for diversion of high-risk, victimized, and primary caretaker youth.</summary>
</bill>
