<bill session="111" type="h" number="5629" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:51Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oil Spill Accountability and Environmental Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure full recovery from responsible parties of damages for physical and economic injuries, adverse effects on the environment, and clean up of oil spill pollution, to improve the safety of vessels and pipelines supporting offshore oil drilling, to ensure that there are adequate response plans to prevent environmental damage from oil spills, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Oil Spill Accountability and Environmental Protection Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oil Spill Accountability and Environmental Protection Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000006"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001060" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2010-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2010-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1244-1246"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 111-567, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-27" calendar="Union" number="326">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 326.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-02-11T16:54:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Oil Spill Accountability and Environmental Protection Act of 2010 - Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to: (1) repeal the limitation on the liability of the responsible party for an offshore facility for damages and removal costs that result from a discharge of oil into or upon the navigable waters or adjoining shorelines or the U.S. exclusive economic zone; (2) increase the amount of financial responsibility required for offshore facilities to $1.5 billion; (3) make responsible parties for vessels or facilities from which oil is discharged liable for damages to human health; and (4) authorize the President to require a responsible party to provide information about claims in the event of a spill of national significance.

Repeals provisions of the Limitation of Liability Act of 1851 that limit the liability of the owner of a vessel from claims, debt, or liability to the value of the vessel and pending freight.

Amends the Death on the High Seas Act to allow a civil action in law to benefit a decedent's survivors for the death of an individual that is caused by wrongful act, neglect, or default occurring on the high seas beyond three nautical miles from the U.S. shore. Amends the Jones Act to authorize a decedent's survivors to recover fair compensation for nonpecuniary losses and the decedent's pain and suffering.

Limits the exploration, development, or production of resources in, on, above, or below the exclusive economic zone to vessels owned by U.S. citizens.

Sets forth provisions concerning safety management systems and standards for mobile offshore drilling units. Requires the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to designate positions to be in the Coast Guard's marine safety workforce to perform vessel and marine casualty investigations.

Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to revoke the President's authorization to allow tank vessels and facilities to operate without a plan to respond to the discharge of oil or hazardous substances. Requires the President to: (1) issue a revised regulation for the development of the schedule for the use of dispersants, other chemicals, and other spill mitigating devices and substances; (2) undertake a rulemaking concerning standards for ceasing and removing a worst case discharge of oil or a hazardous substance and for mitigating or preventing a substantial threat of such discharge; (3) create a database to track all discharges of oil or hazardous substances; and (4) delegate specified responsibilities with respect to oil discharges to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, and the Secretary of Transportation (DOT). Revises provisions concerning: (1) responses to discharges of oil or hazardous substances by vessels and facilities; and (2) penalties for such discharges.

Requires a pipeline facility operator in an area affected by a disaster to notify the Secretary of Transportation of changes to the operational status of such facility within 12 hours of cessation of the disaster.

Requires the National Commission on the BP Deepwater Horizon Oil Spill and Offshore Drilling to develop recommendations for: (1) improvements to federal laws, regulations, and industry practices applicable to offshore drilling to ensure effective oversight, inspection, monitoring, and response capabilities and protect human and occupational health and safety and the environment; and (2) reforms of federal agencies or processes to ensure that such improvements are implemented and maintained.

Requires the Comptroller General to report on the employment during the preceding year of individuals who were Coast Guard officials in the previous five-year period by recognized organizations contracted to administer maritime programs for foreign flag administrations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-567</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
