<bill session="109" type="h" number="3588" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:30Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Home Health Telehealth Access Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for access to telehealth services in the home.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Home Health Telehealth Access Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2005-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000413" joined="2006-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000364" joined="2006-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2005-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9018-9019"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2282" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-03-22T15:42:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Home Health Telehealth Access Act of 2005 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise the current requirements for Medicare coverage of telehealth services under the prospective payment system.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to treat as a home health visit any telehealth services furnished by a home health agency via a telecommunication system to an individual receiving home health services, if the telehealth services: (1) are ordered as part of a plan of care certified by a physician; (2) (as under current law) do not substitute for in-person home health services ordered as part of a plan of care certified by a physician; and (3) are considered the equivalent of a visit under criteria developed by the Secretary.

Directs the Secretary to initiate and carry out projects in a variety of geographic locations that provide incentives to home health agencies to utilize home monitoring and communications technologies that will: (1) enhance health outcomes for individuals enrolled under Medicare parts A and B; and (2) reduce part A and B program expenditures for institutional and other providers, practitioners, and suppliers of health care items and services.

Authorizes the Secretary to pay incentive payments to each home health agency participating in a pilot project.

Provides that, if the Secretary determines that any of the pilot projects results in decreased federal Medicare expenditures, and maintains or enhances health outcomes for the participating beneficiaries, the Secretary may initiate or extend comparable projects in additional areas.</summary>
</bill>
