<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="418" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:56Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="23" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-03-25">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-03-25"/>
  <description>To raise the caps and provide direct first responder funding to localities and for high threat areas through the Department of Homeland Security's Office of Domestic Preparedness in 2003 and 2004, to restore funding for the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Act ("Byrne Grant" program) and the Local Law Enforcement Block Grant Program, and to reduce the deficit, by reducing the size of newly proposed tax cuts.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-03-25" how="roll" result="fail" roll="92">
      <text>Amendment SA 418 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 92.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Amendment SA 418 proposed by Senator Clinton. (consideration:  CR S4353-4355; text:  CR S4353-4354) To raise the caps and provide direct first responder funding to localities and for high threat areas through the Department of Homeland Security's Office of Domestic Preparedness in 2003 and 2004, to restore funding for the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Act ("Byrne Grant" program) and the Local Law Enforcement Block Grant Program, and to reduce the deficit, by reducing the size of newly proposed tax cuts.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 418 proposed by Senator Clinton.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4353-4355" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref=" CR S4353-4354" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 418 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 92.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 418 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 92.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
