<bill session="119" type="s" number="206" updated="2025-11-19T03:46:42Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Trade Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Trade Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to suspend normal trade relations with the People's Republic of China and to increase the rates of duty applicable with respect to articles imported from the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="694" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Trade Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-18T15:18:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Trade Fairness Act

This bill establishes various trade measures related to China, including by revoking&#160;China's permanent normal trade relations (PNTR) status and increasing the rates of duty (i.e., tariffs) on Chinese imported goods.&#160;The bill prohibits imported goods originating from North Korea, China, Russia, or Iran from receiving&#160;de&#160;minimis treatment.&#160;(Current law allows for U.S. imports under a de minimis threshold of $800 per shipment to enter free of tariffs, fees, and taxes.)

Specifically, the bill revokes China's PNTR status. Currently, China's PNTR status allows for Chinese goods to have duty rates set&#160;forth in column 1 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS). With the removal of China's PNTR status, the bill generally sets the applicable duty rates on imported Chinese&#160;goods at the higher rates listed in column 2 of the HTS, with exceptions.

The bill establishes a minimum duty rate of 35% for all Chinese goods, which requires column 2 rates to be at least 35%. However, the bill establishes a minimum duty rate of 100% for a list of specified goods (e.g., various minerals, certain vaccines and drugs, and certain defense-related articles). Duty rates are phased in over five years and adjusted annually for inflation.

The bill also

authorizes the President to take additional actions related to trade with China,&#160;requires merchandise imported from China to be appraised based on U.S. value, and&#160;establishes a trust fund to compensate U.S. producers for lost revenue resulting from retaliatory actions by China.</summary>
</bill>
