<bill session="115" type="s" number="2455" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:24Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ukraine Cybersecurity Cooperation Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage United States-Ukraine cybersecurity cooperation and require a report regarding such cooperation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ukraine Cybersecurity Cooperation Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2018-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2018-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2018-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2018-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2018-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1997" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-27T16:03:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ukraine Cybersecurity Cooperation Act of 2018

This bill states that it is U.S. policy to: (1) reaffirm the United States-Ukraine Charter on Strategic Partnership, which highlights the bilateral relationship's importance and outlines enhanced cooperation in defense, security, economics and trade, energy security, democracy, and cultural exchanges; (2) support continued cooperation between the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and Ukraine; (3) support Ukraine's political and economic reforms; (4) reaffirm the commitment of the United States to the Budapest Memorandum on Security Assurances; (5) assist Ukraine's efforts to enhance its cybersecurity capabilities; and (6) improve Ukraine's ability to respond to Russian-supported disinformation and propaganda efforts in cyberspace, including through social media.

It is the sense of Congress that the Department of State should take the following actions, commensurate with U.S. interests, to help Ukraine improve its cybersecurity: (1) provide Ukraine necessary support to secure government computer networks from cyber intrusions, particularly networks that defend critical infrastructure; (2) provide Ukraine support to reduce reliance on Russian information and communications technology; and (3) help Ukraine build capacity, expand cybersecurity information sharing, and cooperate on international cyberspace efforts.

 The State Department shall report to Congress on the status of U.S.-Ukraine cybersecurity cooperation.</summary>
</bill>
