<bill session="116" type="s" number="3658" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Achieving Racial and Ethnic Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Achieving Racial and Ethnic Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Achieving Racial and Ethnic Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Office of Equal Rights and Community Inclusion at the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2020-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-316.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="619">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 619.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-17T14:35:32Z" status="Reported to Senate">Achieving Racial and Ethnic Equity in Disaster Response, Recovery, and Resilience Act of 2020 

This bill establishes the Office of Equal Rights and Community Inclusion (OERCI) within the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).

The OERCI shall be responsible, among other things, for (1) improving underserved community access to disaster assistance and improving the quality of assistance such communities receive; and (2) eliminating racial, ethnic, and other underserved community disparities in the delivery of various preparedness, response, and recovery assistance.

The bill defines underserved community to mean an historically disadvantaged community, including the Native American, African-American, Asian, Hispanic, Pacific Islander, Middle Eastern and North African, rural, low-income, and disability communities.

FEMA shall (1) administer and evaluate its programs and activities, including those of recipients of preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation grants, in a manner to affirmatively further inclusion and engagement of underserved communities and improved outcomes for underserved communities tied to FEMA programs and activities; and (2) establish an underserved community initiative to award grants to specified nonprofit entities.

The OERCI shall develop measures to evaluate the effectiveness of the activities of program offices in FEMA and the activities of recipients aimed at reducing disparities in the services provided to underserved communities.

During the period of time for which there is a major disaster or emergency declared by the President with respect to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019), the OERCI shall regularly consult with state, local, territorial, and tribal government officials and community-based organizations from underserved communities that it identifies as disproportionately impacted by COVID-19.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-316</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
