<bill session="118" type="h" number="3855" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Digital Reserve Corps Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Digital Reserve Corps Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish a National Digital Reserve Corps to help address the digital and cybersecurity needs of Executive agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2024-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2023-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2024-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000307" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2024-12-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000815" joined="2024-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="162" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-17T15:52:49Z" status="Introduced in House">National Digital Reserve Corps Act

This bill establishes a National Digital Reserve Corps in the General Services Administration (GSA) to address the digital and cybersecurity needs of executive agencies.

The GSA must establish standards for reservist eligibility and must ensure reservists have the necessary resources and security credentials for service. Reservists must agree to serve for three years and for at least 30 days per year as an active reservist, with up to $10,000 in annual compensation; reservists who fail to accept an offered appointment or complete required duties are subject to fines. The GSA may cover the costs of continuing education for reservists to support their service.

The Department of Labor must issue regulations that ensure the reemployment, continuation of benefits, and nondiscrimination in reemployment of active reservists.

In August 2021, President Joe Biden established the U.S. Digital Corps within the GSA to support the technological needs of executive agencies, including cybersecurity needs. The corps offers entry-level positions through two-year fellowships, with the option to convert to full-time career positions after completion of the fellowship.</summary>
</bill>
