<bill session="116" type="h" number="7556" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make a portion of research credit refundable for certain small businesses engaging in specified medical research.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make a portion of research credit refundable for certain small businesses engaging in specified medical research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-07T13:29:01Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill allows certain small businesses whose gross receipts do not exceed $1 million a refundable portion of the tax credit for increasing research activities if such businesses are engaging in specified medical research. It defines specified medical research as any qualified research with respect to qualified countermeasures. A qualified countermeasure is a drug, biological product, or device that is determined to be a priority (1) to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, or treat harm from any biological agent (including organisms that cause an infectious disease) or toxin, chemical, radiological, or nuclear agent that may cause a public health emergency affecting national security; (2) to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, or treat harm from a condition that may result in adverse health consequences or death and may be caused by administering a drug, biological product, or device; or (3) is a product or technology intended to enhance the use or effect of a drug, biological product, or device.</summary>
</bill>
