<bill session="118" type="h" number="6340" updated="2024-08-02T18:30:24Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Housing Outcomes for Veterans Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Housing Outcomes for Veterans Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs to provide certain information to Department of Veterans Affairs medical center staff and homelessness service providers regarding the Coordinated Entry program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T21:04:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Housing Outcomes for Veterans Act of 2023

This bill requires the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) to provide medical center staff and homelessness service providers of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) with information related to best practices for the collaboration on activities under the Department of Housing and Urban Development's Coordinated Entry program. The VA must also ensure that the information and related resources are accessible to VA medical center staff and homelessness service providers.

Additionally, the bill requires the VHA to communicate with VA employees who have responsibilities related to homelessness assistance programs regarding (1) the measurement of performance by the VA's Homeless Program Office, and (2) how to obtain and provide feedback about the performance measures.</summary>
</bill>
