<bill session="119" type="h" number="1082" updated="2025-11-06T16:50:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-23T15:51:44-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-23T15:51:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="display">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a national, evidence-based education campaign to increase public and health care provider awareness regarding the potential risks and benefits of human cell and tissue products transplants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 119-160.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-06-12" calendar="Union" number="127">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 127.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T15:39:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T15:39:26-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2860-2862" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T15:39:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1082.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-06-23T15:51:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2860-2861" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T15:51:45-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="340" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-18T18:05:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Shandra Eisenga Human Cell and Tissue Product Safety Act

This bill establishes civil penalties for violations of regulations governing the donation and handling of human cell and tissue products. It also&#160;requires the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to report on the regulation of these products and to provide related information to stakeholders. (Human cell and tissue products are articles containing or consisting of human cells or tissues that are intended for use in a human recipient.)

Specifically, the bill establishes civil penalties for violations of the FDA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s regulations on donor eligibility and current good tissue practice for manufacturing and distributing&#160;human cell and tissue products.

Also, the bill requires the FDA to conduct workshops to educate stakeholders and facilitate discussion on the science and regulation of human cell and tissue products. The FDA must establish a public docket to receive written comments on this topic, and report to Congress with recommendations. The bill also requires the FDA to support the development of educational materials for health care professionals regarding organ, tissue, and eye donations and related topics.

Additionally, the bill requires the FDA to publish on its website educational materials about the Tissue Reference Group (a working group within the FDA)&#160;and best practices for obtaining a recommendation from them about human cell and tissue products. Also, annually for three years, the FDA must publish on its website information on inquiries submitted to the Tissue Reference Group and FDA registrations and inspections regarding human cell and&#160;tissue manufacturers.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-160</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
