<bill session="118" type="h" number="3655" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Our Next Natural Disaster Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Our Next Natural Disaster Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance predisaster mitigation to prevent future natural disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2023-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-15T16:53:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Our Next Natural Disaster Act

This bill modifies the pre-disaster mitigation grant program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).

Specifically, the bill

 increases FEMA's set-aside for pre-disaster mitigation assistance from 6% to 15% of certain grant amounts; provides for a 2% set-aside for community planning and capacity building assistance; and authorizes FEMA to develop guidance regarding how to incorporate climate change into the National Risk Index, cost-benefit analyses, and improved codes, specifications, and standards to address natural hazards. FEMA must

 prioritize applicants for assistance with the highest hazard risk in coordination with FEMA's National Risk Index, environmental justice communities, and low-income communities (current law covers the latter though this bill modifies the number of individuals in such communities); provide community outreach; and establish a central federal database to consolidate funding data collected by all local, state, and federal agencies involved in post-disaster response and pre-disaster mitigation spending and categorize the data by type of project, funding source, and hazard types using a user-friendly database and interactive map.</summary>
</bill>
