<bill session="116" type="h" number="6671" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Fuels Deployment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to aid States in the deployment of fueling infrastructure to increase the use of higher blends of biofuels, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Fuels Deployment Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2020-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-20T18:33:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Clean Fuels Deployment Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Transportation to establish a program to award grants to states and other government entities to aid in the deployment of fueling infrastructure to increase the use of higher blends of ethanol and biodiesel.

The bill requires any infrastructure used or installed with funds provided under the program to be certified by the Underwriters Laboratory to distribute blends with an ethanol content of 25% or greater.

An entity receiving grants under the program shall ensure that federal funds do not exceed (1) 75% of the per pump cost for pumps that can dispense ethanol blends up to and including E85, and dedicated E15 and E85 pumps (new pumps or retrofit of existing pumps); (2) 50% of the terminal costs for terminals with B100 capabilities; and (3) 25% of the per tank cost for new storage tanks and related equipment associated with new facilities or additional capacity other than replacement.</summary>
</bill>
