<bill session="108" type="s" number="1534" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Post Office and Community Preservation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the closing and consolidation of certain post offices in rural communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Post Office and Community Preservation Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000146"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10665-10666"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10666" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Postal facilities"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-11T16:36:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Post Office and Community Preservation Act of 2003 - Amends Federal postal law to prohibit the U.S. Postal Service from closing or consolidating a post office in a city, town, or unincorporated area with a population of 20,000 people or less (rural community), unless the Service determines that it will have a positive economic impact on that rural community and enhance its quality of life.

Requires the Service, before such closing or consolidation takes effect, to develop a plan, in consultation with people in the rural community, to provide for the rehabilitation and use of the post office for purposes favored by the people of the community.

Authorizes the Service to award grants to State and local governments, private organizations, or individuals to provide for the rehabilitation of any closed post office in a rural community.

Requires the Service to transfer the real property (including all buildings and improvements) located at 415 5th Street in Ely, Nevada, and occupied by the closed post office, to the local county government of Ely County, Nevada.</summary>
</bill>
