<bill session="115" type="h" number="6293" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:15Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Right to Petition Congress Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate to establish a process by which registered voters may sign national discharge petitions with respect to bills and joint resolutions introduced in or referred to the House and Senate, to require the House or Senate to hold a vote on the passage of any bill or joint resolution if a certain number of registered voters sign the national discharge petition for the bill or joint resolution, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right to Petition Congress Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-09T15:23:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Right to Petition Congress Act

This bill establishes a process under which registered voters may sign a national discharge petition to require the House of Representatives or the Senate to vote on legislation if the legislation has been introduced in or has been referred to the chamber, a certain number of voters sign the petition, and other specified requirements are met.</summary>
</bill>
