<bill session="109" type="s" number="1874" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:48Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alien Tort Statute Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to clarify jurisdiction of Federal Courts over a tort action brought by an alien, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alien Tort Statute Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11423-11435"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11435-11436" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-10T21:34:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alien Tort Statute Reform Act - Amends the federal judicial code to revise the alien tort (injury) statute. Grants exclusive, as well as original, jurisdiction to U.S. district courts over tort claims brought by aliens against U.S. individuals and business entities (e.g., corporations and partnerships). Specifies the torts that are actionable under the Act as torture, extrajudicial killing, genocide, piracy, slavery, or slave trading.

Establishes as the legal standard for defendant liability under the Act direct participation with specific intent to commit the alleged tort. Requires courts to decline jurisdiction over an alien tort claim if: (1) the alien claimant has not exhausted adequate and available remedies in the place where the alleged tort occurred; or (2) the President certifies in writing that the exercise of jurisdiction will have a negative impact on U.S. foreign policy interests.

Requires claims under the Act to be brought within 10 years from the date of the alleged tort.</summary>
</bill>
