<bill session="111" type="h" number="6276" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:32Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildlife Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to identify and declare wildlife disease emergencies and to coordinate rapid response to these emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildlife Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-02-10T23:07:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildlife Disease Emergency Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) declare a wildlife disease emergency in one or more states for a disease that is occurring either within the United States or outside the United States with the potential to enter the United States, (2) lead a coordinated response to the emergency, and (3) implement a grant program to provide funding to state wildlife agencies and Indian tribes to address such emergencies.

Directs the Secretary, in making such a declaration, to consider: (1) the level of threat the disease poses to affected wildlife populations; (2) the sufficiency of resources available in the Wildlife Disease Emergency Fund; (3) the ability of the Department of the Interior and other federal, state, and local agencies, tribal governments, and other stakeholders to address and coordinate a response to the disease through other authorities; and (4) any state governor's request for such a declaration.

Establishes in the Treasury a Wildlife Disease Emergency Fund, which shall be available to the Secretary for activities authorized by this Act.

Directs the Secretary to establish a Wildlife Disease Committee to assist the Secretary in increasing the level of preparedness of the United States to address emerging wildlife diseases.

Authorizes the Secretary to convene rapid response teams to address a wildlife disease emergency.</summary>
</bill>
