<bill session="116" type="h" number="8057" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:26Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy Soil, Resilient Farmers Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Soil, Resilient Farmers Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act with respect to the conservation loan and loan guarantee program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001209"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-29T17:49:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Soil, Resilient Farmers Act of 2020

This bill revises the conservation loan and loan guarantee program of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to authorize USDA to provide loans for soil health transition plans. A soil health transition plan is a comprehensive, whole-farm plan, approved by USDA, that, for a farming or ranching operation, identifies the conservation activities that will be addressed with loan funds provided or guaranteed to assist the borrower in making a transition to a farming or ranching production and conservation system.

USDA may limit eligibility for soil health transition loans to certain entities, including farmers or ranchers whose farm or ranch land is subject to the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe.

USDA must establish terms and conditions for making or guaranteeing soil health transition loans that waive principal and interest repayment for up to three years from the date on which the loan is made or guaranteed in order for the borrower to make a satisfactory transition to the farming or ranching production and conservation system under a soil health transition plan.</summary>
</bill>
