<bill session="108" type="s" number="672" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mandatory Prison Work and Drug Testing Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a 50 hour workweek for Federal prison inmates and to establish a grant program for mandatory drug testing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mandatory Prison Work and Drug Testing Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4169-4170"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Prison administration"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners' rights"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sexual abstinence"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mandatory Prison Work and Drug Testing Act of 2003 - Amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require inmates confined in Federal prisons to engage in: (1) work for not less than 50 hours weekly; (2) job training; and (3) educational and life skills preparation study. Allows the services of inmates to be made available to nonprofit entities.Prescribes the portions of an inmate's earned wages to be allocated to offset the cost of incarceration, for victim restitution, to be held for the inmate until release in a non-interest bearing account, to be paid directly to the inmate for mandatory expenses and daily basic needs while incarcerated, and to be distributed to certain States and local jurisdictions.Requires: (1) the establishment of a zero tolerance policy for drug use in the Federal prison system, including random drug testing of inmates and prison employees, routine sweeps for contraband, and residential drug treatment programs for all inmates; and (2) the Bureau of Prisons to ensure that Federal prisoners do not use or possess tobacco, possess or view sexually explicit materials, possess televisions (unless provided by the prison for group viewing), listen to music containing violent or certain other types of lyrics, view cable television which is not educational, and engage in sexual activity.Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to direct the Attorney General to make incentive grants to eligible States and local governments to establish drug-free prisons and jails.Requires the Bureau of Prisons to place in a shock incarceration program any person who is sentenced to a term of imprisonment (current law permits program placement for a consenting person sentenced to imprisonment for 12 to 30 months).</summary>
</bill>
