<bill session="119" type="h" number="3639" updated="2025-11-18T09:05:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VET PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Exposed to Toxic PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to furnish hospital care and medical services to veterans and dependents who were stationed at military installations at which the veterans and dependents were exposed to perfluorooctanoic acid or other per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, to provide for a presumption of service connection for certain veterans who were stationed at military installations at which the veterans were exposed to such substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2025-08-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000602" joined="2025-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000604" joined="2025-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2025-08-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000402" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2025-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2025-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001232" joined="2025-08-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001241" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000622" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001225" joined="2025-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-13T21:14:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Exposed to Toxic PFAS Act or the VET PFAS Act

This bill provides eligibility for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) hospital care and medical services to veterans and their family members (including those in utero) who have specified conditions and resided at a military installation where individuals were exposed to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly known as PFAS. PFAS are man-made and may have adverse human health effects.

Hospital care and medical services may not be furnished for a condition that is found to have resulted from a cause other than the exposure to PFAS at a military installation.

The VA may provide reimbursement for hospital care or medical services provided to a family member only after the family member or provider has exhausted all claims and remedies otherwise available for payment of such care.

For disability compensation purposes, the bill establishes a presumption of service-connection for specified conditions in veterans who served at a military installation at which individuals were exposed to PFAS. Under a presumption of service-connection, specific conditions diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.</summary>
</bill>
