<bill session="117" type="h" number="6410" updated="2023-02-21T15:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NIST Wildland Fire Communications and Information Dissemination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NIST Wildland Fire Communications and Information Dissemination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the National Institute of Standards and Technology to conduct research on public safety communication coordination standards among wildland firefighters and fire management response officials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2022-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2022-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-18T11:31:25Z" status="Introduced in House">NIST Wildland Fire Communications and Information Dissemination Act

This bill requires research on public safety communication coordination standards related to wildland firefighting.

The Public Safety and Communications Research Division of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) must carry out research on such standards among wildland firefighters, fire management response officials, and specified federal agencies responsible for coordinating and mobilizing for wildland fire and other incidents. The research must also focus on improving and integrating existing communications systems to allow for secure, real-time transmission of data, alerts, and advisories to fire management officials and wildland firefighters. In carrying out the research, the division must (1) conduct live and virtual field tests of equipment, software, and other technologies; and (2) consult with NIST's Fire Research Division and communication technology manufacturers.

Informed by the research, NIST must publish recommendations for specified federal agencies to improve public safety communication coordination standards among wildland first responders and fire management officials. In addition, NIST must advise the Office of Management and Budget and the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy concerning the agencies' implementation of the recommendations.

Within one year of the publication of NIST's recommendations, the Government Accountability Office must report on the extent to which the agencies have implemented the recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
