<bill session="118" type="h" number="3911" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ukrainian Adjustment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ukrainian Adjustment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for adjustment of status of nationals of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2023-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-14T19:46:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Ukrainian Adjustment Act of 2023

This bill provides a streamlined process for certain Ukrainian nationals (including accompanying spouse and children) who are living in the United States to receive lawful permanent resident status.

Specifically, the bill permits Ukrainian nationals who have been paroled into the United States after February 20, 2014, to apply for and receive lawful permanent resident status. Additionally, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may waive grounds for inadmissibility (excluding certain crimes or security related grounds) for individuals who apply for status adjustment. DHS must establish vetting requirements (including an interview) for applicants that are equivalent to those under the United States Refugee Admissions Program.

The bill also preserves eligibility for the status adjustment of certain battered spouses whose eligibility for such status stemmed from a marriage that has terminated.

Finally, the bill requires DHS to issue guidance to implement these requirements and establishes a deadline for eligible individuals to apply for adjustment.</summary>
</bill>
