<bill session="109" type="h" number="1653" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:30Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE-ID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Americans From Exporting Identification Data Act</title>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding Americans From Exporting Identification Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the transfer of personal information to any person outside the United States, without notice and consent, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2005-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="810" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-28T19:57:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding Americans From Exporting Identification Data Act or the SAFE-ID Act - Requires business enterprises to give U.S. citizens notice before transmitting personally identifiable information about such citizens to foreign affiliates or subcontractors located in countries with adequate privacy protections. Prohibits such transmittal where adequate privacy protections are lacking, unless: (1) the business enterprise discloses the lack of protections and obtains the citizen's prior consent for transmittal; and (2) such consent is renewed by the citizen within one year before the transmittal.

Prohibits business entities from denying goods and services or modifying business terms for any person based on that person's exercise of consent rights provided by this Act or other law.

Requires violations of this Act to be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act.

Creates a private right of action in State court for violations of this Act. Authorizes States, on behalf of their residents, to bring civil actions in Federal court for such violations. Requires prior notice to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) of State actions and authorizes the FTC's intervention and appeal.

Directs the FTC to certify those countries that have legal systems providing adequate privacy protections. Creates a presumption of inadequacy for foreign laws that are less protective of privacy than Federal law or the law of any State, or where the FTC determines that enforcement is lacking. Requires certification of countries whose laws meet the requirements of the European Union Data Protection Directive, unless such laws are not adequately enforced.</summary>
</bill>
