<bill session="118" type="h" number="8771" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:29Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-28T11:06:35-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-06-28T11:06:35-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2025, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-09">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House. Hearings printed: S. Hrg. 118-603.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House. Hearings printed: S. Hrg. 118-603.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House. Hearings printed: S. Hrg. 118-603.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-14">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-554, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-06-14" calendar="Union" number="457">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 457.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-06-25T21:01:22-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1316 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771 and H.R. 8752. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771, and H.R. 8752, all under a structured rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:50:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1316.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4262-4319" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4266-4297" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:50:20-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771 and H.R. 8752. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771, and H.R. 8752, all under a structured rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:50:45-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1316 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:50:46-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Randy K. Weber, Sr. to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:51:58-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 8771.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:30:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Diaz-Balart amendment en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:32:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:38:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:39:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:45:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:46:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:52:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:53:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:56:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T17:57:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:04:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:11:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burlison amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:18:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:21:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 9, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:22:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:26:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 13, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:27:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:35:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 14, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:35:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:39:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 15, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:40:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:45:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 16, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:47:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:53:14-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 18, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T18:53:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:01:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 19, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Greene (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:02:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:11:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Greene (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:12:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:20:31-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 21, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:21:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:28:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 22, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:29:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Issa amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:35:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Issa amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:42:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lawler amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:50:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:56:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mace amendment No. 35, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Mace demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T19:57:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mace amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T20:05:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mace amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Mace demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T20:06:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moskowitz amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T20:11:03-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moskowitz amendment No. 45, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T20:15:30-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Diaz-Balart moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T20:15:46-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T20:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 8771 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:27:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4326-4354" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:27:38-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:29:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:35:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:41:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:49:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 50, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:50:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T09:59:26-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 54, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T10:00:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ramirez amendment No. 57.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T10:13:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Spartz amendment No. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T10:19:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Spartz amendment No. 59, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Meng demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T10:23:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T10:33:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Steube amendment No. 61, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Issa demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:09:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:16:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:22:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 63, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:23:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:28:19-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 64, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Tenney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:29:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:34:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:40:36-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 68, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:45:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Waltz amendment No. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:54:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Waltz amendment No. 72, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T12:55:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment No. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T13:01:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wilson (SC) amendment No. 75, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Wilson (SC) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T13:01:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Diaz-Balart moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T13:01:55-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T13:02:41-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 8771 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T15:31:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4389-4393" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T15:31:15-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T16:15:33-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 8771.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T16:16:19-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27T16:16:26-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced further proceedings on H.R. 8771 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:54:09-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1(c) of Rule XIX, the House resumed consideration on H.R. 8771.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:54:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4424-4426" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:54:30-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gros as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:55:10-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Meng moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4425" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:55:22-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T11:01:10-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 200 - 212 (Roll no. 334).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="335" datetime="2024-06-28T11:06:35-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 212 - 200 (Roll no. 335).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T11:06:38-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T11:06:39-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 8771.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="507">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 507.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported Original Measure"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity=""/>
    <committee code="SSAP20" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Hearings By (Subcommittee), Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1316" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4797" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="African Development Foundation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Central Europe"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Ethiopia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guatemala"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Inter-American Foundation"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Malawi"/>
    <term name="Maldives"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Morocco"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Organization of American States"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Sri Lanka"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Trade and Development Agency"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for Global Media"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom"/>
    <term name="U.S. Institute of Peace"/>
    <term name="U.S. International Development Finance Corporation"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
    <term name="Zimbabwe"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1066"/>
    <amendment number="h1065"/>
    <amendment number="h1064"/>
    <amendment number="h1063"/>
    <amendment number="h1062"/>
    <amendment number="h1061"/>
    <amendment number="h1060"/>
    <amendment number="h1059"/>
    <amendment number="h1058"/>
    <amendment number="h1057"/>
    <amendment number="h1056"/>
    <amendment number="h1055"/>
    <amendment number="h1054"/>
    <amendment number="h1053"/>
    <amendment number="h1052"/>
    <amendment number="h1051"/>
    <amendment number="h1050"/>
    <amendment number="h1049"/>
    <amendment number="h1048"/>
    <amendment number="h1047"/>
    <amendment number="h1046"/>
    <amendment number="h1045"/>
    <amendment number="h1044"/>
    <amendment number="h1043"/>
    <amendment number="h1042"/>
    <amendment number="h1041"/>
    <amendment number="h1040"/>
    <amendment number="h1039"/>
    <amendment number="h1038"/>
    <amendment number="h1037"/>
    <amendment number="h1036"/>
    <amendment number="h1035"/>
    <amendment number="h1034"/>
    <amendment number="h1033"/>
    <amendment number="h1032"/>
    <amendment number="h1031"/>
    <amendment number="h1030"/>
    <amendment number="h1029"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-09-13T15:58:15Z" status="Passed House">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2025

This bill provides FY2025 appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs.

The bill provides appropriations to the State Department for

Administration of Foreign Affairs,International Organizations, andInternational Commissions.The bill provides appropriations for related agencies and programs, including

the U.S. Agency for Global Media,the Asia Foundation,the U.S. Institute of Peace,the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund,the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship Program,the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program,the East-West Center, andthe National Endowment for Democracy.The bill provides appropriations for other commissions, including

the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad,the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom,the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe,the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China, andthe U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission.The bill provides appropriations to

the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID),the State Department and the President for International Security Assistance, andInternational Financial Institutions for Multilateral Assistance.The bill provides appropriations for bilateral economic assistance, including programs and activities conducted by

the President;the State Department;Independent Agencies, including the Peace Corps, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Inter-American Foundation, and the U.S. African Development Foundation; andthe Department of the Treasury.The bill provides appropriations for export and investment assistance to

the Export-Import Bank of the United States,the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, andthe U.S. Trade and Development Agency.The bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.

&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-554</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
