<bill session="118" type="s" number="1240" updated="2025-11-19T03:30:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Millennium Challenge Corporation Candidate Country Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Millennium Challenge Corporation Candidate Country Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Millennium Challenge Corporation Candidate Country Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the requirements for candidate countries under the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2023-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-05-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="50">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 50.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5009" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3042" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-14T22:48:21Z" status="Reported to Senate">Millennium Challenge Corporation Candidate Country Reform Act

This bill modifies the per capita income requirements for countries to be considered candidates for assistance from the Millennium Challenge Corporation (MCC). The MCC program provides assistance to eligible developing countries through a competitive selection process based on various factors, including a country's per capita income, level of economic freedom, and effectiveness of government.

Currently, to be a candidate to receive MCC assistance, the country must have a per capita income not greater than the lower-middle-income country threshold established by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD). Under the bill, a candidate country must instead have a per capita income equal to or less than the World Bank's threshold for initiating the IRDB graduation process. (This graduation process begins when IRDB determines that a country is able to sustain long-term development without further IRDB financing. For 2024, the threshold for initiating discussions about a country's graduation begins when a country exceeds $7,805 in per capita income.)</summary>
</bill>
