<bill session="118" type="h" number="1697" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Precision Agriculture Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Precision Agriculture Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the participation of precision agriculture in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001221" joined="2023-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1319-1320"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="734" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-04T19:10:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Precision Agriculture Act of 2023 

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to develop voluntary standards for precision agriculture (i.e., managing, tracking, or reducing crop or livestock production inputs, including seed, feed, fertilizer, chemicals, water, and time at a heightened level of spatial and temporal granularity to improve efficiencies, reduce waste, and maintain environmental quality).

 USDA, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), must develop voluntary, consensus-based, private sector-led interconnectivity standards and best practices for precision agriculture to promote economies of scale and ease the burden of adoption. USDA must (1) coordinate with relevant public and trusted private sector stakeholders and relevant industry organizations, and (2) consult with sector-specific agencies and state and local governments.

Further, in developing the standards, USDA must, in consultation with NIST and the FCC, consider

 the connectivity needs of precision agriculture equipment, cybersecurity challenges facing precision agriculture, and the impact of artificial intelligence on this area. The Government Accountability Office must periodically assess and report on the standards.</summary>
</bill>
