<bill session="117" type="s" number="4789" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expand Housing Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expand Housing Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Prevent Evictions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">State Affordable Housing Trust Fund Match Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Workforce Housing Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a competitive grant program at the Department of Housing and Urban Development to support the construction, preservation, or rehabilitation of affordable workforce housing in areas with shortages of affordable housing units for sale, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-10T19:05:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expand Housing Opportunities Act

This bill establishes new, and expands existing, grants for increasing the availability of affordable housing.

Specifically, the bill sets up grant programs that support (1) construction, preservation, or rehabilitation of owner-occupied, affordable housing; and (2) implementation and administration of landlord-tenant mediation programs. Further, the bill allows states to apply for additional funding through a block grant that supports affordable housing activities that benefit low-income individuals (the HOME Investment Partnership Program) to cover certain costs associated with affordable housing incurred during the COVID-19 emergency.</summary>
</bill>
