<bill session="108" type="s" number="2066" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fishery Conservation and Management Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations to the Secretary of Commerce for the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act for fiscal years 2004, 2005, 2006, 2007, and 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fishery Conservation and Management Amendments Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1018-1019"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Subcommittee on Oceans, Fisheries and Coast Guard. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSCM09" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="Oceans, Fisheries and Coast Guard" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean Sea"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economic research"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Overfishing"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tuna"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-03T21:18:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fishery Conservation and Management Amendments Act of 2004 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevenson Fishery Conservation and Management Act to: (1) extend, through FY 2008, the authorization of appropriations under the Act; (2) provide for implementation of a treaty between the United States and Canada concerning Pacific coast albacore tuna fishing; and (3) allow, with respect to Pacific insular area fisheries and fishing agreements, monitoring programs that the Secretary of Commerce determines to monitor harvests by foreign fishing vessels.

Requires fishery management plans (plans) for Federal fisheries to include harvest and processing revenues, production costs, capital expenditures, and other fishing or processing expenses. Allows any plan established by a regional fishery management council to establish a fishing quota system for achieving optimum yield, including compliance with specified quota share and allocation requirements. Requires: (1) a quota system to be approved in advance by more than two-thirds of those voting in a referendum among eligible fishing permit holders; (2) the National Research Council, every five years, to provide an independent review of the effectiveness of fishing quota systems in Federal fisheries; and (3) the Secretary to issue regulations establishing requirements for the quota system. Directs the Secretary to: (1) make a preliminary evaluation of a plan or amendment, or a regulation concerning a plan or amendment; and (2) take specified action, depending on whether evaluation results are positive or negative.

Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations governing fishing after January 1, 2008, that: (1) limit fishing mortality to specified rates; and (2) allocate both fishing restrictions and recovery benefits fairly among fishery gear sectors and communities.

Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) conduct a fishing capacity reduction program in a fishery under the authority of the Secretary, a regional council, or a State; and (2) implement an information collection or observer program for the collection of necessary additional information under a plan. Allows plan information to be disclosed to State employees responsible for plan monitoring.

Directs the Secretary to establish a national cooperative research and management program between fishing industry participants, affected States, and the National Marine Fisheries Service (Service). Requires an independent review of the Service's procedures for ensuring data quality in the data collection phase of the stock assessment program.

Authorizes Federal-State cooperative marine law enforcement agreements.

Requires the Scientific and Statistical Committees of each council to identify and report to the Secretary priority research needs to support ecosystem-based management of fisheries within its jurisdiction.</summary>
</bill>
