<bill session="118" type="s" number="5384" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Returning Education to Our States Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Returning Education to Our States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to abolish the Department of Education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-13T15:40:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Returning Education to Our States Act

This bill abolishes the Department of Education (ED) and terminates any applicable program for which it has administrative responsibility, except for those programs transferred to other federal agencies.

Specifically, the bill transfers from ED to the Department of Health and Human Services (1) all functions, programs, and authorities of ED under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act; and (2) each Impact Aid program.&#160;

Additionally, the bill transfers each authority and program of ED's Office of Indian Education to the Department of the Interior.

The bill transfers the following programs to the Department of the Treasury:

the Federal Pell Grant Program;the Federal Family Education Loan Program;the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program;the Federal Perkins Loan Program;the activities described in Part F (need analysis), Part G (general provisions relating to student assistance programs), or Part H (program integrity) of Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965;the Health Education Assistance Loan Program; andthe programs under the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 and the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002.The bill also directs Treasury to establish two block grant programs, through which Treasury must make allocations to states to (1) support elementary and secondary education, including career and technical education; and (2) support&#160;postsecondary education.

The Department of Justice's Civil Rights Division shall be responsible for receiving complaints and enforcing federal civil rights laws that are applicable to these block grant programs and federal student aid programs.</summary>
</bill>
