<bill session="118" type="h" number="5146" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing Gig Economy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Gig Economy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Commerce to conduct a study on the gig economy and the impact the gig economy has on the United States overall economy, including the impact that State laws have had on the gig economy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000615" joined="2023-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 12 - 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 20.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T18:27:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Gig Economy Act

This bill requires the Department of Commerce to study and report on the impact of the gig economy on U.S. businesses conducting interstate commerce. The gig economy includes businesses that maintain an online application or platform to facilitate the exchange of goods or services by users of the application or platform.

The study shall involve, among other things, (1) outreach to participating entities to establish a list of industry sectors that take part in the gig economy, (2) surveying federal activity on the gig economy to develop a list of agencies asserting jurisdiction over entities in and sectors of the gig economy, and (3) surveying state laws regulating the gig economy to determine their impact on both the gig economy and the U.S. economy.

Commerce must report to Congress the results of such study and any recommendations to promote the growth of the gig economy.</summary>
</bill>
