<bill session="111" type="h" number="4804" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:25Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Human Space Flight Activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000299" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000366" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000553" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001161" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000466" joined="2010-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2010-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3068" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-23T12:44:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010 - Directs the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to: (1) take all necessary steps to ensure that all Space Shuttle Program activities and operations are able to continue, or to be resumed, including flight operations and support, pending the completion of required reviews, requirements, and reports; and (2) ensure space shuttle launch capability through FY2011 by enabling launch, at a minimum, of all payloads manifested as of February 28, 2010.

Instructs the Administrator to ask the National Academies of Science (NAS) to appoint a Flight Certification Review Committee to: (1) review space shuttle certification activities undertaken or initiated after February 2003; and (2) assess their adequacy in assuring vehicle durability, flight-worthiness, and sustainability for continued operations of up to five years beyond the flight manifest planned as February 2010.

Requires NASA to operate the Space Shuttle Program at a flight rate of not more than 2 missions in any consecutive 12-month period during FY2010-FY2012.

Prohibits termination of such Program as of a scheduled date certain.

Specifies the conditions for termination of space shuttle missions operations. Requires a determination by the President regarding termination of missions in support of International Space Station (ISS) operations and Congress to be notified of any such determination.

Sets forth requirements for the decommissioning of the remaining space shuttles and the preservation of shuttle vehicle and systems design and engineering data.

States that is shall be the policy of the United States, in consultation with its ISS International Partners, to support full and complete utilization of the Space Station through at least the year 2020.

Requires a review of all essential vehicles, components, and permanent scientific equipment on board or planned for installation aboard the ISS, including international partner elements, and the Comptroller General to monitor such review.

Establishes responsibility for the ISS United States National Laboratory in the Space Operations Mission Directorate, ISS Program Office. Delegates to a Deputy Associate Administrator for ISS the conduct of ISS operations by NASA and non-NASA organizations.

Establishes a management entity for the National Laboratory to implement research and development projects using the ISS U.S. segment.

Guarantees National Laboratory-managed experiments access to 50% of the U.S.'s research facilities allocation through FY2014, increased by an additional 10% annually through FY2020.

Establishes a National Space Transportation System. Requires a technology development plan. Provides for specified crew and cargo studies, reviews, and activities.</summary>
</bill>
