<bill session="116" type="s" number="2186" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:31Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Personal Information Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Personal Information Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require entities to provide consumers with the opportunity to prohibit the entity from collecting or using certain data concerning the consumer and to request deletion of such data.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-02T16:44:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Personal Information Act of 2019 This bill requires covered entities to provide consumers with the opportunity to prohibit the collection, sale, or transfer of specified personally identifiable information about the consumer and requires the covered entity to, upon request by the consumer, delete any such personally identifiable information that has been collected or stored by the covered entity. This bill applies to (1) business corporations, (2) nonprofits, and (3) common carriers that (1) have annual revenue greater than $25 million, (2) have access to personally identifiably information of 50,000 or more individuals, or (3) derive at least 50% of their revenue from selling such information. These requirements may be enforced by the Federal Trade Commission or by a state attorney general bringing a lawsuit on behalf of the state's residents.</summary>
</bill>
