<bill session="118" type="h" number="3570" updated="2025-11-19T03:28:07Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Comprehensive Response to Fentanyl-Related Substances and Fentanyl-Laced Substances Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Response to Fentanyl-Related Substances and Fentanyl-Laced Substances Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide public awareness and outreach regarding the dangers of fentanyl, to expand the grants authorized under the Comprehensive Opioid Abuse Grant Program, to expand treatment and recovery services for people with opioid addictions, and to increase and to provide enhanced penalties for certain offenses involving counterfeit pills.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001066" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000309" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2023-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2486"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2520"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4272" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-19T19:48:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Comprehensive Response to Fentanyl-Related Substances and Fentanyl-Laced Substances Act

This bill establishes several programs and requirements to address the use of fentanyl and fentanyl-laced substances.

For example, the bill expands the Comprehensive Opioid Abuse Grant Program in the Department of Justice (DOJ) to include training and resources for teachers on how to carry and administer opioid overdose reversal drugs (e.g., naloxone). DOJ must also increase resources and establish an interagency task force for law enforcement agencies to combat the trafficking of fentanyl-laced substances.

Additionally, the Department of Health and Human Services must develop a national strategy to prevent the use of fentanyl-laced substances, award grants to state and localities for treatment programs for those who are addicted to fentanyl-laced substances, and research the health effects of fentanyl-laced substances.

The bill also increases criminal penalties for adulterating or misbranding drugs if the violation results in serious bodily injury or death (imprisonment of up to 10 years, a fine of up to $1 million, or both for violations that result in serious bodily injury, and up to life imprisonment, a fine of up to $5 million, or both for violations that result in death). Penalties are higher for violations that include the intent to defraud or mislead. The bill adds up to 5 years of additional imprisonment if the violation involves drugs that are promoted or sold online.</summary>
</bill>
