<bill session="116" type="h" number="7812" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ORE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Onshoring Rare Earths Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ORE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permanently allow a tax deduction at the time an investment is made in property used to extract critical minerals and metals from the United States, to modify the prohibition on the acquisition of certain sensitive materials from non-allied foreign nations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Revenue Measures.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM05" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Tax" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3694" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4537" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8143" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-04T14:15:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Onshoring Rare Earths Act of 2020 or the ORE Act

This bill allows permanent expensing of property used in the extraction of certain critical minerals and metals within the United States and of nonresidential real property used in extracting such minerals and metals. Expensing is the treatment of expenditures as operating costs deductible in full in the current taxable year.

The bill allows a new tax deduction for 200% of the cost of purchasing or acquiring such critical minerals and metals extracted from deposits in the United States.

The bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish a pilot project grant program for the development of critical minerals and metals in the United States. A grant awarded under such program may not exceed $10 million. In awarding grants, DOD must give priority to projects determined to be economically viable over the long term and must allot 30% of grants funds to the secondary recovery of critical minerals and metals.</summary>
</bill>
