<bill session="118" type="h" number="8649" updated="2025-11-18T18:59:23Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency in Reporting of Adversarial Contributions to Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Transparency in Reporting of Adversarial Contributions to Education Act</title>
    <title type="display">Transparency in Reporting of Adversarial Contributions to Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that parents are aware of foreign influence in their child's public school, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001314"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 118-575.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-07-05" calendar="Union" number="476">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 476.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4822" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-05T15:08:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency in Reporting of Adversarial Contributions to Education Act

This bill requires each local educational agency (LEA), as a condition of receiving federal elementary and secondary education funds, to ensure that each elementary and secondary school served by the LEA notifies parents of their rights to request and receive information regarding foreign influence (e.g., influence by China) in schools.

These rights include the right to

review (and make copies of at no cost) any curricular or professional development material used at the school that was obtained using funds received from a foreign government or a foreign entity of concern;know, by written response, how many school personnel are compensated using funds received from a foreign government or a foreign entity of concern; andknow, by written response, information about funding from or agreements (e.g., contracts) with a foreign country or a foreign entity of concern.Parents must submit a written request for this information.

Each school must post on a publicly accessible website (or otherwise widely disseminate to the public) a summary notice of parental rights under the bill.&#160;

The bill requires the Department of Education to notify state educational agencies (SEAs) about the bill's requirements. Each SEA must, as a condition of receiving federal elementary and secondary education funds, notify&#160;LEAs about the bill's requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-575</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
