<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2798</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:17:05Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:17:05Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-11-18</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
            <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2010-04-21T20:41:29Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-09-27T19:20:12Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-08-05T20:40:52Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-11-18T23:43:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-313</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>4398</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-06-22</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 599.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-313.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-313.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-04-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
            <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-566.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-18</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S11497-11499)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-18</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11496-11497, S11498-11499)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000038</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Mark [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARK</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000584</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Risch, James E. [R-ID]</fullName>
        <firstName>James</firstName>
        <lastName>Risch</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ID</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-11-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000880</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Crapo, Mike [R-ID]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Crapo</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ID</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-02-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-08-27T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 2798, National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21796</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on August 5, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-08-27T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 2798, National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21796</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on August 5, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative and renewable resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arizona</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Colorado</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Ecology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Idaho</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Montana</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nevada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oregon</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>South Dakota</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Utah</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Washington State</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Watersheds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wyoming</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-11-18</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-01T17:56:58Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2009 - Designates certain areas in the states of Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming as insect and disease emergency areas. Allows the designation of additional insect and disease emergency areas in accordance with this Act. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary), in implementing the emergency forest restoration program, to make payments to owners of nonindustrial private forest land to carry out emergency measures in response to an insect and disease infestation emergency under this Act. </p> <p>Authorizes the: (1) Secretary to enter into contracts or agreements with a state to allow the performance of watershed restoration and protection services on National Forest System land when similar and complementary restoration and protection services are being carried out by the state on adjacent state or private land; and (2) Secretary of the Interior to carry out such activities on public land administered by the Secretary of the Interior. </p> <p>Bars the Secretary from obligating funds to cover the costs of canceling Forest Service multiyear stewardship contracts until the date on which they are canceled. Extends permanently the authority under which the Forest Service may enter into such contracts with private persons and entities to perform services to achieve land management goals for the national forests and the public lands that meet local and rural community needs. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-01T17:58:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to identify high-risk areas within the National Forest System in the states of Alaska, Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming (the affected states). Defines &quot;high-risk area&quot; to mean a road, trail, or other area that poses a high risk to public health or safety due to hazard trees resulting from landscape-scale tree mortality caused by an insect or disease epidemic.<br> </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to develop educational materials describing the risk posed by hazard trees in high-risk areas and the measures that can be taken by the public in avoiding or reducing such risk. </p> <p> Directs the Secretary to identify insect or disease epidemic areas within the National Forest System in the affected states and to include with such information an estimate of the annual mortality caused by the epidemic and a projection of future tree mortality resulting from such epidemic. </p> <p>Requires the information identified pursuant to this section to be made available to affected communities, fire departments, and the public.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts or provide financial assistance through cooperative agreements to help in the collection, development, monitoring, and distribution of such information and materials. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary to assist state and local governments, Indian tribes, private landowners, and other persons from an insect or disease epidemic area within the National Forest System in an affected state with the collection, harvest, storage, and transportation of eligible material to a biomass conversion facility in accordance with the Business Crop Assistance Program. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to make payments to owners of nonindustrial private forest land in affected states to carry out emergency measures to restore their land after an insect or disease infestation. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to carry out authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in affected states on National Forest System land. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior to enter into good neighbor agreements with governors to coordinate the procurement and implementation of authorized restoration services. Defines a &quot;good neighbor agreement&quot; as a nonfunding master cooperative agreement between the Secretary and a governor or a memorandum of agreement or understanding between the Secretary and a governor.</p> <p>Requires contracts and subcontracts for authorized restoration services under this section to be in compliance with small business assistance and protection provisions.</p> <p>Terminates the authority of the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements and contracts under this section on September 30, 2019, and prohibits the termination date of such an agreement from extending beyond September 30, 2020.</p> <p>Repeals separate authorities for cooperative services on National Forest System lands in Colorado and Utah. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfire through the facilitation of insect and disease infestation treatment of National Forest System and adjacent land, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>National Forest Insect and Disease Emergency Act of 2010</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-27T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s2798rs/xml/BILLS-111s2798rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-11-18T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s2798is/xml/BILLS-111s2798is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 599.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
