<bill session="109" type="s" number="3743" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:27Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Screening for Health of Infants and Newborns Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve newborn screening activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Screening for Health of Infants and Newborns Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHINE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000121" joined="2006-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8280-8281"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hereditary diseases"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-25T18:50:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Screening for Health of Infants and Newborns Act or the SHINE Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to develop guidelines that states may follow in reporting data from newborn screening tests.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to develop guidelines to: (1) monitor and evaluate newborn screening activities; and (2) coordinate the results of surveillance activities.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC and the National Center on Birth Defects and Developmental Disabilities, to develop a surveillance system for newborn screening.

Directs the Advisory Committee on Heritable Disorders and Genetic Diseases in Newborns and Children to advise the Secretary on the guidelines and on monitoring and evaluating newborn screening and surveillance activities.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) direct the Maternal and Child Health Bureau of HRSA to establish a central clearinghouse of current education and family support and services information, materials, resources, research, and data on newborn screening; (2) award grants for demonstration projects that increase state capacity to screen for all of the core conditions; (3) award Hunter Kelly Newborn Screening grants for demonstration projects that develop screening tests for additional newborn conditions or develop multiple markers to increase the specificity of such tests; and (4) appoint an Interagency Grant Review Panel to select grant applications and provide oversight on the grant program.</summary>
</bill>
