<bill session="110" type="h" number="6494" updated="2021-06-07T20:05:11Z">
  <state datetime="2008-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRO-VETS Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Real Outreach for Veterans Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Providing Real Outreach for Veterans Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide veterans with individualized notice about available benefits, to streamline application processes for the benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001247" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001164" joined="2008-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2008-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2008-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3307" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-10-17T19:15:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Real Outreach for Veterans Act of 2008 or PRO-VETS Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Defense for the transfer of data to the Secretary for providing members of the Armed Forces and veterans with individualized information concerning veterans' benefits that each member and veteran may be eligible for. Requires the Secretary, after receiving such data, to: (1) compile a list of all benefits for which each member or veteran may be eligible; (2) notify the member or veteran (or their legal representative) of such benefits; and (3) provide a second notification if the member or veteran does not apply for a listed benefit within 60 days, as well as annual notifications thereafter. Requires additional notifications based on changed circumstances. Allows each member or veteran the option to decline further notifications.

Directs the Secretary to use transferred data to reduce the amount of information that a member or veteran must provide when applying for benefits.

Requires the Secretary of Defense to provide a member or veteran the opportunity to decline authorization for the transfer of information under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
