<bill session="117" type="h" number="3812" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring U.S. Leadership in International Organizations Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage Foreign Service officers to serve at the United States mission to the United Nations, increase Federal Government details to international organizations, increase multilateral training at the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring U.S. Leadership in International Organizations Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2021-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Development, International Organizations and Global Corporate Social Impact.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA17" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-13T16:02:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring U.S. Leadership in International Organizations Act of 2021

This bill makes changes and establishes requirements to expand U.S. engagement with international organizations.

Changes include eliminating (1) a limitation on the number of foreign service employees on the staff of the U.S. Mission to the United Nations who are eligible for housing benefits, and (2) a requirement that those employees contribute a portion of their pay toward housing costs. Additionally, the value of the housing benefits is excluded from income for federal tax purposes.

The bill also allows consideration of an employee's service formulating policy for or representing the United States at an international, multilateral, or similar organization in Foreign Service processes for promotions, performance pay, and related matters.

The Department of State must establish training on conducting diplomacy at international and multilateral organizations and on negotiating multilateral international agreements. The bill requires this training for certain State Department employees, such as those assigned to U.S. missions at international organizations.

Furthermore, the bill designates the U.S. Special Representative to the United Nations as a standing member of the President's cabinet and outlines U.S. policy for staffing and paying dues to international and multilateral organizations.

The State Department must annually report to Congress about the number of and related information about federal employees detailed or transferred to international organizations.</summary>
</bill>
