<bill session="115" type="h" number="6185" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:19Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct an accurate comprehensive student count for the purposes of calculating formula allocations for programs under the Johnson-O'Malley Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2018-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2018-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2018-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2018-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="943" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-20T19:57:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Johnson-O'Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to annually update the number of Indian students eligible for the Johnson-O'Malley Program (JOM Program). The JOM Program awards contracts to tribal organizations, schools, states, and others to educate Indian students. Under the program, the contract amounts are based on the number of students served.

Under the bill, contracting parties must annually report to Interior on the number of students they serve and how contract funds were used. If they fail to submit the report, Interior must deny them program funds for the fiscal year following the academic year for which the report should have been submitted.

This bill allows Interior to make recommendations for legislation to increase funds per eligible student and to identify additional sources of funding that do not reallocate existing funds utilized by Indian students.

 Interior must confer with Indian tribes, state and local education agencies, and Alaska Native organizations that have not participated in the program to determine their interest in the JOM Program.

This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to review the implementation of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
