<bill session="116" type="h" number="5783" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Equitable Transit Oriented Development Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to modify the transportation finance infrastructure and innovation program with respect to community development financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equitable Transit Oriented Development Support Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Community Development Financial Institutions Fund"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-26T18:35:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Equitable Transit Oriented Development Support Act

This bill revises the transportation finance infrastructure and innovation (TIFIA) program to make community development financial institutions (CDFIs) eligible for federal transportation infrastructure loans.

The loans must be used for CDFI transit-oriented development projects located within one-half mile in an urban area or three-fourths of a mile in a rural area of a fixed guideway transit facility, passenger rail station, intercity bus station or intermodal facility that supports (1) commercial facilities or businesses that are located in low-income communities, (2) community facilities that are located in low-income communities or principally serve low-income persons, or (3) housing that is principally affordable to low-income persons.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) must require any CDFI participating in the TIFIA program to establish a CDFI transit-oriented development account into which the proceeds of a secured loan made to the CDFI and any loan repayments from public or private entities receiving loans made to fund CDFI transit-oriented development projects will be deposited.

DOT must set-aside not more than 10% of funding available to carry out the TIFIA program for CDFI transit-oriented development accounts.</summary>
</bill>
