<bill session="117" type="h" number="5791" updated="2023-08-07T13:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SERVE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SERVE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Service Education Reallocation for Vacant Elected offices Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10 and title 46, United States Code, to allocate authority for nominations to the service academies in the event of the death, resignation, or expulsion from office of a Member of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2022-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2021-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2021-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2021-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2021-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2021-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3127" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-07T13:44:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Service Education Reallocation for Vacant Elected offices Act of 2021 or the SERVE Act of 2021

This bill modifies the authority to make nominations for cadets or midshipmen to the military service academies in situations where a Member of Congress has not submitted a nomination due to death, resignation from office, or expulsion from office and no successor member has been sworn in to office.

Specifically, in the event a Senator does not make a nomination for one of the specified reasons, the nominations must be made by the other Senator from the state concerned. In the event a Representative does not make a nomination for one of the specified reasons, the Senators from the state of the congressional district concerned must make the nomination, with nominations divided equally among Senators and any remainder going to the senior Senator from the state.</summary>
</bill>
