<bill session="116" type="h" number="8850" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:03Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To convey certain Federal land in California to Apple Valley, California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-28T20:06:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area Establishment Act

This bill directs, within five years of enactment of this bill, the Department of the Interior to convey to the town of Apple Valley, California, without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the surface estate of approximately 4,630 acres of identified land to be known and designated as the Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area. Such conveyance does not include the mineral estate.

The conveyance permits the town to use the conveyed land to provide

 a suitable location for the establishment of a centralized off-road vehicle recreation park; the public with opportunities for off-road vehicle recreation, including a location for races, competitive events, training and other commercial services that directly support a centralized off-road vehicle recreation area and town park; and a designated area and facilities that would discourage unauthorized use of off-highway vehicles in areas that have been identifiedy as containing environmentally sensitive land. The land conveyed may not be disposed of by the town without the approval of Interior.

Interior may develop a special management plan for the Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area to enhance the safe use of off-highway vehicles for recreational purposes.</summary>
</bill>
