<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="191" updated="2022-02-03T06:07:50Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2410" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-06-10T15:33:20-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001032"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <description>At the end of title X, add the following:    SEC. 10__. REPORT ON CHILD ABDUCTION.    Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report containing recommendations for changes to the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction and related United States laws and regulations regarding international parental child abduction that would, if enacted, provide the United States additional legal tools to ensure compliance with the Hague Convention and facilitate the swift return of United States children wrongfully removed from the United States as a result of international parental child abduction, such as in the case of Sean Goldman of Tinton Falls, New Jersey.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 11 printed in part C of House Report 111-134 to direct the Secretary of State to report within 60 days of enactment on changes in treaty and U.S. laws that could help improve compliance with the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-06-10T15:33:20-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Holt amendment (A011) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T15:21:43-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Holt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6494-6495" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6494" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T15:21:43-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Holt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6494-6495" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6494" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T15:33:20-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Holt amendment (A011) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T15:33:20-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
