<bill session="109" type="s" number="1846" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:49Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide assistance to rebuild communities, schools, and hospitals damaged by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance to rebuild communities, schools, and hospitals damaged by Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-21T20:03:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Declares that no limitation on the amount or percentage of assistance that may be provided in the form of a community disaster loan under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act shall apply to any community disaster loan to assist any local government with jurisdiction over a major disaster area relating to Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita.

Declares that no prohibition or limitation on reimbursement of salaries shall apply with respect to reimburswement of straight- and regular-time salaries of public personnel that provide, on or after August 29, 2005, essential public services in Louisiana on behalf of that state.

Authorizes FY2006 appropriations.

Provides that, of the amounts made available to the Department of Homeland Security for disaster relief under Public Law 109-62, not less than $1.5 billion shall be available to the appropriate federal agency heads to carry out the programs and activities authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
