<bill session="109" type="h" number="1317" updated="2022-02-03T05:32:37Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to clarify which disclosures of information are protected from prohibited personnel practices; to require a statement in nondisclosure policies, forms, and agreements to the effect that such policies, forms, and agreements are consistent with certain disclosure protections; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2006-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000552" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2005-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001152" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2006-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2006-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2005-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2005-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on 109-544, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Armed Services for a period ending not later than Sept. 11, 2006 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(c), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Homeland Security for a period ending not later than Sept. 11, 2006 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(i), rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Integration, and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-11">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 29, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-11">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Sept. 29, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 17, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>House Committee on Homeland Security Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 17, 2006.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-17">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Dec. 8, 2006.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3097" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="494" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-04T21:22:05Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Federal Employee Protection of Disclosures Act - (Sec. 2) Includes as a protected disclosure by a federal employee any lawful disclosure an employee or applicant for employment reasonably believes is credible evidence of waste, abuse, gross mismanagement, or substantial and specific danger to public health or safety without restriction as to time, place, form, motive, context, or prior disclosure. (Sec. 3) Defines the term "disclosure" to mean a formal or informal communication, but does not include a communication concerning policy decisions that lawfully exercise discretionary authority unless the employee providing the disclosure reasonably believes that the disclosure evidences: (1) any violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or (2) gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, an abuse of authority, or a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety. (Sec. 4) Codifies the legal standard for determining whether a whistleblower has a reasonable belief that a disclosure evidences governmental waste, fraud, or abuse, or a violation of law. (Sec. 5) Includes under the definition of "personnel action" the implementation or enforcement of any nondisclosure policy, form, or agreement. Prohibits taking the following actions against whistleblowers making protected disclosures: (1) the implementation or enforcement of any nondisclosure policy, form, or agreement; and (2) an investigation (other than routine nondiscretionary agency investigations) of an employee or applicant. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the President to exclude certain agencies engaged in the conduct of foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities from whistleblower protections if such exclusion is made prior to any personnel action against the whistleblower. (Sec. 7) Expands the authority of the Merit Systems Protection Board to impose disciplinary action for prohibited personnel practices. (Sec. 8) Requires a Government Accountability Office (GAO) study on security clearances revocations taking effect after 1996 with respect to personnel that filed claims in connection with such security clearance revocations. (Sec. 9) Permits an employee, former employee, or applicant to bring an action against the United States at law or equity for de novo review as an alternative recourse in seeking corrective action with respect to a prohibited personnel practice. (Sec. 10) Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to modify remedy and enforcement authority under provisions relating to the protection of contractor employees from reprisal for disclosure of certain information, including by permitting such an employee who has been subjected to a reprisal prohibited by such provisions to bring an action at law or equity for de novo review in order to seek compensatory damages and other relief available under those provisions. Makes an identical amendment with respect to federal military law relating to the protection of military contractor employees from reprisal for disclosure of certain information. (Sec. 11) Makes certain prohibited personnel practices provisions applicable to the Transportation Security Administration (TSA).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-544</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
