<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3101</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:14Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-03-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-03-10T22:09:13Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see S.3304, which became Public Law 111-260 on 10/8/2010.]]></text>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Army Corps of Engineers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>General Services Administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military procurement, research, weapons development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Office of Management and Budget (OMB)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-03-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-04-15T14:56:39Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Level Playing Field Contracting Act of 2010 - Directs the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council to amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) to prohibit an executive agency from entering into a covered consolidated civilian contract valued in excess of $2 million unless the agency's senior procurement official determines that the contract's consolidation is necessary and justified under specified criteria. Defines such a consolidated contract as: (1) a multiple award contract; or (2) a contract for property or services that combines discrete procurement requirements from existing contracts, adds new procurement requirements to an existing contract, or includes two or more procurement or acquisition requirements and that does not include any consolidated acquisition, procurement, or contracting plan of the Department of Defense (DOD).</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense to modify the DOD Supplement to FAR to prohibit an agency from entering into a covered consolidated Defense contract (a similarly defined DOD contract) valued in excess of $7.5 million unless the agency's senior procurement official determines that the contract's consolidation is necessary and justified under specified criteria or is appropriate in the face of exigent circumstances and national security.</p> <p>Directs the Council to amend FAR to require: (1) an agency to use a numeric grading or other quantitative methodology to evaluate bid proposals for each contract that is awarded through full and open competitive procedures and to disclose the methodology in the bid solicitation documents for the contract; and (2) agencies to encourage prospective contractors to utilize contracting assistance resources that are offered in their communities.</p> <p>Directs: (1) the Administrator of General Services (GSA) to report, annually, on efforts to enforce the local workforce subcontracting requirements included in GSA contracts; (2) each agency to report on the strength and sufficiency of its acquisition workforce; and (3) the Comptroller General to conduct studies of the effects of changes in the definition of and size standards for a "small business concern," the degree to which GSA, the Army Corps of Engineers, and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) have entered into contracts since January 1, 2004, with contractors that have previous experience performing federal contracts, and the size and experience of contractors awarded contracts by such entities.</p> <p>Amends the Small Business Act to require the Administrator of Small Business (SBA) and the GSA Administrator to jointly establish an outreach program to: (1) communicate with small businesses regarding government contracting opportunities; and (2) inform small businesses about opportunities to learn about the government contracting process.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Level Playing Field Contracting Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Level Playing Field Contracting Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reduce barriers to entry in Federal contracting, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Level Playing Field Contracting Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-03-10T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3101is/xml/BILLS-111s3101is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-03-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
