<bill session="117" type="s" number="1619" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reduce Bureaucracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for a 2-year prohibition on employment in a career civil service position for any former political appointee, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reduce Bureaucracy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-25T14:31:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reduce Bureaucracy Act

This bill prohibits certain political appointees from serving in career positions in federal agencies.

Specifically, the bill prohibits current and former presidential appointees, cabinet officials, and other senior officials from serving in career-appointment (i.e., permanent) positions in executive agencies without the approval of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM). Agencies must certify that the appointment is necessary in order for the agency to meet its mission and the OPM must determine that the appointment process was fair, open, and free from political influence in order to approve a request. OPM must also transmit approved requests to specified congressional committees before issuing final approval to agencies.

The bill also prohibits political appointees from serving in career positions for two years after their departure, and directs the OPM and the Office of Management and Budget to take any actions necessary so as to limit the number of political appointees to 2,000.</summary>
</bill>
