<bill session="117" type="h" number="7478" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE PLAY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE PLAY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Athletes, Families and Educators to Protect the Lives of Athletic Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote youth athletic safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5216" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4056" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-19T18:59:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Athletes, Families and Educators to Protect the Lives of Athletic Youth Act or the SAFE PLAY Act

This bill directs several agencies to undertake specified activities and expand surveillance related to cardiac conditions, concussions, and heat-related illnesses among young athletes. The bill also establishes requirements for schools with respect to concussions and excessive heat.

Specifically, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must (1) develop information for schools, childcare centers, and others on high-risk cardiac conditions in children, adolescents, and young adults; and (2) incorporate questions about cardiac conditions in an existing&#160;school-based health survey.

In addition, the CDC must develop guidelines for emergency action plans for youth athletics programs,&#160;and the Food and Drug Administration may issue guidelines related to youth consumption of&#160;energy drinks.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must award matching grants to local educational agencies for automated external defibrillator and cardiopulmonary resuscitation trainings.

The Department of Education, in consultation with HHS and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, must&#160;develop public education materials focused on the health risks of exposure to extreme heat and humidity, and public schools must develop action plans for athletic activities during periods of excessive heat or humidity.

The bill establishes minimum requirements for elementary and secondary schools related to concussions, including but not limited to (1) implementing a standard plan for concussion safety and management, and (2) ensuring students returning to academics after a concussion receive certain services and supports.</summary>
</bill>
