<bill session="116" type="h" number="5391" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:59Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WHERA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a voluntary program that strengthens the economy, public health, and environment of the United States by reducing emissions from wood heaters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WHERA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wood Heaters Emissions Reduction Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2019-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2274" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="5065" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-15T20:11:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Wood Heaters Emissions Reduction Act of 2019 or the WHERA Act

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to implement programs and authorize policy to reduce emissions from wood heaters.

Specifically, the bill requires the EPA to establish a grant program to provide funding for programs designed to (1) incentivize homeowners to replace old wood heaters with more efficient, cleaner-burning heaters; (2) achieve significant reductions in emissions from wood heaters; (3) help homeowners transition to safer and more efficient heating sources; and (4) support retailers, installers, and manufacturers that sell and make more efficient certified clean heaters.

The EPA must also establish a program to (1) inform stakeholders of the benefits of replacing wood heaters that do not meet specified emission reductions standards, (2) develop nonfinancial incentives to promote the proper installation and use of certified clean heaters, and (3) consult with Indian tribes to implement programs and actions to reduce wood heater emissions.

Finally, the bill authorizes the EPA to accept wood heater emissions reductions Supplemental Environmental Projects.</summary>
</bill>
