<bill session="111" type="h" number="2295" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:17Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense Communities Assistance Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assist local communities with closed and active military bases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Communities Assistance Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2010-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000210" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2009-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="590" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-27T21:21:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Defense Communities Assistance Act of 2009 - Expresses the sense of Congress on the necessity of assisting local communities coping with the impact of base closures and realignments and other military actions.

Extends permanently (under current law, terminated at the end of FY2008) the authority of the Secretary of the military department concerned to convey, for certain purposes, real property on a military installation determined to be excess to the needs of the Department of Defense (DOD).

Authorizes the Secretary concerned to contract for the procurement of municipal services for a U.S. military installation from a county, municipal government, or other local governmental unit in the area. Authorizes such Secretary to so contract using procedures other than competitive procedures, under certain conditions and after congressional notification.

Amends the Ronald W. Reagan National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2005 to extend through FY2020 a pilot program for the purchase of certain municipal services for military installations.

Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993 to broaden the indemnification provided to transferees of military properties.

Reinstates provisions of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 which allow military departments to transfer surplus real and personal property at closed or realigned military installations without consideration to local redevelopment authorities when used for economic development purposes, without the requirement to assess the property's value.</summary>
</bill>
