<bill session="117" type="h" number="8326" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-15T15:18:18-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-09-15T15:18:18-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 13, United States Code, to improve the operations of the Bureau of the Census, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2022-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Reform. H. Rept. 117-456.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-09-09" calendar="Union" number="353">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 353.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-09-13T14:35:07-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1339 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 302, H.R. 2988 and H.R. 8326. Rule provides for one hour of general debate each for H.R. 302, H.R. 2988, and H.R. 8326. Rule also provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T15:02:13-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1339 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T16:42:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1339.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7833-7840" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7837-7838" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T16:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 302, H.R. 2988 and H.R. 8326. Rule provides for one hour of general debate each for H.R. 302, H.R. 2988, and H.R. 8326. Rule also provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T16:43:37-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1339 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T16:43:38-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Earl Blumenauer to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T16:43:49-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 8326.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:10:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1339, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Danny K. Davis en bloc amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:16:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Danny K. Davis en bloc amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Comer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:17:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1339, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hice (GA) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:24:09-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hice (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hice (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:24:49-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis, Danny K. moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:25:04-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:25:14-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 8326 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T14:40:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7858-7860" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T14:41:32-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T14:41:36-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on agreeing to amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:07:28-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 8326.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:08:45-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="435" datetime="2022-09-15T15:18:18-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 208 (Roll no. 435).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:18:20-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1339" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5270" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h316"/>
    <amendment number="h315"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2022-10-13T19:51:17Z" status="Passed House">Ensuring a Fair and Accurate Census Act

This bill addresses the operations of the Bureau of the Census.

Specifically, the bill (1) requires the Deputy Director of the bureau to appoint an employee responsible for optimizing racial and ethnic equity in the decennial census of population; and (2) provides statutory authority for specified advisory committees.

The bureau may not include in the census any subject, type of information, or question that was not submitted to Congress.

The bureau must submit to Congress a report biannually that (1) describes each component of the operational plan for the subsequent decennial census of population; and (2) includes a detailed statement on the status of all research, testing, and operations that are part of the bureau's comprehensive plan for the decennial census.

The bureau must submit to Congress a certification stating that any question that has not appeared on the previous two decennial censuses has been researched, studied, and tested according to established statistical policies and procedures.

The Government Accountability Office must review such certification and report to Congress on whether the questions to be included have been researched, studied, and tested according to such policies and procedures.

The bureau, by January 1, 2026, and every 10 years thereafter, must transmit to Congress a lifecycle cost estimate for the decennial census of population first occurring after the date of transmittal.

The bureau must submit to Congress a report on local-level data and local field operations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-456</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
