<bill session="108" type="h" number="999" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:54Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clear Skies Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to reduce air pollution through expansion of cap and trade programs, to provide an alternative regulatory classification for units subject to the cap and trade program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clear Skies Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000213"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000058" joined="2003-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="485" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Bioaccumulation"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Cogeneration of electric power and heat"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Emissions trading"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Eutrophication"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Sulphur dioxide"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Clear Skies Act of 2003 - Amends the acid deposition control provisions of the Clean Air Act with respect to emissions limitations and allowances programs for sulfur dioxide, nitrogen oxides, and mercury by: (1) revising the allowance system and associated transfer, tracking, permit, compliance plan, and penalty requirements, including those for auctions; and (2) establishing new emissions limitations and trading programs (including implementation of a separate sulfur dioxide scheme for States in the Western Regional Air Partnership).Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to: (1) promulgate performance standards (limiting emissions of sulfur dioxide, nitrogen oxides, particulate matter, and mercury) for new boilers, integrated gasification combined cycle plants, and combustion turbines; and (2) conduct a comprehensive research and environmental assessment program to enhance understanding of health and environmental effects of particulate matter and mercury and to demonstrate the efficacy of emission reductions under this Act.Excludes the following units from consideration as major emitting facilities or major stationary sources (or parts thereof) for purposes of compliance with provisions concerning prevention of significant deterioration of air quality and plan requirements for nonattainment areas: (1) those that are subject to the performance standards of this Act; or (2) those with properly operated and maintained equipment to limit particulate matter emissions or subject to a permit under an applicable implementation plan that provides a specified particulate matter emissions limitation and that use good combustion practices to minimize carbon monoxide emissions.Requires States to ensure in implementation plans that: (1) in an attainment or unclassifiable area, any emissions increase from the construction or modification of an affected unit will not result in exceeding a national ambient air quality standard; and (2) in a nonattainment area, the emissions increase will not interfere with a program to assure the achievement of such a standard. Provides for designation of transitional areas under implementation plans and states requirements for emissions inventories, the attainment of standards by the end of 2015, and penalties for not meeting the eight-hour ozone or fine particles standard.</summary>
</bill>
