<bill session="118" type="s" number="2971" updated="2025-11-18T20:03:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unhoused VOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unhoused VOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unhoused Voter Opportunity Through Elections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to remove barriers to the ability of unhoused individuals to register to vote and vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5294" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-29T19:50:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Unhoused Voter Opportunity Through Elections Act or the Unhoused VOTE Act

This bill expands voter registration and voting access&#160;for unhoused individuals.&#160;

The bill specifies that no state or political subdivision may deny or abridge the right of any U.S. citizen to vote because the citizen resides at or in a nontraditional abode.&#160;

Additionally, the bill requires jurisdictions that allow for ballot drop boxes to ensure that these drop boxes are available for in-person use and are accessible and clearly labeled.

If a state requires individuals to show proof of residence in order to vote in a federal election, then the state must accept the individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s written attestation of residence. A state may not prohibit an individual who is residing in a homeless shelter from using the shelter as the individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s residence for purposes of voting in a federal election.

The bill requires chief state election officials to conduct outreach to unhoused individuals.

The bill directs the Election Assistance Commission to (1) develop best practices for election officials regarding voter registration and voting access for unhoused individuals, and (2) make grants to eligible states and local governments for programs and activities to support access to voting for unhoused individuals.&#160;

The bill also revises the National Voter Registration Act of 1993, including by (1) treating emergency shelters as voter registration agencies, and (2) allowing an unhoused individual to use an unsheltered street location as the individual's place of residence for purposes of a voter registration application.</summary>
</bill>
