<bill session="110" type="h" number="1907" updated="2023-01-11T19:43:49Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-22T19:04:20-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-22T19:04:20-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the acquisition of land and interests in land from willing sellers to improve the conservation of, and to enhance the ecological values and functions of, coastal and estuarine areas to benefit both the environment and the economies of coastal communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal and Estuarine Land Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000357" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2007-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000243" joined="2007-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000597" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2007-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2007-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2007-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000549" joined="2007-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000180" joined="2007-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2007-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000113" joined="2007-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2007-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2007-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2007-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2007-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000057" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2007-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee Without Recommendation (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-811.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-07-31" calendar="Union" number="525">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 525.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22T13:51:08-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22T13:51:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8503-8506" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22T13:51:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1907.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22T14:03:41-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22T18:57:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8544-8545" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="617" datetime="2008-09-22T19:04:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 313 - 59 (Roll no. 617).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8503-8504" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22T19:04:20-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="617" datetime="2008-09-22T19:04:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 313 - 59 (Roll no. 617).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8503-8504" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-09-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-10-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1111">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1111.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="1142" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Land banking"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-23T20:49:37Z" status="Passed House amended">Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program Act - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to conduct a Coastal and Estuarine Land Conservation Program to protect important coastal and estuarine areas that have significant conservation, recreation, ecological, historical, or aesthetic values and that are threatened by conversion from their natural, undeveloped, or recreational state to other uses or that could be managed or restored to effectively conserve, enhance, or restore ecological function. Requires the program to be administered by the National Ocean Service of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) through the Office of Ocean and Coastal Resource Management.

Authorizes the Secretary to make Program grants to coastal states with approved coastal zone management plans or National Estuarine Research Reserve units for the purpose of acquiring property that will further the goals of an approved Coastal Zone Management Plan or Program, a National Estuarine Research Reserve management plan, a regional or state watershed protection or management plan, or a state coastal land acquisition plan.

Directs the Secretary to allocate funds to coastal states or National Estuarine Research Reserves through a competitive grant process with guidelines that meet specified requirements, including that: (1) each participating coastal state shall ensure that the acquisition of property or easements shall complement working waterfront needs; and (2) priority shall be given to lands that can be effectively managed and protected, that have significant ecological value, that are under an imminent threat of conversion to a use that will diminish their natural, undeveloped, or recreational state, and that serve to mitigate the adverse impacts caused by coastal population growth in the coastal environment.

Provides that grant awards may be used to purchase land, including an easement, only from a willing seller. Prohibits any such purchase from being the result of a forced taking.

Provides that grant funds under the Program shall require a 100% match from nonfederal sources, subject to a waiver by the Secretary for underserved and other specified communities or for other appropriate reasons. Reserves 15% of program funds for acquisitions benefiting the National Estuarine Research Reserve.

Specifies that when property is acquired under this program, the grant recipient shall provide assurances that: (1) title will be held by the recipient (or another public agency designated by the recipient) in perpetuity; (2) property will be managed consistent with the purpose of the Program; and (3) funds will be returned to the Secretary for redistribution if the property is sold, exchanged, or divested. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-811</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
