<bill session="117" type="h" number="5072" updated="2023-01-01T20:19:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize use of rental assistance amounts for individuals and families from Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Housing for Afghan Allies Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing for Afghan Allies Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-02T17:49:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing for Afghan Allies Act of 2021

This bill allows state and local governments receiving emergency rental assistance funds for unemployed persons, persons with hardship related to the COVID-19 pandemic, and persons at risk of homelessness to use some of those funds to provide rent and utility assistance to certain individuals and families from Afghanistan.

The funds may be used to provide such assistance to individuals and families who are citizens or nationals of Afghanistan, who are present within the United States, and who have been granted special immigrant status or have received priority 2 refugee designation.

A special immigrant is an immigrant who qualifies for a permanent residence after meeting certain criteria. A priority 2 refugee designation grants U.S. Refugee Admissions Program access to certain immigrants, including Afghan immigrants who do not qualify as special immigrants but who may be at risk because of their U.S. affiliation.</summary>
</bill>
