<bill session="115" type="s" number="3397" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:40Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Douglas County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote conservation, improve public land, and provide for sensible development in Douglas County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Douglas County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6676" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-06T15:48:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Douglas County Economic Development and Conservation Act

This bill directs the Forest Service to convey 67 acres of Forest Service land in the Lake Tahoe area in Nevada for the conservation of wildlife or natural resources or for a public park. Subject to the agreement of the permit holder of Zephyr Cove Resort, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall modify such permit to include the Zephyr Shoals.

The Forest Service and the Department of Interior shall convey 7,951 acres of specified federal land to Douglas County, Nevada, for flood control or any other public purpose.

USDA shall implement a cooperative management agreement for the Tahoe Rim Trail North Parcel to: (1) improve the quality of recreation access for such land, and (2) conserve the land's natural resource values.

The Forest Service or Interior shall conduct one or more sales of specified federal lands in Douglas County&#160; to qualified bidders.

All U.S. interest in 1,945 acres of certain federal land and certain land administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or Forest Service (Section 5 lands) shall be held in trust for the Washoe Tribe of Nevada and California.

The bill designates 12,330 acres of specified BLM land, to be known as the Burbank Canyons Wilderness, as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

USDA may transfer from the Forest Service to Nevada or to Douglas County certain Forest Service lands which are unsuitable for Forest Service administration or necessary for a public purpose.</summary>
</bill>
