<bill session="116" type="s" number="29" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish the Office of Critical Technologies and Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of Critical Technologies and Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2019-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2019-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2019-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2019-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="618" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-02T15:26:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill establishes in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Critical Technology and Security, which, among other things, shall

 serve as a centralized focal point within the Executive Office of the President for coordinating policy and actions of the federal government to stop the transfer of critical emerging, foundational, and dual-use technologies to countries that pose a national security risk, and to maintain U.S. technological leadership and ensure supply chain integrity and security for such technologies; lead messaging and outreach efforts by the government on the national security threat posed by the improper acquisition and transfer of such technologies; lead the development of a comprehensive, long-term strategic plan in coordination with U.S. allies and defense partners to protect and enforce intellectual property rights and to develop a strategy to inform the private sector about critical supply chain risks; and use measures developed to monitor and track key trends relating to transfer of such technologies, and relating to U.S. government investments in innovation and competitiveness compared to governments of other countries. The bill establishes the Council on Critical Technologies and Security to advise the President on matters relating to challenges posed by foreign powers with respect to technology acquisition and transfer.</summary>
</bill>
