<bill session="111" type="s" number="926" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:21Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the continuing review of unauthorized Federal programs and agencies and to establish a bipartisan commission for the purpose of improving oversight and eliminating Government spending.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2009-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2009-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4893-4894"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4894-4897" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-19T14:00:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Authorization and Sunset Commission Act of 2009 - Establishes the United States Authorization and Sunset Commission, to be comprised of four Representatives and four Senators.

Requires the Commission to submit to Congress, not later than 18 months after this Act's enactment and at least once every 10 years thereafter, a legislative proposal (referred to as the Commission Schedule and Review bill) that includes a schedule of review and abolishment of agencies and programs. Requires such schedule to provide a time line for the Commission's review and proposed abolishment of: (1) at least 25% (as measured in dollars) of unauthorized agencies or programs; and (2) if applicable, at least 25% of the programs identified by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) through its Program Assessment Rating Tool program (or similar review program) as ineffective or results not demonstrated. Requires agencies performing similar or related functions to be reviewed concurrently.

Sets forth review criteria. Requires the Commission to submit to the Congress and the President every two years a report that analyzes and includes (as appropriate) proposals and legislative provisions to reauthorize, reorganize, consolidate, expand, or transfer each agency and program scheduled for review. Provides for expedited congressional consideration of a resulting bill.</summary>
</bill>
