<bill session="117" type="h" number="6530" updated="2022-12-30T03:48:59Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SENIOR Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Elderly Needs for Infrastructure and Occupational Resources Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SENIOR Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to sustain senior congregate care operations in the wake of ongoing COVID-19 financial burdens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000482"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2022-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-07T22:59:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding Elderly Needs for Infrastructure and Occupational Resources Act of 2022 or the SENIOR Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to assisted living facilities for health care expenses and lost revenue attributable to COVID-19 and other purposes. It also addresses matters related to the senior caregiver workforce.

To receive a grant, an assisted living facility must demonstrate that it had uncompensated losses due to COVID-19 and consistently maintained operations from March 13, 2020, to December 31, 2020. A facility must also certify that the grant is necessary for its ongoing operations.

HHS must also award grants to assisted living facilities for broadband connectivity and telehealth support and other operation and maintenance costs.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the efficacy of these grants.

With respect to the senior caregiver workforce, the bill authorizes grants for assisted living facilities to establish or expand workforce training and recruitment programs. The National Health Care Workforce Commission must also designate the workforce needs of assisted living and other senior care populations as a high priority area and report on those needs.</summary>
</bill>
