<bill session="118" type="h" number="3286" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing Open Source Software Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Securing Open Source Software Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Open Source Software Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the duties of the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency regarding open source software security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000597" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000598" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2023-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 118-160, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Oversight and Accountability discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-27" calendar="Union" number="127">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 127.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-10T19:46:12Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">Securing Open Source Software Act of 2023

This bill sets forth the duties of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) regarding open source software security.

Open source software means software for which the human-readable source code is made available to the public for use, study, reuse, modification, enhancement, and redistribution.

Specifically, CISA must

 perform outreach and engagement to bolster the security of open source software; support federal efforts to strengthen open source software security; coordinate with nonfederal entities on efforts to ensure long-term open source software security; serve as a public point of contact regarding open source software security for nonfederal entities; and support federal and nonfederal supply chain security efforts by encouraging efforts to bolster open source software security. CISA must (1) publish a framework, incorporating government, private sector, and open source software community frameworks and best practices, for assessing the risk of open source software components; (2) update the framework at least annually; and (3) ensure, to the greatest extent practicable, that the framework is usable by the open source software community.

The bill requires CISA to assess open source software components deployed on high value assets at federal agencies based on the framework and provides for a pilot assessment of critical infrastructure.

CISA's Cybersecurity Advisory Committee may establish a software security subcommittee.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-160</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
