<bill session="118" type="s" number="1963" updated="2025-11-18T18:39:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">College for All Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College for All Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to ensure College for All.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4117" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-16T20:22:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">College for All Act of 2023

This bill establishes measures to expand access to higher education, including by eliminating tuition and required fees for eligible students, revising the Federal Pell Grant program, and reauthorizing certain programs to assist students from disadvantaged backgrounds.

Specifically, the bill provides funding to enable states and tribal colleges and universities, through a federal-state partnership, to eliminate tuition and required fees for (1) all students at community colleges and two-year tribal colleges and universities, and (2) working- and middle-class students at four-year public institutions of higher education and tribal colleges and universities.

The bill provides funding to enable private, nonprofit historically Black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions to eliminate tuition and required fees for eligible students.

The bill permanently reauthorizes and otherwise revises the Federal Pell Grant program by

 providing funding to increase the maximum award for each eligible student, increasing the duration limit for the use of Pell Grants, allowing students to use their awards to cover living and nontuition expenses, and expanding eligibility to Dreamer students (i.e., students who have been granted Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals status and who entered the United States before the age of 16) and students with other immigration statuses. Further, the bill requires the Department of Education to award grants to eligible states and tribal colleges and universities for improving student outcomes.

The bill reauthorizes through FY2033 the Federal TRIO Programs and reauthorizes through FY2027 the Gaining Early Awareness and Readiness for Undergraduate Programs.</summary>
</bill>
