<bill session="117" type="s" number="304" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Diaper Need Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide targeted funding for States and other eligible entities through the Social Services Block Grant program to address the increased burden that maintaining the health and hygiene of infants and toddlers, medically complex children, and low-income adults or adults with disabilities who rely on adult incontinence materials and supplies place on families in need, the resultant adverse health effects on children and families, and the limited child care options available for infants and toddlers who lack sufficient diapers and diapering supplies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Diaper Need Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2022-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7158-7159" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7585" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4486" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-08T00:39:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Diaper Need Act of 2021

This bill establishes and expands programs to provide low-income families and other vulnerable groups with access to diapers and related supplies.

Specifically, it provides additional funding for FY2022-FY2025 to meet the diapering needs of certain low-income families and adults through the Social Services Block Grant Program. This grant program provides a flexible funding stream to states and territories to support social services for vulnerable children, adults, and families. The bill exempts these funds from sequestration. Sequestration is a process of automatic, across-the-board reductions under which budgetary resources are permanently cancelled to enforce specific budget policy goals.

In particular, these funds must be used to meet the diapering needs of

 low-income families with one or more infants, toddlers, or medically complex children (i.e., children who are age three or older and diagnosed with a serious condition such as bowel or bladder incontinence); and low-income adults and adults with disabilities who rely on diapers and other adult incontinence materials. Additionally, the bill permits states to use Medicaid funds to provide medically necessary diapers and supplies to low-income families with one or more medically complex children.

It also allows individuals to buy medically necessary diapers and supplies with funds from health savings accounts and other tax-advantaged accounts for health care expenses.</summary>
</bill>
