<bill session="118" type="s" number="3606" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:48Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-05">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2024-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2024-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S150" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="523">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 523.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-05" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6853-6855" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6853-6855" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T14:25:47-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T15:02:16-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-27T20:30:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program Reauthorization Act of 2024

This bill reauthorizes through FY2028 the National Earthquake Hazards Reduction Program (NEHRP) and expands the activities federal agencies must conduct under the program, including activities relating to secondary effects of earthquakes and post-earthquake infrastructure performance.&#160;

NEHRP is a coordinated earthquake hazards reduction program of four federal agencies: the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the U.S. Geological Survey, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the National Science Foundation. Under NEHRP, these agencies are required to conduct various activities relating to earthquakes, including advancing warning systems, hazard reduction measures, and research to improve understanding of earthquakes and their effects.

The bill expands the scope of the activities under NEHRP, including requiring the agencies to&#160;

improve understanding of and develop resilience measures for secondary effects and multiple hazards associated with earthquakes, such as tsunamis and fires;increase post-earthquake functional recovery, which means maintaining or restoring the pre-earthquake functionality of buildings and lifeline infrastructure systems (e.g., infrastructure for water, electricity, and transportation); andassist public entities with developing an inventory, and conducting seismic performance evaluation, of infrastructure with high seismic risk.&#160;Additionally, the bill specifically includes tribal governments in the activities conducted under NEHRP.</summary>
</bill>
