<bill session="117" type="s" number="3939" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SEED Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEED Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Entrepreneurs&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Empowerment and Development Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Act of 1933 to provide small issuers with a micro-offering exemption free of mandated disclosures or offering filings, but subject to the antifraud provisions of the Federal securities laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2022-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-26T18:53:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Entrepreneurs' Empowerment and Development Act of 2022 or the SEED Act of 2022 

This bill creates an exemption to securities registration requirements for a micro-offering of securities. In general, the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) prohibits the offering or selling of securities unless the offering is registered with the SEC or it qualifies for an exemption.

The bill defines a micro-offering as an aggregate amount of securities sold by an issuer that does not exceed $500,000 in a 12-month period. This exemption does not apply to issuers who are convicted of specified financial crimes or are subject to specified disciplinary actions.</summary>
</bill>
