<bill session="118" type="s" number="3558" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:42Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prohibiting Foreign Access to American Genetic Information Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Prohibiting Foreign Access to American Genetic Information Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit contracting with certain biotechnology providers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2024-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2024-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2024-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2024-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2024-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-229.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="521">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 521.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8333" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-06T02:19:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill prohibits federal contracting with certain biotechnology providers connected to foreign adversaries, with exceptions.

Specifically, the bill prohibits executive agencies from (1) procuring or obtaining any biotechnology equipment or service produced or provided by a biotechnology company of concern, or (2) entering into a contract or extending or renewing a contract that uses such equipment or service or that will require the direct use of such equipment or services. Those agencies may not obligate or expend loan or grant funds for such purposes.

A biotechnology company of concern includes BGI, MGI, Complete Genomics, WuXi AppTec, and any subsidiary, parent affiliate, or successor of such entities, and any entity that

 is subject to the jurisdiction, direction, control, or operates on behalf of the government of a foreign adversary; is involved in the manufacturing, distribution, provision, or procurement of a biotechnology equipment or service; and poses a risk to U.S. national security based on specified activities. Executive agencies may waive the prohibitions on a case-by-case basis under specified circumstances.

The Office of Management and Budget must develop and periodically update a list of the entities that constitute biotechnology companies of concern.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-229</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
