<bill session="109" type="h" number="5193" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:43Z">
  <state datetime="2006-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for continuity of Medicare prescription drug coverage for full-benefit dual eligible individuals, for Medicare prescription drug coverage of benzodiazepines and off-label uses of certain prescription drugs and biological products, for optional Medicaid coverage of Medicare prescription drug cost-sharing for full-benefit dual eligible individuals, for authorization to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to waive certain determinations denying Medicare prescription drug coverage, and for holding pharmacies harmless for certain costs incurred during implementation of Medicare part D.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for continuity of Medicare prescription drug coverage for full-benefit dual eligible individuals, for Medicare prescription drug coverage of benzodiazepines and off-label uses of certain prescription drugs and biological products, for optional Medicaid coverage of Medicare prescription drug cost-sharing for full-benefit dual eligible individuals, for authorization to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to waive certain determinations denying Medicare prescription drug coverage, and for holding pharmacies harmless for certain costs incurred during implementation of Medicare part D.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000789"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3151" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4937" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-19T20:29:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program ) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for continuity of coverage of prescription drugs under Medicare prescription drug plans for full-benefit dual eligible individuals.

Provides for Medicare prescription drug coverage of benzodiazepines and of off-label uses of prescription drugs and biologicals.

Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to permit state Medicaid programs to cover Medicare prescription drug copayments for full-benefit dual eligible individuals.

Amends SSA title XVIII to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to waive denial of Medicare prescription drug coverage.

Directs the Secretary to provide for payments from the Medicare Prescription Drug Account necessary to reimburse pharmacies fully for: (1) transaction fees associated with any point-of-sale facilitated identification and enrollment process established to facilitate, at point of sale, the identification of drug plan assignment of full-benefit dual eligible individuals or the enrollment of previously unidentified or new full-benefit dual eligible individuals into Medicare prescription drug coverage; (2) costs associated with technology or software upgrades necessary to make any inquiries as part of a identification and enrollment process; and (3) costs of providing prescription drugs and biological products to part D eligible individuals whose prescription drug plans could not be identified, if the pharmacy involved as not reimbursed for such costs upon completion of plan reconciliation.</summary>
</bill>
