<bill session="117" type="h" number="4160" updated="2022-12-31T04:58:47Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Global Autism Assistance Program.</title>
    <title type="display">Global Autism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Autism Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2021-08-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2021-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-26T16:04:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Global Autism Act

This bill establishes the Global Autism Assistance Program within the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to support developing countries in addressing autism spectrum disorders (ASD).

To carry out this program, the USAID must designate at least two regions in developing countries that (1) need assistance addressing ASD, and (2) have sufficient familiarity with issues concerning ASD to make effective use of the program. The USAID must then award a grant to a nongovernmental organization with experience with ASD to implement the program.

The implementing organization must award grants to local service providers and other groups in the designated regions and offer specialized training for health and education professionals who treat or teach youth with ASD. The organization must also conduct (at biomedical conferences in the designated regions) training on interventions and strategies to improve the health and well-being of individuals with ASD for parents, health care professionals, and others who serve those with ASD.</summary>
</bill>
