<bill session="116" type="h" number="7956" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Critical Medical Infrastructure Right-to-Repair Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Critical Medical Infrastructure Right-to-Repair Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 17, United States Code, to address circumvention of copyright protection systems with respect to the maintenance or repair of critical medical infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2020-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4473" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-29T13:12:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Critical Medical Infrastructure Right-to-Repair Act of 2020

This bill removes certain intellectual property-related restrictions on repairing or maintaining critical medical infrastructure (i.e., a device or product used to provide medical services).

During the declared COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency, it shall not be copyright infringement for an owner or licensee of service materials (such as manuals or computer diagnostic software) to copy such materials if (1) the copying is incidental to the repair or maintenance of critical medical infrastructure, and (2) such repair or maintenance is in response to the emergency.

Similarly, during the emergency, the prohibition against circumventing technology to control access to a work (or trafficking in circumvention tools) shall not apply to an owner or licensee of critical medical infrastructure if the circumvention is done to repair or maintain critical medical infrastructure in response to the emergency.

During the emergency, it shall also not be design patent infringement if the owner or licensee of critical medical infrastructure fabricates a patented part on a noncommercial basis in order to repair or maintain the infrastructure in response to the emergency.

The bill also nullifies any contract provision that restricts the ability of the owner or licensee of critical medical infrastructure to repair or maintain such infrastructure in response to the emergency.

The manufacturer of critical medical infrastructure shall (1) offer for sale on reasonable terms any tool or information for servicing or repairing such infrastructure, and (2) provide information for making such tools to aftermarket tool manufacturers. The Federal Trade Commission shall have the authority to enforce these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
