<bill session="118" type="s" number="991" updated="2025-11-19T04:21:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Labor Relations Board Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Labor Relations Board Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act to reform the National Labor Relations Board, the Office of the General Counsel, and the process for appellate review, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2023-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3833" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-04T13:22:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Labor Relations Board Reform Act

This bill expands the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) and modifies the procedures for reviewing unfair labor practice complaints.

Specifically, the bill increases from five to six the number of members on the NLRB and requires that each major political party is represented by three members each.

It also permits an individual subject to a NLRB complaint of an unfair labor practice issued or authorized by the NLRB General Counsel to obtain review of the complaint in federal district court. An individual must file a written petition for such review not later than 30 days after the complaint is issued or authorized.

The bill further permits either party to a complaint proceeding to appeal to a federal court of appeals if the NLRB does not issue a final order within one year after a report is issued by an administrative law judge or decision is issued by a regional director.</summary>
</bill>
