<bill session="116" type="h" number="4443" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:54Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Wage Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide for a Federal, cost-of-living based minimum wage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Wage Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2080" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-13T17:52:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Wage Act of 2019

This bill phases in increases in the federal minimum wage based on&#160;the metropolitan statistical area or the nonmetropolitan portion in which an employer resides, adjusted to account for the cost-of-living in such area. In determining the cash wage any employer is required to pay a tipped employee, such wage shall be no less than the amount equal to 30% of the federal minimum wage determined for the metropolitan statistical area or the nonmetropolitan portion in which the employer resides.

Any employer may pay a newly hired employee who is 18 years of age or younger, or in the case of the wage that applies in Puerto Rico 24 years of age or younger, during the first 90 consecutive days after the employee's initial employment, a wage which is not less than 2/3 of the federal minimum wage determined for the metropolitan statistical area or the nonmetropolitan portion in which the employer resides.</summary>
</bill>
