<bill session="118" type="h" number="5181" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Feeding Rural Families Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feeding Rural Families Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to modify the thrifty food plan to apply to the urban and rural parts of the State of Hawaii.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2023-09-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-11T20:06:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Feeding Rural Families Act of 2023

This bill provides for separate food cost calculations for urban and rural parts of Hawaii for the purposes of determining Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) maximum monthly benefit allotments. Specifically, the bill requires separate&#160;food cost adjustments in the Thrifty Food Plan (TFP) for urban and rural parts of Hawaii.

SNAP maximum monthly benefit allotments are tied to the cost of purchasing a nutritionally adequate low-cost diet, as measured by the Department of Agriculture-created and -calculated TFP. Maximum allotments are set at the monthly cost of the TFP for a four-person family, adjusted for family size. Under current law,&#160;maximum allotments are higher (to reflect the cost of food) in Hawaii, Guam, and the U.S. Virgin Islands, as well as in urban and rural parts of Alaska.</summary>
</bill>
