<bill session="119" type="h" number="406" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Jewish Student and Faculty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promote Restoring Order To End Campus Targeting of Jewish Students and Faculty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Jewish Student and Faculty Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education, as a condition of participation in programs under title IV of such Act, to include a prohibition of antisemitic conduct in all documents relating to student or employee conduct.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001133" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001222" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001221" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2025-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-14T15:53:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Promote Restoring Order To End Campus Targeting of Jewish Students and Faculty Act or the PROTECT Jewish Student and Faculty Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student aid programs to adopt a standard definition of anti-Semitism in their student and employee codes of conduct and prohibit such conduct on campus.

Specifically, the IHE must include in its documents related to student and employee conduct a definition of&#160;anti-Semitism which states that (1)&#160;anti-Semitism is a certain perception of Jews, which may be expressed as hatred toward Jews; and (2) rhetorical and physical manifestations of anti-Semitism may be directed toward Jewish or non-Jewish individuals, including the property of such individuals, and Jewish community institutions and religious facilities. (This definition is the same as the working definition of anti-Semitism from the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance.)

Additionally, the IHE must include in such documents a statement that&#160;anti-Semitic conduct is prohibited on campus and that such conduct may result in expulsion or termination of employment.</summary>
</bill>
