<bill session="117" type="h" number="5572" updated="2023-03-14T18:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the process for admission of refugees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SECURE America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguards Ensuring Criminal and Unvetted Refugees don&#226;&#8364;&#8482;t Enter America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SECURE America Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001311" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2021-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001088" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000395" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-18T16:54:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguards Ensuring Criminal and Unvetted Refugees don't Enter America Act or the SECURE America Act

This bill imposes restrictions on the admission of aliens, including refugees, and addresses related issues.

Specifically, no refugees may be admitted until Congress enacts a joint resolution setting the maximum number of refugees allowed to be admitted in a particular fiscal year. Currently, that number is set each fiscal year by the President.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must notify Congress at least 30 days before determining that an alien or class of aliens is eligible for refugee status. Congress may nullify the determination by enacting a joint resolution of disapproval.

Further, an alien shall be inadmissible for holding certain beliefs, such as (1) believing that a system of religious law should be implemented in the United States, (2) believing that the alien does not need to learn English if the alien is not already fluent, or (3) any belief that the Department of State determines is incompatible with the principles of the United States.

DHS may not parole into the United States an alien who does not have status under immigration law. Currently, DHS may provide parole in certain instances, including for urgent humanitarian reasons.

Federal agencies must notify a state at least 30 days before resettling a refugee in that state. The refugee may not be resettled in that state if the state expresses disapproval.

An alien who has committed a crime of violence (generally one involving the use or threat of physical violence against person or property) may not be eligible for refugee status and must be removed.</summary>
</bill>
