<bill session="118" type="h" number="1075" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Baseball Diplomacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Baseball Diplomacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To waive certain prohibitions with respect to nationals of Cuba coming to the United States to play organized professional baseball.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2023-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-28T16:51:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Baseball Diplomacy Act

This bill waives various embargo and immigration restrictions in order to allow Cuban nationals to enter the United States to play organized professional baseball.

U.S. embargo authority may not regulate or prohibit various transactions by or on behalf of a Cuban national entering to play professional baseball, nor may the individual be prohibited from returning to Cuba with the earnings made from playing baseball. The President's authority to bar an alien whose entry is deemed to be detrimental to U.S. interests may not be used to deny a visa to a Cuban national entering to play baseball.

An individual entering to play baseball may obtain a visa to remain in the United States only for the duration of the baseball season. The visa need not be renewed for reentry into the United States during the term of a contract between the individual and the team for which the individual played in the preceding season.</summary>
</bill>
