<bill session="116" type="h" number="4643" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Access to Higher Education Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve accessibility to, and completion of, postsecondary education for students, including students with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Access to Higher Education Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2019-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2019-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2019-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2019-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4674" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5312" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3095" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-16T16:33:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Access to Higher Education Act of 2019 

This bill addresses accessibility issues of students with disabilities in higher education. Specifically, the bill revises a grant program that supports postsecondary institutions of higher education (IHE) in educating students with disabilities. The Department of Education must award at least five grants to an IHE that provides professional development and technical assistance in order to improve access to and completion of postsecondary education for students, including students with disabilities. The bill also (1) revises and reauthorizes through FY2024 a program for national technical assistance centers that assist students with disabilities, and (2) reauthorizes through FY2024 a program to promote training and job placement of real-time writers to provide closed captioning of videos. Further, the bill establishes a new program that awards grants to IHEs for certain activities that improve accessibility of instruction and materials, such as distance education courses. The bill also establishes an independent commission to develop guidelines for accessible postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies. In addition, the bill requires each IHE to establish an office of accessibility to develop and implement policies that support students with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
