<bill session="119" type="h" number="1374" updated="2025-03-14T03:38:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10T17:12:15-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-10T17:12:15-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing the Cities Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Securing the Cities Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short">Securing the Cities Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Securing the Cities Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make improvements to the Securing the Cities program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001125"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2025-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Management and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:59:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Green (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:59:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1056-1057" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:59:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1374.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-03-10T17:12:15-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1056" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T17:12:18-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-12T13:48:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing the Cities Improvement Act

This bill makes changes to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office's (CWMD's) Securing the Cities program, which seeks to detect nuclear or radiological materials to prevent terrorist attacks and other events posing a risk to cities in the United States.

Specifically, the bill requires the CWMD to establish performance metrics and milestones for the program and to track performance against them.

Also, under current law, in carrying out the Securing the Cities program, the CWMD may only partner with cities that are high-risk urban areas, which are designated by the Federal Emergency Management Agency under a different program. Instead, the bill requires the CWMD to designate the jurisdictions it may partner with for the program, and the designations must be based on the capability and capacity of the jurisdiction relating to preparedness and response, as well as the relative threat to, vulnerability of, and consequences for, such jurisdiction regarding terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing nuclear or radiological materials.

Additionally, within two years of enactment of the bill, the CWMD must submit a report to Congress regarding participation in the Securing the Cities program, the establishment of metrics and milestones, performance against such metrics and milestones, and plans for any changes to the program.</summary>
</bill>
