<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="715" updated="2022-02-08T23:01:28Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-12-12T13:26:31-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000171"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 5 printed in Part B of House Report 116-334 to create a grant program within HHS for hospitals located in rural and medically underserved areas, including Critical Access Hospitals, to cover the start-up costs for establishing a Graduate Medical Education (GME) program or a partnership with a hospital that has an existing program. It would include a reporting requirement for GAO to analyze whether residents continue to practice in a rural or medically underserved area after completing their training.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment creates a grant program within HHS for hospitals located in rural and medically underserved areas, including Critical Access Hospitals, to cover the start-up costs for establishing a Graduate Medical Education (GME) program or a partnership with a hospital that has an existing program. Amendment includes a reporting requirement for GAO to analyze whether residents continue to practice in a rural or medically underserved area after completing their training.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-12-12T13:26:31-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="677">
      <text>On agreeing to the O'Halleran amendment (A005) Agreed to by recorded vote: 351 - 73 (Roll no. 677).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12T11:34:49-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) offered by Mr. O'Halleran.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10206-10208, H10220-10221" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H10207" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12T13:26:31-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12T11:34:49-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A005) offered by Mr. O'Halleran.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12T13:26:31-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the O'Halleran amendment (A005) Agreed to by recorded vote: 351 - 73 (Roll no. 677).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12T13:26:31-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
