<bill session="117" type="h" number="8087" updated="2023-07-31T17:30:27Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LEO Fair Retirement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEO Fair Retirement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that for purposes of computing the annuity of certain law enforcement officers, any hours worked in excess of the limitation applicable to law enforcement premium pay shall be included in such computation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2022-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-31T17:27:32Z" status="Introduced in House">LEO Fair Retirement Act of 2022

This bill makes a series of changes to certain retirement and premium pay calculations for federal law enforcement officers (LEOs).

Specifically, the bill provides that for purposes of computing the annuity of an LEO under the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees Retirement System, any premium pay earned by such LEO in excess of limitations imposed on such pay shall be included in the LEO's average pay, contingent on the payment of a specified lump sum by the LEO to the Office of Personnel Management. The bill allows for a nonrefundable tax credit with respect to such lump-sum payments.

The bill also makes postal inspectors, federal air marshals, and other specified personnel eligible for availability pay (i.e., premium pay paid to LEOs who are criminal investigators).</summary>
</bill>
