<bill session="118" type="h" number="8445" updated="2025-08-28T17:03:37Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, and the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide for the eligibility of United States citizens who serve in the Israeli Defense Forces for certain protections relating to such service.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title 38, United States Code, and the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide for the eligibility of United States citizens who serve in the Israeli Defense Forces for certain protections relating to such service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001222" joined="2024-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-28T17:03:35Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides eligibility to U.S. citizens who are serving in the Israeli Defense Forces for benefits and protections available under the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act (USERRA) and the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (SCRA). Specifically, the bill requires the service of such citizens to be regarded in the same manner as service in the uniformed services under USERRA or military service under SCRA.

The&#160;USERRA provides protections for members of the uniformed services regarding employment and reemployment rights, including in matters with state and private employers. The SCRA provides financial and legal protections to active-duty servicemembers, including by suspending certain judicial proceedings or financial responsibilities that may adversely affect them during military service.</summary>
</bill>
