<bill session="119" type="s" number="435" updated="2025-07-22T21:39:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the missile defense capabilities of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">IRONDOME Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Response Options and Deterrence of Missile Engagements Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRONDOME Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-22T21:37:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Increasing Response Options and Deterrence of Missile Engagements Act of 2025 or the IRONDOME Act of 2025

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) and other entities to take specified actions to support U.S. missile defense capabilities, particularly with respect to the U.S. homeland.

DOD must submit to Congress a multi-year phased plan to transfer operations and&#160;sustainment responsibility for missile defense from the Missile Defense Agency to the appropriate military departments to allow the Missile Defense Agency to focus on research, development, and prototyping and testing.

Additionally, among other elements, the bill requires

the United States Northern Command and the Space Development Agency within DOD to use a specified acquisition process to conduct rapid testing and development of&#160;certain drone and satellite systems;each commander of a combatant command to include the missile defense interceptor and sensor requirements of the command in annual budget requests;DOD to use all authorities available to accelerate the development, production, and modernization of various defense systems and technology, including certain space-based interceptors; andthe Department of the Army to procure and field airships in support of the missile defense of the U.S. homeland from drones and&#160;ballistic, hypersonic, and cruise missiles.On January 27, 2025, President Trump signed an executive order titled&#160;The Iron Dome for America. The order directs DOD to develop plans for a next-generation missile defense shield to protect the U.S. homeland from ballistic, hypersonic, and advanced cruise missiles, and other next-generation aerial attacks.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
