<bill session="117" type="h" number="2522" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cerro de la Olla Wilderness Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act to establish the Cerro de la Olla Wilderness in the R&#195;&#173;o Grande del Norte National Monument and to modify the boundary of the R&#195;&#173;o Grande del Norte National Monument.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cerro de la Olla Wilderness Establishment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2021-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="177" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-21T16:37:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Cerro de la Olla Wilderness Establishment Act

This bill designates specified federal land administered by the Bureau of Land Management in Taos County, New Mexico, comprising 13,103 acres in the Rio Grande del Norte National Monument, to be known as the Cerro de la Olla Wilderness.

The Department of the Interior shall enter into a cooperative agreement with New Mexico that specifies, subject to certain prohibition provisions under the Wilderness Act, the terms and conditions under which wildlife management activities in the wilderness may be carried out.

Subject to such agreement and such prohibition provisions, Interior may authorize the maintenance of any existing structure or facility for wildlife water development projects (including guzzlers) in the wilderness, if

 the structure or facility would enhance wilderness values by promoting healthy, viable, and more naturally distributed wildlife populations; and the visual impacts of the structure or facility on the wilderness can reasonably be minimized. The bill modifies the boundary of the monument.</summary>
</bill>
