<bill session="116" type="s" number="3605" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food Bank Access to Farm Fresh Produce Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Bank Access to Farm Fresh Produce Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to provide specialty crop block grants to fund State food banks and food access networks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2020-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2020-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-22T19:22:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Food Bank Access to Farm Fresh Produce Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture to provide specialty crop block grants to each of the 20 states that have produced the highest quantity of specialty crops during the most recent three-year period to fund certain state food banks and food access networks.

The grants may only be used to (1) procure and distribute specialty crops; (2) purchase, lease, or otherwise acquire vehicles, including refrigerated vehicles, or other equipment to carry out activities related to procurement and distribution of specialty crops; (3) pay for the cost of additional personnel; (4) pay for travel relating to procurement of specialty crops; and (5) pay for preparation, storage, and transportation of specialty crops, including delivery to end-consumers.

Each grant provided to a state shall be not less than $100 million.</summary>
</bill>
