<bill session="119" type="hr" number="668" updated="2025-09-08T20:00:57Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-03T14:06:59-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-03T14:06:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Directing the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform to continue its ongoing investigation into the possible mismanagement of the Federal government's investigation of Mr. Jeffrey Epstein and Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Directing the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform to continue its ongoing investigation into the possible mismanagement of the Federal government's investigation of Mr. Jeffrey Epstein and Ms. Ghislaine Maxwell, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000311"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000470" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000568" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001093" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2025-09-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2025-09-03T14:06:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 672, H. Res. 668 is considered passed House.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3780: 1" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3780: 1" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="672" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-03T20:51:14Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution directs the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform&#160;to continue its investigation into the federal government's investigation of Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell and to release to the public committee records relating to the committee's investigation, subject to limited exceptions.

Under the resolution, the committee&#160;records to be publicly disclosed include unclassified records referring or relating to&#160;Epstein's detention and death; flight logs of aircraft owned or used by Epstein;&#160;individuals named in connection with&#160;Epstein&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s criminal activities, civil settlements, or immunity or plea agreements; immunity deals, sealed settlements, or plea bargains of Epstein or his associates; entities with ties to Epstein&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s trafficking or financial networks; and internal Department of Justice communications concerning decisions to investigate or charge Epstein or his associates.

The resolution&#160;provides that the committee may withhold or redact portions of records with written justification that such portions contain (1) victims' personally identifiable information; (2) child sexual abuse materials; (3) images of death, physical abuse, or injury; (4) information which would jeopardize an active federal investigation or prosecution; or (5) classified information. The committee may not withhold or redact&#160;records on the basis of embarrassment, reputational harm, or political sensitivity.

The resolution states support for the committee's subpoenas and investigatory actions and encourages timely compliance with them. Additionally, the committee shall issue investigative reports as it deems&#160;necessary.</summary>
</bill>
