<bill session="117" type="h" number="3188" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ANGLE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a forgivable loan program for remote recreational businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ANGLE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assistance Needed for Great Losses Experienced in Isolated Northern Lakes Economic Territory Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000470"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2021-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2021-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1492" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-22T18:18:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Assistance Needed for Great Losses Experienced in Isolated Northern Lakes Economic Territory Act or the ANGLE Act 

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a program to make forgivable loans to certain remote recreational businesses that are impacted by border closures due to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Eligible remote recreational businesses must (1) have experienced a loss in revenue that is greater than 50% between March 1, 2020, and December 31, 2020, as compared with the same period in the previous year; and (2) show that the closure of the U.S.-Canada border restricted the ability of American customers to access the location of such businesses.

The maximum loan amount shall be equal to 75% of the business's FY2019 revenue, and the SBA shall forgive 100% of the value of such loan, less the amount the borrower received from (1) any other loan forgiveness program, or (2) any emergency advance under the economic impact disaster loan program.</summary>
</bill>
