<bill session="110" type="s" number="2818" updated="2020-02-10T17:01:58Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Plans Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Small Business Health Plans Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Public Health Service Act to provide for enhanced health insurance marketplace pooling and relating market rating.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2008-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000445" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2008-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2008-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000180" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2008-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-06-24T19:51:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Health Plans Act of 2008 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for the establishment and governance of small business health plans, which are group health plans sponsored by trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations that meet ERISA certification requirements. Requires the Secretary of Labor to: (1) apply the rules and standards of this Act to Alternative Market Pooling Organizations, such as unions, churches, and other groups; and (2) consult with the domicile state regarding the Secretary's exercise of authority over such plans. Allows other existing plans to be treated as small business health plans under certain circumstances. Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to promulgate Minimum Standards for premium variations and Model Small Group Rating Rules for plans under this Act.

Requires the Secretary to issue the List of Required Benefits of covered benefits, services, or categories of providers that are required to be provided by health insurance issuers in at least 26 states as a result of state mandate laws. Applies covered benefit, service, or category of provider mandates from the List to states with laws requiring such mandates, but does not apply such mandates from the List to states with no such laws. Supersedes any and all state laws relating to such mandates in the health insurance market.

Requires the Secretary to establish the Health Insurance Consensus Standards Board to develop recommendations that harmonize inconsistent state health insurance laws. Provides that any harmonized standards adopted by the Secretary will supersede state laws related to the areas covered by the harmonized standards.</summary>
</bill>
