<bill session="116" type="h" number="6043" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAW Against Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce illegal wildlife trafficking and importation by extending State Department reporting on foreign wildlife trafficking activity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAW Against Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting All Wildlife Against Trafficking Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2020-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-09T22:49:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting All Wildlife Against Trafficking Act or the PAW Against Trafficking Act

This bill sets forth requirements to provide warnings to travelers about wildlife trafficking (e.g., poaching and the illegal trade in wildlife) in foreign countries and reestablishes the Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking.

Specifically, the bill makes permanent the requirement for the Department of State to identify certain countries that are major sources, transit points, or consumers of wildlife trafficking products. Additionally, the State Department, on any State Department website or web-based application providing country-specific information for international travel, must ensure that such countries are clearly identified with a warning label along with a warning that international law or U.S. law may prohibit the export, import, purchase, sale, possession, or transport of products produced from endangered or threatened wildlife.

In addition, the bill revises the duties of the Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking. Among other duties, the task force must assess how consumption of illegally tracked wildlife in the United States may be driving illegal wildlife trafficking in such countries. The task force must also identify potential strategies to reduce domestic consumption of illegally trafficked wildlife products.</summary>
</bill>
