<bill session="117" type="s" number="204" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Press Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of Press Freedom, to create press freedom curriculum at the National Foreign Affairs Training Center, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Press Freedom Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2021-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2022-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2021-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-27T13:20:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Global Press Freedom Act

This bill establishes the Office of Press Freedom to advance the protection and well-being of members of the press abroad and to engage with foreign governments and global press freedom organizations concerning freedom of the press and of expression.

Led by the Ambassador-at-Large for Press Freedom, who shall be appointed by the President, the office must (1) coordinate efforts between relevant U.S. embassy personnel and press organizations or threatened individuals in situations in which press freedom is threatened abroad, (2) publicly and privately denounce oppression of the press abroad, and (3) recommend appropriate responses by the U.S. government when press freedoms are infringed upon. The office must also develop a press freedom curriculum for the National Foreign Affairs Training Center to help Foreign Service officers better understand issues of press freedom and tools that are available to help protect journalists and promote freedom of the press norms.

The Government Accountability Office must assess and report on effects and changes resulting from certain requirements related to press freedom.</summary>
</bill>
