<bill session="110" type="s" number="3513" updated="2017-12-15T00:40:14Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renovation Rule Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Renovation Rule Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to revise regulations relating to lead-based paint hazards, lead-contaminated dust, and lead-contaminated soil, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2008-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3639" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-08T20:46:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Renovation Rule Improvement Act of 2008 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to update the final rule entitled "Lead: Renovation, Repair, and Painting Program" published on April 22, 2008, to include requirements that: (1) independent clearance be performed by a certified risk assessor or certified sampling technician to ensure compliance with lead hazard standards for lead, lead dust, and lead-based paint; (2) a written renovation completion report describing all the actions to reduce lead hazards be provided to owners and occupants of a covered property; (3) work practices be at least as protective as those of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD); and (4) an individual who has completed a lead-based paint training and certification program be present at all times at a work site.

Requires the Administrator to establish a grant program to expand training opportunities relating to lead-based paint that are available at the state and tribal level. Requires grant recipients to provide no-cost, culturally and linguistically appropriate lead-based paint training and certification opportunities for low-income workers.

Requires the Administrator, in collaboration with the HUD Secretary, to submit a report to specified congressional committees on the impact of the final rule on preventing lead poisoning and on training opportunities for contractors and renovators.</summary>
</bill>
