<bill session="108" type="s" number="2094" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Workers Protection Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect United States workers from competition of foreign workforces for performance of Federal and State services contracts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Workers Protection Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2004-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-17T16:11:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Workers Protection Act of 2004 - Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to prohibit: (1) outsourced Federal Government work from being performed by a contractor outside the United States unless Federal employees previously performed such work outside the United States (currently, prohibited by the Transportation, Treasury, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004); (2) work on a procurement contract from being performed outside the United States unless it is necessary in order to meet a requirement for goods and services outside the United States or the President deems it necessary for national security reasons; and (3) Federal funds from being disbursed to a State until the Governor of the State has transmitted written certification that none of the funds will be spent on work performed outside the United States. Provides that this Act becomes effective for States two fiscal years after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
