<bill session="116" type="s" number="3614" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FEED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Empowering Essential Deliveries Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to approve State and local plans to partner with small and mid-size restaurants and nonprofit organizations to provide nutritious meals to individuals in need, to waive certain matching fund requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2020-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2020-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2020-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6700" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-18T13:56:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">FEMA Empowering Essential Deliveries Act or the FEED Act

This bill authorizes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to approve state, local, and Indian tribal government plans to partner with small and mid-size restaurants and nonprofit organizations to provide nutritious meals to individuals in need.

Specifically, during the period following the President's emergency declaration of March 13, 2020, and under any subsequent major disaster declaration that supersedes it, FEMA may approve plans from state, local, and Indian tribal governments that (1) establish contracts with small and mid-sized restaurants and nonprofits, including faith-based organizations and soup kitchens, to prepare healthy meals for people in need; and (2) provide for partnerships with nonprofit organizations to purchase directly from food producers and farmers.

FEMA shall waive federal matching requirements under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act during such period.</summary>
</bill>
