<bill session="118" type="s" number="3658" updated="2025-08-04T20:42:45Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Orbit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Orbit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Situational Awareness of Flying Elements in Orbit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">SAFE Orbit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Situational Awareness of Flying Elements in Orbit Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote space situational awareness and space traffic coordination and to modify the functions and leadership of the Office of Space Commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2024-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7314-7315" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7314-7315" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:12:10-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6385" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3362"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-08-04T20:42:40Z" status="Passed Senate">Situational Awareness of Flying Elements in Orbit Act or the SAFE Orbit Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Traffic Coordination System for Space, which is being developed by the Office of Space Commerce to provide space situational awareness data and services to space operators. (Space situational awareness means an understanding of the space operational environment and the identification, tracking, and prediction of the behavior of space objects and debris.)

As an initial matter, the bill provides for the elevation of the Office of Space Commerce to a standalone bureau within the Department of Commerce. (The office currently sits within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.)

The bill authorizes the bureau to acquire location tracking data, positional and orbit determination information, conjunction data messages, and other data, analytics, information, and services deemed necessary to avoid collisions in space. The bureau must disseminate this information at no charge (1) through a public database of space situational awareness information and services, including space traffic coordination; and (2) through the provision of basic situational awareness services to satellite operators. The bill also sets forth certain requirements for the collection and dissemination of such information, including that, to the extent practicable, the provision of service to satellite operators may not compete with private situational awareness products.

Finally, the bill provides immunity for the United States government from any suit for a cause of action arising from the provision or receipt of space situational awareness services or information.</summary>
</bill>
