<bill session="112" type="s" number="1225" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:53Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer certain facilities, easements, and rights-of-way to Fort Sumner Irrigation District, New Mexico.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2011-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 112-129.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="6343" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-09-30T17:28:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Fort Sumner Irrigation District, located in De Baca County, New Mexico, all works, land, and facilities of the Fort Sumner reclamation project in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement between the United States and the Fort Sumner Irrigation District Concerning Principles and Elements of Proposed Transfer of Title to Fort Sumner Irrigation District Facilities.

Requires the Secretary to report to Congress if such conveyance isn't completed within one year. Terminates, on the date of such conveyance: (1) U.S. interest in, responsibility for, and liability relating to such property; (2) a specified repayment contract between the United States and the District dated November 5, 1948; and (3) a specified payment obligation of the United States under the contract between the United States and the District for the forbearance of exercising priority water rights, dated August 21, 2009. Provides that all other terms of such forbearance agreement shall remain in effect for not less than 10 years after this Act's enactment.

Prohibits, effective on the date of such conveyance, any additional amounts from the reclamation fund established by the Act of June 17, 1902, from being provided for the conveyed land or facilities due to their status as part of a reclamation project.</summary>
</bill>
