<bill session="117" type="h" number="8172" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Diagnosis in Medicine Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Diagnosis in Medicine Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the quality, appropriateness, and effectiveness of diagnosis in health care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2022-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4468" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-20T12:52:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Diagnosis in Medicine Act of 2022

This bill requires various activities to improve diagnostic safety and quality in health care.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must convene an expert panel to make recommendations about the data needed to accelerate diagnostic safety and quality research. In convening the panel, HHS must coordinate with the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and other HHS components.

HHS must also establish an interagency council to develop a strategic plan and recommendations to improve diagnosis in health care.

In addition, AHRQ must (1) establish a quality improvement program related to diagnostic errors that includes dissemination of evidence-based strategies to improve diagnostic quality, safety, and health-care value; and (2) seek to contract with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to study disparities in diagnostic safety and quality.

The bill also allows specified grants provided by AHRQ and by the National Institutes of Health to be used for diagnostic safety and quality research.</summary>
</bill>
