<bill session="118" type="h" number="6315" updated="2025-11-19T02:15:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Billing Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Billing Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to waive the requirement of certain veterans to make copayments for hospital care and medical services in the case of an error by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001133" joined="2024-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2024-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3282" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T23:16:01Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Billing Accountability Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to waive the requirement that a veteran make co-payments for medications, hospital care, nursing home care, and medical services in certain situations. Specifically, a veteran may have such co-payments waived if (1) an error committed by the VA or a non-VA facility delayed co-payment notification to the veteran, and (2) the veteran received such notification later than 180 days (18 months in the case of a non-VA facility) after the date on which the veteran received the care or services.

In requiring a veteran to make a co-payment for care or services provided at a VA or a non-VA medical facility, the VA shall notify the veteran not later than 180 days (18 months in the case of a non-VA facility) after the date on which the veteran received the care or services. If the VA does not provide notification by such date, it may not collect the payment, including through a third-party entity, unless the veteran is provided with (1) information about applying for a waiver and establishing a payment plan with the VA, and (2) an opportunity to make a waiver or establish a payment plan.

Finally, the bill requires the VA to review and improve its co-payment billing internal controls and notification procedures.</summary>
</bill>
