<bill session="111" type="h" number="88" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:41Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">City of Oxnard Water Recycling and Desalination Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">City of Oxnard Water Recycling and Desalination Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of permanent facilities for the GREAT project to reclaim, reuse, and treat impaired waters in the area of Oxnard, California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-15T23:17:43Z" status="Introduced in House">City of Oxnard Water Recycling and Desalination Act of 2009 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of Phase I permanent facilities for the GREAT project to reclaim, reuse, and treat impaired water near Oxnard, California. Limits the federal share of the cost of the project to 25%. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds for the operation and maintenance of the project or for the construction, operations, and maintenance of the project's visitor's center. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
