<bill session="108" type="h" number="2457" updated="2023-01-15T16:18:30Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize funds for an educational center for the Castillo de San Marcos National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Preservation and Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Preservation and Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Preservation and Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Preservation and Education Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000689"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-639.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-07" calendar="Union" number="383">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 383.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-13T16:19:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Radanovich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-13T16:20:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7020-7021" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-13T16:20:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2457.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-13T16:26:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7020" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-13T16:26:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-08">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12020" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-12-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-12-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-23" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-480" type="public" datetime="2004-12-23">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-480.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-04T18:21:48Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 7, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Title I: Castillo De San Marcos National Monument Preservation Act - Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Preservation and Education Act - (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to design and construct a Visitor Center for the Castillo de San Marcos National Monument, subject to such project being prioritized in the National Park Service's five-year, line-item construction program. Requires the Visitor Center to be located and constructed in accordance with the Preferred Alternative identified in the Record of Decision for the General Management Plan for the Monument, expected to be signed in 2005.

(Sec. 103) Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the city of St. Augustine, Florida, the Colonial St. Augustine Preservation Foundation, other Federal, State, and local departments or agencies, academic institutions, and non-profit entities for the planning and design, construction, management, and operation of the Visitor Center.

(Sec. 104) Provides that, if the Preferred Alternative for the Visitor Center is located outside the boundary of the Monument, the Secretary is authorized to acquire the site for the Visitor Center from willing sellers, by donation, purchase, or exchange. Requires, after completion of the acquisition, the boundary to be modified to reflect the acquisition of such land.

(Sec. 105) Mandates that, prior to initiating any planning, design, or construction on the Visitor Center, such project must be reviewed and approved by the National Park Service consistent with partnership construction guidelines established by that agency.

Title II: Castillo De San Marcos National Monument Boundary Modification - Castillo de San Marcos National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary to: (1) convey, without consideration, to the City all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the lands known as Orange Street, a portion of the Monument; and (2) upon completion of the conveyance, revise the Monument's boundary to exclude the land conveyed.

Revises such boundary to include specified land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-639</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
