<bill session="109" type="h" number="5988" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:33Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Predominantly Black Institution Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize grant programs to enhance the access of low-income Black students to higher education.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Predominantly Black Institution Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2006-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2006-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School libraries"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-05T16:31:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Predominantly Black Institution Act of 2006 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to Predominantly Black Institutions to: (1) enhance their capacity to serve more low and middle-income Black American students; (2) expand higher education opportunities for students eligible for student assistance under title IV of the Act by encouraging such students to prepare for college and persist in secondary and postsecondary education; and (3) strengthen their financial ability to serve the academic needs of such students.

Defines such institutions as accredited institutions: (1) serving at least 1,000 undergraduate students, at least 50% of which are pursuing a bachelor's or associate's degree; (2) serving an undergraduate population at least 40% of which are Black Americans and at least 50% of which are low-income or first-generation college students; and (3) whose spending per full-time undergraduate student is low in comparison to that of institutions offering similar instruction.

Allows grant recipients to use up to 20% of their grant on an endowment fund, provided they raise nonfederal matching funds at least equal to the amount of the grant used for such endowment. Allots funding among institutions on the basis of their share of Pell Grant recipients, graduates, and graduates pursuing a higher degree.

Establishes a minimum allotment for each institution of $250,000, which is to be ratably reduced if appropriations are insufficient to pay such amount.</summary>
</bill>
