<bill session="117" type="h" number="5692" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:27Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the spread of aquatic invasive species in western waters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop the Spread of Invasive Mussels Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Spread of Invasive Mussels Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2022-01-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="E1131-1132"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-19T14:32:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop the Spread of Invasive Mussels Act of 2021

This bill directs the Bureau of Reclamation to provide federal assistance to states with certain reclamation projects to prevent the spread of aquatic invasive species. Such assistance shall include financial assistance to purchase, establish, operate, or maintain watercraft inspection and decontamination stations.

In providing financial assistance, Reclamation must prioritize projects such as

 watercraft inspections and decontamination stations that have the highest likelihood of preventing the spread of aquatic invasive species at reservoirs of reclamation projects; or projects that prevent the spread of an aquatic invasive species to waters under the jurisdiction of Reclamation, including irrigation, reclamation, or other water projects. This bill provides authority for each federal agency on the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force, along with state partners, to (1) conduct mandatory inspections and decontamination of recreational vessels; and (2) if necessary, impound, quarantine, or otherwise prevent entry of a recreational vessel. In addition, it expands the membership to include the National Park Service, Bureau of Land Management, and Reclamation.</summary>
</bill>
