<bill session="118" type="s" number="4305" updated="2025-08-27T19:20:28Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-02">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DHS Better Ballistic Body Armor Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Better Ballistic Body Armor Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Better Ballistic Body Armor Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">DHS Better Ballistic Body Armor Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the effectiveness of body armor issued to female agents and officers of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2024-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2024-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2024-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-214.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="492">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 492.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-12-02">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6758-6759" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-02">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-02" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6759" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-03T17:19:53-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-03T17:26:55-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3307"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-08-27T19:18:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DHS Better Ballistic Body Armor Act

This bill requires ballistic resistant body armor issued to agents and officers of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to meet certain requirements related to fit, coverage, and testing on female body shapes. Ballistic resistant body armor means ballistic protection for the torso worn over or under clothing (e.g., bulletproof vests).&#160;

(Testing by the Federal Bureau of Investigation found that certain soft body armor, when worn by women, allowed projectiles to skip off the armor panel in the chest area and project into the unprotected throat area. New body armor models that mitigate this issue are now available and in use by some federal agencies.)

Under the bill, ballistic resistant body armor procured by DHS for agents and officers whose body shapes are most closely associated with female must

be made to conform and provide the best possible coverage to individual wearers, allowing for either flat or shaped front panels;have enhanced and advanced fit technology that stops bullets from skipping off the chest at an upward angle; andhave passed certain testing by the National Institute of Justice, including testing on female-shaped molds.&#160;Within three years of the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment, all DHS agents and officers whose body shapes are most closely associated with female must be issued body armor that meets these requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-214</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
