<bill session="117" type="h" number="9080" updated="2023-01-31T04:45:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Non-Profit Hospital Tax Exemption Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Non-Profit Hospital Tax Exemption Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish new community benefit standards for tax-exempt hospital organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000929"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-30T20:23:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Non-Profit Hospital Tax Exemption Transparency Act 

The bill imposes additional community benefit standards for tax-exempt hospital organizations. A hospital organization must have a board of directors drawn from the community in which it is located and must provide medical care for patients who pay their bills through public programs, including Medicare and Medicaid.

The organization may not limit the number of patients served at any clinical site it owns or controls and must spend specified amounts on (1) training, education, or research designed to improve patient care; (2) improvements to facilities and equipment; and (3) free or discounted care.

The Inspector General for Tax Administration of the Department of the Treasury must conduct a review of the financial assistance policies of tax-exempt hospital organizations.

The Government Accountability Office must review and report on the effectiveness of the Internal Revenue Service in enforcing compliance of tax-exempt hospitals with the new community benefit standards.</summary>
</bill>
