<bill session="118" type="h" number="2566" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:51Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Voter Registration Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Registration Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require an individual who applies for a motor vehicle driver's license in a new State to indicate whether the new State is to serve as the individual's residence for purposes of registering to vote in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001136"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Elections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA08" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="Elections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="156" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-27T13:52:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Voter Registration Efficiency Act

This bill requires a state motor vehicle authority to require each individual applying for a motor vehicle driver's license in the state to (1) indicate whether the individual resides in another state or resided in another state before applying for the license (and, if so, identify the state involved); and (2) indicate whether the individual intends for the new state to serve as the individual's residence for federal voter registration purposes.

If an individual indicates an intention for the new state to serve as the individual's residence for federal voter registration purposes, the state motor vehicle authority must notify the motor vehicle authority of the former state of residence. The motor vehicle authority of the former state of residence must then notify the chief state election official that the individual no longer intends for the state to serve as the individual's residence for federal voter registration purposes.</summary>
</bill>
