<bill session="108" type="h" number="910" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:56Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Disbursement of Offshore Oil Revenue Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the distribution to coastal States and counties of revenues collected under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Disbursement of Offshore Oil Revenue Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Disbursement of Offshore Oil Revenue Act of 2003 - Establishes the Coastal Communities Outer Continental Shelf Receipt Fund as an interest-bearing account in the Treasury.Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to pay into the Fund all revenues attributable to an Outer Continental Shelf lease, any part of which is within 200 geographical miles of the coast line.Directs the Secretary to pay each coastal State and its coastal counties, respectively, one-half of the revenues and any interest earned on them attributable to the State for the fiscal year most recently completed.Preconditions such disposition of funds upon annual enactment by each coastal State and coastal county of the legislation necessary to provide State and local permits for the onshore facilities needed to support offshore oil or gas development or production in the pertinent adjacent area.Declares that if a State or county fails to enact such legislation, the funds attributable to it shall not be disbursed, and the Secretary shall take that failure into consideration before offering any additional leases for sale in the offshore area adjacent to that State or county.</summary>
</bill>
