<bill session="110" type="h" number="5636" updated="2021-09-29T17:06:14Z">
  <state datetime="2008-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Product and Food Safety Information Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Consumer Product and Food Safety Information Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a comprehensive process to inform American consumers about food and product recalls, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2008-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2008-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2008-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-27T19:24:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Consumer Product and Food Safety Information Act of 2008 - Requires the head of each federal product safety enforcement agency to design and implement a public information plan to use agency and media resources to provide information to the public concerning: (1) the role of the agency in ensuring product safety; (2) steps consumers can take to enhance their safety while using regulated products; (3) product recalls; and (4) additional information to enhance consumer safety. Requires such plan to include procedures for developing and distributing product safety information to the public.

Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to establish: (1) a clearinghouse to collect and distribute product recall and safety information to government entities and the public; (2) a toll-free number for such information; and (3) a public website to provide recall information to the public.

Requires the head of each enforcement agency to issue: (1) national public service announcements that contain information on the public safety role of the agency, available resources, and product safety information; and (2) posters and other printed material on the public safety role of the agency.

Sets forth requirements for product recall notifications and quarterly reporting.

Requires any manufacturer or distributor of a product who voluntarily initiates a product recall as a result of safety concerns to provide notice of such recall to the relevant enforcement agency within 10 days.</summary>
</bill>
