<bill session="118" type="h" number="2868" updated="2025-11-11T23:49:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Association Health Plans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Association Health Plans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Association Health Plans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to clarify the treatment of certain association health plans as employers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2023-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 118-112.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-14" calendar="Union" number="87">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 87.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3799" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3167" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-19T15:08:13Z" status="Reported to House">Association Health Plans Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the treatment of association health plans (AHPs) as single, large employer health plans for purposes of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA).

Under AHPs, groups of individuals or small employers join together to purchase health insurance coverage. AHPs were historically subject to the market requirements for individual and small group health plans. In 2018, the Department of Labor issued regulations that allowed an AHP to be considered a single, large employer under ERISA if certain conditions are met. The regulations have been subject to litigation, which is still ongoing.

The bill provides that a group of employers is treated as a single, large employer for the purpose of establishing an AHP if the group, among other listed criteria (1) has been in existence for at least two years prior to establishing&#194;&#160;a group health insurance plan and was formed for a purpose other than offering health insurance, (2) meets any criteria set by Labor in a prior advisory opinion, or (3) meets any other criteria set by Labor through regulations.

Additionally, the bill establishes rules for AHPs to set premium rates and prohibits AHPs from discriminating in coverage based on health status-related factors or denying coverage based on preexisting conditions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-112</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
