<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="496" updated="2022-02-25T17:33:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1249" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-06-23T14:48:59-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-06-23"/>
  <description>Amendment lists criteria that the Patent Trade Office Director must take into account when selecting satellite offices in the United States.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 6 printed in Part B of House Report 112-111 to add requirements to the satellite office location selection process to ensure that (1) the purposes, as described in the bill, of establishing satellite offices are achieved, (2) recruitment costs are minimized by considering the availability of knowledgeable personnel in the region, and (3) the economic impact to the region is considered. It would also require that the Director in the required report to Congress on the rationale in selecting the location of any satellite office include an explanation of how the selected location will achieve the purposes of satellite offices and how the required considerations were met.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-06-23T14:48:59-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lujan amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23T14:45:41-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Lujan.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4486" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4486" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23T14:45:41-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Lujan.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4486" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4486" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23T14:48:59-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lujan amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23T14:48:59-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
