<bill session="117" type="s" number="2914" updated="2023-01-02T00:29:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the First Step Act of 2018 to permit defendants convicted of certain offenses to be eligible for reduced sentences, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Terry Technical Correction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terry Technical Correction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2021-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5455" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-09T11:35:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Terry Technical Correction Act

This bill broadens the scope of crack cocaine offenders who are eligible for a retroactive sentencing reduction under the First Step Act of 2018.

The First Step Act made the Fair Sentencing Act of 2010 retroactive and authorized sentencing reductions for certain crack cocaine offenders convicted and sentenced before the Fair Sentencing Act became effective. Under current law, crack cocaine offenders whose conduct triggered a mandatory minimum sentence are eligible for a retroactive sentencing reduction under the First Step Act. However, in 2021, the Supreme Court held in Terry v. United States that low-level crack cocaine offenders whose conduct did not trigger a mandatory minimum sentence are not eligible for a retroactive sentencing reduction under the First Step Act.

This bill extends eligibility for a retroactive sentencing reduction under the First Step Act to all crack cocaine offenders convicted and sentenced before the Fair Sentencing Act became effective, including low-level offenders whose conduct did not trigger a mandatory minimum sentence.</summary>
</bill>
