<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3853</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-09-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-09-28T17:58:56Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7624-7629)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-28</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7624)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
        <firstName>Thomas</firstName>
        <lastName>Carper</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DE</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warner, Mark R. [D-VA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Warner</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000069</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Akaka, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>AKAKA</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KOHIKINA</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001035</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Collins, Susan M. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Susan</firstName>
        <lastName>Collins</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>V000126</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Voinovich, George V. [R-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>GEORGE</firstName>
        <lastName>VOINOVICH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <middleName>V.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000304</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lieberman, Joseph I. [ID-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOSEPH</firstName>
        <lastName>LIEBERMAN</lastName>
        <party>ID</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>I.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-12-02</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal officials</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Performance measurement</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-23T16:42:02Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>GPRA Modernization Act of 2010 - Amends the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 to require each executive agency to make its strategic plan available on its public website on the first Monday in February of any year following that in which the term of the President commences and to notify the President and Congress. Requires such plan to cover at least a four-year period and to include a description of how the agency is working with other agencies to achieve its goals and objectives, as well as relevant federal government priority goals.</p> <p>Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to coordinate with agencies to develop a federal government performance plan, which shall be submitted with the annual federal budget and concurrently made available on an OMB website of agency programs. Requires such plan to: (1) establish government performance goals for the current and next fiscal years; (2) identify activities, entities, and policies contributing to each goal; (3) identify a lead government official responsible for coordinating efforts to achieve the goal; (4) establish common federal government performance indicators with quarterly targets; (5) establish clearly defined quarterly milestones; and (6) identify major management challenges and plans to address such challenges.</p> <p>Directs each agency to make its annual performance plan available on its public website and notify the President and Congress by the first Monday in February. Requires each plan to describe how performance goals contribute to objectives of the agency's strategic plan and goals of the federal government performance plan.</p> <p>Requires each agency to make available on its public website an update on its performance no less than 150 days after the end of each fiscal year, with more frequent updates of performance on indicators that provide data of significant value to the government, Congress, or program partners at a reasonable level of administrative burden. <br> </p> <p>Requires the OMB Director to coordinate with agencies to develop priority goals to improve the performance and management of the government. Requires such goals to be long-term, updated every four years, and made publicly available concurrently with the submission of the annual federal budget in the first full fiscal year following any year in which the term of the President commences. </p> <p>Requires each agency head to identify priority goals among its performance goals every two years. </p> <p>Requires the OMB Director, with the appropriate lead government official, and the head and Chief Operating Officer of each agency, at least quarterly, to review the progress achieved toward each federal government priority goal and each agency priority goal, respectively, and to identify strategies for performance improvement for the goals at greatest risk.</p> <p>Directs OMB to ensure the effective operation of a single website that provides information in a way that presents a coherent picture of all federal programs and of the performance of the federal government and individual agencies. Requires the website to include information about each agency program and each of the federal government priority goals.</p> <p>Requires the deputy head of each agency to be the agency's Chief Operating Officer, who shall be responsible for improving the management and performance of the agency.</p> <p>Requires each agency head to designate a Performance Improvement Officer, who shall report to such Chief Operating Officer. Establishes a Performance Improvement Council, which shall assist the OMB Director to improve the performance of the government and achieve the federal government priority goals.</p> <p>Requires: (1) agencies to make their strategic plans, performance plans, and performance updates available on the OMB government programs website; and (2) the OMB Director to issue guidance to agencies to provide concise and timely performance information for publication on such website.</p> <p>Requires each agency's Chief Operating Officer, annually, to compile and submit to OMB a list of all plans and reports the agency produces for Congress and a list that identifies a specified percentage of those (at least 10% in the first year) as outdated or duplicative. Requires the OMB Director to include the list of outdated or duplicative agency plans and reports in the annual federal budget submitted by the President and authorizes the OMB Director to concurrently submit legislation to eliminate or consolidate such plans and reports.</p> <p>Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to identify key skills and competencies needed by federal personnel for developing goals, evaluating programs, and analyzing and using performance information for the purpose of improving government efficiency and effectiveness.</p> <p> Requires the Comptroller General to evaluate and report to Congress on implementation of this Act and its effect on agency performance management.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>GPRA Modernization Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>GPRA Modernization Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to modernize and refine the requirements of the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993, to require quarterly performance reviews of Federal policy and management priorities, to establish Chief Operating Officers, Performance Improvement Officers, and the Performance Improvement Council, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>GPRA Modernization Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3853is/xml/BILLS-111s3853is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7624-7629)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
