<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="3563" updated="2022-02-25T17:33:37Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4520" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-07-15">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000294"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-07-15"/>
  <description>To protect the public health by providing the Food and Drug Administration with certain authority to regulate tobacco products, to eliminate the Federal quota and price support programs for tobacco, and to provide assistance to quota holders, tobacco producers, and tobacco-dependent communities.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-07-15" how="roll" result="pass" roll="157">
      <text>Amendment SA 3563 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 78 - 15. Record Vote Number: 157.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Amendment SA 3563 proposed by Senator DeWine to Amendment SA 3562. (consideration: CR S8151-8178, S8217-8218) To protect the public health by providing the Food and Drug Administration with certain authority to regulate tobacco products, to eliminate the Federal quota and price support programs for tobacco, and to provide assistance to quota holders, tobacco producers, and tobacco-dependent communities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3563 proposed by Senator DeWine to Amendment SA 3562.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8151-8178, S8217-8218" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 3563 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 78 - 15. Record Vote Number: 157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3563 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 78 - 15. Record Vote Number: 157.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
