<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="3582" updated="2022-02-25T17:34:05Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4567" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-09-08">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000162"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-09-08"/>
  <description>To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit to Congress, at least 60 days prior to award, a report on the results of an Office of Management and Budget Circular A-76 competition, to include estimated savings, performance improvements, and the impact on jobs and Federal Government employees.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-09-08" how="roll" result="pass" roll="167">
      <text>Amendment SA 3582 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 47. Record Vote Number: 167.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Amendment SA 3582 proposed by Senator Thomas to Amendment SA 3581. (consideration: CR S8947-8950; text: CR S8947) To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit to Congress, at least 60 days prior to award, a report on the results of an Office of Management and Budget Circular A-76 competition, to include estimated savings, performance improvements, and the impact on jobs and Federal Government employees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 3582 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 47. Record Vote Number: 167.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3582 proposed by Senator Thomas to Amendment SA 3581.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8947-8950" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8947" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3582 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 47. Record Vote Number: 167.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
