<bill session="109" type="h" number="3942" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:07Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Professional Sports Responsibility Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Federal Office of Steroids Testing Enforcement and Prevention to establish and enforce standards for the testing for the illegal use in professional sports of performance enhancing substances and other controlled substances.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Professional Sports Responsibility Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="popular">Professional Athletes Standards Drug Testing bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2005-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Basketball"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hockey"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-01T19:18:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Professional Sports Responsibility Act of 2005 - Requires the Attorney General to issue rules requiring major professional leagues (i.e., Major League Baseball, the National Basketball Association, the National Football League, and the National Hockey League) to test athletes for the illegal use of steroids and other performance-enhancing substances and Schedule I substances. Requires such regulations to establish: (1) the number of times each athlete should be tested and the prohibited substances; (2) a means for exempting substances used for a documented medical condition; (3) sufficient penalties for any athlete who tests positive and procedures for publicly disclosing such athlete's identity; and (4) an appeals process.

Requires the Attorney General to authorize a private nonprofit organization to be an accreditation body to annually certify that each league's testing meets established standards.

Allows the Attorney General to assess fines for failure to adopt or enforce the required testing policies.

Requires the Attorney General to report to Congress regarding any league that fails to comply with such policies and the effectiveness of the regulations under this Act.

Amends the Controlled Substances Act to double the maximum penalties for violations regarding anabolic steroids that occur near or at a sports facility or that involve an athlete.

Directs the Comptroller General to study the illegal use of performance-enhancing substances and other controlled substances by college athletes.

Allows the Attorney General to include as a major professional league any additional professional sports league or National Collegiate Athletic Association entities if such additions would prevent the illegal use of performance-enhancing substances and other controlled substances by athletes.</summary>
</bill>
