<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="145" updated="2022-02-03T06:09:58Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2352" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-05-20T15:58:29-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000183"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <description>Amendment adds a new title (Military Entrepreneurs Program) requiring the Small Business Administration to establish and carry out a program to provide business counseling and entrepreneurial development assistance to members of the Armed Forces to facilitate the development of small business concerns. The amendment establishes a liaison to facilitate outreach to members of the Armed Forces with respect to business counseling and entrepreneurial development assistance.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 111-121 to add a new title (Military Entrepreneurs Program) to require the Small Business Administration to establish and carry out a program to provide business counseling and entrepreneurial development assistance to members of the Armed Forces to facilitate the development of small business concerns. The amendment establishes a liaison to facilitate outreach to members of the Armed Forces with respect to business counseling and entrepreneurial development assistance.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-05-20T15:58:29-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Nye amendment (A008) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T15:55:49-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Nye.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5858-5859" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5858" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T15:55:49-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Nye.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5858-5859" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5858" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T15:58:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20T15:58:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Nye amendment (A008) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
