<bill session="118" type="h" number="3214" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veteran Entrepreneurs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Entrepreneurs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow tax credits to veterans for the establishment of franchises.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2023-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-24T19:42:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Veteran Entrepreneurs Act of 2023

This bill allows a business-related tax credit&#160;of 25% of up to $400,000 of the&#160;franchise fees paid or incurred by an eligible veteran&#160;for the purchase of a franchise. The bill reduces the amount of such credit if the veteran does not own 100% of the stock or capital or profits interest of the franchisee.

An eligible veteran is a person who served in the active military, naval, or air service; was discharged or released under conditions other than dishonorable; and who pays or incurs a franchise fee in connection with a franchise agreement with a franchisor.

The veteran may elect to transfer the credit to an eligible franchisor in exchange for a discount in the franchise fee commensurate with the value of the credit.

 The Small Business Administration and the Department of Veterans Affairs must provide information about the tax credit allowed by this bill to veterans service organizations and veteran advocacy groups.</summary>
</bill>
