<bill session="108" type="h" number="663" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:24Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IX of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the improvement of patient safety and to reduce the incidence of events that adversely affect patient safety, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="popular">Medical Mistakes bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000275" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000439" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000213" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000110" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000316" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000159" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000572" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001004" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001045" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000058" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000413" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000784" joined="2003-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 108-28.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-03-06" calendar="Union" number="19">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:08:09-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:08:27-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1766-1774" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:08:32-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 663.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:22:14-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T17:26:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1777-1778" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="60" datetime="2003-03-12T17:32:25-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 418 - 6 (Roll no. 60).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1766-1771" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T17:33:21-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8632-8633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 720 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-07-22" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Gregg; Frist; Enzi; Alexander; Kennedy; Dodd; Jeffords.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>See also S. 720.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="720" relation="related document"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Product coding"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed House amended">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act - Title I: Patient Safety and Quality Improvement - (Sec. 101) Amends the Public Health Service Act to make patient safety work product privileged information. Defines "patient safety work product" as a record concerning patient information either reported to a patient safety organization by a health care provider (doctor, hospital, etc.) or created by a patient safety organization. Defines a "patient safety organization" as an organization, certified under this Act, that collects such information with the goal of improving patient safety and the quality of health care delivery.Prohibits patient safety work product: (1) from being subject to a civil or administrative subpoena or order; (2) from being required to be admitted as evidence in any State or Federal civil or administrative proceeding; or (3) if the patient safety work product is identifiable information and is received by a national accreditation organization in its capacity as a patient safety organization, from being used by such organization in an accreditation action against the provider that reported the information. Requires disclosure to the Food and Drug Administration for safety purposes.Protects individuals who report information to a patient safety organization from adverse employment actions. Permits the voluntary disclosure of identifiable information by a provider or patient safety organization under specified conditions, including that it be for improving quality and safety. Imposes a civil penalty for violating this section. Declares that patient safety work product remains confidential, even if a patient safety organization has its certification revoked or otherwise ceases to exist.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and maintain a database to receive relevant nonidentifiable patient safety work product, consistent with the administrative simplification provisions of the Social Security Act.Permits the Secretary to provide to patient safety organizations and to States: (1) technical assistance with reporting systems for health care errors; and (2) guidance on the type of data to be voluntarily submitted to any National Patient Safety Database.Directs the Secretary to establish a process for the Secretary or another approved Federal or State governmental organization to certify patient safety organizations. Sets forth criteria a patient safety organization must meet to be certified.(Sec. 102) Requires the Secretary to develop or adopt voluntary national standards promoting the interoperability of information technology systems involved with health care delivery. Requires the Secretary to take into account the costs to the health care system from the standards and any efficiencies resulting from the adoption of the standards.(Sec. 103) Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary to issue and periodically revise regulations requiring the manufacturer of any drug or biological product that is subject to regulation by the Food and Drug Administration, or the packager or labeler of such a product, to include a unique product identifier on the packaging. Considers as misbranded any drug or biological product without such a unique product identifier. Permits the Secretary to waive these regulatory requirements or add provisions in order to safeguard the public health.(Sec. 104) Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to physicians and certain other health care professionals for the purpose of establishing electronic prescription programs. Requires grantees to fund 50 percent of the cost of such programs. Directs the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality to conduct a study of the cost-effectiveness of electronic prescription programs. Establishes reporting requirements.(Sec. 105) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to hospitals and other health care providers for new or improved computer hardware and software for the purposes of improving patient safety and health care quality and reducing adverse events and complications from medication errors. Requires grantees to fund 50 percent of the cost of such information technologies. Permits the Secretary to provide technical assistance to applicants and grantees. Establishes reporting requirements.(Sec. 106) Authorizes appropriations through FY 2005.Title II: Medical Information Technology Advisory Board - (Sec. 201) Amends the title XI (General Provisions) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary to appoint a Medical Information Advisory Board (the MITAB). Declares that the MITAB shall make recommendations to the Secretary regarding medical information technology, including on: (1) the best current practices in medical information technology; and (2) methods of implementing records security. Establishes reporting requirements.Allows Federal agencies to detail employees to the MITAB, and permits the MITAB to secure such information from Federal agencies as is allowed under specified Federal law pertaining to Government organization and employees.Applies the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act to the MITAB.Terminates the MITAB 30 days after the submission of its final report.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-28</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
