<bill session="116" type="s" number="4883" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:11Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Brian Tally VA Employment Transparency Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brian Tally VA Employment Transparency Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide certain notice to a person filing a claim against the Department of Veterans Affairs for damage, injury, or death on Standard Form 95, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4526" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-08T16:03:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Brian Tally VA Employment Transparency Act of 2020

This bill prescribes the notice the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must provide in the event a person submits a claim for damage, injury, or death on Standard Form 95 (related to tort claims occurring within the scope of an employee's federal employment). Specifically, the VA must provide to the claimant, within 30 days after the claim is submitted, notice of (1) the importance of obtaining legal advice, including a recommendation that the claimant should secure legal counsel; and (2) the employment status of any individual listed on the form.

Additionally, if the claim involves a contractor that entered into an agreement with the VA, the VA must provide the claimant notice of the importance of obtaining legal advice as to the statute of limitations regarding the claim in the state in which the claim arose.</summary>
</bill>
