<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>174</number>
    <updateDate>2020-02-12T18:54:59Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2020-02-12T18:54:59Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-01-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-01-08T21:08:08Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>365</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-02-04</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-08</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-01-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000025</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inouye, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>INOUYE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KEN</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000361</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rockefeller, John D., IV [D-WV]</fullName>
        <firstName>JAY</firstName>
        <lastName>ROCKEFELLER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WV</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-01-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000663</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Snowe, Olympia J. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Olympia</firstName>
        <lastName>Snowe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-01-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000122</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Reed, Jack [D-RI]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Reed</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>RI</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-01-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Ecology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Great Lakes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine pollution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-01-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-01-28T18:10:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act - Directs the President to establish a a program to develop a coordinated and comprehensive federal ocean and coastal mapping program for the Great Lakes and coastal state waters, the territorial sea, the exclusive economic zone, and the U.S. continental shelf that enhances ecosystem approaches in decision-making for conservation and management of marine resources and habitats, establishes research and mapping priorities, supports the siting of research and other platforms, and advances ocean and coastal science.</p> <p>Directs the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to convene or use an existing interagency committee on ocean and coastal mapping to implement such program and to coordinate federal ocean and coastal mapping and surveying activities with other federal efforts (including the Digital Coast, Geospatial One-Stop, and the Federal Geographic Data Committee), international mapping activities, coastal states, user groups, and nongovernmental entities. Authorizes the Administrator to convene an ocean and coastal mapping advisory panel consisting of representatives from nongovernmental entities to provide input regarding activities of the committee.</p> <p>Directs the Administrator to develop a plan for an integrated ocean and coastal mapping initiative within NOAA that: (1) identifies all ocean and coastal mapping programs within NOAA, establishing priorities; (2) encourages the development of innovative ocean and coastal mapping technologies and applications; and (3) documents available and developing technologies, best practices in data processing and distribution, and leveraging opportunities with other federal agencies, coastal states, and nongovernmental entities.</p> <p>Authorizes the Administrator to establish joint ocean and coastal mapping centers of excellence (including a joint hydrographic center) in institutions of higher education to conduct specified activities, including: (1) research and development of innovative ocean and coastal mapping technologies, equipment, and data products; and (2) mapping of the U.S. outer continental shelf. Requires the Administrator to continue developing a strategy for expanding contracting with nongovernmental entities. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Ocean and Coastal Mapping Integration Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish a coordinated and comprehensive Federal ocean and coastal mapping program.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-01-08T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-01-08</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
