<bill session="117" type="h" number="3011" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Holding Chinese Military Companies Accountable Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the definition of a communist Chinese military company for purposes of the imposition of certain sanctions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Holding Chinese Military Companies Accountable Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4792" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-01T17:19:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Holding Chinese Military Companies Accountable Act

This bill expands the definition of a Communist Chinese military company and addresses related issues. (Current law authorizes the President to exercise certain economic powers, such as investigating or prohibiting payments, involving a person designated a Communist Chinese military company.)

Under this bill, the Department of Defense (DOD) shall apply the designation to a person (i.e., an individual or entity) with significant investments in certain technology sectors, such as fifth-generation wireless communications or artificial intelligence, if the person is owned by, controlled by, or affiliated with the Chinese Communist Party or any person who has ever been a delegate to the National People's Congress.

The bill also requires DOD to continue making periodic determinations regarding such designations until December 31, 2026.</summary>
</bill>
