<bill session="111" type="s" number="2772" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:06Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Criminal Justice Reinvestment Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a criminal justice reinvestment grant program to help States and local jurisdictions reduce spending on corrections, control growth in the prison and jail populations, and increase public safety.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Criminal Justice Reinvestment Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Justice Reinvestment Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2010-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2010-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2009-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11384"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="328">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 328.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4080" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-14T14:40:56Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Criminal Justice Reinvestment Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to states, local and territorial governments, or Indian tribes to: (1) analyze and improve the cost-effectiveness of spending on prisons, jails, and community corrections; and (2) implement policies, programs, or practices to help control growth in spending on corrections and increase public safety.

Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (DOJ), beginning in FY2012, to conduct annual audits of not less than 10% of all grantees receiving funds under this Act to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse. Denies continued funding to a grant recipient who has an unresolved audit.

Requires the Attorney General to: (1) report to the Judiciary Committees of Congress on November 1 of each year concerning the development and implementation of grants and strategies developed under this Act; (2) establish an information clearinghouse for data collected and best practices developed by grant recipients; and (3) ensure equitable distribution of grants among geographical regions and between urban and rural populations, including Indian tribes.

Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2015. Limits expenditures for salaries and DOJ administrative expenses to 5% of funds authorized.</summary>
</bill>
