<bill session="109" type="s" number="2265" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:05Z">
  <state datetime="2006-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pork-Barrel Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide greater accountability of taxpayers' dollars by curtailing congressional earmarking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pork-Barrel Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="popular">Reform Earmarks Process bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000560" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000595" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001078" joined="2006-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S980-981"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2261" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-03-22T18:39:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pork-Barrel Reduction Act - Amends rule XVI (Appropriations and Amendments to General Appropriations Bills) of the Standing Rules of the Senate with respect to consideration of appropriations bills to provide that, upon a point of order, no: (1) new or general legislation nor any unauthorized appropriation may be included in any general appropriation bill; (2) amendment may be received to any general appropriation bill that would add an unauthorized appropriation; (3) new or general legislation nor any unauthorized appropriation, new matter, or nongermane matter may be included in any conference report on a general appropriation bill; or (4) unauthorized appropriation may be included in any amendment between the chambers in relation to a general appropriation bill.

Sets forth procedures for consideration of such points of order.

Amends rule XXVIII (Conference Committees, Reports, Open Meetings) to make it out of order to consider a conference report which includes matter not committed to the conferees by either chamber.

Makes the presentation of conference reports in order only after such reports are filed and made available 48 hours before such presentation.

Prohibits a federal agency from obligating any funds made available in an appropriation Act to implement an earmark included in an accompanying report, unless the earmark is also included in the Act.

Amends rule XVI to prohibit consideration of an appropriation bill or amendment between the chambers which includes unauthorized appropriations, unless such bill is accompanied by a report providing a detailed listing of: (1) all unauthorized appropriations in such bill; (2) an identification of the Member or Members who proposed the unauthorized appropriation; and (3) an explanation of the essential governmental purpose for it.

Imposes the same prohibition with respect to a conference report which includes unauthorized appropriations if it is not accompanied by a joint statement that provides the same detailed listing.

Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require a recipient of federal funds to file a mandatory disclosure report containing: (1) the name of any registered lobbyist to whom the recipient paid money to lobby on behalf of such funding; and (2) the amount of such payment.</summary>
</bill>
