<bill session="116" type="h" number="266" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior, environment, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Additional Emergency Appropriations for Coronavirus Response</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
    <title type="short">Additional Emergency Appropriations for Coronavirus Response</title>
    <title type="short">Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Additional Emergency Appropriations for Coronavirus Response</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001143"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08T19:39:10-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 28 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 264, H.R. 265, H.R. 266 and H.R. 267. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides one hour of debate, orders the previous question, and allows one motion to commit on each bill. The rule waives the requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of January 15, 2019, relating to a measure making or continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T09:18:33-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 28.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H469-498" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T09:18:38-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 264, H.R. 265, H.R. 266 and H.R. 267. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The rule provides one hour of debate, orders the previous question, and allows one motion to commit on each bill. The rule waives the requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of January 15, 2019, relating to a measure making or continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T09:19:24-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 266.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T10:41:06-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T10:41:33-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Calvert moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H497" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T10:42:04-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Calvert motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to decrease the Bureau of Land Management, Management of Lands and Resources account by $6 million and increase the Wildland Fire Management account by a similar amount; and to increase the Forest Service, Forest and Rangeland Research account by $15 million, and decrease the Capital Improvement and Maintenance account by a similar amount.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T10:48:21-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T10:49:03-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion, and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Calvert demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to recommit with instructions until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T11:29:21-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H502-503" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T11:54:59-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 190 - 229 (Roll no. 26).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="27" datetime="2019-01-11T12:04:05-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 240 - 179 (Roll no. 27).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H469-487" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-01-11T12:04:07-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-01-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="12">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 12.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2183-2186" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2020-04-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2184-2186" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-04-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-23T11:37:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Neal moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1920-1952, H1954-1955" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-23T11:37:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the order of the House of April 23, 2020, the House proceeded with 2 hours of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 266.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-23T15:12:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 266, the Chair put the question on the motion, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Brady demanded the yeas and nays, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="104" datetime="2020-04-23T18:13:01-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 388 - 5, 1 Present (Roll no. 104).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1920-1923" label="text of Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-04-23T18:13:02-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2020-04-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2020-04-24" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="116-139" type="public" datetime="2020-04-24">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 116-139.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="648" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hj" number="31" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="21" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="28" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1580"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-04-27T13:08:12Z" status="Public Law">Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act

This bill responds to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) outbreak by providing additional funding for small business loans, health care providers, and COVID-19 testing.

 DIVISION A--SMALL BUSINESS PROGRAMS

(Sec. 101) This division provides additional lending authority for certain Small Business Administration (SBA) programs in response to COVID-19.

Specifically, the division increases the authority for (1) the Paycheck Protection Program, under which the SBA may guarantee certain loans to small businesses during the COVID-19 pandemic; and (2) advances on emergency economic injury disaster loans made in response to COVID-19. The division also expands eligibility for such disaster loans and advances to include agricultural enterprises.

Additionally, the division requires the SBA to guarantee no less than a specified amount of paycheck protection loans made by certain insured depository institutions, community financial institutions, and credit unions.

(Sec. 102) The amounts provided under this division are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO) and the Senate PAYGO rule.

DIVISION B--ADDITIONAL EMERGENCY APPROPRIATIONS FOR CORONAVIRUS RESPONSE

Additional Emergency Appropriations for Coronavirus Response

This division provides FY2020 supplemental appropriations for the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) and the SBA in response to COVID-19.

The supplemental appropriations are designated as emergency spending, which is exempt from discretionary spending limits.

TITLE I--DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES

This title provides $100 billion in FY2020 supplemental appropriations to HHS for the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund, including

 $75 billion to reimburse health care providers for health care related expenses or lost revenues that are attributable to the coronavirus outbreak; and $25 billion for expenses to research, develop, validate, manufacture, purchase, administer, and expand capacity for COVID-19 tests to effectively monitor and suppress COVID-19. The title allocates specified portions of the $25 billion for COVID-19 testing to

 states, localities, territories, and tribes; the Centers for Diseases Control and Prevention; the National Institutes of Health; the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority; the Food and Drug Administration; community health centers; rural health clinics; and testing for the uninsured. The title also establishes several reporting requirements for HHS, including requirements to submit to Congress details regarding COVID-19 cases and a strategic testing plan

(Sec. 101) This section specifies that certain authorities, conditions, and requirements included in the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act apply to the funds provided by this division to HHS.

(Sec. 102) This section sets forth authorities and restrictions that apply to transferring funds provided by this title.

(Sec. 103) This section requires specified funds provided by this title for the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund to be transferred to the HHS Office of Inspector General for oversight of activities supported with funds appropriated to HHS to respond to the COVID-19 outbreak.

TITLE II--INDEPENDENT AGENCIES

This title provides FY2020 supplemental appropriations to the SBA, including

 $2.1 billion for salaries and expenses to administer programs related to COVID-19, $50 billion for the Economic Injury Disaster Loan (EIDL) program, and $10 billion for Emergency EIDL grants. TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS--THIS ACT

(Sec. 301) This section specifies that the funds provided by this division are in addition to funds otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.

(Sec. 302) Funds provided by this division may not remain available beyond the current fiscal year, unless this division provides otherwise.

(Sec. 303) Unless otherwise specified by this division, the funds provided by this division are subject to the authorities and conditions that apply to the applicable appropriations account for FY2020.

(Sec. 304) This section specifies that certain funds provided or transferred by this division may only be used to prevent, prepare for, and respond to the coronavirus outbreak.

(Sec. 305) For the purposes of this division, the term coronavirus means SARS-CoV-2 or another coronavirus with pandemic potential.

(Sec. 306) This section provides that amounts designated by this division as emergency requirements are only available (or rescinded, if applicable) if the President subsequently designates the amounts and transmits the designations to Congress.

(Sec. 307) This section specifies that the emergency funds that are transferred pursuant to this division retain the emergency designation.

(Sec. 308) This section exempts the budgetary effects of this division from the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO), (2) the Senate PAYGO rule, and (3) certain budget scorekeeping rules.</summary>
</bill>
