<bill session="117" type="s" number="857" updated="2023-04-03T18:15:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PLUM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to require the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to establish and maintain a public directory of the individuals occupying Government policy and supporting positions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Periodically Listing Updates to Management Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLUM Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2021-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2043" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3650" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Books and print media"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-03T20:39:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Periodically Listing Updates to Management Act or the PLUM Act 

This bill replaces the congressional publication entitled United States Government Policy and Supporting Positions, commonly known as the PLUM Book, with an online public directory.

The PLUM Book contains personnel information for federal civil service leadership and support positions in the legislative and executive branches that may be subject to noncompetitive appointment, including heads of agencies and policy executives. The book is used to identify presidentially appointed positions and is published every four years (after each presidential election) by certain congressional committees.

The bill requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to publish the information contained in the PLUM Book on a public website in a format that is easily searchable and that otherwise meets certain data standards. Agencies must upload updated information to the website on a monthly basis; OPM must verify the accuracy of the information twice a year in coordination with the White House Office of Presidential Personnel.

The bill terminates publication of the PLUM Book in its current form on January 1, 2024.</summary>
</bill>
