<bill session="118" type="h" number="3703" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEALING Response Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEALING Response Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Evaluate Appropriate Logistical Infrastructure for National Government Response Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct and complete a review examining the efforts of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that the United States is prepared to rapidly produce certain medical countermeasures in the event of a public health emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2023-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4421" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-30T20:43:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Evaluate Appropriate Logistical Infrastructure for National Government Response Act of 2023 or the HEALING Response Act of 2023

This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to review efforts undertaken by the Department of Health and Human Services to ensure that the United States has the capacity to rapidly produce medical countermeasures. (Medical countermeasures are certain medical products that may be used to diagnose, prevent, or treat conditions associated with chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear threats or emerging infectious diseases during public health emergencies.)

The review must address, among other topics, efforts to transition to new initiatives for facilitating the development and manufacturing of countermeasures (e.g., transitioning from the Centers for Innovation and Advanced Drug Manufacturing program to Industrial Base Expansion Connect).</summary>
</bill>
