<bill session="118" type="s" number="5331" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:40Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Humanitarian Tech Corps Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Humanitarian Tech Corps Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a National Science Foundation scholarship-for-service Humanitarian Tech Corps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-09T15:53:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Humanitarian Tech Corps Act

This bill establishes a grant program for colleges and universities to offer scholarships to students studying computer science, technology, and related topics, and who will seek post-graduate employment with a federal humanitarian agency or partner organization. Scholarships shall cover tuition and fees for up to four years of a degree program and provide a separate living stipend. The National Science Foundation (NSF) shall administer the grant program in coordination with the Office of Personnel Management and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID).

As a condition of the scholarship, recipients who have completed their degree program must work at USAID, another federal humanitarian agency, or an approved non-governmental partner to USAID for a period at least equal to the duration of the scholarship. If a scholarship recipient fails to complete their degree or maintain the required post-graduation employment, the recipient shall repay some or all of the scholarship funds. Following completion of the employment obligation, a recipient&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s federal appointment may be converted to a career or term appointment.</summary>
</bill>
