<bill session="111" type="s" number="607" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:44Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ski Area Recreational Opportunity Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Forest Ski Area Permit Act of 1986 to clarify the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture regarding additional recreational uses of National Forest System land that are subject to ski area permits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Ski Area Recreational Opportunity Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ski Area Recreational Opportunity Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000382" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000445" joined="2009-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2009-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3164-3165"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-223.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-304.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="590">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 590.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2476" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-30T17:19:17Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Ski Area Recreational Opportunity Enhancement Act of 2010 - Amends the National Forest Ski Area Permit Act of 1986 to require the term and acreage of permits for the operation of ski areas and associated facilities (under current law, for the operation of nordic and alpine ski areas and facilities) on National Forest System lands to be governed by provisions under the Act relating to such permits and other applicable law.

Provides for the issuance of permits for the use and occupancy of suitable lands within the National Forest System for skiing and other snow-sports and recreational uses authorized pursuant to this Act.

Requires each authorized activity and facility other than skiing and other snow-sports to: (1) encourage outdoor recreation and enjoyment of nature; (2) harmonize with the natural environment of the National Forest System land on which it is located; (3) be located within the developed portions of the ski area; and (4) be authorized in accordance with the applicable land and resource management plan and applicable laws.

Specifies the activities and facilities that may be allowed or that are not allowed under a ski area permit issued pursuant to this Act.

Prohibits the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) from authorizing any activity or facility under this Act if its authorization would result in the primary recreational purpose of the National Forest System land with a ski area permit being a purpose other than skiing and other snow-sports.

Bars the Secretary from considering the acreage necessary for authorized activities and facilities in determining the acreage encompassed by a ski area permit.

Requires the Secretary to promulgate new regulations for the implementation of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-304</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
