<bill session="119" type="h" number="993" updated="2025-03-14T16:25:57Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10T19:08:27-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-10T19:08:27-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="short">Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="display">Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to develop a plan to identify, integrate, and deploy new, innovative, disruptive, or other emerging or advanced technologies to enhance, or address capability gaps in, border security operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000602" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000603" joined="2025-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:39:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Green (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:39:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1052-1053" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:39:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 993.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T16:45:32-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T19:02:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1059-1060" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="65" datetime="2025-03-10T19:08:27-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 406 - 9 (Roll no. 65).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1052-1053" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10T19:08:28-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-14T16:25:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Emerging Innovative Border Technologies Act

This bill requires U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and the Science and Technology Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security to develop a plan to identify, integrate, and deploy emerging and innovative technologies to improve border security operations. Such technologies may incorporate artificial intelligence, machine-learning, automation, fiber-optic sensing technology, nanotechnology, optical and cognitive radar, modeling and simulation technology, hyperspectral and LIDAR sensors, and imaging, identification, and categorization systems.&#160;

The bill authorizes CBP to establish one or more Innovation Teams to research and adapt commercial technologies that may be used by CBP.

The plan must describe how the Innovation Teams have been implemented and also detail

goals and timelines for adoption of qualifying technologies,metrics and key performance parameters for determining the plan's effectiveness,which technologies used by other federal agencies CBP may also utilize,which existing authorities CBP may use to procure technologies,how CBP legacy border technology programs may be replaced,the expected privacy and security impact of security-related technology on border communities, andrecent technological advancements in specified technologies.CBP must provide the plan to Congress within 180 days of the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment.&#160;The bill also requires CBP to annually report to Congress regarding the activities of the Innovation Teams.</summary>
</bill>
