<bill session="117" type="s" number="3608" updated="2023-08-07T18:15:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Social Media NUDGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nudging Users to Drive Good Experiences on Social Media Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Media NUDGE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Trade Commission to identify content-agnostic platform interventions to reduce the harm of algorithmic amplification and social media addiction on covered platforms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-07T18:13:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nudging Users to Drive Good Experiences on Social Media Act or the Social Media NUDGE Act

This bill requires social media platforms that have more than 20 million monthly active users to implement certain content-agnostic interventions to address social media addiction and the amplification or prioritization of certain content.

First, the National Science Foundation and the National Academy of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine must conduct a study to identify reasonable content-agnostic interventions such as limits on account creation and content sharing. Second, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) must issue regulations requiring social media platforms to implement appropriate interventions identified by the study.

The bill provides for enforcement of the requirements of this bill by the FTC.</summary>
</bill>
