<bill session="118" type="s" number="473" updated="2025-11-19T02:45:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Security Drone Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">American Security Drone Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Security Drone Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for drone security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/27/2023 without amendment. With written report No. 118-87.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-08-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="190">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 190.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3974" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2226" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6143" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-28T02:37:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Security Drone Act of 2023

This bill bans the procurement or use by the federal government of unmanned aircraft systems (UAS) that are manufactured or assembled by certain foreign entities, including entities subject to influence or control by China, with exceptions.

The ban includes associated elements that enable the operator to operate the aircraft in the national airspace system.

The Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Defense, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and the Department of Justice are exempt from the restriction under specified circumstances. The bill sets forth further exemptions regarding the Department of Transportation, the Federal Aviation Administration, the National Transportation Safety Board, and the National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration.

All executive agencies must account for existing inventories of UAS manufactured or assembled by a covered foreign entity in their personal property accounting systems.

The Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall prescribe regulations or guidance to implement this bill's requirements pertaining to federal contracts.

Government-issued purchase cards may not be used to procure any UAS from a covered foreign entity.

The Office of Management and Budget shall establish a government-wide policy for the procurement of UAS, taking into account information security. The Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must report to Congress on the supply chain for certain UAS. The bill terminates five years after enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-87</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
