<bill session="118" type="h" number="5527" updated="2025-06-23T14:16:53Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-21T15:47:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-21T15:47:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act</title>
    <title type="display">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 1078 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to increase the effectiveness of the Technology Modernization Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2023-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 43 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Accountability. H. Rept. 118-397.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-02-23" calendar="Union" number="326">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 326.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21T15:35:07-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Mace moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21T15:35:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H364-3367" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21T15:35:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5527.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-05-21T15:47:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3364-3365" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21T15:47:58-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters without amendment. With written report No. 118-332.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="752">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 752.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5527" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-21T00:13:53Z" status="Reported to House">Modernizing Government Technology Reform Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2030 and revises the Technology Modernization Fund (TMF). (The TMF is a revolving fund administered by the General Services Administration to finance technology-related activities, improve information technology, and enhance cybersecurity across the federal government.)

Changes to the TMF include

requiring the Office of the Federal Chief Information Officer to annually submit to Congress (1) a list of the 10 legacy information technology (IT) systems that present the greatest security, privacy, and operational risks to the federal government; and (2) each federal agency's list of high-risk legacy IT systems;authorizing TMF funding for IT projects that improve the ability of the agency to perform its mission and deliver services to the public;additional requirements for agencies that receive funds to reimburse the TMF (for example, funds used for services or work in direct support of a project must be fully reimbursed); andrevising the criteria by which agency proposals for TMF funding are evaluated to include the (1) extent to which they address the greatest security, privacy, and operational risks; (2) impact of modernizing, retiring, or replacing legacy IT systems; and (3) ability of an agency to repay funds provided.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-332</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-397</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
