<bill session="118" type="h" number="3934" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Uyghur Human Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uyghur Human Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate residents of the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region as Priority 2 refugees of special humanitarian concern, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000825"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2023-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2023-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2024-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2023-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-16T17:00:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Uyghur Human Rights Protection Act

This bill designates certain residents of the Xinjiang region in China as prioritized refugees of special humanitarian concern and addresses other related issues.

This priority designation shall apply to individuals (and the spouses, children, and parents of such individuals) who (1) reside in or fled Xinjiang and who suffered persecution on account of their peaceful political, religious, or cultural activities or associations, or have a well-founded fear of such persecution; or (2) have been formally charged, detained, or convicted for certain peaceful actions related to Xinjiang. Such an individual may not be denied admission into the United States based primarily on an arrest or other adverse government action due to that individual's participation in protests.

The bill also waives certain immigration-related requirements for such individuals.

Furthermore, a Chinese national seeking refugee status shall be considered to have been persecuted on account of political opinion if the Chinese government revoked that individual's residency in any region of China because the individual submitted a nonfrivolous application for a U.S. immigration benefit.

Similarly, if the Chinese government revoked a Chinese national's citizenship, nationality, or residency because that individual filed for a U.S. immigration benefit, that revocation shall constitute a changed circumstance. (Among other things, a changed circumstance may allow an individual who has been rejected for asylum to apply again.)</summary>
</bill>
