<bill session="118" type="hr" number="199" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-08T14:06:18-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-08T14:06:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 140) to amend title 5, United States Code, to prohibit Federal employees from advocating for censorship of viewpoints in their official capacity, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 27) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Department of the Army, Corps of Engineers, Department of Defense and the Environmental Protection Agency relating to "Revised Definition of 'Waters of the United States'"; and providing for consideration of the bill (S. 619) to require the Director of National Intelligence to declassify information relating to the origin of COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 140) to amend title 5, United States Code, to prohibit Federal employees from advocating for censorship of viewpoints in their official capacity, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 27) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Department of the Army, Corps of Engineers, Department of Defense and the Environmental Protection Agency relating to "Revised Definition of 'Waters of the United States'"; and providing for consideration of the bill (S. 619) to require the Director of National Intelligence to declassify information relating to the origin of COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001184"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-7, by Mr. Massie.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07T20:34:44-05:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 140, under a structured rule. The resolution provides for consideration of H.J.Res. 27 and S. 619, under closed rules. General debate is limited to one hour of debate on all measures.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-03-07" calendar="House" number="5">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 5.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08T12:22:28-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1161-1173" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1161-1162" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08T12:30:37-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 199.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08T13:58:17-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question on the amendment (A001) and the resolution. Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 217 - 205 (Roll no. 134).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="135" datetime="2023-03-08T14:06:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by recorded vote: 216 - 206 (Roll No. 135).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08T14:06:19-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hj" number="27" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="140" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="619" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h99"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-04-06T19:45:36Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of

 H.R. 140 (Protecting Speech from Government Interference Act, which generally prohibits federal employees from censoring the speech of others while acting in an official capacity), H.J. Res. 27 (nullifies a rule submitted by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the Environmental Protection Agency specifying the bodies of water that fall under the scope of the Clean Water Act), and S. 619 (COVID-19 Origin Act of 2023, which requires the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to declassify all information relating to the potential links between the Wuhan Institute of Virology and the origin of COVID-19). Additionally, the resolution specifies procedures that apply if the President vetoes H.J. Res. 30 (nullifies a Department of Labor rule that permits fiduciaries of employee benefit plans to consider climate change and other environmental, social, and governance factors in investment decisions or when exercising shareholder rights).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-7</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
