<bill session="118" type="s" number="3613" updated="2025-11-19T04:32:35Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-17">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Federal Building Security Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Improving Federal Building Security Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Improving Federal Building Security Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Federal Building Security Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">Improving Federal Building Security Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Facility Security Committees to respond to security recommendations issued by the Federal Protective Service relating to facility security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2024-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-160.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-03-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="347">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 347.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-03-23">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2617-2618" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-23">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-03-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2617-2618" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-26T09:03:38-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-26T09:04:01-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09T14:56:46-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Graves (LA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09T14:57:03-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6529-6530" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09T14:57:06-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3613.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09T15:00:17-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T14:17:49-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6557-6558" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="496" datetime="2024-12-10T14:24:51-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 6 (Roll no. 496).</text>
      <reference ref="12/9/2024 CR H6529-6530" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T14:24:52-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-12-12">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-12-17" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-157" type="public" datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-157.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8530" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1818"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-12-23T17:44:14Z" status="Public Law">Improving Federal Building Security Act of 2024

This act requires Facility Security Committees to respond to security recommendations issued by the Federal Protective Service (FPS) regarding facility security.

A Facility Security Committee is a committee that (1) consists of representatives of all federal tenants in a specific nonmilitary facility, the security organization for the facility, and the owning or leasing federal tenant; and (2) is responsible for addressing facility-specific security issues and approving the implementation of security measures and practices in the facility.

Not later than 90 days after the FPS issues a security recommendation to a Facility Security Committee, that committee must respond to the Department of Homeland Security (1) indicating if the committee intends to adopt or reject the recommendation; (2) describing the financial implications of adopting or rejecting the recommendation, including if the benefits outweigh the costs; and (3) providing DHS with a justification, if it intends to reject the recommendation, for accepting the risk posed by that rejection.

DHS must (1) develop a procedure to monitor the recommendations and responses and take reasonable action to ensure Facility Security Committee response; and (2) report to Congress 270 days after this act's enactment and annually thereafter regarding such recommendations, responses, justifications for rejected recommendations, and risk mitigation efforts.

The provisions of this act only apply to General Services Administration (GSA) facilities under FPS protection and non-GSA facilities that pay fees to the FPS for protection. This act ceases to be effective five years after enactment.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-160</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
