<bill session="115" type="h" number="6039" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:44Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To establish a procedure for the conveyance of certain Federal property around the Jamestown Reservoir in the State of North Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a procedure for the conveyance of certain Federal property around the Jamestown Reservoir in the State of North Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-901.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-08-14" calendar="Union" number="697">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 697.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2074" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Missouri River"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-04T15:17:51Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Bureau of Reclamation to convey to the Stutsman County Park Board in Jamestown, North Dakota, all U.S. interest in recreation land and permitted cabin land at no cost. As a condition of the conveyances, the board shall agree to pay all survey and other administrative costs necessary for the preparation and completion of any patents for, and transfers of title to, the land.

The board shall manage the recreation land: (1) for recreation and public purposes consistent with the Recreation and Public Purposes Act, (2) for public access, (3) for fish and wildlife habitat, or (4) to preserve its natural character. The board shall manage the permitted cabin land for cabins or recreational residences in existence as of this bill's enactment or for any of the recreation land management purposes.

Reclamation shall convey to North Dakota all U.S. interest in the game and fish headquarters, on the condition that the headquarters continue to be used as a game and fish headquarters or for substantially similar purposes.

The bill exempts the United States from liability for damages, including flood damages, except for damages caused by an act or omission of a U.S. employee, agent, or contracts before the enactment of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-901</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
