<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1549</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-13T04:50:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-13T04:50:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2005-07-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2005-07-28T23:49:16Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-07-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-07-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001142</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Smith, Gordon H. [R-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>GORDON</firstName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative fees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fishery management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fishing boats</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licenses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marketing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oregon</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Washington State</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-07-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-09-14T15:27:44Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Cooperative Hake Improvement and Conservation Act - Establishes a program of market-based incentives for management and conservation of Pacific whiting fisheries. Provides for the issuance of Pacific groundfish trawl limited entry permits and processor permits to qualified fishermen and qualified processors, respectively. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to allocate, based on a specified formula, the allowable cooperative shares of Pacific whiting that: (1) can be harvested by each qualified fisherman who owns a Pacific groundfish trawl limited entry permit issued under the Pacific Coast Groundfish Fishery Management Plan; and (2) can be purchased by a qualified processor.</p> <p>Requires the on-shore allocation (that amount of the U.S. catch level required under a Plan to be delivered to processors located on shore in the states of California, Oregon, or Washington) to be divided so that: (1) an amount sufficient to account for the incidental commercial or recreational catch of Pacific whiting in fisheries other than the Pacific whiting fishery, but not to exceed 1% of the on-shore allocation, is available for harvest by any person eligible to harvest Pacific whiting; and (2) after subtracting such amounts, 50% of the remainder is available for harvest using fishermen's cooperative shares and 50% of the remainder is available for harvest using processors' cooperative shares.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to collect fees for the issuance of permits and from shareholders to recover the costs of carrying out this Act and conducting scientific research on the offshore whiting resource.</p> <p>Authorizes the Pacific Fishery Management Council to recommend to the Secretary appropriate amounts of any species of Pacific groundfish (other than Pacific whiting) that may be harvested incidentally to the harvest of Pacific whiting under this and any other Act.</p> <p>Sets forth penalties for the unlawful harvest of Pacific whiting and for any violations of the requirements of this Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Cooperative Hake Improvement and Conservation Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Cooperative Hake Improvement and Conservation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to improve the conservation and management of Pacific whiting, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Cooperative Hake Improvement and Conservation Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2005-07-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s1549is/xml/BILLS-109s1549is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2005-07-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
