<bill session="111" type="h" number="4857" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 5, United States Code, to allow amounts to be transferred from a qualified tuition program to the Thrift Savings Plan for the benefit of any individual who is eligible to participate in such Plan by virtue of being a member of the uniformed services or of the Ready Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to allow amounts to be transferred from a qualified tuition program to the Thrift Savings Plan for the benefit of any individual who is eligible to participate in such Plan by virtue of being a member of the uniformed services or of the Ready Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO25" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-28T19:41:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Allows a person to transfer to the Thrift Savings Fund account of any qualified member contributions previously made by such person under a qualified tuition program for which such member is the designated beneficiary.

Defines "qualified member" to mean any member of the uniformed services serving on active duty or any member of the Ready Reserve in any pay status who: (1) is eligible to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan; and (2) provides any information necessary to identify or establish such member's account and to effect such transfer. Permits such a transfer for the benefit of a qualified member to be made irrespective of whether such member has otherwise elected to participate.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude any such qualified tuition program distribution to a Thrift Savings Fund from the distributee's gross income.</summary>
</bill>
