<bill session="118" type="s" number="555" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Livestock Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Livestock Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve disaster assistance programs of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S533-535" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5691" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-17T15:45:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Livestock Disaster Assistance Improvement Act of 2023

This bill modifies access to Department of Agriculture disaster assistance programs and requires increased interagency cooperation in drought-related activities.

The bill specifies that state and federal grazing permit holders are eligible for the Emergency Conservation Program and the Emergency Forest Restoration Program. Further, emergency measures eligible for payments include new permanent measures, such as permanent water wells and pipelines. The bill also waives the 30-day comment period required for applications under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for emergency measures carried out during a drought emergency.

Modifications to the Livestock Forage Disaster Program allow for one monthly payment when a county has four consecutive weeks of a D2 rating (severe drought) and two payments for eight consecutive weeks of D2. Currently, one payment is available for eight consecutive weeks of D2.

 The bill expands coverage for honey bee producers under the Emergency Assistance for Livestock, Honey Bees, and Farm-Raised Fish Program (ELAP) for losses caused by adverse weather or drought, such as transportation costs and reduced honey crops. Further, the bill requires the ELAP payment rate for honey bee producers to incorporate additional factors, such as per-hive and per-colony rates of loss.

The USDA must establish an interagency working group to improve the consistency and accuracy of U.S. Drought Monitor data.

 Finally, the Farm Service Agency and the Forest Service must enter into a memorandum of understanding to better align their drought response activities.</summary>
</bill>
