<bill session="119" type="h" number="3826" updated="2025-11-18T18:04:57Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Access to Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Access to Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to diabetes outpatient self-management training services, to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test the provision of virtual diabetes outpatient self-management training services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2025-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2025-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2025-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2025-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1925" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T15:50:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Access to Diabetes Self-Management Training Act of 2025

This bill expands Medicare coverage of diabetes outpatient self-management training.

Specifically, the bill specifies that in addition to physicians, other health care practitioners may also provide such services. It also specifies that coverage includes an initial 10 hours of training until used, as well as an additional 2 hours of training per year. The bill also prohibits the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services from limiting training that is deemed medically necessary.&#160;

Additionally, the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation must test a model in which such training is provided virtually and evaluate any effects on costs, services, and health outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
