<bill session="118" type="h" number="2633" updated="2025-11-18T21:51:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Organization Classification Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Organization Classification Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a report on the designation of MS-13, Queen Nation, Sinaloa, Cartel Jalisco Nueva Generaci&#195;&#179;n, and Beltr&#195;&#161;n Leyva Organization as foreign terrorist organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001222"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1564" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-27T23:30:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Terrorist Organization Classification Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of State to designate five specified drug cartels as foreign terrorist organizations. (Among other things, such a designation allows the Department of the Treasury to require financial institutions to block transactions involving the organization.)

The five specified cartels in the bill are MS-13, Queen Nation, Sinaloa, Cartel Jalisco Nueva Generacion, and Beltran Leyva Organization.

 The bill also requires the State Department to submit a detailed report on those five cartels and any other cartels it may identify. Based on this report, the State Department must designate as a foreign terrorist organization any such identified cartel (or faction thereof) that meets certain criteria for designation as a foreign terrorist organization.

The bill specifies that it may not be construed to expand eligibility for asylum.</summary>
</bill>
