<bill session="117" type="s" number="3876" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:30Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Special Measures to Fight Modern Threats Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Measures to Fight Modern Threats Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to place prohibitions or conditions on certain transmittals of funds in connection with jurisdictions, financial institutions, international transactions, or types of accounts of primary money laundering concern.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7128" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-01T19:21:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Special Measures to Fight Modern Threats Act 

This bill expands the special measures available to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) to combat money laundering regarding

 a jurisdiction outside of the United States; a financial institution operating outside of the United States; a class of transaction within, or involving, a jurisdiction outside of the United States; or one or more types of accounts. Specifically, FinCEN may prohibit or impose conditions upon the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or payable-through account by any domestic financial institution or domestic financial agency without requiring, as under current law, that such account be for or on behalf of a foreign banking institution.

Further, FinCEN may prohibit or impose conditions upon certain transmittals of funds to or from any domestic financial institution or domestic financial agency if such transmittal of funds involves any such jurisdiction, institution, class of transaction, or type of account.</summary>
</bill>
