<bill session="109" type="s" number="4096" updated="2018-02-04T01:55:45Z">
  <state datetime="2006-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Barrier Project Consolidation and Construction Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="display">Barrier Project Consolidation and Construction Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to operate and maintain as a system the Chicago sanitary and ship canal dispersal barriers to prevent the spread of aquatic invasive species into the Great Lakes, and to determine the feasibility of a dispersal barrier project at the Lake Champlain Canal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2006-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2006-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2006-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2006-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2006-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-02-06T20:00:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Barrier Project Consolidation and Construction Act of 2006 - Considers the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal Dispersal Barrier Project (Barrier I) and the project related to the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal Dispersal Barrier (Barrier II) to constitute a single project to prevent the spread of aquatic nuisance species.

Directs the Secretary of the Army, through the Chief of Engineers, to: (1) upgrade and make permanent Barrier I; (2) construct Barrier II; (3) operate and maintain Barriers I and II as a system; (4) study options and technologies for reducing the impacts of hazards that may reduce the Barriers' efficacy; and (5) provide each state with a credit equal to the amount of funds contributed by the state toward Barrier II.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) study options and technologies to prevent the spread of aquatic nuisance species between the Great Lakes and Mississippi River Basins through the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal and other aquatic pathways; and (2) determine the the feasibility of, and construct and maintain if found feasible, a dispersal barrier project at the Lake Champlain Canal.</summary>
</bill>
