<bill session="110" type="h" number="6365" updated="2021-06-07T20:04:44Z">
  <state datetime="2008-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Special Needs Plans Extension and Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Special Needs Plans Extension and Amendments Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act with respect to Medicare special needs plans and the alignment of Medicare and Medicaid for dually eligible individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000033" joined="2008-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2008-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-09-19T21:09:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Special Needs Plans Extension and Amendments Act of 2008 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to extend the authority to restrict enrollment for specialized Medicare Advantage (MA) plans for special needs individuals.

Redefines &#147;specialized MA plan for special needs individuals&#148; to require targeted enrollment of high-risk groups.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into agreements with states to coordinate the financing of specialized MA plans for special needs individuals for enrollees entitled to medical assistance under state Medicaid plans.

Establishes additional requirements for dual special needs plans (SNPs) as well as for severe or disabling chronic condition SNPs.





Directs the Secretary to evaluate for Congress the adequacy of the MA risk adjustment system for high-risk, high cost beneficiaries.

Authorizes the Secretary to modify rules, policies, and procedures under SSA titles XVIII and XIX (Medicaid) to provide for alignment of Medicare and Medicaid requirements for dual eligibles, particularly in the oversight of SNPs serving such dual eligibles.

Directs the Secretary to etablish or designate an Office on Medicare/Medicaid Integration to align Medicare and Medicaid policies and procedures and develop tools to support state integration efforts for dual eligible access to Medicare and Medicaid benefits and services.</summary>
</bill>
