<bill session="117" type="s" number="3268" updated="2022-12-30T02:48:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Memphis' Supply Chain Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Memphis' Supply Chain Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to issue a request for proposals for a private-sector entity to develop an operating model for an interoperable gray chassis pool at the rail ramps around Memphis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6073" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6081" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-23T20:07:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Memphis' Supply Chain Act

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to undertake a process, in coordination with the Federal Maritime Commission, to create a voluntary chassis pool operated by a private sector contractor at the rail ramps near Memphis, TN. (Chassis are special trailers used to transport shipping containers.)

DOT must solicit proposals from contractors to develop a model for operating such a pool. The proposals must address, among other matters, a sustainable fee structure, estimates of the number of chassis needed in the pool, and real property necessary to operate the pool.

If any contractors submit satisfactory proposals, DOT must (1) contract with one of them to operate the pool, and (2) evaluate the effectiveness of the pool within one year of its implementation. In the event there are no satisfactory proposals submitted, DOT must provide Congress with alternative options to improve the availability of chassis at the rail ramps.</summary>
</bill>
