<bill session="118" type="s" number="4869" updated="2025-08-01T15:40:12Z">
  <state datetime="2024-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian Health Service Emergency Claims Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Health Service Emergency Claims Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to modify the notification requirement for emergency contract health services for certain beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2024-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-01T15:40:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian Health Service Emergency Claims Parity Act

This bill extends from 72 hours to 15 days the time period&#160;to notify the Purchased/Referred Care (PRC) program of emergency medical care received from a non-Indian Health Service (IHS) medical provider or at a non-IHS medical facility. This bill does not apply to individuals who are elderly or disabled, who continue to have a 30-day notification requirement for emergency services.

The IHS provides medical and dental services directly to American Indian and Alaska Native patients whenever possible. The PRC program pays for medical or dental care that is provided away from an IHS or tribal health care facility. The PRC program must be notified of requests for authorization of payment for health care services from a non-IHS provider.

Currently in emergency cases, the patient, an individual on behalf of the patient, or the medical care provider must, within 72 hours after the beginning of treatment for the condition or after admission to a health care facility, notify a PRC authorizing official of the need for the emergency medical care. This bill instead allows the patient, other individual, or provider to notify PRC within 15 days of the treatment or admission.</summary>
</bill>
