<bill session="118" type="s" number="535" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:51Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to streamline the oil and gas permitting process and to recognize fee ownership for certain oil and gas drilling or spacing units, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin without amendment. With written report No. 118-53.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="125">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 125.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1456" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-21T15:15:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bureau of Land Management Mineral Spacing Act

This bill expedites the permitting process for oil and gas drilling on federal land.

Specifically, the bill bans the Department of the Interior from requiring a permit to drill for an oil and gas lease under the Mineral Leasing Act for an action occurring within an oil and gas drilling or spacing unit if (1) less than 50% of the minerals within the unit are minerals owned by the federal government, and (2) the federal government does not own or lease the surface estate within the area directly impacted by the action. However, this ban does not apply to certain tribal land.

In addition, the bill requires state drilling applicants to notify Interior if their permit or plan would impact or extract federally owned oil or gas. Holders of oil or gas leases must notify Interior when they submit a state permit application to drill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-53</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
