<bill session="111" type="h" number="6326" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:30Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair and Impartial Recruitment Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide waivers and appeals to certain individuals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Impartial Recruitment Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000604"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-20T21:43:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair and Impartial Recruitment Act of 2010 - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]) to: (1) issue regulations to establish a waiver process to allow an air carrier, foreign air carrier, airport operator, or government to hire an individual who has been disqualified for employment for a position as an airport security screener or in which an individual has unescorted access to a sterile airport area because of a conviction of a specified crime; and (2) establish an appeals process for a disqualified individual that includes notice and an opportunity for a hearing before an impartial third party. Requires the Assistant Secretary to issue a waiver to an individual: (1) who, based on certain criteria, does not pose a terrorism risk; and (2) without regard to whether that individual would otherwise be disqualified by reason of a felony conviction, if the employer establishes acceptable alternate security arrangements.</summary>
</bill>
