<bill session="116" type="s" number="2084" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GREEN Streets Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generating Resilient, Environmentally Exceptional National Streets Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GREEN Streets Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to require transportation planners to consider projects and strategies to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2019-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2019-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5354" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-02T15:48:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Generating Resilient, Environmentally Exceptional National Streets Act or the GREEN Streets Act 

This bill establishes national goals to reduce carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions and improve the resilience of the transportation system.

Specifically, the bill directs

 the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish minimum standards for states to decrease greenhouse gas emissions and per capita vehicle miles traveled (VMTs) on the National Highway System; DOT to establish measures for states to assess and reduce carbon dioxide; states and metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs) to consider projects and strategies that reduce carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions and decrease per capita VMT's; states and MPOs to publish an analysis of the impact on per capita VMTs and mobile source greenhouse gas emissions for each project that adds new lanes or otherwise increases traffic capacity and costs more than $25 million; states that are out of compliance with the per capita VMT standards or carbon dioxide or greenhouse gas emission measures to dedicate federal highway funding to achieve compliance; and DOT to establish national transit access standards and performance measures for transit accessibility, transit stop distance, and transit mode share.</summary>
</bill>
