<bill session="111" type="h" number="1911" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:35Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency and Accountability in State and Local Contracting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to require funding to help award recipients defray the costs of data collection requirements initiated pursuant to such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency and Accountability in State and Local Contracting Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO24" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Government Operations and the Federal Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-11T20:49:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency and Accountability in State and Local Contracting Act - Amends the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 to: (1) require (current law authorizes) federal agencies receiving funds under the Act to adjust applicable limits on administrative expenditures for federal awards to help award recipients defray the costs of data collection requirements initiated pursuant to the Act; and (2) authorize such agencies to set aside up to 0.5% of covered funds directed to such agencies to conduct comprehensive, agency-wide oversight and administration of projects under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
