<bill session="108" type="s" number="987" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Health Care Fairness and Medicare Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for national standardized payment amounts for inpatient hospital services furnished under the medicare program and to make other rural health care improvements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Health Care Fairness and Medicare Equity Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2003-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2003-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5731-5733"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Health Care Fairness and Medicare Equity Act of 2003 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for discharges occurring in a fiscal year beginning with FY 2004, to compute a standardized amount for hospitals in rural and small urban areas that is equal to the standardized amount computed for the previous fiscal year for hospitals located in a large urban area increased by the applicable percentage increase for the fiscal year involved.Sets the wage index at 62 percent for discharges occurring in FY 2004, except that hospitals receiving lower payments as a result of such new wage index would be held harmless.Creates a wage index floor for use in determining payments for discharges occurring in FY 2004 for hospitals with a wage index under 0.85.Directs the Secretary to publish and use alternative guidelines for geographic reclassification of certain hospitals located in sparsely populated States.Establishes a floor of 1.00 for the work geographic cost-of-practice index under the physician payment system.</summary>
</bill>
