<bill session="119" type="h" number="1095" updated="2025-07-23T19:11:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Military Focus Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Military Focus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the position of the Chief Diversity Officer of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-23T19:10:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Military Focus Act

This bill eliminates the position of Chief Diversity Officer within the Department of Defense (DOD), as well as the position of Senior Advisor for Diversity and Inclusion within the military departments. Additionally, the bill prohibits the use of federal funds to establish similar positions to that of Chief Diversity Officer or Senior Advisor for Diversity and Inclusion within DOD.

On January 20, 2025, President Trump signed an executive order titled&#160;Ending Radical and Wasteful Government DEI Programs and Preferencing, which&#160;directed the termination of all federal diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility programs, offices, and positions, including Chief Diversity Officer positions. On January 27, 2025, President Trump signed an executive order titled&#160;Restoring America's Fighting Force, which specifically directed the abolishment of every diversity, equity and inclusion office within DOD and the Department of Homeland Security with regard to the Coast Guard.</summary>
</bill>
