<bill session="118" type="s" number="2281" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lummis-Gillibrand Responsible Financial Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lummis-Gillibrand Responsible Financial Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for consumer protection and responsible financial innovation, to bring crypto assets within the regulatory perimeter, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee)"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1357" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-16T20:17:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lummis-Gillibrand Responsible Financial Innovation Act 

This bill provides for the regulation of crypto assets.

The bill outlines agency jurisdictions over types of crypto assets and ancillary assets. For example, the bill provides that the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) has jurisdiction over crypto assets that do not provide their holders with financial interest in a business entity.

The bill also establishes consumer protections, including by requiring (1) a crypto asset intermediary to provide proof of possession or control of all its crypto assets, and (2) an annual verification of assets by an independent public accountant. The bill also provides for the establishment of customer protection and market integrity authorities upon approval by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the CFTC.

In addition, the bill imposes criminal penalties for violations of certain financial recordkeeping requirements involving crypto asset transactions. Further, the Department of the Treasury, the SEC, and the CFTC must assess the compliance of the entities they regulate with anti-money laundering programs and countering the financing of terrorism requirements.

Under the bill, any stablecoin must be issued by depository institutions. Institutions must hold 100% of the value of all outstanding stablecoins in reserves and allow stablecoins to be redeemed at par.

The bill also provides for the tax treatment of crypto assets, including an exemption from income tax for purchases using digital assets that result in a gain or loss of $200 or less.</summary>
</bill>
