<bill session="111" type="s" number="3431" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:58Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Cozy Relationships with Big Oil Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the administration of the Minerals Management Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Cozy Relationships with Big Oil Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2010-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-653, pt. 5.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-01T21:37:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Cozy Relationships with Big Oil Act of 2010 - Prohibits an employee of the Minerals Management Service (Service) of the Department of the Interior, or a successor agency, from: (1) knowingly accepting a gift from an entity engaged in the business of mineral mining; (2) owning stock or any other interest in an entity engaged in the business of mineral mining during such employee's employment by the Service; (3) being employed (outside employment) by an entity engaged in the business of mineral mining during such employee's employment in the Service; or (4) working for an entity engaged in the business of mineral mining during the two-year period beginning on the date of termination of employment by the Service.

Requires financial disclosure by employees of the Service in positions equivalent to GS-13 or higher.

Prescribes criminal penalties for violations of these prohibitions.



Amends federal criminal law to subject to fine or imprisonment any officer, employee, or agent of the Service who knowingly and willfully makes a materially false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation in the conduct of activities relating to oil and gas regulation.</summary>
</bill>
