<bill session="117" type="h" number="9024" updated="2023-08-22T20:00:33Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DRILL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Directing Responsibility to Interior for Leases and Licenses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRILL Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to submit a report and maintain publicly available data on expressions of interests, applications for permits to drill, and offshore geological and geophysical survey licenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2022-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7298" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9087" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-22T19:51:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Directing Responsibility to Interior for Leases and Licenses Act or the DRILL Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior to issue permits under the Mineral Leasing Act for all pending applications to drill for oil and gas on public land if the applications are complete and meet the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and other applicable law.

In addition, the bill creates a variety of requirements for Interior to report on and publish data concerning leases and permits to develop oil, gas, and renewable energy.</summary>
</bill>
