<bill session="117" type="h" number="3917" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Making Aid for Local Disasters Equal Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enure that a declaration for a major disaster or emergency is made on a timely basis, rural areas receive assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Aid for Local Disasters Equal Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MALDEN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2021-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2021-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2021-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-05T14:20:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Making Aid for Local Disasters Equal Now Act or the MALDEN Act

This bill modifies requirements pertaining to the time frame for approval of major disaster or emergency declarations and the ability to make federal resources available to rural communities.

Specifically, a major disaster or emergency declaration must be made not later than 30 days after a request by a governor or the chief executive of an affected Indian tribal government. Failure to meet the 30-day requirement shall result in an automatic approval of the request.

Additionally, if a disaster or emergency occurs in a rural area, regardless of whether a declaration has been made, the Small State and Rural Advocate within the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall work in coordination with local agencies to provide guidance on developing a recovery team, including resources to help prevent flooding, mudslides, rockslides or any other natural disaster that could result after a wildfire and identifying available resources for both short-term and long-term recovery.

If a request for individual assistance for residents in a rural area is made but denied, the Small State and Rural Advocate shall work in coordination with local agencies to make disaster case workers available to such residents.</summary>
</bill>
