<bill session="108" type="h" number="4942" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Material Support to Terrorism Prohibition Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain forms of material support for terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Material Support to Terrorism Prohibition Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000545"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-22T20:19:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Material Support to Terrorism Prohibition Enhancement Act of 2004 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit knowingly receiving military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization. Grants extraterritorial jurisdiction over such offense if specified conditions apply, such as if: (1) the offender is a U.S. national; (2) an offender is a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States; (3) the offense occurs within the United States; (4) the offense occurs in or affects interstate or foreign commerce; or (5) an offender aids or abets or conspires in such offense with any person over whom jurisdiction exists.

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to prohibit granting visas to or admitting, and provides for the deportation of, aliens who have received such training.

Expands the scope of the prohibition against: (1) providing material support to terrorists to include providing resources or concealing or disguising material support or resources, knowing or intending that they will be used for an act of terrorism, where the offense occurs in or affects interstate or foreign commerce); and (2) financing terrorism to cover proceeds of funds used to knowingly disguise any material support to terrorists and knowing that funds are to be provided or collected for such proscribed purposes.</summary>
</bill>
