<bill session="118" type="h" number="6006" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a vehicle summer meal delivery pilot program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a vehicle summer meal delivery pilot program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001094" joined="2023-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-24T19:10:56Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Summer Food Service Program (SFSP) to establish a vehicle summer meal delivery pilot program. (The SFSP is a federally funded, state-administered program that reimburses providers that serve no-cost, healthy meals and snacks to children and teens at summer sites in low-income communities.)

 The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must award one-year grants of up to $100,000 for service institutions (e.g., school food authorities) to purchase or retrofit vehicles to facilitate the distribution of noncongregate meals as part of the SFSP. USDA must give priority to service institutions with high rates of students who are eligible for free or reduced-price lunches and that serve a high proportion of students from socially disadvantaged backgrounds. USDA must also ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that service institutions receiving grants are located in diverse geographic areas.</summary>
</bill>
