<bill session="116" type="h" number="8470" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:36Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Correctional Facilities COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Response Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Correctional Facilities COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Response Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish procedures related to the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in correctional facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2020-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4811" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-16T14:51:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Correctional Facilities COVID-19 Response Act

This bill requires federal correctional facilities to provide COVID-19 tests at no cost to inmates and employees and otherwise addresses the management of COVID-19 in these facilities.

Correctional facilities operated by the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) and private facilities that house inmates under contract with federal entities must provide initial tests within 15 days of the enactment of this bill and also establish a weekly testing program that will remain in effect through the end of the COVID-19 pandemic. Inmates may opt out of this testing. In addition, facilities must provide appropriate follow-up services for those who test positive for, or display symptoms of, COVID-19, including necessary medical care for inmates and access to paid leave for employees.

Furthermore, each facility must report specified COVID-19 data to the Department of Justice (DOJ), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), and the public health authority of the state in which the facility is located. Specifically, facilities must report COVID-19 outbreaks to the CDC, and the CDC must deploy staff to facilities with outbreaks to prevent further spread of the disease.

The bill also applies certain federal privacy standards for health records to, and restricts the use of, any data collected as a result of the testing and reporting activities.

Additionally, the BOP, in consultation with the CDC and other experts, must update certain guidelines on managing COVID-19, and DOJ must also report to Congress on COVID-19 prevention, mitigation, and control activities at federal correctional facilities.</summary>
</bill>
