<bill session="115" type="h" number="5229" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:18Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tuition Fairness for Citizens Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 505 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to clarify the prohibition on postsecondary education benefits for certain aliens, to grant a private right of action to persons injured by a violation of such prohibition, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tuition Fairness for Citizens Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2018-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2018-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2018-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2018-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2018-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Border Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-30T21:39:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Tuition Fairness for Citizens Act

This bill amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to make aliens who are not lawfully present in the United States ineligible for postsecondary education benefits (e.g., in-state tuition)&#160;unless all U.S. citizens and nationals are eligible for the same benefit. Under current law, states are not permitted to give postsecondary education benefits to&#160;such aliens on the basis of residency, but are allowed to give such benefits based on other criteria. This bill eliminates the option to give such benefits based on any criteria if they are not available to all U.S. citizens and nationals.

In addition, the bill grants a private right of action to a person who is aggrieved by a violation of this requirement.</summary>
</bill>
