<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1520" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:46Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the situation in the Republic of Kyrgyzstan.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the situation in the Republic of Kyrgyzstan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2010-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-08-05T12:57:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Commends: (1) the peaceful conduct of the June 2010 referendum and hopes that the new constitutional order will promote greater democracy in the Republic of Kyrgyzstan; and (2) the government of Uzbekistan for cooperating with the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, the International Committee of the Red Cross, the United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), and other international nongovernmental organizations in meeting the needs of ethnic Uzbek refugees who fled Kyrgyzstan.

Regrets the loss of life in the recent ethnic uprisings and expresses concern for the welfare of those displaced.

Encourages the development of ties between members of the House of Representatives and the Senate with members of the Parliament of Kyrgyzstan.

Calls upon the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe to take an active role in assisting the government of Kyrgyzstan.

Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives concerning steps to be taken by the government of Kyrgyzstan to restore order, provide for transparent parliamentary elections, and address political, social, ethnic, and economic tensions.</summary>
</bill>
