<bill session="116" type="s" number="3014" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:00Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing the Spread of Nuclear Weapons Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing the Spread of Nuclear Weapons Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require congressional approval for civilian nuclear cooperation under certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5387" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-12T18:11:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing the Spread of Nuclear Weapons Act of 2019

This bill requires the President to obtain congressional approval before entering into or renewing a nuclear cooperation agreement with a foreign country in certain cases.

Before entering into or renewing such an agreement, the President shall report to Congress on (1) any credible evidence that the foreign country intends to pursue a nuclear program that is not inherently peaceful; and (2) any instance where the country has violated international standards related to weapons of mass destruction, including certain treaties relating to nuclear and chemical weapons.

If the report contains any such credible evidence or instances, the President may not enter into or renew the treaty unless (1) the President submits a proposed agreement with the foreign country that meets specified statutory requirements related to nuclear cooperation agreements, and (2) Congress passes a joint resolution approving the agreement. These provisions requiring a proposed agreement and congressional approval do not apply if the foreign country is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and a nuclear weapon state.</summary>
</bill>
