<bill session="116" type="h" number="1891" updated="2022-11-01T18:17:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">White Sands National Park Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the White Sands National Park in the State of New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">White Sands National Park Establishment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000484"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2019-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="871" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-14T16:08:41Z" status="Introduced in House">White Sands National Park Establishment Act

This bill establishes the White Sands National Park in New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System in order to protect, preserve, and restore the park's resources and recreational values and to enhance visitor experiences.

The bill abolishes the White Sands National Monument and incorporates the lands and interests that comprise the monument in and as a part of the park.

The Department of the Interior shall not nominate the park for inclusion on the World Heritage List of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) unless each county in which the park is located concurs in the nomination. Before submitting such a nomination, Interior must notify the Department of the Army of its intention to nominate the park for inclusion on the list.

Interior must complete an official boundary survey of the park.

The bill modifies the boundaries of the White Sands Missile Range in New Mexico and the Public Land Order 833 (relating to the withdrawal of certain public lands in New Mexico for use by the Army for military purposes and the revoking of certain executive orders and public land orders) to exclude the land transferred to Interior and to include the land transferred to the Army. The Army shall administer the land transferred to it as a part of the missile range.</summary>
</bill>
