<bill session="116" type="h" number="5140" updated="2022-10-28T02:00:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Satellite Television Community Protection and Promotion Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 17, United States Code, to narrow the category of households eligible to receive signals under a distant-signal satellite license, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Satellite Television Community Protection and Promotion Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Satellite Television Community Protection and Promotion Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-354.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-12-17" calendar="Union" number="282">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 282.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1865" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-29T13:36:35Z" status="Reported to House">Satellite Television Community Protection and Promotion Act of 2019

This bill permanently reauthorizes a provision that allows satellite television providers to retransmit distant television signals to unserved households under a statutory license. (A statutory license allows a satellite provider to rebroadcast the signals by paying set fees and without negotiating with the relevant copyright holders.) The bill also limits what constitutes an unserved household under this provision.

Under the bill, an unserved household is (1) a household in a local market where any of the four most widely viewed television networks nationwide is not transmitted by any network television station in that market, or (2) a recreational vehicle or commercial truck. The bill removes several categories of households that currently qualify as unserved, such as households that can receive a local broadcast signal but received satellite retransmissions on certain dates.

To take advantage of the statutory license, a satellite provider generally must provide retransmissions of local television stations in all designated market areas (DMAs). However, a provider that does not provide such retransmissions of local stations to all DMAs may obtain a temporary statutory license by (1) demonstrating that the provider has made reasonable and good faith efforts to do so, and (2) filing a notice with the Copyright Office.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-354</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
