<bill session="108" type="s" number="1462" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cumberland Island National Seashore Wilderness Boundary Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to adjust the boundary of the Cumberland Island Wilderness, to authorize tours of the Cumberland Island National Seashore, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cumberland Island National Seashore Wilderness Boundary Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000286"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001141" joined="2003-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9973-9974"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-278.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National seashores"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-02T20:47:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cumberland Island National Seashore Wilderness Boundary Act of 2003 - Designates certain land (excluding specified roadways) in the Cumberland Island Seashore as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System and names it the Cumberland Island Wilderness (the Wilderness). Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to include in the Wilderness specified land to be acquired and also certain other land once all prohibited uses on it have ceased. Directs that the Wilderness be administered by the Secretary in accordance with the applicable provisions of the Wilderness Act, with references to the Secretary of Agriculture in such Act where appropriate to be deemed references to the Secretary.

Allows: (1) persons with an existing right to utility service on Cumberland Island to retain such right in the Wilderness after the enactment of this Act; and (2) the Secretary to grant contracts, as deemed appropriate, for the provision of tours to visitors of the Cumberland Island National Seashore.</summary>
</bill>
