<bill session="118" type="s" number="3554" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FAIRR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIRR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Artificial Intelligence Risk Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to provide the Financial Stability Oversight Council with duties regarding artificial intelligence in the financial sector, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-08">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7036" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Federal Housing Finance Agency"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-16T20:55:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Financial Artificial Intelligence Risk Reduction Act or the FAIRR Act

This bill addresses the impact of artificial intelligence on financial markets.

The bill requires the Financial Stability Oversight Council to coordinate with agencies regarding threats to the financial system posed by artificial intelligence, including the use of false representations of the likeness, speech, or actions of persons to manipulate or to cause disruptions to financial markets. The council must report on its findings and make policy recommendations to Congress. After congressional review, the council must implement these recommendations.

The Securities and Exchange Commission is allowed to seek treble civil penalties for violations of federal securities exchange law that involve machine-manipulated media.

The bill establishes liability for a person who, directly or indirectly, deploys or causes to be deployed an artificial intelligence model involved in a securities law violation.

The bill also provides for the regulation and supervision of certain financial organizations and service providers. For example, if a credit union that is subject to examination by the Board of Directors of the National Credit Union Administration delegates the performance of certain activities and services, this delegation must be disclosed and is subject to regulation and examination by the board.</summary>
</bill>
