<bill session="118" type="s" number="2152" updated="2025-11-19T04:23:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reproductive Health Travel Fund Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reproductive Health Travel Fund Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize grants to eligible entities to pay for travel-related expenses and logistical support for individuals with respect to accessing abortion services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4268" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-19T20:20:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reproductive Health Travel Fund Act of 2023

This bill authorizes a grant program to provide assistance with travel-related expenses for those seeking an abortion.

Specifically, the Department of Treasury may award grants to nonprofit or community-based organizations to provide assistance to those seeking abortions with round-trip travel, lodging, meals, and other travel-related expenses. Priority must be given to organizations that serve individuals who are in jurisdictions that have banned or severely restricted abortion access or who travel to another jurisdiction for an abortion, or organizations that have or plan to have programs in place that help individuals access abortion services.

In order to qualify for a grant, organizations must assist individuals seeking abortions through unbiased and medically and factually accurate programs, services, or activities. Organizations may not discourage individuals from seeking abortions. Additionally, federal entities that implement the grant program may not participate in any state, tribal, or local antiabortion proceedings (e.g., prosecutions) in connection with grant services.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
