<bill session="118" type="h" number="2453" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Immigration Parole Reform Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Parole Reform Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform immigration parole, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2023-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="505" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2640" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2324" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2824" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-31T01:01:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Immigration Parole Reform Act of 2023

This bill limits the authority of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to grant immigration parole (i.e., give official permission for an individual to enter and temporarily remain in the United States).

Specifically, the bill (1) limits what qualifies as an urgent humanitarian reason or a significant public benefit that would justify granting parole, and (2) prohibits granting parole based on an individual's membership in a defined class of individuals.

An urgent humanitarian reason is limited to specified medical emergencies and a significant public benefit is limited to assisting the U.S. government in a law enforcement matter.

Individuals granted parole on the basis of an urgent humanitarian reason or a significant public benefit are not permitted to work while in the United States.

Additionally, the bill provides statutory authority for DHS to grant parole to (1) certain Cuban nationals, (2) certain family members of active-duty Armed Forces members, and (3) certain removed individuals for the purpose of attending their immigration hearing.</summary>
</bill>
