<bill session="116" type="s" number="4026" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:11Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Vital American Citizen Services Overseas (EVACS) Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Vital American Citizen Services Overseas (EVACS) Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expedite and expand provision of American Citizen Services worldwide during the COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2020-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6595" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-07T14:47:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expanding Vital American Citizen Services Overseas (EVACS) Act of 2020

This bill establishes requirements for the Department of State to expand American Citizen Services at U.S. embassies, consulates, and missions worldwide during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic.

American Citizen Services are the range of services provided by the State Department's Bureau of Consular Affairs, such as emergency passports, consular reports of birth abroad, emergency financial assistance, and repatriation.

The State Department must petition the government of any country that closes borders and airspace or establishes travel restrictions due to COVID-19 to make provisions with the appropriate U.S. consular service in that country to ensure U.S. citizens, nationals, lawful permanent residents, or the immediate family members of such persons can travel to U.S. government evacuation points or access commercial travel. The State Department must also waive or reimburse certain repatriation travel expenses incurred due to COVID-19.

Further, the State Department must

 provide U.S. embassies, consulates, and other diplomatic missions with explicit guidance to protect American lives abroad during the COVID-19 pandemic, increase certain consular affairs staffing, develop a comprehensive plan for COVID-19 infection risk mitigation procedures for all persons under chief of mission authority at overseas posts, regularly report on the Bureau of Consular Affairs' response to the COVID-19 pandemic, and prioritize regular and continued hiring of Foreign Service officers and specialists.</summary>
</bill>
