<bill session="108" type="s" number="1911" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:29Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the provisions of title III of the Trade Act of 1974 relating to violations of the TRIPS Agreement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the provisions of title III of the Trade Act of 1974 relating to violations of the TRIPS Agreement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2003-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trademark agreements"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-14T15:13:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to make specified determinations about U.S. rights within 30 days after a dispute settlement procedure is concluded if the USTR considers that U.S. rights are involved under the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights (TRIPS Agreement) or the GATT 1994 relating to products subject to intellectual property protection.

Amends the Andean Trade Preference Act (ATPA) and the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act (CBERA) to require the USTR to ensure a timely review and disposition of requests received from an interested party that the President reconsider the status of a country as a beneficiary country under such Acts.

Amends the Trade Act of 1974, CBERA, and ATPA to revise the requirement that the President, when making a determination to designate a country as a beneficiary developing country entitled to certain trade benefits, to take into account, among other things, the extent to which such country is providing adequate and effective protection of intellectual property rights. Requires the President to make such determination notwithstanding the fact that the country may be in compliance with TRIPS (thus making TRIPS compliance necessary but not sufficient evidence of adequate and effective protection of intellectual property rights).</summary>
</bill>
