<bill session="117" type="h" number="3520" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring National Constitutional Rights for Your Private Telecommunications Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To preempt State data security vulnerability mandates and decryption requirements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ENCRYPT Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring National Constitutional Rights for Your Private Telecommunications Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2021-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-22T16:46:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring National Constitutional Rights for Your Private Telecommunications Act of 2021 or the ENCRYPT Act of 2021

This bill prohibits a state from requiring a manufacturer, developer, seller, or provider of a technology product or service to (1) alter the security functions of its product or service to allow a government agency to conduct a physical search or user surveillance, or (2) use its product or service to decrypt encrypted information.

A technology product or service includes a commercial computer product, electronic device, or online service that is publicly available.

Additionally, it bars a state from prohibiting the manufacture, sale or lease, or provision of a technology product or service because it uses encryption or similar security functions.</summary>
</bill>
