<bill session="118" type="h" number="4062" updated="2025-05-27T14:11:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Chief Risk Officer Enforcement and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chief Risk Officer Enforcement and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to require certain large banking institutions to have a Chief Risk Officer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001117"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2023-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-07T15:02:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Chief Risk Officer Enforcement and Accountability Act 

This bill provides statutory authority for requiring large bank holding companies to appoint a chief risk officer and expands which companies must establish a risk committee and appoint a chief risk officer. Currently, only large bank holding companies that are public companies are required to establish risk committees and, by regulation, have chief risk officers. Under the bill, risk committees and chief risk officers are also required for (1) privately-held large bank holding companies, and (2) large banks that do not have a holding company.

Further, the Federal Reserve Board is allowed to require smaller bank holding companies to establish a risk committee and appoint a chief risk officer. Currently, the board is allowed to require smaller bank companies that are public companies establish risk committees.

Chief risk officers are responsible for the establishment of risk limits, monitoring compliance, and reporting any deficiencies to the risk committee.</summary>
</bill>
