<bill session="117" type="s" number="1759" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:06Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MicroCap Small Business Investing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a MicroCap small business investment company designation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MicroCap Small Business Investing Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2021-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2021-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3842" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-21T17:03:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">MicroCap Small Business Investing Act of 2021

This bill authorizes the Small Business Administration (SBA) to issue up to ten Small Business Investment Company (SBIC) licenses each year to certain applicants. An SBIC is a privately owned company, licensed and regulated by the SBA, which invests in small businesses through debt and equity.

A license issued under the bill must be awarded to an applicant

 that would otherwise be issued a license except that the management of the applicant does not satisfy certain qualification requirements such as investment experience; where the fund managers have a documented record of successful business experience, a record of business management success, or knowledge in the particular industry or business in which the investment strategy is being pursued; and that will make at least 25% of its investments in specified areas and businesses (e.g., low-income communities, businesses owned or controlled by individuals in underserved communities, and rural areas). The SBA must prioritize applicants that are located in states with fewer licenses and establish a streamlined application process for those licenses.</summary>
</bill>
