<bill session="118" type="s" number="1970" updated="2025-11-19T03:45:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Informed Student Borrowing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Informed Student Borrowing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify requirements relating to financial aid disclosures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2023-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1972" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4616" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-12T18:59:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Informed Student Borrowing Act of 2023

This bill revises and expands loan counseling for borrowers of federal student loans.

Specifically, the bill requires an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs to provide loan counseling to a student borrower of a federal student loan at the first disbursement of a loan in each award year. Currently, an IHE must provide one-time entrance counseling to a student who is a first-time federal student loan borrower.

The bill also revises and expands required elements of loan counseling. For example, required elements of loan counseling must include (1) an explanation that the borrower must affirmatively determine and manually enter the federal loan amount that the borrower will borrow for each award year, and (2) sample monthly repayment amounts based on the standard repayment plan and the most commonly used income-driven repayment plan.

Each IHE must ensure that student borrowers and parent borrowers manually enter the exact dollar amount of the loan that they wish to borrow for the year.

If an IHE provides a student or prospective student with a financial aid award notification that includes funds under the Federal Work-Study Program, then the IHE must ensure that the notification includes an explanation that these funds are not directly awarded to the student or IHE and that such amounts must be earned through the student's completion of work over time.</summary>
</bill>
