<bill session="118" type="s" number="130" updated="2025-11-19T02:54:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Internet Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Internet Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to reauthorize and improve the ReConnect loan and grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2023-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S148-150" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3216" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-28T14:23:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Internet Improvement Act of 2023

This bill merges the pilot ReConnect Loan and Grant Program with existing loans and grants provided by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to facilitate broadband access to rural areas that lack sufficient access to broadband. Unobligated amounts available for the pilot program must be transferred and made available, without further appropriations, to this merged program.

The bill specifies eligibility criteria and other requirements that apply to the merged program. For example, the bill limits funds from the merged program to projects in areas where at least 90% of the households lack sufficient access to broadband services, which is currently required under the pilot program.

Other changes in the bill address procedures for contesting the accuracy of broadband maps that are used to identify eligible areas. It also requires efforts to increase coordination concerning broadband initiatives between USDA, the Federal Communications Commission, and the National Telecommunications Information Administration.</summary>
</bill>
