<bill session="117" type="h" number="3047" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Moms Matter Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve postpartum care for members of the Armed Forces and dependents of such members, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Moms Matter Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000396" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2021-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2021-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000479" joined="2021-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-15T20:12:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Moms Matter Act of 2021

This bill addresses Department of Defense (DOD) policies regarding parental leave and postpartum care for service members.

The bill authorizes primary caregivers to take 12 weeks of parental leave, and up to 6 weeks of medical convalescent leave (which may not be considered in calculating the 12 weeks of parental leave), in connection with the birth of a child. Additionally, primary caregivers are authorized to take up to 12 weeks of parental leave in connection with the adoption of a child.

Under the bill, secondary caregivers are authorized to take up to 12 weeks of parental leave in connection with the birth or adoption of a child. The bill also removes the requirement that secondary caregivers must take such leave in one increment.

Among other requirements, DOD must also

 provide at least four postpartum mental health assessments and other medical care in the year after a service member (or their dependent) gives birth, ensure that a service member (or their dependent) who gives birth at a military medical treatment facility has the option to schedule a postpartum follow-up appointment concurrent with the date of the follow-up appointment for postnatal care for the newborn infant, develop a standardized policy prohibiting each military branch from requiring a service member to take a physical fitness test until one year after giving birth, and issue guidance on the development and implementation of standard protocols for the treatment of obstetric hemorrhages.</summary>
</bill>
