<bill session="109" type="h" number="5028" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:55Z">
  <state datetime="2006-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Project Bioshield Material Threats Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve and expedite the assessment and determination of chemical, biological, radiological and nuclear material threats by the Secretary of Homeland Security under the Project BioShield program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Project Bioshield Material Threats Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001152" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2006-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-18T20:40:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Project Bioshield Material Threats Act of 2006 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Homeland Security (the Secretary) to utilize existing risk assessments to assess current and emerging threats of chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear agents and determine which of such agents present a material threat against the U.S. population sufficient to affect national security. Requires the Secretary to group such assessments to facilitate assessments by the Secretary of Health and Human Services on the availability and appropriateness of specific countermeasures to address more than one such agent or address adverse health consequences that are common to exposure to different agents. Requires the Secretary to complete assessments by December 31, 2007, for those agents known to the Secretary by the date of enactment of this Act that are capable of significantly affecting national security.

Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reauthorize appropriations through FY2009 for the Secretary to carry out such terror threat assessments. Authorizes additional appropriations to enable the Secretary to meet the deadlines established under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
