<bill session="108" type="s" number="1243" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:44Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gun Trafficking Penalties Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 924, title 18, United States Code, to increase the maximum term of imprisonment for interstate firearms trafficking and to include interstate firearms trafficking in the definition of racketeering activity, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gun Trafficking Penalties Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-08-08T19:47:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gun Trafficking Penalties Enhancement Act of 2003 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to increase the maxiumum term of imprisonment for: (1) selling or otherwise disposing of a firearm or ammunition knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that the recipient is prohibited from owning a firearm or ammunition (such as a fugitive, drug addict, person who has been committed to a mental institution, or an individual subject to a court order restraining stalking an intimate partner); (2) traveling from any State or foreign country into another State and acquiring, transferring, or attempting to acquire or transfer a firearm to engage in certain illegal conduct; (3) transferring a firearm, knowing it will be used to commit a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime; and (4) illegally engaging in the business of importing, manufacturing, or dealing in firearms.

Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to amend the Federal sentencing guidelines to raise the base offense level for interstate firearms trafficking and increase the punishment for related violations.

Includes illegal firearms trafficking within the scope of the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act.</summary>
</bill>
