<bill session="108" type="s" number="1845" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:31Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Service to Country Reimbursement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 37, United States Code, to provide financial assistance to State and local governments that continue to pay employees who serve on active duty in a reserve component of the uniformed services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Service to Country Reimbursement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14452-14453"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14453" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="State budgets"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-04T17:33:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Service to Country Reimbursement Act of 2003 - Requires the Secretary of the military department concerned (Secretary), at the request of a State or local government that continues to pay all or a portion of the civilian compensation of an employee while that employee is absent due to a call or order to serve on active military duty for a period of more than 30 days, to reimburse the State or local government up to an amount not to exceed the difference between: (1) the amount of civilian compensation that would otherwise have been payable to the employee if the employee's civilian compensation had not been interrupted by active-duty service; and (2) the amount of military pay that is payable to such employee for the active duty service performed. Requires an employee who fails to return to such civilian employment to refund to the Secretary the total amount of reimbursement provided with respect to that employee, but allows the Secretary to waive such refund requirement if such recovery would be against equity and good conscience or contrary to the best interests of the United States. Requires the Secretary to waive such refund if the failure of the employee to report or apply was due to an injury or disability that is not the fault of the employee.</summary>
</bill>
